so making this video because I first
started writing a blog post about
something that I find important and
interesting that I wanted to share with
you but I realized that the impact of my
words would be far greater through
seeing me and me actually speaking to
you as opposed to writing it so you know
literally sitting here on my couch I put
my laptop down picked up my iPhone and
decided I'm just going to talk this out
to you I spent the last two days hanging
out with eating with training with
speaking with one of the most
interesting people that I've come across
in a very very long time
and and I feel that he and you both
deserve an introduction because he has a
lot of interesting things to share with
you and he'd benefit by you knowing
about how expansive his understanding is
how creative how entertaining he is
because obviously that built is you know
the awareness of him and who he is but
also because it is a gift to you and I'm
speaking about Frank yang and if you're
the type of person that can appreciate
art and all the subjectivity that that
it brings you know it comes from then
you're going to appreciate his style of
sharing the life style of bodybuilding
but also music and deep thoughts
spirituality philosophy he blends so
many things together I think part of the
reason why I enjoyed the past 48 hours
with Frank so much is because he and I
are of kindred spirit in the same way
you know I spend a lot of time lifting
and building the body focused on very
aggressive activity but I also carry a
tenderness with me and that's part of
the reason why so many of you are
attracted to
to listening to means because I come at
you very aggressively but you also sense
a tenderness where you can yield to me
and it allows my words to penetrate a
bit more and I'm grateful for this skill
I'm grateful for you two to dance with
me in this way and and I know when I
find someone else that could possibly
potentially depending on you know we all
have different tastes potentially offer
you something very similar a lot of the
things that he does is far more abstract
than me yeah I'm not nearly as abstract
as Frank yang but the message is the
same a lot of it stems from this desire
to share the dualistic but yet unified
nature of the world and everything that
we do he just happens to be interested
in bodybuilding so he uses the barbell
in many ways to as a metaphor for for
these lessons for these principles of
life and although we're different in our
presentation our essence is very much
the same so I'm going to stop here with
an invitation to check out a video of
his that really I mean it it binds it
all together he calls it the Odyssey of
Frank yang quite the name and I think it
really captures his essence and like I
said is merely an invitation because
number one I feel he deserves an
invitation and and you trust me you know
you're an audience of individuals who
take what I have to say seriously and
I'm serious about how I feel about Frank
and I also believe that he's a gift to
you if you can receive him in this way
he's the getting's very abstract strange
it you know weird if you will but if you
can if you have an artistic poetic side
to you you can you can appreciate it not
everyone will and I don't expect
everyone to but those of you are a
little bit more like I am even though I
you know I come across as very hard
driving an aggressive there's also a
tender soft yin
creative side that I know is a
foundation or driving force for what
makes my presentation so appealing to
you so um you'll receive a lot of the
same from watching Frank but again it's
a bit more abstract not as grounded we
created a lot of videos over the past
couple days that are going to be
uploaded to this channel and into his
channel he's actually creating a profile
documentary on me right ah but uh what
we're looking forward to that and and
I'm looking forward to sharing that the
all the other footage that we created
with you but anyway check out this this
one video if you like it continue to
follow him he's going to create a lot of
more a lot of artistic type stuff that
also has a hint of body building in it
so I think you'll appreciate it talk to
you soon