I got a question here from one of our
friends who has what he calls social
anxiety disorder says he wasn't
diagnosed but he struggles with being in
social situations particularly for the
past two to three years what happens is
he anticipates an engagement with
someone and his heart rate goes up his
hands get real sweaty and then worst of
all is its face turns bright red and it
happens in when he meets new people so
on and so forth so there are a couple
things couple ideas that I'll share with
you the very first one is not to judge
it you know I think most of our anxiety
comes from what's happening in our body
and our judgment placed on it there's a
moral judgment placed on what's
happening in your body what's happening
in your body is never wrong right your
your autonomic nervous system doesn't
fuck up that's the part of your nervous
system that makes your heart rate go up
that makes your eyes dilate that's
making your palms sweat that gives you
an erection that makes your hair grow
that replaces cells in your body it
helps your food digest that makes babies
grow this it's pretty freakin
intelligent and what it does is very
intuitive right if it senses something
it produces a response in your body
either you know there are different
types of responses so that's not the
point of this video so what's happening
is a lot of your anxiety a significant
portion of your anxiety is caused by you
judging what's happening in your body so
I want you to recognize that first just
recognize that it's your moral judgment
placed on the brilliance of the response
that your body's providing you that's
giving you a lot of beef and what you've
got to do is just say fuck it it's not
wrong there's nothing wrong I might not
like it
I've come to to see it as something
that's inappropriate or I don't you know
I just I'm not in favor of it but it is
what it is be with it that's the very
first thing just be with it own it don't
fight it just own it and what you do in
order to have that be the case is just
you know think that way it's mine I'm
owning it this is just what's happening
in my body the second thing you've got
to do
is to completely detach from the
opinions of other people because what's
happening is you know your body is
producing this response to what other
people other people may be responding to
you so you're going into a situation and
the mind it's all about the fucking mind
your minds fucking you the minds judging
the body and it the mind is also going
into it creating the situation by
anticipating that person's response to
you so the second bit of advice or
invitation I would offer you is to even
if you have to be vulgar and it's even
if you have to kind of like separate
yourself from people by saying fuck
everybody else right that's thing you've
got to be a mean person but you've got
to convince yourself that it really
doesn't give a fucking two shits like it
does not matter what other people think
of you it really really really does not
I mean bottom line it does not matter
what other people think of you right I
mean we that's an entire conversation in
and of itself you know and there could
be great debate around it but I'm
offering you this because it's causing
you problems to forget about the
opinions of others those are the first
two things that's setting the groundwork
right see most people want a technique
they want a tip right tip is what right
at the top of the pyramid I'm giving you
the foundation the foundation of that
pyramid is what I just described right
is recognizing the moral judgement
recognizing other people's judgments and
ignoring both and then the tip right
because it all boils down to what's
happening in your body your body is
taking the form of whatever is happening
below you're going to cap it off by
working to breathe deeper calm your
energy down when you're about to
approach someone in a situation so
number one you're going in as a well
grounded and self appreciative person
respecting yourself you're stepping in
also the next foot saying it makes no
difference what other people think of me
not that I'm a hateful person or a
rebellious person towards them I'm just
detached and third is the tip is the
technique focus on breathing into your
belly if you find that you start to rise
so what it is it always is the case your
energy starts to rise right why do you
think your face is turning red why do
you think it faces turning red and your
feet don't turn red right right
why don't your balls turn red right you
might not know anyway right what do you
do peeking your pants
why don't your knees turn red why
doesn't your your nipples turn red right
what the fuck look why is it your face
turning red because all of your energy
is completely rising and it can't go
anywhere is gonna go that your skull is
literally the container for all of your
energy where's gonna go go it's gonna
explode out of your head right that type
of release would probably be something
like crying or yelling or screaming
that's the only where the Energy's gonna
be released from your face but don't let
it rise keep it down low
notice if you're getting tense in your
neck notice beginning tense in your face
chest
notice if you're getting tense in your
solar plexus your belly your hands your
legs your butt you're holding your butt
cheek together notice all the muscles in
your body and keep them relaxed and then
come back to your breath right even as
that other person's talking you're
getting ready to say something that
individual speak slowly and speak from
your balls that's what I mean when I say
this I mean speak from a place of
grounded energy bring your energy down
into your belly take a deep breath relax
your shoulders and breathe I promise you
that if you build a foundation that I
described and use that breathing
technique you are going to be masterful
in your approach your social situations
with other people so that's a dude good
luck
Elliot's it what