so I got a pretty typical question from
a high school kid here by the age of 16
he's at the age of 16 and he wants to
quit high school so our friend goes on
says that he's a sophomore in high
school and he is not that he's not a
good student it's just that he feels
that he's wasting his time in high
school he'd much rather go and pursue
his passion of strength-training right
and he's heard Elliott Hulse say things
like the ills and indoctrination
associated with our compulsory education
system is all fucked up and things of
that nature you know my rants against
college and university education and
stuff like that will make no mistake I'm
going to preface this entire
conversation around the fact that there
is a big difference between schooling
and education make no mistake the
education is right at the top of my list
of values in fact I'll turn my camera
round for a moment you can see this that
is my library you see that that's one of
my libraries the one that happened to
having my gym again if you look at my
desk
I've got boats inanimate books and all
types of stuff right so I want you to
understand the reason why I decided to
turn the camera around give me a moment
what you understand that I value
education to a very great degree like I
said it's right at the top there so when
you hear me say these things you got to
understand that it means that the
schooling system is designed in such a
way that it doesn't allow you to
maximize the amount of any true
education that you could have if you
were to self educated now here's the
thing most people I'm going to say 95%
of the people that I've ever met are not
self motivated enough and I've never met
a 16 year old although you may be unique
you know when you may be gifted that is
self motivated enough to shut out all
the distractions including television
Internet and all the other crap
girlfriends so that they can educate
themselves to such a degree that you are
great at something you've got to be
fucking awesome and about what you at
what you're about to approach if you're
going to just abandon ship with
everything else and then go do it
so my father used to say to me my father
was big on education my father's the
first generate I'm a first-generation
American my father came here from Belize
and the one thing he hammered into our
heads was you got to get an education
you got to get an education you got to
get an education he understood that
education was the key to any type of
success that you were going to have in
America and that's why he came to
America and raised his family here and
we constantly be telling us to read read
books read books read books and I hated
it I hated school I hated reading books
I hated him for forcing me to do this
shit but what I didn't understand then
and I understand now and a great deal of
the success that you see me have is due
to the brainwashing that my father
afforded me which is educate yourself
educate yourself educate yourself the
thing is I realized that educating
yourself and going to school or two
totally different things and I'm not
going to go into that rant today so my
advice to you my 16 year old friend who
wants to drop out of school and wants to
pursue his passion is number one just
for the sake of achievement I'm going to
invite you to stick it out it's only two
fucking years more two years it's
nothing it really is nothing it may seem
like a lot to you at 16 but trust me
blink of an eye it's over if you really
just cannot stand it and you believe
that you're self motivated enough I
would say homeschool yourself I'm in the
United States we've got in many states
in the United States I'm not sure if all
of them do you've got Internet school I
think if you go to k12 comm in my city
at least k12 comm all the great or the
curriculums for all the school grades
are in there and you can go and take a
test and get your diploma you know you
can go to get your GED is one of the
things a lot of kids that didn't
graduate high school did
some sort of achievement under your belt
associated with the traditional path
right if you decide you want to go to
college or not totally different story
totally different conversation but being
16 I say get your GED or go to
homeschooling or just suck it up and use
the next two years if you happen to be a
genius right not bragging but my young
my oldest daughter happens to be pretty
brilliant and I've shared the idea with
her that perhaps she could skip high
school by studying her ass off and
getting her diploma at home and that way
I can teach her other things to do but
you know it's neither here nor there
that's me and my interesting ideas for
life or crazy ideas right so that's it
beyond just approaching it so that you
make that it you have that achievement
of graduating getting that piece of
paper cultivate and test yourself on the
type of self motivation that you have
and then you have to become great at
something not good enough not a warm
body not a mechanical part in a machine
but fucking awesome at something that
you can then go and serve the
marketplace with it because really if
you have nothing to serve people with
then you're no you're of no use you're
useless that's another thing my dad used
to say it say don't be useless
don't be freaking useless he would say
this person is useless go you see this
guy my dad do you think I'm crazy here
my dad talk you say look at this guy
he's useless and they would say it to
him right in space this guy's useless
what good is what uses he right and it's
not to say that people are pieces of
meat that are meant for production but
you've got to be able to serve people
that's your only value in this world how
were you serving people so you you enjoy
strength how are you going to serve
people through the idea of strength that
should be at the top of your mind and
recognize that you can't serve people in
an effective and efficient way if you're
not great you're not awesome if you're
not the best at
Eliot said what