so our buddy cross that's as a screen
name says that he for 10 years he's been
addicted to video games and it's it's
really it's destroying his life because
he doesn't go out anymore and all he
won't he's literally addicted this thing
he doesn't go out he's good at sports
apparently he's gifted in playing
football and he loves football but he
won't even go do that anymore now this
sound that might sound silly to some of
you guys you know oh you fucking loser
just turned off the video games and go
outside and play it's easy to say shit
like that it's easy to give advice and
just be like hey just man up and go and
do it but I totally get it dude I
understand you're you're physically
physiologically emotionally addicted to
this shit and I know why it can be
because you're literally living in an
abstract world you all of your personal
identification with the characters in
the game tie you up with it's like
you're living in the video game I
understand we had and I see a lot of
people that happens to that's my rant on
video games laughing so I see a lot of
my friends I'm like dude your life sucks
because you won't turn that fucking
thing off but anyway so he wants to know
how do I break free of this addiction
it's just like any other addiction you
know we just addicted to cigarettes or
whatever the case may be talking to a
friend yesterday and we're talking about
how is it that some people can can
advance in life how is it that some
people can move forward and some people
just seem stuck they're just stuck in
their life they're stuck in mediocrity
they're stuck in the the comfort that
the zone that they've created for
themselves it's because the we as human
beings need one of two things it's
always going to be one of two things and
the first is the one that I'm going to
tell you you're going to need to do you
need either a tragedy or you need a goal
so big that it draws you it pulls you
out of bed it's much more difficult to
be pulled towards something then I have
something chasing your ass right so you
need a tragedy you need something that's
like biting you at your ass you know
it's much easier to run when a dog is
chasing you and nipping at your ass then
running towards a prize you know you get
you give to people you give one person
two options and or you put them into
different circumstances one
dogs chasing is s he's gonna run you're
gonna fuckin run because it's a tragedy
or you can get your ass bit and then you
put a million dollars at the at the end
of another one that guy's going to run
too but you know if you know this
ability knowledge is going to be there
he's not gonna run nearly as fast or
with as much what's that word like you
know intensity there's a guy that's
getting his ass bit so you've got to
create a situation and I'm gonna tell
you what to do yeah it's going to be the
most irresponsible advice you've ever
heard me get but it's the only one
that's going to make you do what you
have to do because I know that you can't
reach otherwise you would have reached
it's been ten years you're not going
you're not a goal person and to be quite
frankly to be quite frank it's difficult
for even myself at times I don't have
something nipping at my ass oh why go
after something right you've got a
really like brainwash yourself to do
that that's a different story but anyway
bro you need to literally pick up your
video game machine smash it the fucking
pieces walk out your house get in your
car and go live in your car go somewhere
go go check into a homeless shelter you
need to shake up your life like it's
never been shook up before go and you
know I'm being extreme here but go live
with your grandmother just just smash
your video game machine go live with
your grandmother and you have nothing
now now you have no choice because you
have no comfort and you have no
stability and you have nothing but I got
to get off my ass go and live with your
grandmother is going to be it's gonna be
too easy you really need to go where
create a situation where you sink or
swim and you learn how to swim
you've got to place yourself in the
midst of a storm and it's got to be a
self created storm otherwise you know
most people have to wait till the shit
comes crumbling down before they they
take action in life I'm inviting you to
create a shitstorm for yourself so that
you will be motivated by the wolf crying
at the door by the dog nipping at your
ass by the fire under your ass all right
dude so if there's no nice way to do
this right rip the fucking band-aid off
throw yourself off the cliff and learn
how to fly on the way down