so we got this question from our buddy
Christian who in his work environment
there's a woman there's a girl and they
switched shifts so basically she comes
in in the morning around 7:00 he's on
his way out but they sit and they chat
for about 20-30 minutes they've been
doing this for several months and the
chats just keep getting warmer and
warmer she giggles and he tells a joke
and they're flirting and Christian is
feeling as if like you know we're kind
of falling in love here but it's really
awkward because she has a boyfriend all
right and one of the conversations that
starts coming up right now now I'm
starting to teach you the lesson right
because that was a situation you guys
are all cuddly and cozy with each other
you see each other for 20 minutes a day
and then you go by your day but the
conversation whenever the conversation
with a woman goes towards what her
current relationship is like and how
she's dissatisfied a red flag should go
up because that is a very poor taste and
is an indication of character weakness
and that being said it's usually a
fucking trap now I'm not saying she's a
bad woman or the relationship with her
is going to be a trap but what she's
doing is she's creating a situation that
is appealing to all men no matter what
and that is damsel-in-distress
oh oh a dragon has me I mean it's
fucking fairy tales hello the ugly troll
has seized me under the bridge come and
save me hero that's what they fucking do
and it's just it's inherent in the
sexual energies so she talking shit
about her boyfriend and calling him
garbage and you use that term also don't
get caught up with it right you want to
leave him out of it as much as you can
because she could potentially just be
playing a fucking game right we need to
get that clear first we need to figure
out what she's up to
right because you know you don't know
her that well so you've known her for a
few years but this sort of dance that
you're doing with her is fairly new
maybe a year I think he said fine don't
judge her boyfriend because he might be
a pretty cool fucking dude that she's
tripping on right now all right so don't
get caught up in that
story don't let her drag you down that
fairy tale of damsel in distress come
save me right because that tugs on your
balls it tugs on your heart in your
balls it's very it's very visceral right
you don't think when you see a damsel in
distress or a woman who's in distress Oh
right you want to save her right away
don't be a fucking saver do not be her
Savior
not saying that you can't move forward
with her and I'm going to give you very
practical steps to see what that might
look like I'm sure she's a good girl I'm
sure she things might turn out really
well with you but don't get caught up in
her bullshit right don't drink her
kool-aid so the situation is that you
guys are growing closer and worming with
one another she has a boyfriend talk
shit about the boyfriend either here no
there you want to figure out how you can
move forward with him right and this is
how you do it without being a
homewrecker cuz I know that's your
concern and as it should be she hasn't
she hasn't fooled you so much to believe
that like you know he's a douche bag I'm
gonna save her good you're a smart guy
you got to get out of that environment
where you've got 20 30-minute shots of
each other passing right that's all it's
been then you know what you might not
love her as much as you love that
routine see there's a pattern and
environments create patterns there's a
pattern of behavior she comes in you see
each other you smile you talk boom you
need to break that pattern to see what
she's like in other circumstances so in
a very neutral way obviously we're
pursuing but you haven't done anything
yet you haven't professed your love
you're not trying to kiss her you go and
you meet somewhere else coffee real
neutral go for coffee go for you know
lunch something definitely not dinner
lunch or coffee or a walk in the park
we're just going to go for a walk in the
park would you like to go for a walk not
drinks after work like Toby Keith would
say ah that that sends all types of
signals get her into a situation where
you guys can see each other speak to
each other in a different light
something might happen it could go one
of two ways you see her in this new
light and all of a sudden you're like
ah I didn't know you were like that or
you're going to be like oh my god I just
love her that much more look at the way
she is with her dog look at the way she
is when she's pushing children on the
swing look at the way she sips coffee
whatever the fuck it is you're going to
fall deeper in love with it right so now
you've got a broader perspective of this
woman right you need this you need this
in order to take the next step okay so
that's that's what you do then this is
this is my invitation it's my idea for
you if you decide after a few moments
like that you know maybe two three times
that you're like dude I want this woman
I want her I want her to be mine
whatever that means to you you want to
be with her you want to have her and
she's in this situation where she's said
she's unhappy but you got to test that
there okay and you've got to be very
practical with her you see emotion
sometimes although you're in love
emotions have to be set aside to get
shit done and you're going to use
emotion to manipulate her wrong word but
to sway her persuade her but you're
going to do it in a very practical way
for yourself just for your own
understanding and so that you could
either go on with your life or you can
get what you want
either way it's what you want you want
to go on with your life if she doesn't
she doesn't respond to this the way we'd
like her to buy her something beautiful
that she can wear preferably a bracelet
or a necklace not a ring a beautiful
bracelet you know
or necklace and you know what spend a
little bit more on this because if she's
not the right one you'll get it back and
you can always take it back to the
fucking store so if you got to spend a
thousand dollars or more you know do it
think of it as sort of like a you know
what do they do like a holding you know
it's in holding insurance buy this
beautiful diamond bracelet and say to
her one day I have something really
important that I want to give to you but
only if you're willing to accept it
she's gonna be all curious Oh what is it
oh of course
let me know then you go and you open it
up and you say to her I want you to have
this and she's gonna look at it she's
gonna be like oh my god where did this
come from
oh oh I want you to have this but only
if you'll be mine and you're basically
giving her an ultimatum in a very
heartfelt way because you want to share
something beautiful with her I want to
share your love with her but the piece
of jewelry is just symbolic that's all
it is it's just a symbol you know
obviously the more beautiful it is the
more
dazzle she'll be so it's kind of like an
illusion but it's symbolic and you you
know you let her put it on or whatever
the case may be if she decides to it
that way I just watched the video and I
changed my mind
don't give her the opportunity to put on
the bracelet or not put it on her right
so whatever it is that you buy don't
don't just open it and show it to her
take it out and put it on her wrist or
put it on her neck and then have the
conversation because that's what'll
happen is she'll embody your words that
much more she'll it'll feel more because
she'll the whole time she'll be looking
at it and feeling it on her you want her
to feel you do you understand by putting
the bracelet on her she's going to feel
what you're about to say about a lot
more okay cool and you explain the
conditions you say listen I want you to
have this but I I feel that you need to
end it with your boyfriend I know that
you need to end it with your
boyfriend if you're going to continue
moving forward with me if you don't want
to or you don't have the courage to
break up with them that's fine I just
need to know by you wearing this when
she leaves why are you taking this with
you you're essentially saying that you'd
like to move forward with me if not we
can leave it here until you're ready
right and there's a good chance she
might say she might take it off or she
might not put it on wait till she's
ready give her and you got to be kind of
diplomatic with this give her a set
amount of time before she gives you the
yes other no right if she takes it at
that moment she's like yes I'm going
home to break up with him oh I love you
hmm then you're good move what if she's
like she's stuck right she needs to
either sack up just fucking grow some
balls right it sounds strange writing
for a woman but she needs to she needs
to toughen up and break up with her
boyfriend that she doesn't love if
that's the case or she needs to come
clean with you and say you know the
truth is I'm not breaking up with my
boyfriend I never will I enjoy your
company it's been nice and don't let her
tease you any longer don't let you don't
to be caught up in that you don't want
to be led any longer and then it's over
but if she's standing on the fence give
her a little bit of time to stand on
that fence I wouldn't let it last any
more than a week you know and you don't
have to say it that way you could just
say hey you know what next Saturday why
don't we meet here again and then you
could tell me what you've decided right
it sounds a lot better than you've got
one week bitch
ha ha you know you don't have to like
belly ultimatum if she's not sure just
say you know what take your time why
don't we meet back here next week and we
can we can talk about it a little bit
more you gave her a week if after a week
it doesn't seem like anything's going to
budge then you need to basically take
that back get your money back and just
be
piece with her you know she comes in
just you know what talk but you can't
let your feelings go any further because
you're just you're getting dragged along
you know they call that pussy lips you
don't want to be pussy whipped she
doesn't want you she's playing with you
don't get caught up in that it's ugly
do you see ugly for you ugly for her
ugly for the whole situation just move
on it's difficult Eliot house always
says that you should move with your
heart move with your feelings move but
you know what like I said also today
sometimes you got to use your fucking
head in order to to place boundaries so
that you don't hurt yourself or other
people right you've done the best you
could you got to cut it off so that's it
dude good luck I'm done