when you do that when you go to us you
should end up like a band I can
disappear before you can't go anymore
slay it all out exhaust the body
completely completely exhausted it'll
hold anything oh no oh baby that is let
it all out then class I saw you before
next senator you let it all out that's
how your last the bioenergetic tension
in the body because it's neurotic
holding patterns it's we're doing it
does that make sense we're doing it
you're holding it and the best way to
release the whole angle is to exhaust
the body go ducks you did a little bit
of a temper tantrum yesterday all right
Tony getting involved right all your
tensions up in your head that's why you
had want to stay stay on adjusting it
story except attention when the head is
like this and use constantly yeah and it
shows in your movement so someone who
doesn't want to let go who stole my
orgasm dance video now work as advanced
with y Gasset days of like if you wanna
know a woman orgasms if she's give you
go to a dance club the girl attentions
like this she can have full orgastic
release was their life
hey it will be a little something but if
you want a girl that's uh watch your
dance the reason why it's metaphoric but
it's literal it's so funny like I
described this and I keep a tight ass
yeah really connects letting go is the
hands losing her head and grounded she's
willing to be earthly gravity sexual as
well as let go let go of the ego like
over the Vice really ahead go and just
be free you doing right she's gonna get
let go so with you your your cheeks are
red yeah so it's all held up right here
that's the reason we know that you got a
band attention right here so you're
charging and it stays right there you're
even kind of loose down here your belly
read all attention is here so when you
threw the temper tantrum you know if you
listen if you look at a child into a Sun
potential which the temper tantrum is
like is a right
it's all right the human being to
protest it is it's the first protest
it's a temper tantrum and if you want to
have free thinking creative children
give them the option to protest nothing
that they're going to get their way all
the time because the reason why the
protest sense is like no you can't have
ice cream for breakfast so doesn't give
them the way but you give them the right
to protest war protest don't tell them
this is just my experience get up from
there straight up and don't make that
noise you want to protest protest good
luck of ice cream for breakfast but
throw a temper tantrum if you watch a
child to attend to its the hole
ah fuck you fuck you see the difference
let the head go let it go check it out
lorem it doesn't need to be muffle time
the body is intelligent enough it does a
shitload without that your mom let it go
to not let your head go your body made
its public blood digesting food creating
themselves your woman I believe another
human being inside doing a shitload of
stuff would have to have a think about
it will become so attached can't let go
you just started
more tape and I feel like most of my and
that only gets a point where I know what
I'm
share of myself
I just constantly
well I'll share my experience and then
offer some insight I was just as tense
as you were what apply to my stomach I
tend to vote for attention like I like
Otto does in the belly I butterflies for
probably a year maybe longer I could not
breathe deep why I'm not as heavy as you
maybe what I held a lot of tension it
was here I actually that's what I
discovered that I had a bacterial
infection kind of makes sense because
I'm reduced by the energy in that part
of my body it was malnourished you know
how you felt like wow let us come in
here now imagine which you don't have to
imagine you have for decades or four in
my case here not getting the nourishment
the Chinese call it cheap a lot of
people you know say that's bullshit call
ready boy one cheap but there's no cheap
that area because and everybody I don't
think I everybody your survival it's
like I mean you're you're proceeding
from most base the emotion most what you
need you know hiker message hierarchy of
needs safety and security private
association I mean self-actualization
which is HIPAA world after some strokes
version something to pay up at the top
if you don't have what Matt little
describes as safety and security then
the way you know if you're
if you're moving from a place of safety
and security the sympathetic nervous
system is on your dreidels our fri or by
turning and you're doing the best
chicken to control a situation with your
head yeah while shutting off the body
because the body is more attuned to
pleasure lies one opportunity to
relaxing parasympathetic rest and digest
brain is very sympathetic so my
experience was that I was in a
sympathetic state like you for quite a
few years not knowing what to do when
I'm just freaking doing just going going
going going no family my daughter and my
wife or mortgage to start this is like a
bloody poof like food okay much less
than warriors survival
the turning point was when a friend
shared a CD with me actually I can say
that the foundation for that for my
success it will ability to get out of
that was I brainwash myself Brian
Tracy's love backup CD listen to it over
and over and over again just like
positive application but then a friend
shared holistic talk about how ol same
ol same protection he said I didn't know
anything about meditation I do each
other better take I can't even stop
thinking it like for two seconds it was
like just listen to me CDs man just do
it just put it on once a day it would be
pretty you listen to it and it's just
they just out of the grand rain and wind
okay I trust you so I'm doing so I
listened to these cities for every study
single day for about 30 days and
normally my behavior was neurotic you
know thinking going up doing and it's
always coming from a place of
nervousness it's always more fun place
of survival so one day I'm sitting down
after I've been doing for a while sit
down on the couch and there's no tension
in my body I'm breathing relaxed not
worry buddy and I freaked out
what's going on I felt so weird because
I was relaxed it was no tension in my
body I don't know why oh and not only
that because what happens is neuron
patterns like this if there is no
tension in the body your brain antenna
feel like we were increasing attention
because you're in a constant sympathetic
state and to become due soon and he's
doing there you you're there all the
time so when you move out a bit more
people if you have an opportunity about
it besides getting hammered drink
everybody relax that when you move out
of it you freak out cuz you're like oh
my god I just let go it's almost like
let go of the reins what you think
you're doing is holding on to the reins
of the horse and when you realize that
drop the rain to the horse which do
freak out this guy did animal this
animal is taking over and that's what
happened through the meditation the
jockey you follow my analogies the
jockey let go of the reins and the horse
started galloping but the horse was a
fucking beautiful brilliant Beast that
knew where to go what to do so the
minute that the job he realized that he
let go of the reins you freaked out you
who's going continues like grains
freaked out did whatever you can do to
ground again then you realize the jockey
goes horse is doing pretty good did a
good job and started fighting here and
any time I stop meditating I started
going like this try to grab wings again
and you know what happens when I got the
reins divorce and I'm stressed out
because I'm trying to steer this one
horse the horse is not able to do what
it wants to do because of course is
brilliant and the horse feels better
than the jockey because the horse
understand
follow my analogies are probably to do
so through the meditation I was able to
let go and when I let go and let the
force steer the direction take me where
I was going to go and I'm scary stuff
because the horse is asking me to do
some weird shit like a horse told me the
horse head hey honey you don't have
enough on your bread right now but I
think you can come up with two thousand
dollars a month to pay off credit card
debt and your mortgage Oh your wife
spreading the words told me this and I
was like oh thanks jacoub like goddamn
force that does make sense him to be
grabbed great but because i was able to
let go the jockey to try to grab the
reins and the horse intuitively guiding
the situation and said yes let's do this
okay 2000 hours a month fucking couple
2000 hours month i couldnt and a visit
family and mortgage couldn't pay for
anything before the horse Satan did
everybody get this or might like smoke
the point is that you gotta find a way
to trust the horse yeah no beast in you
silly make a describer let me go with
the reins and it's scary because you've
been holding on to the Ranger so long
but you're doing a lot of right things
you've got your clearly creative and
intuitive but get comfortable let me go
and the only way I couldn't let go with
the meditation not selling anything
monitor Philly the whole thing I just an
idea to be completely their artists it's
what got me to relax let the board scary
situation and now my animal care exactly
that's why I'm so weird in a lot of ways
of course tell what it always wants to
do you know every once in a while I have
to like pull back the horse of
embarrassing
but more plus actually that's where i'm
at right now is and I can empathize I
know what it's like trying to get things
to happen and thinking that you got
stable horse got even and got tighten up
you got all that shit is just an achy
tired and make more pissed off and this
is ancient ship that sounds not like
like mystical very very weird a little
shit but this is like and I'm not a
Christian my quote Bible but often
because it was pretty good shape it's
kind of like removes I talking to Mike
the other day yeah where Christ says be
like the birds of the field who are fed
regardless of what they do you want you
think I feed you and be like the lilies
we've never toured over spit but yet I
feed them with the Rays of the lights
and so poetic stuff I'm told Jesus stuff
but it's like white shit I've
experienced it not just repo'd home
strip shit just full description it's
like able to that was a neurotic about
that life pulp fiction this is my
experience my experience is what Jesus
said that birds
flowers work
easier said than done breathing deep
dancing like a maniac crazy has such a
visit meditating being free is
essentially metaphorically letting go of
the reins you gotta find a way you'll
fly if it works for you what my
experience is the meditation biogenic
sighs temper tantrums
admit i think i am holding off holding
patterns
kick and scream get it out laughs
divided we free the force guide take one
No
now is that helpful though I mean if
you're in a situation where would you
still there only parents i can offer you
these dresses just ideas
eh it's just such a science buildings
just flexible do it fuck you want to do
sure
one of the things I find helpful please
to put yourself
it's cool so I hope you said if you
tomorrow who better character how ya
doing that contributes
you got going on
will be challenged let me just gross you
work at a gym right we got shower shower
you got a call what do you want what he
limited them with a lot of time you jump
off the deep end that's when you are
asked with friends said to me the other
day she said I jump in and learn how to
fly a lot of times I only way in nature
you look at like birds eagles when put
them up with the weather recognized to
the bigs have wings you know what they
do sometimes I've done it I've done a
lot size of utility I put my child with
no glides and a mortgage my family and
it was just like
it was nerve-racking yeah but it's the
only way sometimes when there's a back
door or sometimes when it's still a
little comfortable but it's like it's
still Europe you still kind of like
supplement it
a little little too comfortable to take
some risks my experience has been
beautiful
that's what life is
grown-up more comfortable said
culture that's all about comfort
secure safety
haha that's the biggest lot a solas
really safe it'll be safe about living
on this rock it's spinning at millions
of miles an hour and going around a ball
of fire you think insurance is going to
take care yeah I have your fucking steak
so that's what's countries based on
livery 30 that's what you say
do whatever you want