yo Eliot hey what's up guys today we got
a question from our truck camp online
member Tom who goes on to say that he
has a hard time being aggressive
especially with other men he explains
how at school that there are other boys
who step up and they're really
aggressive and they can really go after
him in particular and he wants to know
how can I be aggressive to how is it
that they feel ok in their bodies being
this way towards others and I shrink and
shrivel they come at him he shrinks and
shrivels in fact he says that he tried a
boxing kickboxing and he says I get so
freaked out in competition that I just
puke and pass out he can't bring himself
to to that type of aggression where he
can really go out and lash out even
makes reference to some of the my videos
where I described how when I was you
know kid I would get into fights and
stuff and I go I go attack people I
think what needs to be understood is
that there is a distinction between
aggression you gotta understand what
aggression is the aggression is merely
the opposite of regression right all
grass is to move forward regress is to
move backward so any any activity that's
associated with moving forward is
aggressive right so I mean you are being
aggressive right every time you you get
out of bed you walk to the refrigerator
and putting something your in your mouth
your aggressing you're moving towards
something that you want right and
assertiveness the difference between
being aggressive going out and being
assertive assertive means knowing what
you want and setting up boundaries
right so being assertive means this is
what I'll stand for this is what I
expect this is what I I believe in and
these are the boundaries associated with
it you see so I'm not don't think you
need to be any more aggressive meaning
you know you've got just the right
amount of aggression in you to get what
you need in life right you can get out
of bed you can go to the refrigerator
you're at school you can study you can
you can you can work out in the gym
these are all moving towards activities
you can set a goal and you can achieve
it
being assertive with other people is
going to be very important so what
you're going to have to make in and it
requires quite a bit of communication
what it will require is that you are
clear about what you hold valuable
meaning what you will and won't stand
for and where those boundaries are I'm
doing this you can't see this right this
is this is assertiveness assertiveness
is saying I'm here and here's my
boundary this is what I'm about and
these are the walls by which you shall
not cross it has nothing to do with
attacking anybody it has everything to
do with standing your ground and when
you have these muscle knuckleheads I
don't wanna say muscle heads because I'm
a muscle head these knuckleheads write
that for whatever reason they feel like
they want to pick on you they want to
aggress themselves wards you got to
understand too that they've got their
own problems
what you've got to do is make it very
clear where your boundaries are you
might not want to fight you might want
to make it very clear to them that I'm
not going to fight you I have no
interest in fighting you but if you
cross this boundary I will make your
life miserable do you understand so if
he wants to aggress himself towards you
and you set up that boundary and he
still disrespects that boundary well
then you make it very clear what you're
going to do you come any you come one
step closer now bite the shit out of you
all right I mean no how can you defend a
a bite right I mean you do what you have
to fucking do to make sure that boundary
is not crossed let him know you cross
this boundary I promise you might kick
my ass but you're gonna hurt right get
him later
tell him to it's not sneaky when you
tell him you cross that boundary and you
come one step closer to me I'm going to
grab your computer and throw it out the
window I'm going to slash all your tires
you see I'm going to have sex with your
girlfriend right you'd really love that
then you really fucking attack you so
set up boundaries make
very clear where those boundaries are
and what will happen if they're crossed
and hold them to it go ahead come on I
think the movie is a Shawshank
Redemption where the the guys in jail
you know he's kind of like a he's a
softer feminine kind of guy and you know
there's a bunch of thugs in there and
one of the things they were going to
make him do was give him a blowjob by
the way this is my new neighbor
so one of the things that the you know
the thugs that were in the jail were
going to make him do because he was kind
of a passive guy was give him a blowjob
and and he said that well okay if you
make me do this I guarantee you that
your life will be miserable because I
will bite your dick off something to
that effect was like yes I'll do it go
ahead make me force me but you'll lose
your dick so tell those boys come at me
motherfucker please do cross this
boundary so that you can lose your dick
done Elliott sit what