so gotta get questions because it's one
that most people struggle with even I've
struggled with and at times still
struggle with but there is a resourceful
solution to it and that is self-doubt
how do you deal with proceeding in life
if you're always doubting your ability
to do the next thing
without going into a lengthy rant about
how we are conditioned to doubt
ourselves and why people doubt us and
why there's so much heaviness being
placed on what would be an expression of
our true selves are the strongest
version of ourselves it's always being
stuffed down by others and then
ultimately by ourselves and that's
what's happening self-doubt how do you
remedy do this how do you how you handle
something how do you get rid of it you
don't get rid of self-doubt through the
same means by which you learned it and
that is in the head self-doubt is purely
a head created phenomenon you were
taught it and you do it to yourself
your heart and your balls have a
brilliance to them that allow them to do
some magnificent shit without this guy
getting in the way and that's what it
means when you get in your own way
that's what self-doubt is the fastest
band-aid ripped off remedy to fixing
this terrible situation is to do the
thing you're afraid to do do it it's not
about feeling confident about going into
the situation it's not about knowing
that it's going to work out it's not
about having the most detailed plan for
how this thing will happen it's about
doing it courage you get Courage's what
you will experience and what you will
grow when the doubt is there but you do
it anyway so your problem isn't doubt
your problem is courage doubt is going
to be there but doubt gets out of the
way when you express courage right doubt
is like it's burned off by courage Ralph
Waldo Emerson said do
the thing and you will have the power
we're waiting waiting waiting waiting
for the power waiting not to self doubt
any longer right whatever it is that
you're deciding that you want to do with
yourself that you're doubting your
ability on just do it fuck it up
completely that's another thing that
you've got to get through your mind is
that success is not doing the right
thing and it definitely isn't doing the
right thing the first time success is
having the courage to move in the
direction of your dreams move in a
direction that your heart is taking you
that is what success is as you are
progressively realizing that thing
people think success is I've got a plan
and I go and work out that plan it never
ever ever ever ever works that way
success is the progressive realisation
of a worthy goal but progressive
realization means that you're doing
things that you don't know how to do
you're stepping out in faith you're
being courageous your self-doubt will
step out of the way when you build the
balls to do the thing and the power will
be added to you