so this morning I posted a picture of a
book that I'm now reading or listening
to on my Facebook Wall it's a book by
paulo coelho and if you've watched
enough my videos you know that i highly
recommend his books they're fictional
and they're probably the only fiction
books that i read they're fantastic and
they've been supportive to me on
becoming the strongest version of myself
and a big part of my mission is to
simply share the resources that have
supported me and growing stronger in
hopes that perhaps they could support
you and I don't ever I don't expect
everyone to have the same experience or
two or to receive all of these gifts
they're not for everyone but anyway one
of the comments that I received on the
picture was from a gentleman through
what I believe was his truest sentiment
from his heart says be careful when
reading this author and of course the
very first reaction in my body is
defense and it's just you know who I am
it's what I'm working with but instantly
I began to think to myself why would
somebody say something like this what
exactly is his particular superstition
so of course I begin with prejudice and
I think boy you know what kind of
superstition is this guy holding on to
that doesn't allow him to expose himself
to any ideas you see the greatest form
of of slavery is the barring off of
particular ideas that might perhaps
embolden you to take action in the
direction in a direction that perhaps
others would tell you no don't do it you
know they set up their own rules and
their own boundaries and for whatever
reason they feel as if they need to
subject you to those rules and
boundaries and in order to keep those
rules and boundaries stable you've got
to keep people ignorant you've got to
keep them blinded from particular ideas
and that's why in my model of personal
development you do not reject any ideas
before exploring them fully nothing is
off limits when it comes to trying to
find gems of wisdom that might be hidden
under all types of strange rocks
nothing is off-limits if it has a
potential to help you grow and become
the strongest version himself regardless
of where it comes from or what it's
called you have to experience this so
then I began thinking about what should
be off limits what things should we not
subject ourselves to what ideas should
we not expose ourselves to and I often
say things like don't listen to to music
that is aggressive or not even
aggressive aggressive is a beautiful
thing but violent violence is an ugly
thing violent or watch movies that are
violent and then I began to think you
know when I say these things they're
merely my experience and a better way
for me to simply place this is when
you're growing stronger when you're
becoming a stronger version of yourself
you'll find that your body rejects
certain things without you having to
think about it there's a sense of
intuition and awareness that you now
carry with yourself in your physiology
in your heart in your gut that doesn't
require you to reject anything or to be
cautious at all because in the same way
that if you ingest rotten milks boiled
nasty milk you don't have to be very
cautious because your body will
instantly reject it that is the
brilliance of your body it knows that an
intuitive level what is poisonous to it
the same it is the same is it it goes
with ideas exposure to ideas there are
some ideas that when you're exposed to
your body simply rejects without you
having to do anything about it so when I
hear music or I watched or their movies
that are being played in my vicinity you
know there's music that's played in my
vicinity that simply doesn't resonate
with my physiology I don't have to be
vigilant my body simply rejects it I
don't listen to it I don't hear it it
could be playing blasting in my ears but
I don't hear it so
when I say these things like exposing
yourself to violent music might not
allow you to become a stronger version
yourself I'm wrong when I say that what
I really mean to say is in the same way
that Jesus describes the kingdom it
isn't so much a Dow Alton thou shalt not
but this is what you'll experience when
you find the kingdom this is what you'll
experience when you become a stronger
version of yourself you'll experience
that your body will instantly reject
certain things without you having to do
so and there is no need for vigilance
there are certain ideas that you'll be
exposed to that you're simply not ready
for and there's no need to reject it you
just set it aside okay especially if
those ideas seem to be working for other
people and you know if ideas are working
for other people by the look in their
eyes not the station that they carry in
life or what they call themselves but by
the look in their eyes and the smile on
their face clearly that idea is working
for you but it'll not ready for it right
now that doesn't require rejection it
requires sensitivity and openness so how
do you come to this place where you
begin trusting your heart and your body
your physiology your gut as opposed to
always having to stand vigilant and
never allowing yourself to be exposed to
certain things that might nourish you
even though you've been told that
they're evil or wrong or to be cautious
against it the answer is simple it's the
one that I often offer that is to
breathe into your balls and when I say
this i don't necessarily mean that you
need to have a set of testicles what I
mean is that you come home to the
awareness of your body and recognize
whether or not your body is unready for
a particular idea simply rejecting an
idea which means you don't need to do
anything your body just rejects it you
could be told a certain thing thousand
times you could be exposed to a certain
thing a thousand times but it won't get
through because you're not ready for it
we say get through but really
it's not getting through your body and
then there are those ideas that
revolutionize you through courage and
passion and the minute you're exposed to
it you know that it's for you not
because of who told you it's for you not
because of anything except for the fact
that you're emboldened your heart rate
goes up your body feels a sense of
excitement and all you want to do is
dive deeper and deeper and deeper into
the idea until it takes over your life
and transforms you from the inside out
and then all you can do is share that
experience with other people because you
know that it supported you on becoming a
strongest version of yourself that is an
act of love but when you hold so tight
to that experience and the place where
you receive that experience that you
begin forcing it on other people you
start telling them how this is the way
and this is the only way look at what
I've experienced now you're being
violent be vigilant my friends yes but
be vigilant that you come that you
always retain yourself be vigilant that
you're always in tune with yourself be
vigilant that you always trust yourself
and be vigilant that you could hear the
voice in your body louder than the
voices from the outside done