so I'm in a nice restaurant last week
it's me my wife and my four children
I've got three daughters ages 7 23 and
I've got one and a half year old son so
we slip into the restaurant of course
people are a little disturbed by the
sight of seeing all these children come
in but anyway we slip into a booth we're
sitting down and we're deciding on what
we want to eat my seven-year-old
daughter starts doing this while she's
in her seat the people next to us
started living us some weird looks and
my wife becomes uncomfortable so I tell
her Kyle relax let her do what she's
doing she's discharging her energy
better that she discharges her energy
than a trapping fuck what other other
people are thinking her whether or not
they are disturbed by the actions of a
seven-year-old all right not too
concerned she's not really causing
anybody any harm now the thing is that
she doesn't get that energy out she's
going to end up like most neurotic
adults who are tense and clenched up
don't breathe deep because we're so
worried about our environment we're so
socialized that we're worried about what
other people are going to think about us
so one of the best ways to just get out
all of that energy that you've got
trapped in you and you know you have it
trapped in you because you've got tense
muscles right is to do this
it's called the silly dance just like a
silly seven-year-old would do it you
will know you're neurotic intense
because if you can't let your head a
little flop around you're so attached to
who you think you are that you're not
willing to lose yourself also the
shoulders will be really tense and tight
and unable to release again if you're
trapping a lot of nervous tension go
home do the silly dance and show your
friends how to do it to elliott's it