just dropped off my two oldest daughters
to school so as you know I have four
children three daughters and a son and
as I'm driving them and having
conversations bat you know going back
and forth between each of them I'm
realizing just how much a parent wants
to give each one of their children you
know one has such great potential in one
area that if given the opportunity a
parent could totally exploit in other
words really give everything that that
parent has to offer in order to help
develop the child in that particular way
right and that character that those
virtues that you could help develop in
that child may be very different than
the ones that you helped develop and the
other child this is exactly what I
experienced my children is so very
different anybody the children would
agree you got children that are very
very different and very very gifted in
their own ways a sense of guilt comes
over me and I'm sure comes over other
parents or if you're thinking of having
children these are things that you may
experience where by you would like to
offer everything that you have as a
parent one hundred percent of yourself
towards the development of the virtues
and the talents and the gifts and the
abilities in each one of your children
but if you've got multiple and you're
you know you're living the quote-unquote
rat race this matrix that were in where
we've got you know we've got school
we've got work we've got business we've
got money we've got bills all the shit
that we've got to do how do you
cultivate the energy where do you find
the time to give one hundred percent to
one hundred percent of your children and
to yourself and then to your spouse and
then to your it's fucking impossible you
cannot do it so one of the things that I
tend to do in all areas of my life is to
create stories for myself when I say
stories I mean just trying on different
positions or paradigms that may prove
resourceful in getting through these
these different types of challenges and
one of the stories that I tell myself
with regard to my parents go out to
parenting
and towards my raising of my children is
that I come to recognize that my
children don't belong to me first they
belong to God or the universe or nature
or whatever the intelligent design
whatever is you want to call it they
belong to that animating force first
they belong to the force that causes
trees to apple and causes the earth two
people to the NSA what I'm saying so
they are not mine first I am simply a
facilitator of their development in the
same way that a nature is actually what
creates develops cultivates animals
nature trees foliage to everything in
the world right including us but the
root organism through which the fruit
comes you know the tree the parent
through which the child proceeds is
merely a facilitator is there to support
what God is doing in the creation of
these children or in the the making of
these children or in the creation of
these plants and and fruits so there is
a there's a bit of relief in that it is
not all our responsibility in fact it's
quite narcissistic for us to believe
that it's up to us to make sure that our
children are so and so because a lot of
our drive towards developing them in a
particular way that we see as
resourceful or that we are attached to
is uh is is neurotic you know my oldest
daughter is quote/unquote gifted right
so I want to give everything that I can
to developing her intellectual
giftedness but I realize a big part of
my drive to forcing her into becoming
all that she could be with regard to
intellect is a manifestation of my
neurosis about being labeled as an a.d.d
kid that has learning disabilities yeah
I was labeled as stupid there's a
fucking kid so it's like I've got a pro
move that I'm not stupid because look at
how brilliant my daughter is fucking
narcissistic and neurotic and I have to
see this and the most resourceful
position is to facilitate that which God
is doing through her be there to support
what God is doing through each one of my
children but not be attached to making
it happen right that relieves so much
pressure relief so much guilt and in i
believe and all this is just an
experiment to me so everything that I
come up with check back with me in five
years yeah this shit works out I believe
that it's a it's far more beneficial to
not only the parents to relieve them of
the guilt of not being able to make
their children superstars but also it
relieves the pressure from the child to
living up to the expectations of what
the world through the parent has imposed
upon them let them be let them grow into
what nature is doing in them and just be
there to facilitate and support that
process