got a great question from our buddy
James here about respect and feelings of
inferiority especially amongst the
people he's closest to it goes on to say
that I'm the oldest child in my family
and for years I was superior mentally
and physically as comes with age
I'm 18 years old right now and my next
oldest brother who was about to be 15 is
already my height and my weight and he's
starting to challenge me with insults
and testing my reaction so far I've
taken it and stayed quiet but I can't
help but to feel threatened though he's
my dad's favorite and it's ultimately
going to be bigger than me on top of
this my dad is always competed with me
and beaten me at everything I can't help
to feel frustrated at the sensation of
inferiority my question to you is this
should I continue to work on becoming
the strongest version of myself while
ignoring their criticisms and challenges
or rise to their challenges and play
their game very first thing I want to do
is extend a bit of sympathy but also
congratulations for the spot that you
find yourself in it's a tough spot to
have been the oldest and the strongest
and the biggest and the smartest and
then to have what seems to be a threat
coming up from behind you know your
younger brother as always you've always
been able to be superior to who perhaps
he sees them even looked up to is now
recognizing huh getting bigger than you
bro and he's going to continue
challenging you in the way that he is
fit to challenge you he's bigger right
so that comes with the obvious benefits
associated with it and then you got your
father now I'm going to make some
assumptions here about the competitions
between you and your father and the
where it's coming from
of fathers many fathers have a tendency
to feel threatened by their son
particularly their older son
depending on many different
circumstances that could be presenting
themselves number one could be that you
are and I'm not saying this in a
derogatory way derogatory way but you
may be a mama's boy
meaning the mother now just pay
attention and just if this happens to be
the case so be it the mother might be
working to build you up build up your
character build up your self esteem in
order for you to overcome your father's
throne to take your father's place in
some way not that he's going to be
you're going to become her husband but
there's a tendency oftentimes for mother
to see the weakness in the man that
she's chosen ie your father or husband
and then start investing a bit more into
the son and the father begins to resent
this now it's either that or your father
just has some serious inferiority
complex where now he has to exert
himself not only amongst the men in his
environment but the one that he should
be building up to ultimately surpass him
over take the throne my father used to
say I want you to be better than me see
my father was a balanced man in this
particular way he didn't feel threatened
by me he felt as if he wanted me to grow
stronger than he was so that I could
expand continue to grow his legacy
through DNA right why would you want a
weak son but you're you know I don't
know the motives here but I'm just
describing the circumstances you find
yourself in and the very first piece of
advice I want to share with you is that
you have got to brainwash yourself to
succeed in that circumstance and a part
of the reason why I said you know I'm
kind of happy for you is because these
are some good challenges bro these are
perhaps some of those important
challenges for a young man to deal with
because it has to do with living
in this world that is dominated by
patriarchy there's always someone who is
out to prove themselves better than you
there's always someone out there to
conquer you to step on your neck
so make their way through you this is
this is the paradigm and the system we
live in of patriarchy and it's an
imbalanced
it's an imbalanced and violent way of
living but it's how we got where we are
and you're going to need to make your
way in this and you happen to be in a
somewhat safe environment in your home
with people who you know generally know
you and like you but you're gonna go out
to the world you're gonna deal with this
you can deal with a boss that that
ultimately wants to put you down or keep
you down or or degrade you in some
particular way so that he can maintain
his sense of superiority and you can
have coworkers we have guys that are
just waiting to take your spot boy I
can't wait till I just I can fuck this
guy up in two with intelligence
creativity hard work I'm ready to beat
him
there's always a younger dude ready to
beat you there's always somebody coming
up behind ready to take your spot so
you're gonna face this figure it out now
while you're in the circumstance at home
first piece of advice is that the way
you're going to overcome this in your
home and the way you're going to
ultimately be able to carry yourself in
life is going to be contingent upon how
you think of yourself and how you think
of yourself is more important than the
circumstances you find yourself in what
you think of yourself determines how you
behave and how you behave is going to
dictate the mirror reflection that the
world gives back to you I hope you
understand
so what you're going to need to do on a
daily basis but better off multiple
times a day is to look in the mirror and
this is what you've got to do you've got
to brainwash yourself and you brainwash
yourself by making cognitive concrete
statements that you drive into your
implicit memory through very emotional
affirmation so you can look in the
mirror and you're gonna look at yourself
I'm gonna nod your head I would invite
you to begin breathing a little heavier
rocking back and forth like you see me
doing right now this is a position of
power readiness I'm gonna say to
yourself I am whole perfect strong and
powerful I am whole perfect strong and
powerful I am whole perfect shrub and
powerful I am strong powerful Oh perfect
I am perfect I am whole I am strong I am
powerful
now I want you to take very close pay
very close attention to my body language
my face the way I'm behaving when I'm
saying this I'm rocking I'm breathing
I'm using my using facial expressions I
know what you're looking in the mirror I
don't want you acting as if you are
convincing yourself like you're
convincing someone someone else even
point that guy in the face the man in
the mirror I don't know who you are but
you know what I see I see whole perfect
strong and powerful you go out there and
you make it happen because you are whole
perfect strong and powerful do you see
what I'm doing right now I feel whole
perfect strong and powerful cuz I do
this shit some people wonder how is it
that Elliot comes across so so damn
confident all the time
because I tell myself I'm confident to
understand the movement and the
animation associated with the
affirmation is very very very important
because if you understand that there are
two forms of memory and I've spoken
about this in other videos I think I did
one on an implicit memory on my other
channel not too long ago but you've got
mind memory brain memory it's called
explicit memory it's recalling memory
remembering shit cognitively right you
know you memorize your alphabets right I
know but you know what you sing your
alphabets when you memorise it right
that means it becomes implicit because
singing is a it's kind of an activity of
the body let me think of another one
your your timetables you you memorize
your times tables you memorize your home
address you memorize shit that's
happening up here but there's another
memory called implicit memory an
implicit memory is kind of like when you
learn how to ride a bike right and then
a ten years later you pick up the bike
again and you never had to you don't
have to tell yourself all the things you
had to tell yourself in order to learn
the bike learn to ride the bike the
first place right you're not to remember
put your foot on this and do this and so
on and so forth right implicit memory is
feelings it's emotions it's emotional
responses it's in your body it's in your
autonomic nervous system it's what
causes your heart rate to increase when
you are in a when you when you see a
dangerous circumstance arising there's
an it's the intelligence of your body to
do what it does without you having to
think about it but the cool thing is
about this part of your brain what makes
you human being so incredible is that
you can train your body to feel certain
things and how you feel is going to
determine how you behave and how you
behave is going to be a perfect
reflection of what the world gives you
people give me back confidence do you
understand because I checked confidence
because I feel confident because I
conditioned myself to be confident and
you need to do the same damn thing
you can use whatever affirmation you
want but the one I just gave you is a
really
goddamn powerful one I am whole meaning
you have integrity wholeness integrity I
am perfect meaning that there's nothing
that needs to be changed about me I am
perfect the way I am I am perfect just
the way I am even though I'm not as tall
and big as my brother I am strong I am
powerful you understand and when you
convince yourself in this way those who
challenge you will feel this also you
know I've often talked about vibes vibes
we were all vibes were all vibrations
we're all particles and vibrations what
a particles do they vibrate and
depending on how the particles vibrate
is going to determine the world around
you I know this sounds like woowoo crazy
bullshit but you got to understand try
this shit out and then give it whatever
language you want I'm calling it vibes
cuz you're gonna give off some goddamn
strong vibes dude you guys feel my vibe
through these videos whose camera
much less standing next to someone in
the same physical location
you gotta make people feel you and when
you feel yourself and you're vibrating
at whatever frequency you happen to be
vibrating based on the story you told
yourself they feel you right when you're
with a chick you want to cultivate kind
of a little bit of a laid-back vibe
right you don't want to crusted vibe
when you're amongst these guys that are
trying to earth soup your power you want
some aggressive vibes confident vibes
strong powerful whole perfect vibes
that's number one number two bro I know
you said that you've ignored your
brother and you've kind of stepped aside
you started doing your own thing and
you're working on becoming strong expose
yourself and your you know you're
staying you're staying away from him and
you know you feel inferior to your dad
of course I mean he's our dad but you
know there seems to be some sort of
provocation he's provoking you how
liking this onto
what what you might experience if you go
to prison never been in prison but like
what I would imagine or any anywhere
where there is a hierarchy being
established where you need to assert
yourself you need to establish yourself
within the hierarchy and your best bet
is to first create a force field of
protection around you and that's not an
easy thing to do because that force
field is determined by the amount of
respect that you can gain now feeling
good about yourself is one thing sending
out vibes is another thing but actions
sometimes oftentimes all the time
matters big time so you probably have to
do this just once with your little
brother just once I would invite you
first to warn him warn him this way let
him know that you respect him you get
what you give
listen dude I respect you and I also
recognize that you're getting bigger
than me but remember that I am your
older brother and I don't appreciate the
way you're behaving right now and I'm
going to ask you to stop you look him in
his face make sure he understands and
then make sure it's done and if he
agrees okay cool I'm done recognize this
you don't like it you look his fucking
eyes you look people in the eyes man
make sure he understands send out those
vibes those powerful vibes he might back
down and never come again
but that might not be the case he might
come back there's good chance he might
then you have to fight you got a scrap
you got a scrap with him you gotta just
like one just pop in the face one day
tell him I'm gonna punch you in your
fucking face right now and if he if he
keeps acting goofy and silly like fuck
you populate his fucking eye he's your
brother you're supposed to punch him
every once in a while he's a little
brother and he's got to remember that he
has to respect you not because you're
older but because you deserve the rest
respect you don't do for the deserve
respect if you don't put your foot down
you put your foot down if he's a little
bit bigger and stronger than you if he
happens to be a better fighter than you
you might want to give him a cheap shot
break his fucking finger he ain't coming
at you again go to the hospital when he
breaks when you break his finger and
give him a gift and say look man I did
what I had to do but I warned you don't
do it again right by him okay
your father little different
circumstance a little different
especially if you're still living in his
home I would invite you to just have a
talk with him the same way you did first
with your brother
explain to him look dad I respect you
I'm getting older and I don't appreciate
these challenges I don't appreciate your
your provocation and I'm just going to
ask that you please with all due respect
keep offering your respect with all due
respect I would like you to stop
man I tell you with those two pieces of
advice first training yourself to be
strong powerful hole perfect through the
affirmation I just shared with you do it
every night before you go to bed every
morning when you wake up and a few times
or in the day if you have time and by
putting your foot down
and expressing your conviction about the
circumstances with your brother or your
father you will you you will win this
battle that you're supposed to face for
your own character strength and you will
have tools but you can carry out with
you into the world so you will always be
able to dominate to win to succeed to be
the strongest version of yourself to
cultivate all the character strengths
you need to hold your ground and to move
forward in life done