so we got a question from our buddy Nuno
right and it's about him and a friend so
apparently his friend is an older woman
right and and you know you're a funny
dude because he goes on to describe her
ills she has I eight children with a guy
that she no longer loves and the sex is
terrible
he says that you he only lasts three
minutes and you I mean you give some
detail as to the quality of their sex
life you know between her and her
husband they're eight children and his
two-pump chump miss it begs me to to
question your motives a bit and then you
kind of give light as to what your
motives are here so he feels bad for
this woman in Portugal who was eight
children by a man who gives her bad sex
she wants something else a fucking
children and uh you know she cheats on
him now so on and so forth Nuno is just
a friend who's watching what's going on
few storms for her want some advice the
thing is
Nuno wants to fuck her - trap trap Nuno
also has a pretty young thing that he's
trying to get with no girl that he's
liked a lot and he's torn now I want to
save this older woman with eight
children who is so fucking sexy
and I want to have sex with and my you
know my young love what should I do
Nuno dude I shouldn't have to tell you
this is this is obvious but I you know I
had to bring it up I have to answer this
that pussy's a trap
she is a fucking trap first of all she's
older than you she's you don't know the
situation with her husband you know
apparently they must have been doing
something must have been right for eight
children to be there she fucking kids
and any woman who talks to a man about
her sex life with her husband right if
any any woman who talks outside of their
relationship about the sex they have
with someone in their relationship is a
bitch
she's she's looking for something
especially if she talks negatively about
it she wants to absorb your maleness she
is a she's a sand trap that's really
what she if she's fucking quicksand and
she's looking for as many men as she
could pull into her trap as possible she
sucked this man dry eight fucking kids
bro and he can only last three minutes
now she she sucked all the maleness out
of that guy that no wonder why the guy
probably resents her and she's looking
for more she's insatiable and you're
gonna fuck her she's gonna take from you
don't get that bitch pregnant
do not get her pregnant don't fucker I'm
telling you right now it's not worth the
pussy it is not working matter how sexy
she is she's a sex trap get it get away
from her get out of your head what she's
doing also is positioning herself as a
victim because men certain men were to
save a woman you come to me like you
want to save this bitch don't save her I
don't care who she is to you you got to
get the hell away from her bro with that
you will be reduced of the heavy load so
that you can prance about with your
pretty young thing you say your
brother's friends younger sister or
whatever you need your energy for that
right needs your energy now for that
letter wit she was gonna steal your
sexual energy and and add it to the pot
of cum and lies that she's already
stirring up with other men's sexual
energy she's a witch so that's it dude
it's a crazy predicament I get it you're
you know you're young you're getting
boners this older lady wants to have sex
with you you kind of feel bad for her
that's her problem we create our own
circumstances right as empathetic as I
am towards people in their circumstances
and half as much as I work to inspire
people to become the strongest version
of themselves I recognize that there is
a energetic pull there's karma there is
you did this shit you fucked up and
you're probably gonna keep fucking out
people are just trapped that's their
karma that's what she's going to do
unless she is sincerely wants to get out
of that trap which would require like
you know hitting rock bottom or like
Jesus appears to her one day she she's
going that's she could be old lady she's
gonna be 60 doing the same shit all
right
she's a trap get out of it and go hang
out with your you're pretty young girl
and hope that works out for you
peace