I noticed you like put a lot of emphasis
on the head being in line versus like
anyone else like sporting I got your
choise Ghazis they look forward how
important is them and because that I've
tried that and it does make it harder to
the lower back right so how important is
that it's really important because we
don't want to build imbalances between
the musculature that forces lumbar
extension thoracic extension and
cervical extension we would like them to
work together but what ends up happening
is you don't have just mostly goes out
of fashion you've got this shit that
like ties all the muscle together like
saran wrap and you can cheat by having
one group within that fasho within that
loop of Muslims that should be working
together then over works and then gives
the other guys a break you see so we
like the three musketeers writing using
that term to describe extension and the
three portions of the spine to work in
concert you know one guy helps the other
guys up there all your dance back and
forth and they're all helping each other
but if you get end up with one guy that
over extends the other guys to be lazy
think of it in balanced team got one guy
who's going to end up burnt out tired
and resentful the other guys just
fucking lazy someone's time for that
would really work it's like we don't
know too is that yeah you know this area
I'm starting to rant want to stop this
area the jaw neck area becomes very
tense rigid strong and overdeveloped in
most people and that's why the tendency
is to
do this and for a number of reasons it's
a part of the physical manifestation of
our neurosis it causes our own neuroses
it makes it such that the head is almost
cash traded from the rest of the body
the powerful muscles of the jaw on the
neck and the head get very tense in time
we want almost relaxing and by using
extension and actually trending the
deprogramming here we actually great
bring more balance to the entire neck
that would suggest extensive I spoke
about that video yeah you can have older
one they've all text