hey what's up guys in today's blog post
that you could read down below I speak
about five ways that strength training
training with barbells dumbbells and
weights saved my life now many of you
guys know that I've been training since
I was 14 years old I'm 36 now so that's
well over two decades of training being
under the bar challenging myself with
heavier weights building muscle playing
sports all the things related to growing
stronger physically I began doing when I
was 14 years old when my uncle became a
personal trainer and started training my
brothers and I in my parents basement 14
years old is a critical time in fact
that's like you know your first your
dipping your toe into the water of
adulthood or adolescence because you
know you're not so much a kid anymore
but you're also not so much an adult and
I think it's a perfect opportunity to
give initiation and a sense of hope and
a sense of destiny to young people by
offering them something that they can
immerse all of their their vital
resources and sexual energy that's
coming up at that particular time in
life because otherwise I know for myself
when I was 14 years old had I not found
the sport of football but in particular
the activity of weight training to
support my ability to get stronger for
football I would have ventured down a
path that I was already started on which
included being arrested getting into
fights stealing doing drugs and a lot of
shit that 14 year old boys who don't
have an outlet or somewhere to focus
their the aggressive energy that's
coming up in their bodies would have
ultimately ended up being you know lots
of gangs and drug dealing and you know
all these ways of unruly tend to come up
for young men around the ages
14 16 17 were avoided in me averted
because I was able to take my energy and
focus it towards weight training by the
blessing of my uncle and my parents were
buying the barbell when I was 14 years
old so today I'm going to talk about
five different ways that shun training
has supported me the very first one
would say keep me out of trouble I
mentioned that just now a lot of energy
and it was great to focus it on
something productive rather than beating
up more people and getting enough in the
fights and stealing things the next one
is my experience of sowing and reaping
now you understand that's a principle i
think brian tracy once called it the law
of the farm meaning if you don't put in
the sea you don't put it in the time you
don't put in the effort you don't put it
into patients you have no heels there's
no gains and for the first time in my
life did I experience the act of putting
forth of energy concentration and hard
work in order to have something on the
other end to be fruitive my works to be
fruitive was never a very good student
so studying for a test didn't really
help me that much but lifting barbells
all of a sudden gave me the results that
came from hard work it was the first
time I was able to to put the two
together right hard work equals results
focus concentration smart work equals
results that's number two number three
chef training gave me the sword by which
I carved out my life I was able to get
an athletic scholarship playing football
because I was so much bigger stronger
and faster than many of the other
athletes my size and in my position
playing the sport sport of football and
I also experienced what it was like to
be coached and I knew immediately that
that's what I wanted to do when my uncle
coached me when my football coaches
coached me when my strength coaches
coach to me when my mentors in the
profession of fitness and ensuring
coached me I was able to absorb all of
their professional skills and find a
broke profession for myself a vocation
for myself so all my coaching at the gym
strengthcamp videos blogs anything
related to being able to put food on my
table came as a result of being shown
and handed a barbell when I was 14 years
old number 4 I was a better student
because I really didn't care too much
about tracking and testing and reading
and journaling and things of that nature
until I started tracking testing
studying and journaling my results in
the gym never before did I take up such
a cadet academic work until I started
training with the barbell this is my
very first trading Journal you can see
here where it says 1994 1995 even 96 and
I began keeping notes of my workouts I
began keeping records of my the weights
lifted I began tracking my body weight I
began planning for the future that's a
really important one you know so for
example this is a six to 12 week program
never before that I think 12 weeks ahead
when I'm 14 years old you're not
thinking what's happening three months
from now but when I was handed a barbell
I began thinking hmm three months six
months a year from now where my ID who
might I become if I put in the effort
the time and the concentration to build
my body methodically through weight
training so there's so much more than
just my physical growth it was also my
intellectual mental growth and then
finally my heart's growth my soul weight
training opened my mind and opened my
heart to the fat and my personal
experience that what I do who I become
the activities I engage in and how they
impact the lives of others I began to
realize that the stronger I had become
not just physically but as i shared
mentally the better prepared i was to
deal with the challenge
of the world and specifically dealings
in relationships when you subject
yourself to an activity that requires
struggle when you face challenges and
that's what weight training does to you
you experience all that is required for
personal growth and you also begin to
have some compassion for yourself
realizing that you know being hard on
yourself is no good being down on
yourself is no good realizing your
weaknesses this is one of the things
that strength training dud did for me it
showed me where I was weak where I was
lacking where I could be better and in
pursuing that growth personally in
recognizing those sore spots and weak
spots and shadows personally through my
experience with strength training I was
better able to and as I am a coach today
I'm still better able to spot the
inherent weaknesses ignorance is lacks
and shadows in my customers clients fans
and friends you can only have compassion
if you've had compassion with yourself
first the understand compassion is
recognizing the source spot on our own
hearts respecting it dealing with it and
then using that experience to approach
other people from a place of knowing
what they're going through knowing how
to get through the challenges and
supporting them I'm becoming a stronger
version of themselves done