we got a really good question for my
buddy Sam who works for his dad Sam's 22
years old his dad owns a landscaping
company and Sam works for his father in
this company apparently there's a power
struggle going on between Sam and his
father parent Li Sam's dad dogs him
according to Sam anyway dogs him gives
him a hard time
treats him worse than the other
employees now Sam comes to us wanting to
have a better relationship with his dad
he wants to work for his dad he wants to
work with his dad but he does not
appreciate the oppression he's wondering
now should I just quit working for my
father go in and build my own business
do my own thing and then suffer the
consequence of not having a good
relationship with my father or is there
a way that I could help mend things up
because I would like to enjoy my
father's presence and I and I want to
work for him you know things can go well
and they have gone well but right now
I'm struggling here's the thing Sam you
got to recognize that there is a very
strange dynamic that goes on between
fathers and sons and it is a microcosm
of what happens in society men in
particular have an aggressive character
right this is just this is just
typically male we go out and we want to
achieve we want to strive we want to we
create Wars where there's is there's
always someone on top of us that we're
looking to crush and then climb up and
I'm not saying that this is all men and
I'm not saying that there are no women
this way but what I'm saying it's a very
male characteristic it's very
characteristic of male energy and when
you've got two men in a home and both
are struggling for positions of power
especially when there is one that is you
know based on the patriarchal hierarchy
is above the other one you run into a
situation where the one that's below the
one above will fall into one of three
different categories of behavior right
so you've got your father and you've got
you right then the power struggle is
such that you're becoming a man you are
a fucking man
and and your dad is is still exerting
himself as if he's you know Big Daddy
and and I want to show you exactly why
he's making a big mistake
especially for your development in your
psychological development and the way
you proceed in the world so you got one
of three things that are stiffly going
to happen right and it goes like this
number one the person below will
typically yield you can get this type of
response to yield to the person above
but resentfully so so you'll bite your
tongue you'll bite your lip you'll do as
told but inside there's a growing seed
of resentment and that is going to show
up in your relationships with your wife
with your friends with your child right
because we pass this shit on your dad's
doing it to you and all that resentment
that you have for the oppression you're
going to subconsciously do to your
children or you do it to your dog do you
see
but that resentment is there that seed
of of anger frustration and defiance
that you just can't act out because
you've decided you've chosen to yield to
the power structure it's growing in you
right it's like a cancer inside you
that's one option a lot of men in
society this is what we do when we go to
jobs that we hate when we go to see
bosses that are oppressive to us this is
what I mean when I say we become slaves
to a system because we're doing what
we're told yes sir yes sir yes yes sir
to the power structure but there's this
seed of resentment that grows and grows
like a cancer and eats at you so I want
to say that a good percentage maybe 75%
or more end up in fit in this place we
just bite our tongue and we take it up
the ass then you've got the second type
of person that just completely rebels
says fuck this I can't deal with it I'm
rebelling and finds a way to destroy the
whole fucking thing right this is a very
rebellious type of person and it can
manifest itself positively in their
rebellion they're basically saying you
know what I'm gonna I'm making this
work for me I don't care what anybody
says or they can say I'm just destroying
everybody and everything in my way and
they become a very destructive type
person they maybe become an alcoholic
they may they may make everyone else's
lives miserable in their rebellion
because that there they're not soft
enough right when I say solve them I'm
literally saying that they're not as
much of pussies as the other guys at 75%
because they're not willing to fight
their lip and suck it down but they're
just as dysfunctional because they're
learning it out but they're shitting and
vomiting all over the place and making
everybody including themselves miserable
right that's typically what happens and
you see this in the way the person
carries himself or the other you know
that within that one option that person
in their rebelliousness could create
some kind of good and then there's a
third option and this is the healthy
option this is the option that our
ancestors recognize when they created
rites of passages for young boys to
become men which we don't have anymore
right young boys never get that
opportunity to know when they're they
breather becoming a man like a little
girl she gets her period bang blood all
over the place you're a woman now right
for boys it's like well when am I
actually a man you know I beat my dad in
an arm wrestle I remember that day like
it was yesterday very important day to
me but I'm not sure what it meant to him
and I'm not sure what it means to
anybody else but it had to do with
physical strength and the opportunity to
one-up that which is above but it's not
an official celebrated recognized
passage into manhood right
it's where am I going with this
that third option would if it was to be
executed healthy would look like this
a young man exerts himself as becoming a
man and the power structure above that
that which is above recognizes and sees
this in the young man coming up and
develops an opportunity to yield and let
that boy become a man now that's the
problem your dad doesn't want to yield
to you and allow you to become a man
because he's too far wrapped up in his
bravado he's too wrapped up in his
maleness
he's so male that he's a pussy I don't
know if that makes sense you understand
that he's so male that he's not willing
to embed or accept the femininity
femininity associated with true maleness
with the bat with a balanced male that's
what I'm trying to say a balanced male
knows how to exert himself all right but
he also knows when to say hmm it's a
balanced male but he's so imbalanced cuz
it's all you're not gonna get the best
of me I'm still the fucking man I'm
still your daddy huh right that he's a
pussy it takes a lot of courage it takes
a lot of balls to yield especially to
your son he's that willing to do that
right so
I would invite you as a young man and
myself I recognize this and I paid
attention to this and I have a son - at
some point recognize that your son will
need to exert himself as a man and as
they say an old saying is that a student
must kill his master you will have to
die as the dominant or seemingly
dominant aggressive force in the home or
in the relationship or the dynamic
between you and your emerging man of a
son now in your situation right because
that gives you kind of a perspective for
what the hell's going on right your
dad's too much of a pussy to man up and
it doesn't mean he's bad man she just
means that he's not aware of these
things you are and now you're in a
situation where you've got to do one of
those three things right do you bite
your lip do you bite a lip and you suck
it down you just keep being a yes man
and ignoring your heart ignoring your
balls and just not becoming a real man
do you fight throw it all away just like
make his life miserable destroy the
business just explode while you guys are
on the job or do you find for yourself I
do step outside of the relationship with
him and find for yourself a place where
you can execute and exert yourself as a
man within a power structure that's
willing to yield and allow you to mature
guess what that third option is
available to you and you've alluded to
the fact that you're willing and able to
step out on your own build your own
business as a speaker and a radio
personality something like that I think
you described but what it's going to
require is a ton of courage to step away
from the confines and structure that
your family has created for you step out
into a cold cold world that really it's
completely objective does not care about
you
and make your own way for yourself as a
man not so that you can have the things
associated with wealth and grandeur
right those things come but so that you
can grow and become someone
become a stronger version of yourself so
that you can grow and become more of a
stronger man right the reason why we do
what we do and the reason why it's it's
so beautiful in our culture our country
and you know many many others throughout
the world where you can go out and make
a living for yourself is because you not
only find a way to put food on the table
by serving other people but you become
the type of man that all men should
ultimately become and that is one who
has exerted himself within a structure
that allows him to recognize appreciate
and cultivate the self esteem that is
owed him so that's it man go out there
do your thing you have to step away love
your father
bow down one more time step away and
it's not a severing of relationships
keep it peaceful it's not a severing of
ties
it's not a removing of your heart from
the situation and the relationship it is
merely you now realizing you've got to
go and clip the umbilical cord and
become a man on your own and it's going
to be scary it's gonna require a lot of
courage but you will be a man a bigger
man your own man on the other end of the
wall good luck buddy Elliot's it
[Music]