got this question on my facebook wall
about approaching women building up the
confidence to approach women our friend
goes on to say yo Eliot how do I build a
confidence to walk up to an approach and
speak to women I'm not a weak man
in fact I weight training in the gym I'm
a little overweight says that he's a big
guy but he also goes on to say that he's
heard that women look on the inside of
men instead of the outside so much what
are your thoughts on this and what what
should you do that's really a question
look what I want you to understand here
is that there is a dualistic nature to
all things in the universe right there
is night and day there's winter there's
summer there's a systolic and diastolic
soul and diastole of your heart dizzy
inhalation exhalation of your breathing
there's this contrast this digital world
that we live in has to do with a series
of on and off switches the reason why
I'm telling you this is because a truly
balanced man one that a woman is going
to open up to and accept his approach is
going to balance tenderness and
aggression right in his approach and his
dealings with the opposite sex you'll
know and she'll know that you're too
tender if you end up in the friend zone
right and what that means is that you've
been so tender without balancing
aggression that she says something like
this I love you like a brother nothing
worse than hearing that a man it's
probably the worst things you could hear
I love you like a brother right because
you know what that means that means you
ain't got a chance in the world man
you've been to fucking tender a lot of
big guys a lot of fat guys overweight
guys I'm not making fun of you I'm just
putting you in a setting light on the
situation here end up in the friend zone
because they realize that an opening of
the heart is a form of tenderness and
they use that to bring women close right
we're going to talk about that in a
moment
but the other side of the spectrum is
that aggressiveness aggression you've
got to balance the two you know that
you're overly aggressive when women are
very they put up walls against you
they're a little standoffish because you
just come at them just a little too hard
you know these guys the reason why women
are curious and not so sure about the
extremes of either a tender man they
never really want to let him in because
he doesn't have the aggression and an
overly aggressive man who doesn't have
the tenderness to open her up is sexual
and psychological in nature if you're
too tender you seem impotent you don't
have the strength to give a woman what
she wants now this means also in bed
impotence means your limp your limp your
soft your soft guy and also in life and
overly aggressive man is one that is
premature in its ejaculation as one
that's just too excited too much he's
reaching and touching way too quickly
without any tenderness so you want to be
able to balance these two so I'm gonna
give you tips on how to stimulate your
tenderness and aggression if you find
yourself on too heavy on one side or the
other you use some of the tips I'm going
to share with you to bring yourself back
into balance I'm assuming you're
probably too much on the tender side
right this is my assumption but I'm
gonna start with the tenderness because
you probably already know this by
instinct but a lot of aggressive men
pretty majora jack you laters right
don't understand this you've got to
soften a woman first and you've got to
give her a mini or
Yasim right what I mean is that you've
got to get her to giggle right when a
woman does that woman giggles its
spontaneous in the same way that it
orgasm is spontaneous you can't force a
giggle you can't force a laugh
especially a deep belly tearful laugh in
the same way that you can't force an
orgasm but if you can give her a mini
orgasm one that she instantly opens up
when you know she touches her heart when
she does this she's just opened up to
you you've given her a tiny orgasm that
softened her just a little bit so that
you could come in with an aggressive
move right so the tip is get her the
laugh get it a laugh or get her to cry
or feel emotional in some way to open
her heart without your aggressiveness
first if you're good at the tenderness
then recognize that the minute she opens
up like that bud like that flower you
got to do just like the honeybee and
dive in and the first way to dive into a
woman that opens up to you is with your
eyes when you get her to giggle then
make eye contact and you'll see the
softness in her soul once that eye
contact is made she may even shift away
because she knows that you're looking
into the depths of her soul make eye
contact and go in for a touch just a
simple touch right not necessarily a
groan but a touch so you just opened her
up through orgasm and showed her your
aggression this my friend is the essence
of a balanced man is the essence of all
balance in nature it's tenderness and
aggression so try these tips if you're
already getting her to giggle go in with
the aggression if you're already too
aggressive start with the mini orgasm
get her to giggle Elliot