so I've gotten two emails this week from
guys in high school young guys who want
to know when it's okay to fight
apparently specifically with one of
these guys there's a kid at school
that's kind of been egging him on
provoking him and making threats hasn't
done anything physical yet but the
threat of attack is there now for full
disclosure I fought many times in the
past I was a high school kid just like
you in college getting in bar fights
through my experience and wisdom who I
am today
I will share with you my strongest
sentiment and that is your best bet is
not to fight I don't say that like a
horny adult I say that from a place of
sincere experience and and and love
honestly you know because I don't want
to see anything happen to you and fights
are getting weirder and weirder as the
generations go on you know kids carry
razors they carry guns here is what the
big again this is just not corny adult
shit I'm 33 so I'm I'm getting corny I'm
getting old but the fact is that the
bigger man the stronger man the man with
the more the most courage is going to be
the one that steps up and instead of
attacking preemptively begins preemptive
preemptive peace talks I see the thing
with fighting is that it's mostly done
in a hysterical state you know you're
attacked you don't fucking thank you
just go crazy and you want to start
fighting it's not throwing arms or you
know it's all emotionally driven there's
no grounding there's no pragmatism it's
all in motion and to react emotionally
or even to to attack emotionally is weak
plain and simple you've lost your head
you've lost your grounding and your
manhood is based in your grounding right
it's down here down below when you're up
here you're all fired up you know you're
up here and you've lost your balls when
you stop breathing deep you'll know this
right away he comes around and your
breathing becomes shallow your shoulders
tense all your energy moves up now
you're moving from a place of hysteria
emotion you're not a man at that point
your balls have been severed from your
character what you've got to do is this
when you are in the vicinity or
approaching him take a deep breath
several deep breaths if you can lower
your voice the lower you could you can
bring your voice down the more of your
grounding you're going to access the
more manly and in control you will be
more you're up here and you're wild and
you're thinking oh what's up what's up
you're a bitch
high-pitched voice a lot of energy get
down get down here down to your belly
down into your balls proach him and look
him in the eye he's gonna freak the fuck
out because nobody expects this and
extend your hand the next thing you say
is very important and this is going to
be the toughest thing for you extend
your hand and apologize you tell him
that you're still sorry I'm sorry that's
going to be your words your very first
words I know you're thinking Elliot with
the foot the fuck what the fuck it's not
me it's him listen you're being the
fucking man right now extend your hand
and say listen I want to apologize in
the past you and I have not seen eye to
eye but I want to put an end to it right
now
can we do that with your deep grounded
voice look him in the eye and wait is
that know what the fuck to do okay if he
extends his hand and shakes you guys
shake embrace him that's it it's fucking
over because men are like that
it's fucking over it's done never to
mention again women they might beg back
and stuff like talk about each other
behind each other's back even after they
shook hands not men squash it you squash
it if he reacts hysterically moves up
and you'll know this because you can get
real active on top his breathing will
get short if he hit you you fucking hit
him back no question about it if he hits
you
after you extend your hand you hit him
back
okay so I've given you two scenarios one
he extends his hand when he hits you you
hit him back
there's that's just defense the third
scenario is he turns his back on you
bitch move on his part what you've got
to do next is very important go and tell
as many people as you can what happened
splain go to your teachers with your
parents go to your friends but everyone
listen I went to this guy extended my
hand in peace and he refused it here's
what's going to happen next if he comes
at me I'm going to hit him I'm going to
hit him if he comes at so you're
basically you're setting yourself up for
a win because you're letting everyone
know that you preemptively created peace
talks and if he attacks you you're going
to attack him back let the principal
know listen I don't want to fight okay
but I've extended my hand and he made it
known at that point that he's not
interested in peace I'll keep my
distance but if he comes at me I'm going
to tear him apart okay this is your best
case scenario dude this is the best
thing that you can do being a kid in
high school being a kid in college and a
college is a different story because you
start drinking and all the fighting is
beer goggle be your muscle drinking it's
all stupid high school you know you're
fighting for your position I get that
you will be a bigger man if you use the
scenario I just shared with you share it
with your friends share this video with
your friends all right good luck do the
right thing
Eliot sick