okay so I've got this really interesting
question here from our buddy got any
prunes that's his screen name he goes on
to say that he's in his last year of
high school and he's done really well in
school he gets great grades and
everybody seems to praise him he gets
awards and such and he just doesn't care
doesn't get too excited about it he's
really good at sports he plays sports he
excels he makes all types of MVP status
and awards and again everybody's excited
for him to him he shrugs it off yeah who
cares also on the flip side when things
aren't going the way they should go
things that should make him upset angry
sad so forth it's just like water off a
duck's back nothing seems to get to him
he's what you might call a stoic the
thing is he didn't choose a stoic
philosophy to live his life by he simply
just does not feel and it's causing him
not even to feel anything but he's
confused because he can't have that much
anxiety because he's all up in his head
but he rationalizes which is a good
place to start that I should probably be
feeling something when things are going
well I'd like to be excited but I'm just
not when things are going bad it looks
like those people that are upset they're
having such a good time I mean believe
me it's better to feel upset anger
frustration joy happiness than to have
none at all especially if it's not your
own choice you know those are those who
choose philosophies and religions that
are based on non-attachment
but that's a choice because you can
experience life which you choose not to
grow too attached to it what you're
experiencing is very different the vital
energies in your body are not expressing
in such a way that you can you can feel
anything you basically are just not
feeling so there are a few things that
you need to understand that the vital
energies in the human body no matter
what you call it we all experiencing it
experience it but you know if depending
on where you live in the world the
tradition you've studied they might call
it Chi they call it prana they call it
the Holy Spirit depending on
where it is you come from in in in
medical science they might say the
functions of the nervous system if we if
we break it down it's the functions of
the nervous system and the hormonal
system both are animating systems that
animate the body right the nervous
system is the quick mover the hormonal
system is the slow mover you know if you
somebody pricks you with a with a pin
you'll feel it quickly because of the
nervous system but then there will be a
slow hormonal response right and the
same thing with all of the responses in
our body there are those that would have
you believe and really justifiably that
those are their sexual energies that
energy is of sexual nature and it can be
expressed or not expressed in certain
ways the way I'm going to approach this
for you is by labeling that energy the
charge in your body the way that energy
charges your body you can either have no
charge and I'll describe a person with
no charge in a moment because that might
not really be you might there might be a
charge there there might be a low charge
which might be the situation which
situation for you because I suspect
especially for those who happen to do
well in sports there's always a charge
there you had no charge you probably
couldn't animate yourself to do
athletics and then there's some with low
charge and then there are people with
held back charge if you study the work
of Wilhelm Reich and character structure
he would call that like a schizoid which
is someone who almost has
depersonalization so essentially they
just it's almost like their head is in
the clouds
all their charge is up here a lot of
time those people have really tight
necks because there's a lot of muscular
restriction all their holding pattern is
right here it's almost like they've been
psychologically castrated from their
body and these people are often know of
a very intellectual creative type but
it's almost like they're ghosts floating
and they don't feel or experience
anything then you have the second type
the second type which is more of an
aural characteristic this is the person
who has low charge and this is a person
who sexually the first one sexually
there would be impotence they would if
she was a female there would be
be completely dry vagina no sexual
desire even they don't even look at the
opposite sex the person of the low
charge now if you're a man this is going
to look like your ability you call it an
ability but really it's it's
dysfunctional in a way to have sex for
as long as you want you get a boner
because there's enough charge to
sexually stimulate you but you can just
stroke stroke stroke stroke strip and
then when you do ejaculate or orgasm
it's like what well there it is right so
this is enough charge to get you going
but not enough charge to get you to
explode this shows up in other areas you
like not just sexually I'm using sex as
a metaphor based on the work of Reich
and then there's a rigid type the
neurotic this is kind of like the way at
where I'm at and where a lot of people
are this is the person who has healthy
sexual charge in their body but they're
holding it back because they've been
told sit down shut up don't express and
then we hold it back we're holding tight
the muscular system becomes very tense
in certain areas and sexually that
expresses itself as premature
ejaculation so excited that when I get
the opportunity bang I break out I open
up can't even hold back the floodgates
there's so much there but I'm constantly
fighting against myself that when I get
the opportunity boom I explode so if
you're not feeling life it's either
because there's no feeling in your body
there's no feeling in your body or
there's held back feeling in your body I
hope you see that I use the word charge
and feeling interchangeably so what
you've got to get to happen now is to
bring feeling back into your body I'm
going to give you suggestions based on
where you feel you might be on that
spectrum if you happen to be someone
that just has no feeling in their body
right and you can accept this
consciously because a lot of times we're
so attached to our way it will being
that we're just like who cares like I
don't even wanna look at that someone
just puts up a mirror and you don't want
to see it if you're of no charge and
you're willing to look at that and see
it as not fully expressing yourself in
experiencing life feeling life allowing
life to happen through your body because
that's where we experience joy pleasure
anger frustration sadness
then what you're going to need to do is
get someone manual therapists to
physically work on your body massage is
a very good technique for bringing the
vital energies out of your head
down back into your body if you find
that that's the type of person that you
will you are right you feel if there if
you just have no desire even for
physical experience you're probably up
in your head as a schizoid type and you
need someone to almost massage it back
down into your body down into your heart
down into your balls down into your feet
right tapping is also very helpful the
thing is with this person that first
type the type that has no charge at all
is that if they do their own work they
try to try to do their own bioenergetics
if they try to do their own tapping
because there's so much in their head
they're going to resist the full
expression they'll do it but they'll be
like nothing's happening I'm in my head
now try bioenergetics you'll try
releasing emotionally through exercise
but it'll all be with a detached mind
the heads doing it doing one thing and
the body doing another and there's no
integration the second person you're
someone who needs your energy is a
little bit lower you're more in your
heart they call the oral the lover
because they have their energy stops
here they're trapped in their heart you
probably if this is you you probably
have a bit of a high photic posture
you're probably a little bit rigid right
here you on the other hand can can do
some of the work on your own by laying
over a bioenergetic stool doing anything
to open up the thoracic cavity because
that's where a lot of the charges is is
being held the schizoid it's all up in
the head that's why I said there's
probably a lot of rigidity right up here
you you're trapped in your heart
okay so laying over the bioenergetic
stool anything to open up your breathing
particularly in this portion of your
torso from the mouth throat down into
your solar plexus opening up the
thoracic cavity Oh spot
thoracic portion of the spine the spine
is going to be very supportive to you
okay and then the third type the one
that's holding back you just need to let
it out the problem is that you're
holding back you're holding back it's
not that you don't have deep sexual
energies that want to be expressed to
your body the problem is that you're
always holding it back but if given the
opportunity to release it it's it's
great these people often feel really
good drinking alcohol because that's
when they the ego lets down and the
their full expression happens the only
problem is that it's when it's under the
influence of a drug it's never
long-lasting you wake up the next
morning and feel worse this type of
person and I have a lot of experience
because that's the type person I am as
expressive as I am I have to practice
expression otherwise I start to hold
back hold back hold back hold back again
there's a there's some fun shit you can
do right here of course is bioenergetics
that i've taught you and i teach you and
i show you through this channel but it
could be as simple as dancing I've said
this before turning on your favorite
music and dancing letting it all out
just go with it if you're not feeling
anything because you're holding back
giving yourself an opportunity to let it
loose especially in a joyful manner
through dancing is going to allow that
to it's going to break the shell that's
holding you in now the other thing about
that dancing is you should probably do
it around other people because life
happens through communion with other
people so your best bet is to go to
dance clubs go and you know how most
guys are standing on the wall there beer
go and friggin dance doesn't mean if you
doesn't mean you have to know how to
dance well doesn't you have to be a
great dancer you're not 50 fucking
Michael Jackson but go out there and let
your body do what it wants to do through
the music and you'll find that as your
breath deepens because you're moving
around a lot and because you let go of
the egos hold on the body and you can
move freely regardless of what it looks
like you will find peace you will find
joy you will find feeling once again in
your body so that's it my friend your
experiencing life because life is
experienced in the body and you either
lack charge have low charge or you're
holding back your charge you've got to
figure out which one you are and employ
techniques to get the body to experience
again feeling is called feeling because
you're not thinking it this is what we
end up doing start thinking about all I
should be feeling how can I feel and you
try to force it from here
it has to happen here and here how's
happening your heart and your balls the
middle person open up the heart the
third person the rigid person opened up
threw their balls dance shake move your
hips that's it dude good luck