hey what's up guys this morning I wrote
an article that you could read down
below about building the foundations for
physical strength you'll also find a
link to my advanced five by five
strength training routine down below but
today in this video what I wanted to
talk about our how the foundation
principles related to building physical
strength also relate to becoming a
stronger version of yourself in
absolutely all realms of life now if you
watch enough of my videos it's very
clear to you that I am of the opinion of
the belief of the conviction if you will
that the body is the mind and the way
you care for your body the way you carry
your body the way your body is presented
to the world is a great reflection of
your internal character your psychology
and if that is the case then the way we
build our bodies carry our body
strengthen our bodies detoxify our
bodies use our bodies all are
reflections of and add to and I'm
correct that are commensurate with our
psychological character and mental
strength it's one thing body and mind
one thing so when I use language like
core mechanics work capacity as it
relates to strength training understand
that when those things are present in
you whether or not you're a football
player or a strong man sure a strong
professional strawman or power lifter it
still applies because you want to have a
solid strong physical foundation to
carry your soul to work in the world
with you understand so we have to honor
it you know there's some people that are
so spiritually minded that they're
physically useless right and that's not
the case that's not what we want right
we want to be physically strong mentally
strong we want every every facet of our
character to be enhanced by the things
that we do in would be gauging so today
I'm going to talk about the three
foundation principles for success i'm
going to use language as it relates to
strength
training because we're all on the
journey of becoming stronger versions of
ourselves very first foundation
principle for success is core strength
now this term is thrown around quite a
bit and a lot of people have a lot of
associations and confusion in fact about
what poor strength actually means I
think paul chek does the best way of
describing the core by saying it is
everything from the tip of your head to
your perineum right right down to
between your balls in your butthole top
of the top of the head to the bottom of
the spine if you look at a if you look
at a skeleton of a human being
essentially it's the skull the spine and
the pelvis everything else is
extremities the arms the legs are
extremities but the head the neck the
torso the lumbar spine the sacrum and
the pelvis all of that tied together
equals the core now what's interesting
about the court important about the core
is that the core houses and protects
your organs so your brain is protected
by your skull your spinal cord is
protected by the vertebrae each
vertebrae has a protective as well as a
agility and movement capacity associated
with it right so your spine and then
down in the pelvic floor if you look at
the pedal of the pelvis like a bone
right turn it up like this it's sort of
like a basin it's a bowl because it
houses your internal organs all of which
include the digestive organs the sexual
organs down there and then stacked up
right up into your rib cage right
because you can continue can consider
the rib cage a part of that whole
mechanism as well you've got the heart
you got your stomach and you've got your
lungs all housed in the ribcage you got
a head the ribcage and the pelvis which
comprise the core now the muscles on a
superficial that wrap around that are
associated with
the core are there for a number of
reasons number one again is to protect
right like your rectus abdominis for
example is the big bulky muscles on the
top of your abdominals the ones that
give you the six-pack look those muscles
have a protective mechanism protective
role that's what if you will in the
mechanics of that of the core if you get
punched in the stomach back then that's
the muscle that tenses up and tightens
so that a boxer won't get his liver
blown apart when somebody punches him it
also helps to prevent hinging right if
you're playing football and you go up
for for a catch and somebody comes from
behind and hates you puts their
shoulders right in your low back you if
you didn't have the rectus abdominis
keeping your ribcage tied down to your
pelvis you just you crack flap you plant
right open you crack your back okay we
also have the necessity for movement and
pumping muscles that are associated with
pumping would include your the solar
plexus or your diaphragm right the heart
is a muscle cardiac cardiac muscles its
associated with pumping also the stomach
you're the stomach muscles are in a way
a part of the pumping mechanism that
supports your digestive ability or
ability to digest food and eliminate
that is particularly eliminate food
right we're designed as human beings in
orders it's a squat down in order to use
the bathroom that means that the thighs
rest on the belly and compress the the
colon and help support elimination also
being down in that squat position also
relaxes the sphincters of the anus and
rectum and allow you to defecate that
much easier so you can see that the
muscles in the abdominal region the
muscles in the chest shoulder neck
Faith's Elvis all contribute to far more
than just being able to squat 600 pounds
it contributes way more
then just being able to look sexy on the
beach in fact your livelihood your your
vitality your life force is
intrinsically linked to the muscles of
your core if you're using the model that
I share with you right now so we want to
make sure that those muscles are
conditioned one of the things that we
I'd like to share with you with regard
to principles today number one is core
strength our mechanics biomechanics is
the second principle I want to share
with you today and in becoming stronger
version yourself in building up physical
strength biomechanics is of concern
because it all has to do with your
movement your ability to move and every
movement emanates from a position of
rest so biomechanics is also associated
with your posture right so you're going
to have certain muscles in the core in
the extremities most muscular imbalances
begin in the core head neck shoulders
pelvis muscular imbalances that of
course they could destroy your
physiology like I just to look about
before their their muscular imbalances
that can affect the effectiveness of
your eyes the way you see your jaw
anybody ever have clicking in the jar
grinding in the teeth or malocclusion
alright they'll tell you today your boss
will fuck me up you have bad jaw muscles
you're not masticating your food
properly you're having half digested
food particles in your and your belly or
digestive systems gonna have to work
overtime to break it up I ain't chewing
right it's all associated your solar
plexus is tense and tight your solar
plexus is not relaxed and fully allowing
the drop down is associated with
expansion of your lumps and the
expansion of your belly right because
when your when your diaphragm drops your
belly aches expands but if you've got a
tight tense rigid diaphragm do too many
psychological energetic but also
physiological and just poor use of the
body habits you're going to have a
problem physiologically right but when
it comes to bio
mechanics is I'm talking all over the
place here today you know what I'm
talking about muscular imbalances
screwing up your physiology if you're if
you're your solar plexus if your
diaphragm doesn't it doesn't work
properly you can't breathe properly
breathing problems lead to everything
from head problems to digestive problems
that's why the soul it's called the
solar plexus it's the Sun it's right in
the middle here right it's that critical
tight it's all associate with the heart
the lungs life and so on and so forth
it's just very obvious if you have
problems breathing you're going to have
problems in other areas of physiology I
don't need to explain too deeply but
mechanics wise posture wise if you've
got a tight rectus abdominis upper upper
abdominals you got tight muscles in your
neck remember these muscles are
associated with the core because they
balance your skull tight shoulders right
then your mechanics are often anything
that you do be it squatting lunging
twisting pushing pulley is going to be
compromised every movement emanates from
a place of rest how is your posture how
is your position of rest so many
implications associated with that also
make anything I could do if I out video
course on that and then finally work
capacity as the third principle for
success both in the gym and in life you
see the metaphor your ability to keep
going past seeming exhaustion your
ability to work until the job is
complete your work capacity is highly
linked to the results you're going to
get in fitness in the gym based on the
amount of volume and frequency that your
goal you're using in your training
program but your ability to keep at it
to have endurance and agility in your
work in your relationships in your life
at large is once again intrinsically
linked to your health if your heart and
your lungs are not healthy if the
pumping mechanisms associated with it
are not active
your digestive system can be compromised
your brain can be compromised your
relationships than are compromised
because you're constipated you're
farting you got bad breath and you got
headaches nobody wants to hang out with
you you can see why strength training
physical training yoga calisthenics
exercise that supports principle number
one core strength principle number two
biomechanics and posture and principle
number three work capacity all relate to
you becoming a stronger version of
yourself all around done
you
[Music]