so this video is to finally respond to
the reason why I removed my depression
bioenergetic catharsis video from
YouTube that I put up in the fall of
last year right so what better time than
while I'm driving home so for those who
don't know I put up a video me do going
through I was going through a pretty
hard time to begin with things are you
know very difficult in my life but in
order to get the psychological stress
out of my body because I believe that
it's psycho-emotional psychosomatic you
know the stresses that we feel in our
head manifest themselves physically in
restricting our ability to deep breathe
things like that I always talk about my
video so anyway I actually use
bioenergetics and I express the
frustration that's in my body through a
bout of exercise and I did it and I
would you know one day I said to myself
why don't I just put this on video to
show people how it's done because that's
far more beneficial than me just talking
about it you know it's very heady to
talk about these things but to actually
show people how it's done was my purpose
in putting on this video and I mean it
was ugly you know some people said it
was beautiful
some people said was ugly the whole
thing is that you know was um eccentric
eccentric with eccentric right my wife
calls me she says you're so eccentric
like what is your problem why do you
always have to be oh so eccentric well
just because I'm not afraid to be myself
I'm not afraid to to do the things and
say the things that most people just
hold private I've got a big bow that I
you know
I'm willing to put that stuff out there
so the vidi there there may have been
several reasons why I would potentially
take down a video like that number one
because I would be made fun of right but
if you know me know that I just don't
give a shit what anybody says about me
so that really wouldn't be one of the
reasons why I would take out take down a
video like that you know people made
parodies and they made fun they call me
all sorts of names in fact I'm kind of
like flattered by the by the parodies
and the names like you know a part of
what I get off on is is that type of
attention I don't know I was a attention
horn as a kid I don't know you can say
but um but it doesn't bother me in fact
I get a charge from people saying that
I'm crazy that's just fine with me and
it's invitation when I behave in this
way it's an invitation to other people
not to be so afraid of what other people
say and that's one of my biggest stances
in life and one of the biggest lessons
that I want to share with people you
know is that you shouldn't be afraid of
what other people say in fact screw them
and you should be happy that they're
talking about you because that means
you're actually doing something I should
put my seatbelt on right
so it has nothing to do with anybody
giving me a hard time about having up a
video like that the reason why I took it
down is because plain and simple my
children are watching this video and I'm
dead and gone this is the reason why I
took the video down is because I had a
nightmare one night out of the blue that
my children would be harassed at school
because their dad is freaking nuts their
dad is crazy that hurt me more than
anything was to know that my daughter
might go to school one day and the other
children tease and laugh at her because
you know her dad is it's a nut that
wasn't a lesson that I wanted my
children to have to learn that way
do you understand what I mean I didn't
want them have to learn the lesson of
not caring about what other people think
about you because their dad was so
eccentric and their dad was in went nuts
on a YouTube video and now the other
kids are making fun of me I would hate
for one of my children come home and
have that be the reason for tears in
their eyes
so without second thought I immediately
took it down and it was because of my
care and empathy for the potential
harassment that my children might have
you know the other end of the spectrum
was that I still to this day get emails
for people who say that that video
impacted their lives in such a positive
way and I've gotten emails that are 17
paragraphs long about how someone was
deeply in depression and the invitation
that I offered in that video just to
express yourself
help move them out of a very bad place
that they were and a part of me is
regretful for taking it down and it's
because I know that it was beneficial to
a lot of people of course there were
those that you know were offended by it
or completely turned off and again that
no I kind of I go out to offend people a
little bit I I go out to make people
uncomfortable just a little bit to shake
them up and see where they're at so
that's that's really neither here no ver
with regard to that so that's it will I
put the video back up well I really
don't have to because you've got people
who have reloaded it I'm sure you can
find it if you really want to see it you
can find it and I'm not embarrassed of
it I'm not ashamed of it it's it's me
it's Elliott Hulse in my rawest at my
lowest and at my Rost for you to
experience so you know enjoy yourself it
decide to grab some popcorn and watch
that but I am considering not heavily
but perhaps at some point creating a
video very similar but more of it in a
instructional manner
you know I I really wanted it not to be
an instructional video because I wanted
it to be raw real and give you
permission just do the freaking thing
because Elliott Hulse has the balls do
it but just so that people can truly
appreciate the intention of the video
which is to help I'll probably I may
make another one that's a bit more
instructional that offers helpful tips
about how to do it you know a lot of
people have come into the Elliott Hulse
fold if you will through that video you
know feeling that this guy is batshit
crazy once you get an opportunity hear
him talk you realize okay there's
something to this this guy is not as
crazy as he seems there's there's a
little bit of a common sense not even
common sense but there's thought behind
what this guy is doing and if I created
another video would be with the intent
bringing people in framing what I do in
the right way so that when they come in
is not just this guy's batshit crazy and
then they discover that I'm I've
actually got a couple brain cells in
here so that's it I hope that's helpful
for you guys I hope clears anything up
you know a lot of you guys are really
good fans and I appreciate you to a
degree that you probably don't
understand and I get that from you guys
as well that you appreciate me to a
degree that I probably will never
understand
hey that's what this whole thing about
in life is about it's about sharing
ideas supporting one another growing
stronger inspiring others and that's why
I do what I do and I'll continue to do
it I just want to share my gratitude for
those of you who appreciate use utilize
and benefit from the things that I share
with you in these videos