yo so we got a question from our buddy
mr. Park or he calls himself and
essentially he's fallen in love
now our buddy is kind of what he calls
an introvert right and there's this girl
that he's been sitting next to in class
for two years and he fell in love with
her instantly she didn't know only he
did because he never professed his love
and he's been watching Elliott Hulse
videos long enough that he has come to
the realization and has built the
courage to speak his heart and he's told
his love
he's professed his love to this girl
that's in class with him and she
friendly kindly turned him down and now
he's distraught essentially his heart's
been broken he put himself out there to
be challenged and her and now he doesn't
know it like he's at ease is it a loss
he doesn't know what to do there's no
how to go about proceeding with the girl
in order to ultimately get over the
situation or end up having someone else
to be his life partner or girlfriend you
know and I'm assuming this is probably
one of your first girlfriends look dude
one of the things that I want you to
recognize is that every single
experience we have in our lives
everything that we go through both
positive and negative across the board
serves two purposes
the first purpose is the more
superficial one it's the one we're
focused on and that purpose is to give
us something either give us a new
girlfriend or to give us you know and
some sort of success right it's what we
get is the attainment of the goal it's
that thing that we can tangibly say yes
I have attained the other thing that all
these experiences offer us that is very
different it's far more subtle but
thousands of times
more powerful potent and transformative
for you and your life is who you are
becoming through the challenges who
you're becoming through the experiences
so I've once heard that if you take
someone who's a millionaire right
someone who's gone through all the
challenges that that's required to build
a million-dollar business become a
millionaire this man has a million
dollars right in his hands or in his
bank he's got a million dollars he's
attained the goal he's gone through
everything that he has had to do in
order to get that thing right just like
you opened up your heart that's what you
had to do to ultimately hopefully get
that thing your girlfriend right didn't
work out that way but that's okay if you
take all that money away from him and
you take all the way his connections
away from him and you put him in a
foreign country within a year he will be
a millionaire again the reason why is
because he's the type of person because
of the experiences that he has had that
can make a million dollars he is a
million dollar person it's not the
million dollars that matters so much
it's that you become a million dollar
person now to become a million dollar
person you've got to go through some
penny broke days you got to go through
all sorts of ups and downs challenges
disappointments minor successes and
setbacks to ultimately become a million
dollar person you would like to be the
type of guy that can approach women
create a relationship with one and
whatever your aspirations are with
regard to how you want to proceed in
that relationship with her and and then
that sets in your heart is what you want
right maybe you want maybe you want to
have a life partner you want a wife
maybe you just want a girlfriend maybe
you just want to get laid whatever it is
that's your thing but you're gonna have
to go through several you're gonna have
to fall down and hurt yourself a couple
times in order for you to become that
type of person because if you got what
you wanted
without the challenge associated with
the pain and failure that you're
experiencing right now it wouldn't
really be your
you wouldn't be able to appreciate it
the way you should be appreciating it
the way that God of the universe wants
you to appreciate it now you might say
to yourself Oh Helia that's bullshit I
really love her I really wanted her if I
would have had her things would be
exactly the way I want them and my life
would be great what I'm telling you is
no she was set there as a opportunity
for you to scrape your knees grow
stronger based on the challenge so that
you can try again and you might need to
try it now here's the thing when you try
again you already have the experiences
associated with failure
you won't make some of the same mistakes
right now don't get this twisted putting
your heart out there is never a mistake
opening yourself up to even get stabbed
even get hurt even for your heart to get
trampled on it's never a bad idea always
open your heart up never become callous
in your heart do it again but the
lessons you should learn are how you go
about opening your heart right a lot of
this is physiological and energetic so
breathe into your balls might be one of
my pieces of advice breathe deeper be
more grounded be more centered have a
stronger or more concrete intention when
you approach the next woman what's your
situation with her is over even if she
does decide to get with you again in any
time in the future if she's just like if
you said the right thing at the right
time one day and she decides to get back
with you it's the relationship will not
be founded on strength right
she will resent you in in in some very
subtle way for a very long time you
might end up getting with her several
years from now after you've grown
through the experiences of doing this
several different times and you're a
different person she won't fall in love
with you she's not gonna get with you
who you are right now she might get fall
in love with a stronger version of you
right that you're going to become by
through these challenges to understand
so be grateful and I'm
happy for you that she didn't give you
what you thought you wanted be grateful
for the challenge because in the same
way that when you go to the gym and you
challenge your muscles with greater and
greater extrinsic forces right basically
heavier heavier heavier weights you grow
stronger every week this was a heavy
load for you to carry and you're still
carrying gather what you need to
experience from this you know be very
practical about it what did I learn here
and what can I do differently gather
that make it a part of who you are if
they're tools now you now have tools to
navigate the next step of this journey
and then do it again
and guess what put your heart out there
and it might get hurt a second time cry
feel the emotion associated with it
mourn and then do it again and you might
get hurt again and you might get hurt
ten times before you find that one woman
at one circumstance that one experience
that transforms your life forever and
don't be fooled it won't be that singled
out opportunity gonna be that tenth
thing that made you happy it would have
been all nine that made you strong
enough to handle number ten you see that
buddy good luck