the bottom line here is that in your
early 20s you are becoming there are a
lot of question marks at this time but
at the same time you're doing a lot of
hard work when I say hard work I mean
you're testing things out but you're
going hard into the things that you test
don't try do so those who watch my
videos long enough you're probably
familiar with this type of language
forget about trying forget about making
an attempt forget about testing it out
although you may not end up in the
profession or in the area that you're
starting out you don't want to go
halfway you don't want to just dip your
toe in you want to jump in hard
do not try do go hard it requires a
tremendous amount of courage to say I'm
going to give this thing a chance I'm
going to give it my all and if it
doesn't work out that's okay but I know
that I tried my best
you