so we got a question from our buddy
Jason here who he's 19 years old and
he's been friends with his buddy since
they were in third grade I believe so
longtime friends and now that they're
nearly adults one of the things that his
friend has done since day one is
starting to wear on Jason and it's the
fact that he doesn't respect Jason's
time now mind you this is not some
playground third grade bullshit Jason's
19 years old damn near a man and his
friend isn't the same age so he's
wondering where is this disconnect such
that my best friend for so many years
has such disrespectful behaviors towards
me
more specifically what happens is he
makes plans with his friend his friend
doesn't show up or shows up very very
late but the thing is he's always been
doing this and Jason comes to me for for
a little bit of insight you know first
of all he wants to know like what's up
with my friend and should I just move on
and Jason is very specific about it the
course of action that he's thinking
about taking he's considering just
detaching himself completely from his
friend and moving on you know making him
no longer a part of his life because of
this disrespect for Jason's time Jason
also goes on to say that he doesn't want
to do that simply because this is really
his only friend Jason doesn't have a an
easy time making more friends so there's
a little bit of distance there because
if he lets go of the one friend he does
have it disrespects his time then he's
gonna have to go out and either be by
himself
or find new friends the reason why I
take this question because it might seem
to those who are watching it as like
well you know big deal toughen up go get
some new friends right you know it's
very easy for us to be callous about
other people's situations right it's
more difficult to be empathetic with
someone who reaches out with a problem
that seems mundane right or banal
it's a new word i started using right
just kind of mundane boring right what's
the big fucking deal
it is a big deal and there's a lot of
significance of what's going on here and
there's a lot of significance to how we
experience all the relationships in our
lives it's my conviction that every
single person in your life is there to
act as a mirror reflection of who you
are there are parts of you that you are
made to see through these people and
sometimes these are people that are very
rude to you sometimes they're the
meanest people to you sometimes they're
people that share lots of love with you
sometimes they're people that almost
seem as if they you know they serve no
point in your life but what I'm asking
you to explore is what is your friend
trying to tell you now obviously he's
not going to say something out of his
mouth and he doesn't know what's
actually going on what I'm asking you to
do is to be subjective about the
relationship about your experience with
the relationship and ask yourself what
is it that I'm supposed to learn through
this person and the experience that I'm
having with them right that's for you to
answer that's completely for you to
answer but what I'm inviting you to do
is to look at the circumstances in your
life and ask yourself how you're
creating them how you're attracting them
bringing them into your life because you
brought this boy into your life this
friend into your life and he's still
there you're still hanging on right
there's an attraction that's causing you
guys to be together there's something
that you're fulfilling for him and he's
fulfilling for you right there's an
emptiness there and you've got to ask
yourself I'm gonna throw out some random
ideas that I might have but I could be
completely wrong you know my my
assumptions are just based on the way
things typically work out but you got to
really answer these questions for
yourself if you're sticking around with
this guy and you don't have the capacity
to go and make new friends this and the
fact that he's disrespecting you in this
particular fashion means that you're
being shown
right you're giving you're given an
opportunity right now you're being
tapped on our kit by God or the universe
or you know whatever it is that you the
intelligent forces amongst us is trying
to wake you up to a particular idea that
perhaps you are the leech perhaps you
are the problem and you have some
working to do on your ability to get
people to honor and respect appreciate
and deal with you fairly or your ability
to say no and cut ties where you are
clearly being trampled upon right those
those could be the case based on the
type of character that you are because
if I was in the same situation it'd be a
totally different story I've had people
who are brought into my life that end up
disrespecting me but for me just because
of who I am and that's why this is all
very subjective I have to typically look
at how is it that I need to soften up
say I'm too hard I just know that about
myself I'm very very yang right this is
my natural predisposition so usually
when people are brought into my life
that that disrespect me in this
particular fashion or seem to be wishy
washy it's usually because it's showing
me Elliot relax a little bit grow soften
your heart let this guy in not
everything has to be transactional not
everything has to have a hard purpose
that's what I have to learn but from
what I'm listening to you when I'm
listening to your question and you're
telling me that you can go out and make
friends and that this guy's been
stepping on you you feel stomped on you
probably need to harden up right and I
don't say that in a condescending way
like toughen the fuck up what I'm
telling you to do is to do some deep
reflection on why you're letting this
happen and then what practical pragmatic
grounded steps you can take to change
yourself you see that's the most
important thing change yourself so that
the mirror reflection that other people
provide you with looks more like what
you want to see do you see it's not that
person's fault we war we go around
and through our lives pointing at other
people as if they're somehow outside of
us but like I invited you to consider
everyone that's in your life is a part
of you you've drawn that person into
your life so we don't fix other people
we fix ourselves so that we can see in
other people what we want to see so
that's it my friend
I hope that's resourceful for you do
some deep reflection about the type of
character you are but the version of
yourself that you are and would like to
become work on yourself and you're going
to notice that people are going to treat
you differently good luck