hey what's up guys before I get started
today I want to draw your attention to
this chalkboard behind me I'm getting
ready to begin creating some brand new
coaching videos a brand new series I'm
going to share with you pretty soon and
now since I'm a visual learner and
teacher I figured bringing back the
whiteboard like I used to back in 2008
2009 might be a good idea anyway today I
figured I'd answer a question I got a
question here from our Freddie a friend
Adam and Adam goes on to say hey Elliot
you're most likely not going to read
this but it never hurts to try
you're right buddy never hurts to try
I've been working out lately but I don't
see the point anymore since my chest
sticks out a lot and I mean it it's
called pectus carinatum the thing is I
hate my body every time I look in the
mirror I see my chest and I be like
killing myself I can't take my shirt off
at the beach or the swimming pools or to
even change at the gym locker room
without feeling like shit I don't know
how to tell my parents that I want to
see a doctor about it and about my
depression do you have any advice well
Adam I just discovered what ekta skerin
Adam is because you use the word in your
question and before I share a few bits
that might be supportive to you I
figured I'd do some research and punch
that word in to good old YouTube so I
punched it in up above and I found this
wonderful video from this incredible
young man who teaches people how to deal
with the very problem that he struggled
with isn't that amazing he apparently
has had the very same problems that
you've had and he's took it upon himself
to instead of allowing it to drag him
down and deform his outlook on life too
feature it and bring a gift to the world
in fact that's one of the very
principles that I live by that if you
cannot fix something absolutely cannot
fix something
then you must feature it right of course
you do the best that you can to deal
with the thing that you're dealing with
but owning who you are owning what you
have owned in your mindset owning your
circumstances owning your body is the
first step to life mastery self love and
I know that's hard when we have
challenges but my man we've all got
challenges but yours happens to be the
protrusion of a part of your body or
chest sticks out right mine
interestingly enough I didn't like
myself I struggled a bit had some
problems with the way I look as well
right I grew up where there was a clear
delineation in my neighborhood and in my
school between what's a black person and
what's a white person and Puerto Ricans
speak Spanish and I fit nowhere right
how's that to live but over time I've
discovered that the greatest gift that I
could give to the world is get over
myself and then pose various tools and
ideas and mindsets that I've used in
order to transcend the challenges that
God gave me purposefully so that I could
be a stronger version of myself and
inspire others just like our friend in
the video that I'm going to put actually
I'm gonna put the damn playlist our
young friend has a playlist all about
how to deal with pectus excavatum in
fact you know I keep calling him young
men because I don't remember his name
but I'm gonna pull it up right now
because he deserves a fucking shout-out
and I'll tell you why in a moment
Joely Fitness you'll see him here
putting on a pectus brace and he's got
exercises and stuff and of course I'm
directing you to go look at what this
young man has done not just because of
the information he's going to give you
but because of the young man's attitude
right
he like yourself like myself like every
fucking human being on earth has been
born with challenges things that make us
different things that hurt us things
that make other people hurt us things
that we don't like that we reject that
we want to get rid of but offer us the
greatest gift we could ever have which
is a challenge to grow stronger I often
use the metaphor the reason why I'm I
speak in terms of strength training is
because I'm a coach in that way but
unless there's some resistance unless he
adds some struggle to the barbell
there's absolutely no opportunity to
grow stronger and not only will you grow
stronger if you embrace except look in
the mirror right if you've watched
enough of my videos on my Elliot Hills
channel because this question came to my
shred cam channel you've watched enough
my videos you know that it's up to you
to love yourself to feature your
weaknesses to embrace your limitations
to grow beyond them not for yourself my
man we got to get over ourselves and I'm
not yelling at you I'm yelling at all of
us I do the same day same damn thing our
challenges aren't just for us we tend to
be so selfish that we want to take our
own lives because the challenge that we
have feeling so sorry for ourselves but
if you man the fuck up sometimes that's
what has to happen their chest friend
whew man fuck up you handle this and you
get over it you own it
not fix it but featuring you're going to
give hundreds thousands maybe tens of
thousands or millions of other young
people out there who had the same
problem similar problems all of the
motivation inspiration they need and
information to grow stronger themselves
bro you don't grow stronger for yourself
you don't deal with your challenges for
yourself you don't grow into the
strongest version for yourself
a neither do i we do it such that we may
empower others overcoming your
challenges is not just your right it is
your responsibility done