so we have a question from our buddy
Christie he he has a hard time starting
and maintaining conversations with new
people and obviously that can be a
detriment to our world you know if you
wants to meet women he wants to make
friends he's 16 years old he's up in a
difficult time approaching or
maintaining a conversation with someone
without it turning awkward because we
all know how that starts you know two
people come together and it seems as if
well you know we're good we're about to
engage and then it just quickly it turns
very awkward I got to completely be
honest with you I have a tendency to to
get into those awkward situations quite
often and it's because and this is my
problem not yours I'm going to share a
solution for you as well I'm very up in
my head a lot of times and people are
kind of distractions I'm busy you know
so I'm either on my way to doing
something thinking about doing something
and then here comes someone and my
challenge is really just to slow down
and afford people a piece of my time you
know the thing is that I'm a bit greedy
with my time greedy with myself so the
situation is that I now have to me
personally I have to calm down and
employ the tools and techniques of
conversation and mindful communication
that I'm going to share with you now
it's been said that he who asks the most
questions rules the conversation if you
want to engage in conversation with
someone the very first thing is what is
the sentiment from which it proceeds
that basically means what is your
objective here if your objective here is
to get something to do something like me
it's always like I'm always moving
forward I need to calm down but for you
if it's I just want to die genuinely
just want to create a relationship with
someone I generally want some friends I
genuinely would like to speak to this
woman and move forward in some sort of
relationship if you come from a genuine
place this is going to be far easier
than if lying is a technique but as a
technique it will help you also ask as
many questions as you can to that
individual find out where their hot
buttons are the things that really get
them excited most conversations start
out like you know what do you think of
the rate
I live in Tampa Bay what do you think
about the Rays ah they lost this weekend
blah blah or what kind of work do you do
and most of the time it's very
superficial very on the surface about
the weather and crap like that which you
know it's fun but really it for me again
it's like mindless bullshit conversation
just irritates me dive in if you ask
someone one question and they give you
kind of a surface answer follow follow
up with well how did for example if it's
what kind of work do you do ah you know
I'm an accountant what interesting how
did you get into that ah I do you see
now you're starting to take it one step
further in that particular direction
whenever you have someone would they do
follow up again listen closely follow up
again with how did you get into that and
then they'll tell you you know apply in
a situation my dad was an accountant and
you know he taught me when I was a kid I
used to work for him
that's fascinating your dad was an
accountant did he work for someone and
started his own business oh my dad owned
his own business in fact you know he uh
he hired me my first job was with my dad
that's really cool so you work with your
own family how does that work you know
how is it working with your own family
oh man you know that the truth is me and
my sister do you see do you see where
I'm going with this you start taking a
little bit deeper and you get closer and
closer to the individual and you listen
intently and move from a place of
genuine interest in that individual the
more interested you are in that
individual the more they soften the more
they yield the more they open up to you
right because they feel like what this
person's safe this person genuinely
cares is asking me questions far more
than the norm and you don't want to be
like a stabber you know they got some
people that are like they're
interrogating you you've got to be
sensitive and this requires practice you
got to be sensitive to where the
conversation is going and sort of be the
leader of it by asking more questions
refrain from telling too many stories
about yourself refrain from talking
about yourself and your own aspirations
too much if that person turns it around
on you and starts asking you questions
well that's cool now you're dancing most
you
fucking dance now you're dancing I'm
giving you a little bit you're giving me
a little bit and really it's that rhythm
that creates a fun conversation right
keep at he who asked questions rules the
conversation and show genuine interests
and what that other person is saying is
asking is telling you about ask them
more questions listen intently a little
trick you know this is this is a tip
it's a technique it's a tool so it's not
genuine but if you practice it it
ultimately may become genuine someone
says something and you don't necessarily
have something to say right away act
like you're thinking right there's a
little evil right I'm giving you a
little evil tip but you'll see how
effective it is and having that person
want to continue being with you go like
this hmm that's interesting right it
just lets that person feel confident
that you're actually thinking about what
they're talking about
see if they've got like a deep question
that they asked you you know what do you
think I should do about this Bob that's
a really interesting question pause for
a moment pausing is very powerful in
conversation a lot of times we're so
hysterical was so ungrounded we're so
focused on and anxious on moving this
conversation forward that we don't pause
enough it makes us feel awkward you know
they say that awkward pause pause for a
moment hmm my person to be standing on
their toes waiting to see what's going
to come out of your mouth next you're in
control of the conversation so there you
have it I often talk about being as
opposed to doing but sometimes doing
things supports you in your ability to
become something these are tools
techniques tricks right that you're
using to ultimately develop the
character associated with someone who
knows how to have long healthy useful
conversations and make more friends good
luck