I wrote a little intro I like to like
just preface the way we begin each time
what I'm feeling in my heart so I wanted
to share this with you guys before we
get started and then essentially it's
just a fire away you guys have me at
your disposal disposal for the next four
hours that lift you want to breathe into
your balls laughs oh you guys going to
do and do it now facilitate things make
sure they don't have was nice okay so in
my industry I'm a strength coach so the
next time science and in most industries
in general accepted Europe artist or a
poet writer depending on the type of
rider you're in a position where people
should look to you or you're trying to
position yourself as the expert as the
right person as the person that has all
the answers and in order to do that
you've got to prove everyone else wrong
I am NOT interested in that in any way
shape of pink in fact if I'm wrong
that's okay my ideas are supportive to
you or social too that's all that bad
esteem so I kind of wrote this when
we're at the hotel just to lay it out
there for you guys so we can get started
with slightly
place of pure service groundedness I'm
not the business of being right or
proving anyone or anything else wrong
like the court Chester or fool in
medieval times and nothing approval no
agenda will lofty aspirations only blunt
visceral sometimes crude and offensive
will always thought-provoking
entertainment purely the service of my
people I'll offer our heartfelt
annotations that may perhaps seen
thinking nonsense to ninety-nine percent
of everyone you use it but if my
regulation sparks in even a slightest
glimmer of hope courage or inspirations
who wanted is intended for done my job
and what I offer provides no support
that is my responsibility to reposition
my offer I'll show the person where they
might get to support the thing a lot of
times that's really what I'm doing it's
I really don't know but I heard this guy
talk about that rather than an expert or
guru sorts I act as a bigger than that
mighty point of something within you
that uh that you might not have seen
it's very difficult to become self
objective I think that's one of the
strongest was important to those that I
try to invite people to develop self
objectivity but I've got a big like my
father but like my father I have a big
mouth but I'm willing to say don't I see
you might not like it but that's one job
of the finger the other one is to point
you in direction that you may not have
known even existed I tend to explore a
lot of ideas I have no a lot of courage
with regard to what I will think about
what I was studied or a lot of people
there's taboos on what your she should
think about her
should study so if i can put you in a
direction or simply simply particularly
but that's a with that said I'm grateful
for your presence of approval for your
support I'm grateful for your admiration
and I'm grateful to earn a living by the
same score an old position that my
fourth grade teacher granted me 24 years
ago so that being said folks this is
this is the show true I'm going to ask
you to raise your hands first and it
goes up I'll do my best to support you
and and then I'll just view the
direction you guys team let's dance