so a few days ago I made a video about
how to deepen your voice and one of the
commenters writes Elliot I have a quick
question how is it that you become so
charismatic so I had nothing to do with
the deepening of the voice but
apparently a lot of people had the same
question because if you don't know in
YouTube if you hit the thumbs up button
for a comment it shows up higher and and
it gives an indication as to what the
readers of the comments are interested
in knowing more about or agree with and
apparently this one got a lot of thumbs
up so I figured I'd make this video for
you so with regard to becoming more
charismatic I'm going to take a bit of a
poetic approach the first thing I want
to draw to your attention is that we've
got three brains I've talked about this
before this is all very well documented
and believed in the scientific community
that we have a neocortex or cortex and a
medulla or brain stem type brain right
each one of those has a particular
function the neocortex is really the
human brain so one that makes human
beings unique it allows us to do things
like create technology mathematics
language things of that nature it's the
one that we spend most of our time
learning how to use in school and in
society then we've got the middle brain
which is the the cortex or also consider
the mammalian brain because it's the
same brain that most mammals have
monkeys have the same brain it's the
brain that creates tribal Association
loving feelings caring for our young
right so it's more of an animal brain
but it's higher than the lower brain
which is the reptilian brain or the
medulla or brainstem this is the brain
that does all the stuff 99% of the stuff
that happens inside us as human beings
that makes us human beings or alive is
controlled by the brain stem and the
reptilian brain it takes care of things
like beating your heart right so if you
didn't have that brain it just you die
digesting food secreting hormones making
a baby inside a woman even without her
having to think about making a baby
it grows your hair it grows your teeth
that grows your bones
it does all of the functions that we
don't have to think about that keep us
alive okay now with regard to that so
that's a scientific approach let's take
for a moment a religious approach to
this so bear with me but if you consider
Christianity the same triad also exists
you've got the Father the Son and the
Holy Ghost and if you consider how the
characteristics of each of those three
in that Trinity associate with the three
parts of the human nervous system you
can see how the father is sort of the
higher consciousness the higher brain
the one that is far more creative
perhaps and the other ones right father
the Creator then you've got the middle
brain right the son the son is also
synonymous with the mother in other
traditions now so if I if you consider
Native American traditions you have the
father the mother and they call it the
child we've got the father of the son of
the Holy Spirit so the son is like Jesus
Christ is the lover it's the one that's
associated with primal association with
caring for our young that's what makes
enamels unique love emotion in that
regard so the lower brain the lowest
brain is associated with the Holy Ghost
or the child simply because it acts
without having to think the highest
brain is the thinker you got the feeler
and you've got a doer right and the doer
like the Holy Ghost because the fecking
goes you can't see a ghost right but it
does shit without you seeing it the
entire peripheral nervous system
everything below your neck right below
that cortex your brainstem and
peripheral nervous system is all ghostly
the shit it does what it has to do
without you having to think about it
it's powerful it's the mover it's the
shaker it's the one that all vertebrates
have right so I also take a poetic
approach to that triad and I've used
this these terms before where I say
you've got your head brain your heart
and your balls right if you look at how
each of them correlate it's the same
thing at your head brain that basically
is our analytical
logistic rain you've got your heart
which is the feeling emotional brain and
you got your balls which is the doer
this is the the one that gets things
done this is where your hormones are
secreted your sex center you know sexual
energy is a lot of is really what
animates a lot of what happens in the
bodies I call the balls and it's also
the doer
you know if someone who does things as
what balls a guy's got some balls reason
what reason why it's because he does
stuff he gets off his ass and does
things so when you asked me Eliot how is
it that you're so charismatic right
we've got to consider that 90% of the
people us in the Western world and that
live in societies our condition through
school systems that cause us to sit down
shut up and just use our neocortex use
our head brain to ignore everything from
down below in most schools you're now
recognizing the fact that there I was
talking to my sister the other day and
my brother and my brother is a school
teacher and the kids don't have recess
anymore they can't use their body's phys
ed is country you know they keep
shrinking it down so this whole idea of
the intelligence of the body of the
heart and the balls is shrinking and
it's causing a lot of dysfunction in our
lifestyles and in our in our health but
anyway the fact is that we're shrinking
the value of our heart and our balls the
body brain right the the Son and the
Holy Ghost right and what happens is it
leaves people robot-like it leaves us
computer-like because we're taught to
sit down shut up and just absorb via the
head brain and then regurgitate so
everything that we do stays up here
right we go in to watch TV we play video
games everything excludes the bodies or
the motility of the individual motility
is a term used to describe how the body
will bring forth its it's feeling how it
expresses the feelings the heart and the
balls work together to create motility
so when you ask me how I become so
charismatic it's because I've decided to
trust my heart in my balls to trust the
Son and the Holy Ghost and ignore what
is happening in the head brain to a
particular degree it doesn't mean that
I'm you know so crazy that I just shut
off my brain but that term shut off your
brain is something that I allow to
happen so I don't script any of these
videos because if I script them they're
in my fucking head when you watch me do
live events like in my my a lot Elliott
live I field questions without thinking
about it but what you'll notice is that
I'm moving all over the place when I
make these videos I'm rocking off then
people like why are you
why do you rock so much when you're
talking away I embody everything that I
say everything that I say like I'm
saying it right now I embody look at
what I'm doing I'm using my heart and my
balls to bring forth the things that I
want to share with you right so you say
charismatic but there's another term
which you can't fucking remember right
now we're basically it's coming from my
heart
see when I share with you guys I don't
share with you things that are in my
head of course there are things that
I've learned and there are things that I
absorb but I bring them down into my
body through experience so most of the
shit that I share with you guys it's not
because I read a lot of books it's
because I read it and I experience it
and I either experience it through my
imagination right and through my
imagination stimulates my heart and my
balls to make it feel as if the thing is
happening in me they've done Studies on
Olympic athletes who where if they
visualize sprinting their body actually
is stimulated they put like these
testers things on their muscles and
their muscles are twitching as they're
imagining what's happening I embody the
things that I learn right and this is I
don't know why or how I learned how to
do this because it's in my nature when I
was a kid and I was in school they had
to give me attention deficit disorder
drugs to shut me down and quiet my body
because I got up and I moved around and
I was just way too active for the
teacher to teach me and you know made me
feel like you know this key and everyone
else think that this kids retarded
there's something wrong with him but as
I grew up I realized that my genius is
in my ability to embody the things I
learn and bring it forth in a
charismatic fashion so what I would
invite you to do right you were hoping
that I'd give you buy tips and secrets
shit that your head could use to apply
on your body in order to be more
cosmetic but I can't what you've got to
do is you've got to let go of your head
you've got to literally shut off that
neocortex it's a valuable tool but we've
allowed it to become our master you've
got to shut off that part of your brain
and trust your heart and your balls to
produce the truth of what you want to
express now the thing is not everything
that I say is right or true but it is
genuine it is heartfelt it's from my
balls because I literally just opened up
I don't script I don't think I just give
so because I trust the Holy Ghost
I trust the Sun a lot of Christians out
there you call yourself Christians but
you don't trust the Jesus Christ in you
the son or the Holy Ghost it's all about
the father the father father father
father father father father father head
brain get out of your fucking head get
into your heart get into your balls and
look it's scary you gotta have courage
to do this shit right it takes me a lot
of courage to share this way with you
guys I make some videos and you've seen
them or it's like this guy people think
I'm nuts but I don't care you know it's
like I don't know if it's courageousness
or carelessness I just don't care I'm
bringing forth because I know that it's
genuine so and I trust God right I trust
the spirit in me I trust the Holy Ghost
that if I'm just genuine it's good it's
from my heart it's true and perhaps
maybe maybe not but perhaps it may be
resourceful to other people that's why I
put on this camera and I do it for you
so that you can perhaps gain something
perhaps permission to let your heart and
your balls speak so that's it bro shut
off the brain and speak from your balls
good look Elliot sit what
you