today we got a question for my buddy
Robby who says what do you do
about life when it just doesn't seem
fair how do you maintain your motivation
and continue on with life when you've
been hit with a blow he basically says
that he enjoys working out things have
been going great but his girlfriend just
broke up with him for reasons of her own
and says that she says she just wants to
find herself and of course they've been
dating for a while and life was going
good and he was happy jovial and getting
great gains at the gym but now all of a
sudden boom I go to the gym and after
this blow to my to my ego to my spirit
to my consciousness I go to the gym -
just robotic and I can't seem to get
motivated for the thing that I actually
love to do for myself what do i do
Elliot how do I break out of this slump
so one of the things that you got to
understand about my grande of fitness my
brand of exercise is that it is a
medicine I truly believe that exercises
of medicine and that we can choose
different forms of movement to evoke
what needs to happen in each individual
so sometimes I'll make a video and I'll
talk about pounding your chest and
screaming and pumping your fists
well that's type of exercise where it's
a medic it's a prescription for a
particular type of person in particular
type of way sometimes I say you need to
breathe deeply and just feel your body
feel your feet feel your hands feel your
belly sometimes I say you gotta flip
tires and push yourself to that
transcendence rep right you see
sometimes I say you've got to work on
structural integrity sometimes I say you
got to work on core strength sometimes I
say you gotta lift heavier sometimes you
need more volume you my friend are in a
place where you're going to need a
specific prescription of exercise to
help you in your current circumstance
because obviously doing your robotic
body building type routine that you did
before when you didn't have the illness
but you have now that mental illness
that you have now and it worked well but
now you need a new prescription and I'm
going to invite you this is just my idea
of course I can't write prescription
I'm not I'm an exercise doctor I don't
know if they actually write
prescriptions do there oh yeah I guess
when you write programs my prescription
for you my friend just go run go jog go
jog because you're going to fill your
body with oxygen one of the things that
you need to do especially at this point
where your heart is broken is you need
to exercise your heart your heart is ah
let's close down I want your heart
beating see doing this and doing this
will get your heart rate up a little bit
but I want you to have a deep rhythmic
OB that means you can do sprinting
sprinting is the problem with sprinting
and sprint intervals and if intervals
I'll get your heart rate up but then
allow them to subside is that they don't
allow your mind to get to something
happens when you jog or you repeat a
particular mantra or a movement over and
over again you fall into almost like a
meditative place so now your body is
it's under the control of your
physiological responses heart beating
and they're in a rhythmical way your
body's moving in a rhythmical way but
also your mind falls into track with
that rhythm and it's a form of
meditation really all of this is a form
of meditation and I think with a heart
break like yours and knowing that you
need to go to your body to find peace
solace gain and grow the strongest
version of yourself I say back off the
weights were a little bit they're not
serving you obviously anymore you don't
feel good about them but lifting weights
and get out into the street or even get
onto a treadmill and start trucking your
way back to health
done