hey what's up guys today I decided to do
one of my good old yo Eliot q and A's
got a question here from one of our
viewers but before I get started I want
to say thank you to all you who read my
daily article or newsletter today I've
written an article that might be
interested to people who want to improve
their core strengths I got an offer in
my blog post so you can read it down
below as you can read it every day by
clicking the link down below but today
we're going to talk about something a
little different
taking a question here from our friend
Randy I thought was so fascinating and
interesting and long so those you were
watching I hope you have some patience
with Randy and I as I described it
circumstances but I've got a very
succinct answer and invitation really
for Randy and I think some of you will
find it very resourceful given where you
might be on your journey of growing
stronger so Randy goes on to say oh
Elliot have that massive question for
you which I hope you could shed some
light on maybe even make one of your
videos if you feel like it yeah I feel
like it today
I think I'm smart and strong minded I've
worked full-time ever since I got out of
high school and I've worked at the same
factory for the past 13 years I'm really
good at playing guitar and I love it I
have some relationships with women here
and there I'm 33 years old 6 foot 4 and
220 pounds however I feel like I'm in
the middle of a crisis I often feel like
my problems or habits are taking over my
life problems like foot problems it's
got some crooked toe problems makes it
very difficult for him to stand without
being in pain really bad anxiety had
high blood pressure panic attacks bad
posture obsessive-compulsive disorder
fear of people seeing me have a panic
attack that one's kind of fucked up so
yeah panic attacks your favorite panic
attacks and favorite people seeing you
have panic attacks man that's a bad
place to be bad posture
shortness of breath high LDL cholesterol
my doctors telling me about then the bad
habit on top of that is heavy beer
drinking about a six-pack of Bud Light
during the week about 12 on the weekend
usually not on Sunday because it's the
Lord's Day all right and he smokes
cigarettes not always eating healthy no
exercise lack of motivation after I work
a 10-hour day with a 30-minute commute
back and forth the panic attacks usually
happen I want to better myself but I'm
not sure where to start so my ultimate
question is where should I begin to
become a stronger version of myself in
my situation
damn Randy yeah where do you begin
because you just listed about 17 things
that you're dealing with brah
not only dealing with problems but
you're dealing with problems that create
more problems and then problems that
don't even exist yet so you're all kinds
of problems man you've got this
cornucopia of shit to deal with it where
do you begin good damn question do you
begin with the social anxiety disorder
you know maybe there's a pillow for you
there or a special doctor or counselor
or a piece of information la can help
you with with social anxiety or do you
do with the panic attacks do you deal
with do I begin with your heavy beer
drinking where do we begin man it's all
fucked up right and that's why you come
here so I'm not shedding making light of
your situation but the immensity of it
is very clear through your language you
spoke it this way I'm just reading it
and reiterating it so I said I'd be
succinct short to the point there are
two things you need to do my man you
don't need to do 17 only two things that
will revolutionize your life if you do
these two things on a consistent basis
for a minimum of six
today's you will no longer be the Randi
who's watching this video now you must
change two things very simple things
number one is the conversation you have
with yourself first thing in the morning
whether you know it or not whether
whether not anybody watching these
videos or a cognizant of it or conscious
of it you have conversations with
yourself you're saying things to
yourself you're feeling certain things
every day when you first wake up and for
most people it is oh no oh no no no no I
gotta get up again
I gotta do my job again I got a deal
with bullshit again I'm gonna have
anxiety again oh no no no no so they
begin their day with negative vibrations
they begin their day by saying no you
don't need to change a whole lot of
things man but that one moment in the
morning when you first become aware that
you're waking up say yes yes to the
world yes for the opportunity to live in
this world yes to be able to breathe yes
to the Sun rising yes to you becoming a
stronger version yourself because you're
going to do the next thing which I'm
going to offer you number one is to
change your thought very first thought
in the morning you can go deeper by
using affirmations and visualizations
throughout the day but I've made videos
like that and your problems are big I
don't want to give you too much shit to
do only give you one thing man and if
you do that one thing with a fox seed
first thing in the morning and you do it
every day you'll be a new man number two
is an actual practical application of a
principle called exercise we often think
of social anxiety or panic attacks and
depression and all these things that are
unrealized in your head something wrong
with my head maybe there's something
I can read or maybe there's a video I
can watch or maybe there's a pill I can
take that can rewire the the neural
pathways in my brain or subdue some of
these bad hormones that are making me
feel horrible and we think it's all
happening in the head take notice of
where your social anxiety is stop right
now we live the experience and tell me
where you feel it because you're not
feeling it in your brain your brain
don't really have feelings in fact
you're feeling it in your body so you
can either when you're doing both but
given this perspective that the body is
of mind you can either work to change
your mind by working the body to
exercise and use exercises the medicine
is medication prescribed properly for
where you are in your life given the the
state of your nervous system given the
state of your biomechanics given the
state of your health exercise needs to
be appropriate you begin changing your
body you begin getting and fit into
physical shape by doing simple physical
activities particularly a daily ritual
your body will change and it will
support the change that you're already
starting in your mind get up every day
and say yes then put on your shoes and
take a walk I don't know where you live
I don't know how cold it is but it
really doesn't matter because the
elements outdoors invigorates it's 30
degrees out which people in Florida
freak out about
then get outside and walk man sucking in
that cold air and blowing out that smoke
all that pumping is going to cleanse
your lungs it's going to cleanse your
heart it's going to stimulate energy and
Chi in your body you're going to feel
like shit at first because you're gonna
detox cuz you need a lot of shit and
drink too much beer but eventually I
give it a week two weeks three weeks
I've given
I've made a video by the law of threes
three days three weeks three months
commit to three commit to three commit
to three once you get to the end of
three months you're not the same person
you're different person commit my man to
gettin up and taking a walk start with
half an hour if it's too much for you
then build up to an hour if you can't do
in the morning cuz you're rushing off to
commute then do it in the evening when
the Sun Goes Down fine you don't have
here's the other thing bro as I'm
reading your your story you really have
nothing to lose you have no woman gonna
have any children according to this if
your job you've been in for 13 years
that's a different story
beyond nothing lose all you have to do
and all you have at your disposal is
time for yourself how are you using that
time for yourself are you grocery
shopping and preparing food I don't want
to give you too much that's just an idea
so I'll keep my promise and keep this
short
wake up with a yes and go for a walk
your life will transform done