hey what's up guys today my blog post
which you could read down below is
titled go hard then go home how not to
be lazy lifter essentially I point to
the fact the principle that you've got
to balance out your anabolic work and
your catabolic work your go hard work
and your rest work your striving work
and you're resting work your yang
activity and your e'en activity and yang
activity is bright hot and penetrating
where Yin activity is cold dark and
receiving and this is a principle of
life we even see it in the daily
rotation of the earth and our experience
of the Sun and Moon right these are
principles that's why the Tai Chi symbol
is such a powerful description I mean to
describe how to live our live so today I
figure I'd give you guys 6 dark
principles a personal growth and I call
them dark principle principles because
they reflect the in aspect the soft
aspect the recovery the reflection the
soft aspect of growing stronger which is
intrinsically linked you absolutely
cannot sever this from the coin right
you can't have one that can't have heads
without the tails right very often we
ignore this though and that's why I
often try to point to these two these
principles in my blog post in my videos
and in fact if you watch my videos for
several years this is something
requiring theme but today I'm going to
give you guys did I say 6 I'm in five my
bad 5 I want to give you five principles
dark principles of personal growth the
very first one these are all by the way
these are all tools I personally use
many of them are used for years some of
them I just started choosing recently
because of course I'm just learning as I
go along and
made some really big mistakes especially
with regard to going hard and not going
home
being all yang and aggression and not
having enough softness being real
aggressive with no tenderness right so
I've spoken about this in multiple
videos and now I'm being forced to
practice and execute and really master
many of the things I've known and I've
talked about and now what I'm going to
share with you today here are just a few
the practices that some of which I've
used but some of which are new the very
first one which is new is to work in
spurts I'm the type to just go hard
without stopping that's just my natural
tendency I'll go till I collapse that's
how I train in the gym that's how I run
my but that's how I do my work my
business I just go when I used to make
videos I was making three four videos a
day sometimes four years I did this with
no break grind grind grind grind well I
was forced to yield I was forced my
physiology my psychology yeah pressed on
me and forced me to take a freaking
break and that's why you see me the way
you see me here today because months ago
I stopped making videos I moved my gym
and I had to restructure my lifestyle my
lifestyle my work habits to be in
congruence to be in integrity with
natural law so working in spurts this is
how I do it now I take 33 minute work
intervals what I do is I set a clock for
33 interval 333 minutes 33 minutes the
number 33 comes from a an interesting
lecture I once heard by Eugene Schwartz
who's a famous copywriter and he said
take 33 minutes and 33 seconds okay and
set your clock anyway I thought it was
interesting that he said 33 point 33 so
I set my iPhone clock for 33 minutes and
I dig it I go hard what's interesting
though is that sometimes I'm going so
hard that beeper goes off and I have to
force myself to stop I have to be strong
enough to stop it beeps and I say I'm in
the middle of something
okay toughen up you got to do this you
got to rest and I'll take about ten
minutes I'll either just go for a walk
around the block I'll lay in my hammock
or I'll just read or do something else
the whole idea is that you got to take
at least ten minutes away from your
activity if you're studying if you're
working at a job when you're training
you know that you have to take rest
intervals it's a training principle and
it's a life principle so work in
intervals first number two go to sleep
this is crazy I remember being in
college and having friends who would
cram right so what that means is that
they had a test or they had to
accomplish some gargantuan feat of
scholarly activity right you know you've
got a report or you got a test or
whatever you got and it would stay up
all night trying to get it done now me
just I just followed my intuition from
an early age I kind of liked what my
body says is where I try to go I would
just go to sleep
I was tired ten o'clock eleven o'clock
twelve o'clock whatever case maybe you
want to stay up studying I'm going to
fuck to sleep because I have to honor my
Physiology what at what becomes of your
activity is completely intrinsically
linked to your physiology to your weight
the way you take care of yourself to
your health your health is number one
right even though this is my Elliot
Health Channel and not my shred cap
channel I'm talking about health here
folks because without a strong
physiology without a strong body without
a strong mind no matter what you do even
if you're great at what you do you're
bound to be less than your best and
you'll ultimately break the fuck down
and that's a recipe for not being the
strongest version yourself so ah my wife
she's a PTA president and one of my
children at my children's school and
they brought in an expert recently in
the expert spoke about the the number
one factor for children who don't
succeed when they are you know when they
reach high school and college and the
number one factor the number one factor
was nuts not studying
enough not reading enough not spending
enough time at school but it was not
sleeping enough isn't that crazy you
want an expert on education in the
school system is telling us that in
order to do well in order to do better
in order to succeed you must sleep crazy
as fuck isn't it get to bed as early as
you can I say 10:00 10:30 latest I've
been getting a bit about 9:00 9:30
because I get up about 5:00 5:30 right
that's just my rhythm but I say get to
bed as many hours before midnight as
possible right 8 9 10 when the Sun
starts going down you should start going
down start thinking about when can I
start winding down and getting into bed
so that you could fully recover not just
physically physiologically mentally you
will be a better person by taking this
dark principle to heart and getting your
ass to bed number three rehydrate your
brain thrives on water your entire
nervous system if you can think of it as
like an electrical system what happens
when well what happens when you take a
blow dryer and you throw it into a
bathtub full of water that electricity
Sparks and flies all over the place
magnificent lights show especially if
there's somebody in there right because
water is a transmitter of energy you
want more energy you want to think
better you want to succeed drink more
water sounds crazy because it's just too
basic number four cardio
instead of coffee right oftentimes
especially in the middle of the day or
you know at any time that we've been
working our asses off in a minister date
or sedate matter right with sedentary
matter right all of us are forced at
some time particularly during the day
unless you you know you have a physical
labor job which even that you know in
that case you still want to change the
rhythm of the beat of the activity every
once in a while most of us are kind of
sitting and we're kind of were sedate
were sedentary I keep saying sedate
instead a sedentary or a sedentary
sitting at school we're sitting in
traffic or sitting in our office
or sitting sitting sitting sitting and
slowly our metabolism begins to drop and
our attention begins to wane and we
start to lose our ability to crush it
instead of dehydrating yourself with a
with another cup of coffee right I have
nothing against coffee I took a cup of
coffee in the morning but know that in
the middle of the day if you did take a
cup of coffee it kind of screws up your
circadian rhythm also so you screw up
principle number two right principle
number two can't be executed if you're
drinking coffee at 4 o'clock in the
afternoon so instead go for a walk I
recently bought a treadmill and I put in
my office and I know that every day
around midday after I've been crushing
it and grinding and making videos
writing blog posts and creating products
I get on my treadmill for a number of
reasons of course it's great exercise
for fat loss and whatnot but because it
brightens me back up it gets the pumping
of the heart the pumping of your
physiology another really good activity
that you could engage in that's not
analogous to walking or doing some
cardio is our rebounding right they've
got these little trampolines and if you
can get one and put in the corner of
your room or your office or your dorm
room wherever you study and whatnot and
just get on it and bounce the pumping
effect drives energy through your body
builds energy in your body all right you
can do it without a trampoline I've
eight
crazy-ass Elliott Hulse videos where I'm
bouncing and breathing at the same time
this is a magnificent way in in forms of
various forms of martial arts and
Chinese medicine they call that bone
washing bone marrow washing they just
shake and vibrate it brings up your
energy and it grounds your energy it's
an interesting thing because the
vibration the shaking kind of opens up
and relaxes the the muscular system
around your chest your belly your pelvic
floor and even if your face is you allow
it to relax so it's right you know of
course you got to be courageous enough
not just to take the time
but to do silly shit like that
especially if people are watching but
maybe you start the movement right and
explain to them that this is a this is a
powerful technique for achieving success
maybe you should do it to get your whole
office at your old school get all your
friends bouncing around and vibrating
and making deep sounds and then finally
number five when you're done be done all
too often we engage by putting our full
effort forth and then when it's
completed either the deadline is up or
we just can't do anymore and we're done
we complete the activity but carry the
stress with us we're thinking about it
right we leave the job we leave the
office and we go home and we're thinking
about the shit that we've already done
right oh I should have done this oh I
wish I would have oh I hope it did oh I
wonder if oh maybe uh uh uh uh uh
cut the shit off when it's done it's
done done