what's up guys today one of our friends
asks us what's probably one of the
oldest questions that thinking man has
asked himself since the dawn of language
and when it comes to Elliott Hulse for
some support about how to navigate it
hopefully I can offer you an idea or two
from some of the greatest teachers that
have graced our presence human humanity
and maybe shed some light on what
they've been trying to tell us with
regard to the purpose of life and our
friend is feeling as if there is none
and I can't argue with him because he
makes a good point so let's listen he's
21 years old he has an issue he says
that he has this gift and his gift is
actually his thirst for more knowledge
he's insatiable he wants to know more
and more and more and that's a great
thing especially living in the world
that we live in because check it out
because of his continuous thirst for
knowledge he is a incredible student
he's been lifting so he's in good shape
his a great student is a top of his
class he has an offer from a
multinational corporation for when he
graduates he's ambitious he has goals he
plays instruments he taught himself how
to play the guitar now he's teaching
himself how to play the piano he's uh he
does very rarely strays away from
anything he's looking to achieve he's a
winner in shorter words I could possibly
put it he's a fucking winner our dude is
making shit happen he knows exactly what
he wants he knows how to get the
information to support it he goes and
gets it but now he has an issue it seems
as if it's a double-edged sword his gift
has become a curse in a way because he's
constantly asking questions looking for
answers and recently he's been delving
into the universe and astrophysics hey
we got a badass here he was raised as a
Muslim but he has long let go of that
belief because he says he's more
spiritual similar to Elliott in the
sense he says I take bits and pieces of
everything and come up with my own
philosophy interesting don't you do that
because you come into this world alone
and you die alone your experiences are
alone yours the stories that people tell
you even though they're theirs you alone
have to interpret them and blend them
into how you navigate your
so for your philosophy and for your
religion to be your own it's pretty
fucking human but anyway he's and he
says in any case recently the idea of a
no afterlife has been bugging me the
point where I've lost ambition I'm
changing from who I used to be I don't
push that transcendent rep anymore he
says he just doesn't push himself he has
dull conversations with friends and
family where before he was filled with
philosophy and questions but now his
question is why am I even bothering why
am I doing this what is the point at the
end of the day we're all made from
hydrogen atoms we're just going to die
we just happen to be highly evolved
capable beings everything is worthless
so on and so forth Elliot please you
know what's the point of all this if
there's no afterlife
well you're the very first thing because
there's so much my friend the very first
thing is you're experiencing the
cognitive dissonance
you're breaking up some eggs to create
an omelette meaning there's some pain
associated with growth and you've been
newly introduced to a story or an
element that has fucked up a story that
you've believed for a long time that
there's an afterlife now I'm not making
any judgments about whether or not
there's an afterlife or not but the fact
is you're 21 years old he probably just
came across the idea or significantly
big koe you just recently started really
uh considering the idea that something
you've been told since the time you were
a child doesn't exist right there's no
afterlife right that's like if someone
said to you tomorrow listen our 21 year
old male friend you're not actually a
male you're a female but you didn't know
that did you
you'd be freaked the fuck out like it
just does make any sense because from
the time you were born you've been told
I'm of this this is what the world is
made of this is the stories that we we
didn't we don't they don't say stories
they say truth but every truth is a
story in a way this is the truth about
the world and the afterlife and so on
and so forth and even though you're
clever even though you're intelligent
even though you're free-thinking an
objective you still have to break up
with that old truth because you've got
new information to support what you are
now
thinking about where you now seem to be
going so any pain that you're
experiencing right now look at it
objectively also don't get wrapped up in
the melodrama of there's no purpose of
life and I feel because what happens is
our body is intelligent so the very
first place that you experience the pain
cognitive dissonance I say cognitive
dissonance but you feel it as pain in
your body take a look at how your
breathing notice if you're becoming
depressed and when I say depressed I
don't mean here I mean notice if your
breathing if you're breathing less
shallow you're not exercising as much
you're not going out you you're just not
expressive you're becoming depressive
take notice of what you're doing to your
body or what is happening in your body
because that's a very place first place
to go it always is sometimes United some
comments you guys are sick and tired of
me saying this but that is my message
that is my message so that's what my
videos will always be about go to your
body it's about the body but take notice
that is just a reaction it's simply a
reaction it's not telling you anything
except that your physiology is
responding to a severe stimulus and
guess what happens to stimulation and
physiological responses to them they go
away if you don't attach to them right
because you can become very enrolled in
this experience that you're having and
now you think about it meaning you're
going to perpetuate you're going to
Kindle the problem by thinking about it
I feel pain in my body it's associated
with an idea I just got right that
there's no afterlife
now you're attaching bigger words to it
no significance purpose fullest life now
you can become depressed because you're
kindling the story and it's going to
keep depressing your body so that's my
very first thing dude stop stop stop
stop stop stop stop stop for a moment
stop talking about it feel what you're
feeling in your body if you can breathe
exercise go walk go for a run start
jogging
get some energy back in your body so you
don't get fucking depressed ha cuz
that's the worst thing you can happen
now
cuz now you're screwed and you're
intelligent and all we need is more
screwed-up intelligent people walking
around with all their cleverness feeling
depressed and fucking us all up okay
being depressed and clever at the same
time means you're fooling yourself
you're drinking your own kool-aid and
you're to go you're gonna fuck with
other people you can start writing books
and stuff making people depressed I'm
being facetious but hang in there dude
it's the very first thing the second
thing is this story that we've always
wanted to enroll in we constantly do and
we even have teachers and when I say
teachers I talk about I'm talking about
the profits and when I say that word
profit I don't necessarily meet in the
religious sense I mean someone who's
prophetic someone who's poetic someone
who is who has an insight to the deeper
realities to the deeper resourcefulness
of a resourceful way of being able to
live on earth you know and what happens
is mankind we take these profits and
then we end up worshipping them and then
they're like you know they come back
later on they're like oh you guys got
all fucked up Jesus comes back right
Jesus comes to them what they were
waiting for the Messiah and he looks at
all the people all the Jews who were
waiting for him doing the things that
were associated with what the ancient
wisdom taught them but they got it all
fucked up and he's like ah guys you're
idiots come on right Jesus does that
Muhammad comes back and he sees it or
comes and he sees that they've got it
they're worshipping all these idols and
he's like hi you know there's just one
and then he gets all upset and he breaks
up all the idols in the temple Buddha
comes and sits under a fucking tree and
just says you motherfuckers don't get it
so I'm just gonna chill out here until
you guys you really want to know do
because I ain't gonna bother you you
really want to know good I'm gonna sit
right here ask me something right this
is how all the teachers did it but then
we we turn it into religions and and
then we go back to the story that fucked
us up to begin with that there's some
end point to life there's some place to
get there's somewhere to go there's
something
to win do you see your problem the
problem is that you're a winner and you
recognize that not only that but you're
intelligent at creative warrior winner
you know how to you know what you want
you know how to think you know how to go
get it
so you've been posed with the the
biggest question the one that there's
reason why we have philosophy and
religion and is eating you alive because
it's very difficult to win it's very
difficult to answer that question what
is the purpose of life from the logical
standpoint because we win with logic you
see you you use your cognition to learn
new languages you use your cognition you
use your brain you use your your logic
and your analytical skills your
objective reasoning what makes human
beings have technology and language
right that marvels us we're so marveled
by ourselves because we have the ability
to do the things that we do but it's
just that gift that fucks us up because
you try to answer the bigger question
the more subtle overreaching question
with that type of logic and it won't
work it's like trying to bite your teeth
with your teeth that's what Alan Watts
would say it's trying to smell your nose
with your nose it's trying to touch the
tip of this finger with this finger
because you are it do you see you can't
you can't touch the tip of this finger
with this finger because this finger is
it so you have to give up the whole
thing completely and just enjoy the
finger I hope you can follow I hope you
understand what I'm saying here now one
of the greatest metaphors I've ever
heard for the purpose of life
is the flower and if you if you study
Buddhism the foot and even Hinduism in
the East they kind of I don't know how
they figured it out or or they probably
didn't corrupt it the same way we didn't
in the West in the West we I think we
destroyed wisdom you know like the
Library of Alexandria like we just you
know with with one succession they were
like fuck everybody else and their ideas
destroy because when you destroy ideas
you destroy wisdom and when you destroy
wisdom you have an ungrounded culture an
ungrounded culture is very easy to
manipulate right like I always say an
ungrounded body is very easy to live
late because you're up in your head so
in the West we've gone to the head we've
got the technology associated with all
the abilities of the head but we've lost
our grounding because wisdom has been
destroyed in the East I don't think that
was the case now I'm not a historian but
I think they respected the wisdom enough
that even if I've my empires gonna take
over your empire we're keeping all the
books for read nation we're gonna we're
going to infuse it into our
understanding you know I believe
Alexander the Great had that as a as an
idea in his expansion of the Roman
Empire in that particular time but uh
but again Alexander's library got burned
huh anyway I'm of course I'm digressing
quite a bit today
follow me quick please if you can sow
that wisdom of the east in the in their
wisdom they would often use the flower
as a metaphor for life and you've got
many different petals flowers you know
flowers with two petals flowers with a
thousand a million petals so on and so
forth and each the purpose of each
flower is to be a to peddled flower or a
thousand petal flower and we marvel at
all the significance associated with
each flower doesn't matter what kind of
flower if you're looking at a sunflower
you're looking at a tulip you're looking
at a rose you're looking at a dandelion
the purpose of the dandelion is just as
significant as the purpose of the
rosebush
meaning that science the universe
quantum physics astrophysics God Allah
whatever story you've told yourself
about the overriding intelligence that
guides us that's we we think we're doing
life but life is actually doing us
because this greater intelligence is
moving this whole fucking thing now we
have objective reasoning about it and we
sort of contribute in a way but not
always that intelligence saw the soil
and said I want a dandelion shit it says
I want weeds
I want thorn bushes I want a thousand
petals flower and each one is as
significant as the other the thorn bush
is as significant as a thousand petaled
Lotus because it comes out of the
metaphysical soil that we all come out
of if the rosebush is - or the thorn
bush is too rapid it doesn't have this
ability from as far as we know but I
wrapped it rapid objective ability its
ability to see the future to see the
past and to make its way and said to
itself god damn I'm really sharp people
don't like to touch me it makes no
fucking sense that I'm this sharp and
look at that tulip ah two lips soft and
kissable such an interesting term for a
flower two lips it's like a vagina
mmm ah what a nice flower people want to
snap smell and pick and sell and touch
and kiss this flower but me they stay
away from it would be a little silly you
see but of course human beings attach
stories to different pieces of nature
also you know we call you know we call
light we use light as a metaphor for
good and darkness as a metaphor for for
evil well that again is the story humans
we made that shit up because there is no
there is no light without darkness there
is no you cannot understand appreciate
and kiss the tulips if there is no
contrast of the thornbush meaning that
the thornbush mix the tulip what it is
because of contrast and it is good I
create all these things and it is good
did you say that's what our ancestors
wanted to tell us so the purpose it is
nothing more than to stand in its place
and be one of what God is doing through
it that's it that's the only purpose of
all of these flowers all of these bushes
all these lotuses they're significant in
that they come out of this intelligence
but their purpose is far beyond anything
they could ever even recognize I gave
both of those a purpose saying that
their purpose is contrasts so that one
could foretell of and tell the story of
the other but really you know what if
you ask a if you have if you ask insects
but the purpose is one would be like
well the foreign one its purpose is to
keep the you know the animals that would
eat us out of here because they get
burned up and I can't live here if if
they don't get thrown up by the thorn
bush and oh you the tulips yeah we love
to just hang out we live in them
sometimes because they're so cozy that's
what the purpose is to those particular
things you can't nail down your purpose
I make these videos I say my purpose is
to become the strongest version myself
and inspire others well you know my
purpose is to some people so annoy the
shit out of them so be watch my videos
they fucking hate me some people there's
I mean their their channels of their
videos well they just make fun of me hey
the purpose of Elliott Hulse is to be an
idiot so we have something to giggle
about
that's my purpose that's how it hosts
purpose from that perspective
perspective is everything
shit I'm throwing a lot at you guys
right now perspective is everything and
there's a billion perspectives which one
are you going to enroll in which story
because there's a billion of them are
you gonna choose to make yourself a
slave to you're making yourself a slave
to the story that there's no afterlife
and somehow that's bad it's just a story
it's just a perspective get over it
don't allow it to ruin the beauty of
your of your tulips of your two lips
don't let it ruin your beauty and hey
guess what you know what if what God
wants to do through you is make a
miserable suicidal what could have been
something with great potential downer
you know I can't argue with that
right cuz guys know what God's doing
maybe that's the point I might not like
corn bushes cuz they fucking cut me but
hey that's just my perspective so let me
end this on a positive note because
although life has no purpose there's no
single purpose to life there's no single
purpose to your life there's a myriad of
perspectives on who you are and what you
do for the other people for the
ecosystem in your life and that's your
purpose to all of that even though you
have not even not even considered it
when I say there's no purpose I mean you
can't pin it down you just ride
but now this is very important although
there's no purpose no single purpose
there's great significance because you
come out of an intelligence call it
astrophysics whatever you want to call
it there's an intelligence that you know
we're trying our best to figure out but
we just we just don't fucking know here
into astrophysics and you like Neil Neil
deGrasse I think that guy's awesome I'm
watching a series with him recently he
knows so much but in the end he goes but
we don't know and that's fucking awesome
right so you can even I mean he's he's
most famous physicist at this particular
point you know he's taking the place of
I can't remember
Sagan Carl Sagan Carl Sagan brought
science into our into our era and this
man is taking us into the next era he's
fantastic I happen to like him he's a
brother even he says look we're figuring
it all out but we don't know shit so
it's just a game but look at how
significant it is look out into into the
if you've watched the series with him I
can't remember the name of it something
about the universe but you look out into
the magnificence of the universe and how
tiny we are in it look at time in our
perspective with regard to time and how
significant it is and if you delve down
into the depths and deepness of our
organic physiology each organ and its
cells and each cells organelles and down
and down and down and down until they
get to the particles of the atoms the
electrons or quarks and bosons and
there's nothing there but there's
everything there it's really goddamn
significant I say goddamn interesting
huh cuz damn god you're good this shit
is so fucking significant it's really
significant for each part to play the
part that it's designed to play I
believe they call that your Dharma
in parts of East your just look hey I
don't know your name gonna call you Bob
for a moment but you're just a bob in
the same way that tulip is just a tulip
and be a fucking awesome Bob be a great
Bob but do not be a slave to the stories
you've been told about what this is and
don't add too much purposefulness to any
piece of it but recognize it and your
significance you are Stardust ha right
dude
you're fuckin Stardust and your
electrons your bosons your orcs your
moving in and out of time zones that we
don't even understand you know we
perceive I can't sale it but we perceive
a on a time-space continuum but it's one
of perhaps Millions
don't get too wrapped up in that either
because another fantastic story one that
I find very resourceful it's just one
perspective that I happen to like
because it makes my life good I feel
good in my body when I adopt this
perspective is that with our ignorance
associated with other time-space locales
there could potentially be and there's
the it probably is because it's like
logically in my mind in my heart kind of
makes sense that when we die we don't
really die and in fact I think it might
be amazing
to consider that we reincarnate we come
back as someone or something else and we
get to keep going
life ain't over now I'll tell you why I
think that perspective is fantastic
because it means when I die it ain't
over so I have nothing to be depressed
about I don't have to won or lost I
don't you know I don't need all the
virgins in this fucking sky I'm taking
care of several versions right now on
earth I got three daughters you
understand what I'm saying I understand
the significance of that
I'm nourishing the upbringing the
education the development
psychologically emotionally physically
of three women I don't need a hundred
virgins in the sky when I die I am
offering such a gift here on earth
I don't need gold and riches in the
clouds when I die and when I meet my
maker and he says yes sir Elliott you've
been good or you've been bad because I'm
doing it right here right now and the
pieces that I don't develop because I
just wasn't strong enough I just didn't
have the time to develop in myself I can
come back and deal with later but I get
to carry the care and nourishment of my
three virgins at home
meaning I affected the lives of other
people I was here I read seeds of
understanding my understanding
perspective to perhaps millions through
the videos that I create I'm fucking
awesome and I'm enjoying this and I feel
good and I'm discovering new things I
like science
I like philosophy I like religion
because it's the stories that our
ancestors use to come to understand what
we now call the universe in science but
I'm not attached to science or religion
I just enjoy it all enjoy it all my
friend learn another instrument learn
ten instruments not for achievement sake
but because it brings joy to your life
and if you learn 10 languages and 10
instruments and you make a discovery
that impacts positively I really believe
that's one of my beliefs is that our one
rule is the Golden Rule do unto others
as you wish they would do unto you cause
no violence
any religion or philosophy that causes
you to hurt others is wrong my
perspective not attached to that either
but all that you do will be carried
forth with you into the next life
meaning when you come back you'll be one
of those kids that learn languages like
what the fuck like I'm dumb your mom's
dumb but are you're my son
you're seven years old and for some
reason wherever we take you you pick up
their language he's gifted he ain't
fucking gifted he just wanted that shit
his last life and he brought it with him
all of our gifts come to us from what we
developed in our last life I speak this
way in front of this fucking camera now
I'm pretty sure than my last life there
was no camera of this sort but I'm
pretty sure that I use my rhetorical
skills my animated body and mind and
speaking ability to entertain and
perhaps enlighten lots of people right
now it took a little bit of this guy to
figure it out and I discover and I had
to hone it in a little bit but it's like
a it's Who I am
who you are it's fucking as amazing as
that thornbush and as the tulips
you are amazing you are phenomenal you
are magnificent you are beautiful you
are a success just by being who you are
just get out the way and allow God or
the universe to develop in you
everything that you really are let go of
the stories that depress you let go of
the physical tension in your muscles
that are associated with the stories in
the conditioning that you're holding on
to exhale relax breathe pucker up
like the tulips kiss the world and die
done