what's up guys Elliott Hulse here on a
Sunday morning because quite frankly
that's the only time I can get to
strength camp to make a video we're so
busy all week long and it's part of the
reason why I haven't been making very
very many videos is because well I don't
have the time to at strength camp right
we've been so busy here the old gym was
more like a studio right I had open gym
we trained some athletes in the evening
but for the most part it was me
this camera and carte-blanche so it's a
Sunday morning the gyms empty empty we
got a dog barking in the back there so
introduction to my new neighbor who's
got dogs and he likes to Rev his engine
and I'm about to preach Church up in
here on Sunday morning so today I'd like
to open up with a phrase that I heard
when I first listened to the audible
book but here's the actual book iron
John by Robert Bly incredible book if
you're a man you should probably read
this book you should definitely read
this book and in the book he goes
through many he describes many of the
stages and many of the experiences that
a man will go through in his personal
evolution and in one section he uses the
term every wound is a womb right in fact
he says uh the wound as a male womb I
marked it here the wound as a male room
on page 233 and if you listen to the
audio it's incredible also and it got me
thinking because I I've shared ideas
like this with you guys in many
instances in fact most of the time when
you've sent me questions about things
that have challenged you in your life I
refer to the idea that life works in
very in the very in a very similar
fashion to how things happen in the gym
right you go to the gym you go to lift
weights what are you doing you're
literally breaking yourself down you
were literally wounding yourself right
this is science science says that if you
go in the gym you break down the tissue
there are micro tears you become
catabolic it's a very break
down activity when you go to the gym but
there's a reason why we do it right why
do we go to the gym to beat ourselves up
and have micro-tears in our tissue and
put ourselves in this catabolic state so
that we can become anabolic right
catabolic is the down process anabolic
is the up process and this shows up
everywhere in life from the into the
yang from the night to the day from the
winter to the summer it also happens in
the cycles of your life now you've
probably heard me use the term hero's
journey and if you if you've studied
Joseph Campbell if you've watched any
movie right they always follow a pattern
that goes like this you know the hero
comes full circle things in life happen
in this cyclical fashion catabolic and
anabolic so on and so forth be a
breakdown build up I've even said to you
guys
failure is important you need failure in
order to succeed right these a lot of
these things now I hope right ideas
spread so quickly these days it's
incredible because I felt like when I
was sharing a lot of these ideas they
were new and a lot of people like man
Elliot I've never heard this before but
I think you know we live in a viral time
and ideas are viral and at this point
you know the head should be doing this
when I say yeah failure is a part of
success you must fail you must break
down to build up you must go down to
grow up so in fact through some of my
recent videos right a couple months ago
I was creating some videos where I was
training the gym they're very artsy
videos where I wasn't saying very much
they had like a dark feeling to it and
and I call them Khattab assists videos
and you know a lot of people were
curious like what the hell are you
talking what does this get Tabitha's a
lot of people looked it up and whatnot
and wanted to know I'm looking it up
right now so I can ship I can show you
this I put it on Instagram if you guys
want to look on my Instagram I'm going
to read it here to you now but it's
taken right out of the book what Khattab
Assist means right and this is what I'm
doing right now is I'm setting the
context for some pretty
important stuff in fact some pretty
important personal experiences and
stories that I would like to share with
you here today in this video and it is
my hope that everything that I'm going
to share with you is going to support
you in becoming a stronger version of
yourself right because if you think life
is a linear process right you think it's
just sunshine and and skyways the whole
time right puppy dogs and tootsie rolls
you're bullshitting yourself there is a
going down process right I mean it's
even in our wisdom literature look at
Jonah in the whale right Jonah was a
fucking winner then he ended up in a
belly of a whale down an ocean right so
let me back up for a moment for I give
you too many metaphors and analogies
catalysis the mark of descent whether
undertaking consciously or unconsciously
is a newly arrived at lowliness
associated with water and soul as height
is associated with spirit water prefers
low places right I said Jonah was in the
whale in the ocean water low places the
lowliness happens particularly two men
were initially high lucky elevated right
I'm familiar with that I'm definitely
familiar with being high elevated you
might say lucky right and it goes on the
way down and out usually separates the
young man from his companion fliers and
from their support and it makes him
aware of a depression that may have been
living unnoticed in him for years
a mean life of ordinariness heaviness
silences cracks in the road weightiness
and soberness begins and I could tell
you that silence and soberness is
something I'm very familiar with and of
course you've been watching me go silent
for the past several years right and
it's kind of like well you know you
consume what I'm doing you consume these
videos you relate to Elliott Hulse in a
particular way right now maybe even have
supported you in certain endeavors in
your life be it at the gym or in dealing
with the breakups right you're good how
many times have I said it's good that
your girlfriend cheated on you and
dumped you right heartbreak is good
that's one of my most popular videos
heartbreak is a good thing because you
go down you burn up you die to a part of
yourself so that you can be resurrected
this has been in a foundation principle
in my teachings for many years well I'm
not a guru meaning I'm not the perfect
being standing here preaching to you in
such a way that I am I'm offering
celestial insights because I'm a pure
being that's bullshit I'm far from pure
right crazy wisdom crazier than chögyam
trungpa perhaps right this is the idea
that you know we're all no matter how
how much you hold someone in reverence
they still shit right and I take shits
so catalysis is something that we're all
going to experience including myself and
when I share these videos or any of the
youtubers I don't know you know I really
don't watch so many others but um if
they're being real with you and I have
no other choice but to be real it's
really hard for me to fake this and to
put on to put on a smile when you know
there's really no reason to or my heart
is not smiling when we put it that way
right you get you get full transparency
with Elliott Hulse it's very hard for me
to put on so when I'm down you're out
right I'm just going to be obvious and I
disappear so what I'm saying to you is
that you're literally watching it is my
desire that as you watch my videos you
can see the process rather than just
hear the process right allow me to be an
inspiration by the way I live my life
rather than the words I share with you
all right and I think that gives us more
of a real relationship a real
connectedness when I shared the
catalysis quote on Facebook the other
day someone said
Eliott that what you just shared makes
me feel that much closer and related to
you because that's how I've been feeling
well yeah I hope that's what these
videos do provide some context for where
you are in life by looking at perhaps an
older brother right look at me as a
older brother I call myself uncle
sometimes when I write alright so
whatever the case may be it's just my
experiences that I want to share with
you so what I would like to do in order
to show you how wombs become wombs
because that's even better than
catabolic and anabolic a wound meaning
like you you've been cut open right this
is the way he describes it to a wound if
you think about a wound an opening is
like a vagina right you get you get
stabbed or you break something or you
open up your flesh it is so in a way and
when Robert Liars describes it very well
in the book and I would love for you to
read the book but he says it is an
opening so that the soul can come in so
that there can be an awakening so that
you could people who are too healthy he
says people that are that are too
healthy too strong require and break
down and opening their body has to
physically be wounded so that they could
be humbled right interesting that word
humble that begins with H um which is
also the prefix for human humility
humiliation humor and houmous which is
dirt which is going down earthliness
that opening that wound is also being a
vagina like I said is also a womb what
is a vagina right what is an opening in
the body that allows something to grow
something to be manifest right in the
unconscious - right because when a baby
is growing inside a woman nobody sees
what's going on inside there it's a
mysterious happening with it with the
biology of the body and some celestial
force right we don't really know right
science gives us so much but there's a
mystery there her human being born well
the mystery happens within the mail room
all
so and there is a grope there's a growth
within so that you could be reborn
without every single wound be it a
psychological womb and emotional wound
right how many people all right someone
related the story to me the other day
about you know the two sons who grew up
with an alcoholic father right growing
up with an alcoholic father is a wound
all right one son grows up to be worldly
successful all right when he makes a lot
of money and shit and the other one
grows up to be a drug addict or whatever
and both of them answer what would you
do if you had the same kind of father
what they're saying is that what would
you do if you had this wound one guy
took the wound and because he had
perspective because he was able to
connect deep within because he gave
himself time to go down granted that
he's truly successful not just a
neurotic sociopath who's makes a lot of
money which looks successful right we we
love sociopaths in our society because
they make a lot of money and they rule
right they a lot of power I'm talking
about a truly successful plant man takes
that wound and grow something of a
better version of himself right this is
this is this is the growing stronger
process this is the becoming a stronger
version of yourself process and some
people without the perspective
they allow they allowed the wound to
fester how many people have a injury
psychological emotional and abuse or
physical were born with and they allow
it to allow to destroy them right they
let the womb fester and it turns and
they go down and they stay down these
people will never rise up if never given
perspective these people will never rise
up if they don't take responsibility
every single one of our wombs if we take
responsibility for it we are empowered
enough to turn it into a wound but we're
a stronger version of yourself is grown
well folks Elliott Hulse is no stranger
to this and you might take a look at
some of my previous videos to take to
understand to see me actually going
through the process and I'm going to
bring you up to date with where I am in
in a new cycle right because like I said
once once your eyes up you go down but
you always rise
begin right so interestingly you know I
made I began making videos in 2007 and I
made videos I did what I had to do I was
really involved in straw man at the time
I had become a professional strongman
and I was winning I didn't even make
very many videos when I was being a
professional strongman because it was
all I wanted to do is lift heavy shit
right and I became pro and I took it one
step further right it's so funny my
first cycle of steroids after becoming a
pro and saying well you know what I'm
gonna compete with these big boys
because I was competing with guys over
60 pounds heavier than me well I'm gonna
do what they're doing first cycle and
you know what popped my bicep popped my
right bicep in that moment that I popped
my bicep and interestingly enough it was
after a strongman practice when I was in
the yard helping my dad pull up some
dead roots as soon as that bicep tore
it's so funny because I it's not that
funny I'm gonna wear dude as soon as
that bicep popped I said to myself well
there goes a version of Elliott Hulse
now the bicep can be repaired but I was
just given an omen I was just given a
sign I was just giving a womb for me to
be reborn into something else that was
about 2010 all of the popularity that I
gained through creating these videos
happened directly after that it wasn't
until it was very shortly after that
that I wrote a book and I'll make it if
I remember I'll put it down below for
you guys to get it for free called the
manifesto of strength where I where I
basically in the manifesto strength told
my story right and I pop my bicep and I
knew that I had to tell a new story to
myself into the world telling and
retelling stories your particular story
is very important very resourceful
you'll always be trapped in your dungeon
if you can't reframe right so I had to
retell the story I wrote a book
manifesto of strength I wrote it down
below you'll see it down below in that
time from that
wound I did a I near the bird birds
distracted me I went in and I learned a
lot of new things about myself this is
where I rediscovered dynamic meditation
this is where I discovered bioenergetics
bioenergetics has been a tremendous gift
for me in that stage between 2010 and
about 2015 2014 really and as well as
many of the other many of the other
things that allowed my videos to be of
great resource to you but I denied in
and of myself meaning I wasn't willing
to shed conscious light on but it guided
me right bioenergetics was one but also
the Baha'i faith many of you may know
most of you probably don't know that my
wife Colleen and I decided to become
Baha'i is a religion I'm a religious
dude I've always been I just didn't talk
much about it from the time we got
married it's been over 15 years right
since we've been behind and much of what
I've been able to achieve and many of
the words that I've shared with you that
were of great resource you come directly
from my experience with the Baha'i faith
now I'm not going to share too much
about that with you here today because
you know maybe it doesn't fit maybe it
doesn't apply to our conversation at
this point but again I'll put another
link down below where I have a Facebook
group where we can talk a little bit
about it and I rose up right tore down
rent destroyed not the bicep rose back
up and became Joe Elliott right Joe
Elliott was at the top you look you Liat
was when I described what Robert Bly
says here as high right Oh Ellie wasn't
high early it was high rising up spirit
and uh you probably if you've been
watching these videos for long enough
and if you haven't I'm going to do my
best here today to create some resource
links down below for you but around the
end of 2000 merit 2000 in 2014 a
conscious it was happening but I became
very conscious of a going down process
happening within me right and I'm just
gonna read that again he says uh I was
on my phone either conscious or
unconscious Tirzah going down process
and and I felt it I felt it happening in
my soul and maybe made some videos where
I was like yeah I was real Amenti right
again Elliot with his trans parents I
was just with lamenting it so at one
point finally I said I'm going to quit
I'm gonna I can't make videos anymore
because to go down means to be silent to
be unseen right and I began the going
down process right and as much as I knew
I was supposed to go down in order to
soul retrieve in order to heal in order
to be reborn I struggled and I fought
against it this is where you see me
coming back with premature attempts at
resurrection like the video series in
April 2015 resurrection I wasn't ready
to be resurrected I just started going
down but from business partner pressures
you know you guys you know people who
want where are you why why'd you
disappear so many other pressures I
prematurely came back right and I knew
it was premature I knew it was premature
so much so that even when I made videos
I started wearing my sunglasses because
I didn't want to be seen alright if you
watch some of the videos in 2015 where
I'm interviewing the people with all the
celebrities that came here for the shunt
cam challenge I was doing that because I
wanted to do it and I honor those people
but I also didn't want to be seen and
I'll talk to a little bit more about you
know how that came about that where I
decided like that's it I'm just going to
put on my sunglasses later on but I
didn't want to be seen quite frankly you
know it's called boundaries it's called
putting a bandaid on the wound you've
got to cover up and I've wanted to cover
up so the going down process
was stunted because I prematurely keep
kept coming back until I popped my other
bicep some of you've noticed in some of
the videos I made earlier this year that
my bicep looks funny it does this is the
one I tore in 2010 this is the one I
tore in 2015 looks a little funny right
it doesn't go all the way through and
and that's because well it was a wound
to keep me down ha right this happened
in September after I came back from
Europe or I was jumping and screaming
and yelling and doing dynamic meditation
when I should have been praying and
meditating and sitting silently right
but I did what I had to do until one day
interestingly enough I come to strength
camp right now and I had known that I
shouldn't have been training I had known
that it was time for me just to do yoga
and meditate but ego I came back in here
one day and Mark is coaching and and I'm
real flamboyant I'm you know hey Elliott
Hulse got a lot of energy so I'm
throwing my energy all over the place
we're doing the workouts and in between
sets I decide to get on the Rings and I
do what I've done a thousand times which
is a skin the cat's in the cat up skin
the cat down with the fuck first time
skinned it scanned it tore my bicep ha
ha ha I'm eat it now unlike the first
time when I tore my bicep and tears came
because I was mourning the death of a
version of myself that I knew wasn't
sustainable when I tore it this time I
was fucking mad at myself I was like god
damn it Elliott because I knew I
shouldn't have been there I even said to
my guys I was like I don't belong at
strength camp I don't belong here right
now right in that stage in that time in
my life it didn't make sense for me to
be here because I'm in a going down
process and so god knows what I'm really
supposed to be doing I know what I'm
really supposed to be doing and every
time we all of us can I share this
because I think maybe you
might bind some semblance in your story
knocks you right back on course
so the tearing of my bicep was a brand
new wound that at that point I said
that's why you haven't seen much of me
since the fall of last year I said well
that's it
I'm going down and I don't know when I'm
coming back up that's it
and and I shouldn't have been coming
back up because this either way I can
talk to you here right now again like I
used to back in the day I couldn't even
do that I didn't have the enthusiasm I
was still in a healing process healing
here healing here in my body but also
healing here so since that time I've
been doing a lot of internal work and I
have been doing a lot of soul-searching
and in April of this year it seems as
almost as if I had a dream it seems
almost as if I was reborn right now of
course you look at me and you're like I
let you're full of shit you weren't
reborn you didn't die I'm talking about
character birth and rebirth the death
isn't just of the physical body death is
of the ego ego death a lot of young
people and I share this with you because
again you might find yourself in this
place a lot of young people a lot of
people in general who have a hankering
for death who think I need to kill
myself
suicide is thoughts of suicide those are
not wrong those feelings aren't wrong to
want to die to yourself to want to
commit suicide is not wrong it's just
that you're looking at it the wrong way
it is not a physical suicide it's not a
physical death it is a character or an
ego death who you are right now right
I'm preaching all over the place today
but if you're watching this right now
and you have the feeling that you want
to kill yourself or you have the feeling
that I want to die it's good just know
that you're looking at it the wrong way
you must
dye your ego must die who you are today
is no longer resourceful for who you're
going to be who you are to be next for
you to fulfill your greatest purpose
here on this planet in this lifetime you
have to have multiple deaths too
immature versions of yourself so that
you could be reborn as a stronger
version of yourself that's how the
process goes right so as I experienced
my rebirth in April many things began to
start coming together for me many things
started making more sense the bigger
picture began to appear I mentioned in
my last video how strength camp all of a
sudden now has all these multiple pieces
all of which were very important but me
being Elliott Hulse from 2014 even 2015
prior to my second wound couldn't do it
who you are today might need to die for
you to do what you need to do for the
next phase and and I knew what the new
phase was I knew that it was important
for me to get strength camp running as a
entity in and of itself without Elliott
Hulse I knew I needed to ruin myself
from the videos I know I needed to
empower the other coaches look at the
part of the reason why I give a carte
blanche why I open up the possibility
for all my coaches to have all their own
videos on this channel and that I
feature them is because I want to
empower them it can't be the Elliott
Hulse show all the time Elliott Hulse
will die I'll die and I'll die you know
that I can't be here forever
nobody can be here forever so my
character will die I have to make sure
that my family can carry on
I may physically die I got to make sure
that the family can carry on so when you
see these videos of the other coaches
here it's a matter of me stepping out of
the way so that strength camp can live
on its own it can breathe on its own
also as I spoke about there is no reason
why strength camp can't be worldwide
none if you're watching this you might
be in Mumbai right is that even a
country Dubai and then with an M I made
that shit up is it a real country let me
know you might be somewhere else
that I've never even heard of there's it
there's an there's a place called Isle
of Man I think off the coast of Scotland
or Ireland the Isle of Man I once when I
first started I had the bracelets the
wristbands and I was promoting them and
it me and my children were would send
them out for my living room and we see
all the addresses to where we were
sending it and that was the most
interesting one apparently there's a
place whole Isle of Man and I will be
there someday it's destined to happen so
strength camp international strength
camp medium I began this whole process
by creating products but I stopped I
needed to have the wound to be rebirthed
so that I can work with my team work
with my family work with my soul in
order to build up these other things so
that their so that their gifts to the
world right the videos I make are gift I
get that but there's so much more to be
done right so much more we can do why
limit yourself right why limit yourself
to your own self-imposed limitations and
I don't do that too much I'm pretty
fucking limitless but then other people
right so why settle and it's not a
neurotic chasing after anything it's not
a neurotic having to win I don't even
keep track of how much money I make not
because I make so much of it because I'm
just as long as I got food on the table
I really don't care
want that creative process I want to do
these things because they're fun I want
to make stuff I want to help people
right and above and beyond reconnecting
with my faith knowing that the work that
I'm doing supports eternity right
because so many of us want to be
successful for our own narcissistic
desires right I want a hot tub where I
can get a blowjob by a model with big
boobs and then get into my Ferrari and
drive in Beverly Hills and then I see
all these things what the fuck does that
do for anybody else right if you're not
serving others which you know in many
cases the only way you can get that is
to serve others but I've never been a
you know flashy guy I bought a Range
Rover once and I gave it back six months
later because I was like I bought myself
a fucking Nissan it's just me right no
but you've got to be true gotta be real
and I'm just trying to be real here so
knowing that the work that I do is not
just about Elliott Hulse me growing in
popularity and fame does nothing for
eternity for the world for when I'm gone
when I'm dead sure these videos will be
here but if I do these videos so that I
could put more money in my pockets well
who gives a fuck but if I do the work
that I do with the intent on making this
a better place unifying mankind
believing in the strongest version of
you and you and you and you and giving
you the tools that you could then take
the strongest version of you and empower
other people now it's a virus right it's
a love virus you're good about that and
then of course bioenergetics and dynamic
meditation I need the time and need the
space I need to be the type of person
that could handle those gifts so my
friends think in terms of your
particular wound even if you're dealing
one with one right now and know this
whatever struggle you're dealing with
whatever challenge you're facing
whatever injury whatever wound you
have right now it is a birth opportunity
is an opportunity to like the female go
in and allow the internal processes to
put the pieces together where Anu you
can be rebirthed it is the principle of
death and rebirth it is the principle of
catabolic and anabolic it is the
principle of going down so that you can
rise up done