so everybody jay from Macedonia has
never been good at sports any sports
whatsoever you just he's always been
awkward in that way and what he's
growing a particular feeling that that
is moving him towards the sport of
kickboxing he wants to go and he wants
to kick and punch right this is what's
happening in his body and he's asked his
dad on several occasions can you know
dad I'd like to do this apparently our
buddies 15 years old apparently his dad
just kind of laughs at him like giggles
at it was like all you you know I guess
his dad realized that his son is not
that athletic and now that he wants to
go and kick and fight he's he's kind of
brushing him off and like what our
friend says he basically like giggles
Adams just like I silly so for six
months our 15 year old friend has been
asking his dad can i dad can I please
gonna just go and do this thing like I
give me one more chance I want to go
when I want to do kickboxing and dad is
giggling Adam and brush him off can't
get through don't know what to do and I
understand dude because like i've said
in other videos like we we can laugh at
you also but the fact is that this is a
critical junction in your life ever
every single challenge that were faced
with even if you're 15 years old and
it's a challenge against your parent
it's a critical junction in your life
because you're gonna have to learn the
skills and develop the tools in order to
overcome this challenge you have a
challenge right now and it's your dad
and it's not that your dad doesn't love
you or as an asshole or that you need to
reject him in a shaper way shape or form
but you got to learn how to get through
to someone who doesn't respect you
especially someone in authority position
right so you need to get through to your
dad so that he respects what's happening
in your body because apparently you
respect it you want to move forward but
he's not giving you that room here's my
invitation write him a letter get a pad
and pen and write a lengthy letter on
your history how you feel and what you
would like to achieve in your life and
how this is going to support you write
an essay it's a letter you know do it
like a like a letter but pour your heart
and soul into
letter and instead of wine because he
doesn't want either the respect your
form he doesn't respect your figure you
showed you walk up to him and he's
already giggling right people already
have feelings about you before you you
get there so you show up with whatever
you have matter how sincere it is he
sees you and it's just like what do you
want you see what I'm saying you're
wearing a costume for him it's like
you're a clown a clown doesn't show up
and you can you take them seriously like
yeah but I shows up and your automatic
inclination is to respond to what you
see in front of you when you show up
with a letter folded up and like even
put it in an envelope and you say hey
dad this is really important and I want
to share with you and you hand him that
envelope and say maybe we could talk
about it after dinner and he goes and he
reads it now it is just him and the
sentiment that she poured out on that
piece of paper to nothing but symbols
and he has to construct for himself the
entire story of what's happening in
absence of your meddling because your
presence metals with his head he and if
you're sincere and you know how to evoke
emotion with your words which is
probably something you should practice
you know but you don't have to get it
right this first time but but do it but
just be you know what there's there's no
more powerful position than that of pure
sincerity just give him your all of your
tears all of your anger all of your
sorrow all of your love pour it into
that piece of paper handed to him he
will come at you with a totally
different attitude he will be moving
from a place of respect for you for a
number of reasons number one because he
SAT needed to reconstruct what he thinks
of you while reading that right because
you weren't actually saying it to him he
had to reconstruct and the words that
were being presented on that piece of
paper help him construct the new version
of you
you want him to see you strong words in
your letter it's almost like your letter
is your opportunity to to re be reborn
in his eyes write what you would like
him to see you as in that letter be very
respectful be very formal right you
mentioned that your dad's more like your
buddy more so than a guardian and you
know if you approve you approach him and
with an alpha attitude and doesn't mean
that you need to overcome overtake him
but a very respectable grounded attitude
his relationship with you will change
from that day forward I promise you good
luck buddy