so we got this question from our buddy
fishing 24/24 he's 20 years old he just
moved out of his parents home for the
very first time he's in a city all is it
all by himself
no it knows nobody he's on his own very
first time he's had this call to
adventure very important very
interesting very potent time in every
man's life but he's feeling alone and
depressed because he can't seem to make
friends he can't seem to cross this
threshold by which he would receive love
and compassion friendship companionship
with other people in his in his new city
he tries his best but he keeps bumping
up against this resistance he's sad
lonely misses his home but doesn't want
to go back because that in a way it's a
it's a sign of failure and you're right
and in a way it is what does he do what
I'm going to invite you to look at today
is some of Joseph Campbell's work Joseph
Campbell is and it was an incredible man
who studied the depths of human
consciousness that was shared to us
through generations and generations
through cultures and cultures of the
world since recorded history of all the
myths and rituals that helped us guide
our lives we've totally detached from
these you know we see them as untrue or
you know a lot of them are religions a
lot of them are our ancient stories told
by Native Americans and aboriginals and
you know we're too sophisticated now to
like be bothered with any of those
talking birds and shit and what we miss
is what Joseph Campbell tries to share
with us is that we've used these stories
up until now we're really developing a
new story
that's essentially what mankind is doing
and we're just not there yet so we're
without myth with world without stories
but he studied these stories and he
shares them with us through his work and
and and shows us how the symbols used by
our ancestors
really design these stories really
designed to to help us navigate the
world that we live in and there's one
concept that he really delves deeply
into in many of his books and it's what
I want you two to look at and he calls
it the hero's journey it's the same
story that's told in Star Wars about
Luke Skywalker in fact Lucas George
Lucas was highly influenced by
Campbell's work and this hero's journey
I also have a book here called the hero
with a thousand faces and and in this he
talks about all the mythical creatures
all the guys you know he talks about
Jesus and he talks about Luke Skywalker
you know all the guys that we tell
stories about that support us in our
journey now this now back to you the
this hero's journey that you are going
on is one that men have always gone
through and you're in the beginning
stages of it what we've done up until
this point was they will create we've
created rites of passages but they no
longer exist we just don't use them
anymore you know unless you're if you're
Jewish you might have like a Bar Mitzvah
Bar Mitzvah if you're if you're Catholic
they still retain the tradition of
I don't remember you to your communion
Holy Communion
you know I did it I was raised as a
Catholic these are rituals that were
used and they were far more potent back
in the day it wasn't just like a recite
these words and get this bread now
you're a man there was a lot more to it
but we you know we dumbed down
everything yeah in our culture now
nothing's that as potent as it once was
but anyway that we don't have that
anymore and our young men suffer your
suffering right now because you don't
have that but what you do have are the
stories told by our ancestors and the
hero's journey that Joseph Campbell
documented for us in his work please go
look it up what I'm going to do right
now is I'm going to share with you the
stages in the hero's journey because
you're going to notice that you're
you're at a very critical junction in
your journey I experienced this I was
lucky enough to find to make my way
through it a lot of men don't I think
most of us don't I look at a lot of
grown men and I'm like you know you're
35 you're 50 but you're still in the
beginning stages of your hero's journey
you're not a hero yet you're still
you're still a boy in an old body
because they the junction at which you
are right now they faltered you know
scary out there nobody wants to nobody
wants to delve into their fears so if
you even look up there grab their
diagrams of Joseph Campbell's work
especially on the hero's journey and in
the very first step is the ordinary
world this is the world of dependency
and are on your parents you know you're
told what to do how to do it and you're
very dependent on your parents and in
the home tribe if you will then step two
is when you turn about in the ancient
days maybe 14 years old but today you
know 20 21 years old there's a call to
action you're called away from the womb
of the home or the tribe every man feels
it every man is encouraged in some way
to move out of the womb you know that
was there were very ritualistic ways
that our ancestors would go about this
you know
it was a very symbolic and many of the
things that they did I remember reading
about a an African tribe to this day
that when a boy turns 14
he's ritualistic we ripped or they
actually not exactly 14 but they wait
till he starts exhibiting manly like
behavior you know he starts acting like
he thinks it's a man they they they
create this drama I know you know that's
a conspiracy against the kids so all the
men in the village and the women they
know what's going on and they come in
and the men come in with big ugly masks
and they tear the pillar they scare the
boy and they tear him away from his
mother and they take him out into the
jungle and for a few days he's out there
with just the men and they put him
through several tests you know I think
one of them is like you've got to kill
some sort of an animal you know kill
this lion or something and there's
several different things that they make
him go through because he now he's
becoming a man he had to be shipped from
the womb which realistically
metaphorically forced to become a
fucking man you know do shit like this
anymore right you go to college what
does that get drunk and passed tests
that are you know completely abstract
and have nothing to do with the reality
of the world right and then get him dead
now your slave to the fucking machine
you're a slave to the Empire right
that's the dark side that's Darth Vader
right there you know you know Luke
Skywalker doesn't even get out of the
fucking get out of his jet before he's
snatched up by the Empire right that's
what they that's dead that's why they
want to get you in debt so quickly the
Empire once wants you the Empire is one
form of the challenges that you meet
when you're out in the world and that's
that's the system if you will that's the
government that's civilization anyway
very long video I'm ranting now there's
a critical junction when there's that
call to action first year very excited
about that call to action but then
there's a point of refusal there is a
refusal of the call I would like to say
I just in my experience in dealing with
with many young men in adult men then
perhaps fifty percent maybe more refuse
the call because it's just too fucking
scary see what you're experiencing right
now is is the fear being alone we all
have different fears it manifested shows
a
in different ways some of us some some
of us it's it's the excitement of
freedom and then they go and
self-sabotage party drinks too much
friends that's their challenge they and
that's a refusal of the call also
because the call really is designed to
bring you to to bring you full circle to
maturity so when you're an old man
you've gained heroship
and if you if you if you treat that
fearfully or you're too flippant with it
you fucked the whole thing up you know
you end up a fifty year old man who
still parties and looks at women like he
was when he was 25 and it's like dude
you're you're an old man you're getting
drunk and talking to teenagers like
that's fucked up and weird or they're
they're very conservative and very
afraid to express themselves and you
know they're just they're yes men they
go to their job they do what they're
told then they get wives to tell them
what to do and they live their life just
you know yes many never really fully
experiencing themselves you don't want
either one of those you want that middle
path where you own yourself so that
refusal call is your first challenge and
you're there right now what are you
gonna do are you going to go home cry
your way back home be a little boy right
look most of a lot of us do that now
they go to college and come back home
cuz they're broke
but you're not broke you're just too
fucking scared to go do something or you
you sort of numb yourself with activity
you know and that activity could be it's
always dysfunctional but it could be
seen as as you know society sees it as
something good Wow look at him he's
going and uh he's become very neurotic
and his drive towards earning riches or
he's completely detached and and like
drinks all day long now and plays video
games what you're doing in both cases is
you're refusing the call to look at
what's out there and those are monsters
they're demons
right there you're demons you look at
your fear you got a look at the reason
why you're trying to escape either run
back home get into drugs or throw
yourself into work very interesting
stuff
the next step if he if he does continue
is he meets a mentor right if he decides
I'm fucking doing this I'm going
hardcore this is my calling these are my
peers and I'm looking them dead in the
eyes he's going to meet a mentor happens
every single time obi-wan Kenobi right
every single time we meet a mentor and
that mentor shares ideas with you
because he's been there before and he's
giving you some ideas and encouragement
about how to get through this shit he
steers your your consciousness just a
little bit you've got to make your own
choices you've got to make your own
mistakes you could at receive your own
blessings but you will find that if you
go on your way you're going to meet men
that are that are going to be very
willing to support you on your way and
then there's a question crossing of the
threshold now you're really in it you're
in the thick of it number six Tests
allies and enemies now you're really in
the world this is where you know Luke
Skywalker starts meeting like who's the
guy you know you meets the with the the
Queen the Princess Leia and he meets the
other dude you know the cowboy dude
meets all types of interesting people
then he has tests you know they're bad
guys that are coming after him you know
that there's challenges to see if he's
mentally tough enough know you know and
it also he meets Yoda
you know Yoda Yoda is his one of his
mentor's also these wise dudes along the
way ordeal death and rebirth you go
through the big challenge right that's
and that's your purpose in life
they were deal death rebirth reward
seizing the sword you became a fucking
man takes a long time most of us stop at
that second one I'm on number nine now
the road back that means you've learned
some things you've gained you you you've
been granted that sword you come back
and now you become they say you returned
with the elixir you come with some sort
of message you come with some sort of
gift that you want to share with the
world now that you've been through that
hero's journey fascinating fast
dating stuff so of course this is a
long-winded video and you know it's
deeply re-involved with a lot of Joseph
Campbell's work and so I'm excited about
it I want to share that with you but my
friend listen you're in a tough place
but you're not alone every single
walking man Dead Alive and in the future
will be posed with the hero's journey
there's a call to adventure and there's
then which is number one and number two
or are you going to go on it or are you
going to refuse you refuse you will have
to be rebirth again you'd have to build
you'll have to come back and do this
shit all over again you'll be you'll be
a baby in an old man's body which many
people are I'm grateful for you this is
good see your fears for what they are
their challenges seek out that
mentorship it could come in the form of
videos in the form of books Brian Tracy
was a big mentor to me and never met the
man in my life Ralph Waldo Emerson died
100 years ago over a hundred years ago
great mentor to me and then there were
men that that I had men that came to my
gym when I was going through difficult
times
these were guys who were my clients they
saw what I was doing and they offered me
support and advice and then you just got
to go and fucking do it good luck my
friend