I was wondering if we could elaborate on
that maybe anyway - three days ago for
me it's entitled the computer geeks navy
seal apps and I kind of kicked me in the
gut a little bit because what you talked
about this kid having the decision to go
to college for computer engineering or
joining the Navy SEALs I had that
decision and I went to the Navy I'm
actually shipping out in a few weeks and
I passed my seal PST so at some point
I'm going to get that opportunity and I
was wondering why you told this kid but
no matter what decision decision he
would make it would be a bad decision on
that poor man who's you know shipping
out in two weeks
occasionally I tried that's cool shirt
thank you I think I might have said this
in the video very first things are to
give yourself permission really what it
is really what I'm offering is
permission to act instead of thinking
what happens to our body life doesn't
happen in the abstract we stay there
believing that somehow we can fix our
situation by thinking about it this is
going to help you get out of that when
they call paralysis of my analysis this
or that successful people don't make the
right decisions they make their
decisions right so it doesn't matter
really which way you go because you can
build a case for and against either and
both will be valid people wouldn't you
forget you the right answer but what's
the right answer
what's the truth it's very subjective I
don't know you I wasn't there when you
were born I don't know what books you
read I know how your dad spoke to you I
don't know if your mom breastfed you I
don't know if you're constipated
oh shit and those are all things that
may affect your physiology of psychology
and who you are
so for me to say yeah yeah this one or I
was a Marine Ohio's in AZ yes this one
or my experience in the Navy SEALs was
terrible I said no this one we care who
what
yuzuru say what helps me navigate a lot
of times and this is just my perspective
because I'm kind of a mess so instead of
saying whichever one I swim because
you're really that's your opinion do you
see and then there are those are gonna
say you know what they're not American
kill them all
this thing oh really good think about
your pen which one they books now like
asshole so the thing is that you've done
it make your choice and it doesn't
matter you just stepped and you make
sure that shit is right you win and
every experience even if it is painful
is a win if you can come out of it and
say what did I learn what did I learn
who you know what I didn't like that
what I learned and not only that if you
can't extract anything else for me guess
what you practiced courage