got a question from one of our friends
who's got sort of a typical social
anxiety situation going on but he's got
a a unique problem in that he wants eat
he's very good at what he does he says
that he's developing his mastery in his
field of work and he realizes or he's
come to appreciate through my videos
that by developing himself developing
his mastery in this particular area at
some point perhaps the world will open
up to him and he will have the
opportunity to meet friends and meet
people and meet women because right now
it's the situation is such that he can't
do any of those things you know he he
has aggressively worked towards ridding
himself of the social anxiety by
actually going out and trying to talk to
people but what he's experiencing what
he believes is happening is that people
are nice to him you know they'll smile
and say yes very good but never really
want to go out with him never really
want to do anything with him and he's
feeling lonely you know now he's faced
with this situation where he wants to
know whether he should just deny himself
relationships with other people women
and immerse himself fully into his
mastery with just hopes of perhaps being
able to to receive in the future or does
he try to juggle this thing where you
know do I keep trying do I keep trying
to develop relationships with people
because it's not working me and
apparently it's not working I had to sit
with this one for a little while but I
want to share something with you when I
first went into business and when I say
that it's because I do this because it
wasn't necessarily a business I was a
personal trainer in a in a big box gym
you know commercial gym and you had to
sell yourself you had to be a
salesperson you had to sell your
services and this was the very first
time in my life that I had to learn a
new skill and actually actively engage
with people in order to ask them for
money right it's a very difficult thing
to do especially you know what I
when everything's basically handed to
you most people have jobs where you're
just get a paycheck I had to step
outside myself and develop the skills
associated with offering my services and
asking people for money and and it was
very uncomfortable but what I did
instinctively but I now look back and
consider your problem with it with
regard to it is I motivated the other
personal trainers to do better in their
sales you see I didn't know shit about
sales but when the other trainers were
down and kind of Amanda sucks nobody
wants to hire me I always motivated them
to do better so that they could get more
sales for themselves and in turn what
really ended up happening was all of my
words of encouragement to them really
brainwashed myself they say one of the
best ways to learn is to teach and I
taught themselves even though I was no
salesmen myself but I tell you what over
time I sales skills improved to the
point where I was the top salesman in a
at that gym the reason why I immolate
the story to you is because there is a
skill that you would like to develop
there's somewhere that you'd like to
grow stronger and my invitation to you
is to find someone who is in relation to
you weaker right socially weaker and
those who are typically socially weaker
when I say socially I just mean that the
amount of influence that they have in
their environment and in the world are
children ok so my invitation to you is
to look for a big brother opportunity
look for a situation or organization
where I don't know what country live in
where there are younger boys who don't
have father figures or just you know
that either there they're orphans or
what the case may be and they've
enrolled in this big brother-type
program they exist all over the world
i'm pretty sure and then you know older
men go you know you're 21 years old you
go there and there's a nine-year-old boy
who's like you know life sucks my dad
left us when we were a kid I don't
nobody wants to throw a baseball with me
and you go when you support that kid
coming the strongest version of himself
throw the ball with him tell him why
he's awesome why he's cool why that girl
in his class will hang out with him you
know I don't know what nine year old
boys and girls do but you know maybe
write love letters or trade stickers or
whatever the case may be but anyway the
point is that he's going to have
problems of his own you're 10 years
older than him 11 12 years older than
him you have a perspective basically
what we're doing those were igniting the
law of relativity basically you know
contrast where compared to his situation
you're like Superman dude you're ten
times better than him he's nine years
old and he's got no no father figure or
no whatever lack there is in his life
he's looking to you to fulfill to fill
for him and in doing so in developing
and supporting and inspiring others to
become stronger versions of themselves
like I said the best way to learn is to
teach support him and you will grow
stronger this is a this is not a direct
approach this is a totally indirect
approach this is not going to help you
with different skills and tips for being
able to get over your social anxiety but
it's going to make you a different type
of person you're gonna be the type of
person that lists people up and in doing
so you will lift yourself up and you
will feel better about yourself that
will ultimately translate into you being
able to get out there and live a life
that's worthy of you good luck