hey what's up it's Sunday morning and
I'm in front of my house that's why I
look and sound the way I do but I wanted
to bring you this quick video because I
just had a conversation with my daughter
my second oldest daughter Emerson around
the dinner table and I thought it was
something that I might want to share
with you before I share the idea with
you I completely made this up but I
thought it was interesting and perhaps
useful to you if you have children that
you'd like to share these ideas with or
something that will be resourceful for
your own journey of growing stronger but
anyway I have a daughter and we live in
a world and a culture where beauty is of
great importance to women and their
expression of femininity it's just the
way it is we can't call it right or
wrong
so my daughter asks me daddy what's the
difference between fancy pretty and
beautiful right because we're always
using these words interchangeably
seemingly so I had to think for a moment
and then I shared this idea with her and
it gives perspective with regard to what
words we use with our children I
explained to her that fancy is something
that's done on the outside where things
are added to you so fancy would be
wearing jewelry or fancy clothing shoes
even makeup makes you fancy that anybody
can be fancy you can be a pretty or a
beautiful person or not but you can
always be fancy fancy can be bought the
next level up from there is pretty and I
explained to her that pretty is what you
do pretty is I'm smiling I've got a
pretty smile on my face you're standing
up tall you're sitting up tall you're
walking gracefully you're speaking
kindly to people you're using a pretty
voice pretty is something that you do
and you can it and you know people can
be beautiful or not you see where I'm
going with this but play pretty you can
play pretty you can do pretty beautiful
on the other hand it's a completely
different phenomenon in that beauty is
who you are
and that is measured by your virtues so
are you
generous kind loving humorous courageous
what virtues are you displaying who are
you being and that is going to give us
an indication of what type of beauty of
beauty you're displaying so again like I
said I completely made that up but it
sheds light on contrast between these
different ideas and how we speak to
others and think of ourselves so enjoy
the rest of your Sunday I'll be going to
the beach yes I live in Florida it's
January and I'll be going to the beach
enjoy
you