yo Elliot what's up guys today we got a
question from our strength camp online
member who goes on to ask Elliot what do
I do when I'm a black sheep amongst all
these white sheep he says he says how is
it that the whole all these other sheet
want me to be like them white and I'm
black I'm different all right and they
just keep making me want to be like them
but I want to be black I don't now do I
continue to be my black sheep and then
become a lion you know kind of playing
on that thus spoke zarathustra video I
made once or you know do I fight against
all these white sheets trying to kick me
down and it had me thinking you know
because I've often felt like that you
know and I think we all feel like that
at some point you know and um I think
it's pretty human to feel like a black
sheep I don't think there are real black
sheeps I think there are people that act
out in a black sheep fashion I think
there are people who are really addicted
to the idea that I'm a black sheep but I
think the whole black sheep thing is
pretty universal we all think we're
special right and we all are special and
everybody else is just a landscape of
homogenized milk right they're all the
same and mixed and I am special it's a
normal feeling but um taken too far and
coming from the wrong context can sort
of screw you up what do I mean taken too
far it becomes narcissism meaning that
we become attached to the image that
we've created for ourselves such that we
can create contrast between ourselves
and others in other words you got to
keep trying harder and harder to be more
and more different right because it's
all about that image how can I continue
being more different you know because
there's tension there it's almost like
when you know I've got children that are
becoming teenagers or becoming adults
and I see what's happening and I
understand what's happening they've got
to create con
trust between themselves and me and
their parents because for you to stand
on your own two feet for you to have
your own identity you have to create
separation you've got to create tension
between that which you know houma
homogenized white milk sheep and me
right and it's okay so it's not it's
normal natural but taking too far you
spend your whole life as a teenager I
don't know how old you are but it's a
very adolescent idea it's a very
adolescent behavior I gotta give
completely honest a lot of my life a lot
of a good part of my early adult life
was being caught in the adolescence of I
have to keep being different I mean I
was different I look different from you
know majority I was homogenized milk
around me and Here I am you know not too
sure what you are you know and uh you
know and in various other aspects so it
kind of was like a little bit of a black
sheep but then I identified with it and
I carried it with me and then and when I
spoke earlier about context the context
of it continued to grow in the negative
frequency of fear and having to prove
myself right so if you're you're a black
sheep and you've got all these white
sheep around you and you've created this
contrast now what you got to do is you
got to prove yourself that you're good
enough and that that having to prove
yourself having to prove that you're
good enough having to constantly show
how you're different and how you're
better comes from fear it's a fear-based
frequencies fear-based ideas fear-based
attitude and everything that you get
will come from your fear everything that
you don't get will be a byproduct of
your fear and you'll be the scared black
sheep feeling all alone amongst all the
white sheep were cool and they all think
they're different to you see but you've
isolated yourself you know no wonder why
so many people feel isolated you know
stop isolating yourself man unless it
comes from the other end of the spectrum
is what you're doing coming from your
love
because if it's coming from love than
there really is no tension to be a black
sheep which we all are in our own way
but from the pure context of love means
that we really don't have to create any
tension we really don't have to create
any contrast between ourselves you're
just being who you are you're just doing
who you are you're like that bird I
spoke about in various videos you know
where the bird is just singing it song
if you like it the birds like well I
that's great I'm happy that you like me
but I'm just doing my thing tweeting my
song if you throw a rock out in it does
you the birds like fuck you don't like
me or you say I don't like you bird you
woke me up this morning what the bird
says I don't give a shit I'm gonna be
here singing my song anyway I don't even
know you I don't notice you when you're
moving from love you don't even notice
the contrast you're so busy doing the
thing that you love that you don't have
any time to be talking about how you're
a black sheep so forget the whole black
sheep thing enroll and developing your
love for something think about how
you're going to contribute to the white
sheep right because they're just as
black as you and you're just as white as
them you think we think we're so much
different but we're not we're special
but we're not different we're all kind
of the same we're all having it's very
similar experiences rather than proving
yourself right proving them wrong and
trying to get something for nothing
serve the white sheep be careful with
that one too man people people
especially a lot of these like
missionaries they like to serve from
this place of piety and I'm better than
you but if you really are in love if you
really are moving with God not just you
know trying to shove your religion down
people's throats or or trying to prove
you're right save people and you're
gonna have a nice comfortable even
frequency love-filled wonderful life
stop the fight done Elliott's it what
[Music]