see yesterday I get an email from one of
our subscribers he goes on to tell me
about a little problem that he's having
turns out that he broke up with a girl
about a year ago and towards the end of
that relationship she started becoming
very belittling and berating towards him
causing him to feel rejected in the
heart and as is normal and natural as a
person feels rejected the object of
rejection no longer has sexual appeal so
he couldn't extend himself physically
towards her any longer basically
couldn't perform sexually his ability to
get an erection with her diminished
completely normal and natural the body
wasn't charged with love and sexuality
and couldn't extend itself no matter how
much they had told it to so they broke
up several months later he's dating
other women the problem now is that he's
projecting the hurts of the past on
these women in the now his heart in his
body is still in that rejection mode it
still feels rejected as protecting
itself from the hurts of other women so
what's happening is he can no longer
extend himself to these new women he
connect an erection with new girls girls
that didn't hurt him now he doesn't have
a problem physiologically getting
erection because he goes on to mention
how he gets morning wood every single
day so he doesn't have a physical
problem it's a psychological problem
it's it's it's tension its neurosis he's
thinking way too much and the heart is
way to shut down to allow the dick to do
what it needs to do so the entire body
becomes rigid when posed with that
threat of rejection in another woman
although you have all the desire in the
world to be with this woman you're
getting in your own way and what we've
got to do is number one get you in a
situation where your mind feels safe
enough to let your heart open up okay so
I would suggest and this is just you
know it's going to be difficult but to
find a woman who's understanding of your
situation explain to her would I explain
to you just now I was rejected in the
past and complete
turned off by this woman and
unfortunately it's projecting itself on
you right now and I want to get past
this because it's not fair to either of
us explain to her that you're going to
need to do some things and you're going
to need some time to open up your heart
and your body so that you can extend
yourself towards her it's going to be
difficult because most of us are way too
narcissistic number one to open
ourselves in that way and it's may be
difficult to find a woman who's that
accepting of you but you're going to
have to do it otherwise you're gonna be
stuck with this problem for the rest of
your life or for a very long time until
you get over it and once you find that
woman you open up your heart to her
eventually you'll feel free enough to
express yourself not only verbally but
physically towards her when you open up
you'll be able to get an erection and
you'll be able to have great sex with
this woman that's the first thing you've
got to do your brain has to get on board
with a deal the next thing we got to do
is we've got to break up the physical
rigidity that's associated with the with
the clenching down with it with the
repression with the the walls that
you're putting up against other women
it's happening in three places it's
happening in your head we can talk it
out a little bit but we also got to get
it out it's happening in your heart
which is evident by your inability to
breathe deep notice when you are about
to perform sexually with her you'll see
that your breathing becomes very shallow
and that's because you're tensing your
muscles in your chest it's not allowing
your chest and your heart to expand so
that you can extend so you can bring
energy bioenergy into your body through
breathing and have the ability to charge
and ultimately discharge with this woman
and obviously down within your sex
center within your with your within your
balls and your dick you're not even
getting down there you're completely
shut off it's almost like someone took a
belt and wrap it around your waist and
cinched it down so that no energy no
feeling can get down there so we got to
break up all the rigidity and you're in
your head and you're in your heart in
your chest and stomach and down in your
cock
what I'm going to show you is an
exercise that you can use it's going to
take some time it doesn't work by itself
you still got to talk it through with
your woman what it's going to do is
going to let you let go and open up and
become freer mentally within your heart
and sexually try this out do it every
day do it several times a day until it
feels real good go to your woman explain
to your situation I promise you'll be
all right dude life is good
Oh
Eliot's it