what's up friends back in my office
today and I'm gonna start by answering a
question that was posted in the comments
area on one of my recent YouTube videos
our friend goes on to say Elliott how
would you recommend I soften the blow of
I'm leaving University to live at a
Buddhist retreat for three to six months
to Christian parents who were under a
significant amount of stress already he
goes on to say that this is something I
have to do at some point in my life and
his time goes on the urge should tear
myself out of the expected manner of
living his only building my mom cried at
the thought of me doing this for less
than a week during the summer so I
stayed put
but life is far too short to waste these
opportunities damn right it is man and
just cuz your mommy's crying doesn't
mean that you've gotta stay attached to
the apron strings your mom's supposed to
cry that's what mommies do when big boys
grow up right so but I get it you know
we love our moms but there is a deep
primordial psychological need
particularly for men this is this is the
case for girls and boys men and women
but the difference that the challenge
that men have to deal with is quite
different than women what I'm talking
about is separating from the parents
right at some point the ego develops and
the baby recognizes that he is not his
mom if you study the infant
psychological development you you
realize that there's a stage when the
human being is steeped in the see of
oneness and the infant doesn't know the
difference between himself and his mom
or herself and her mom so a very
well-documented normal natural makes
sense the ego hasn't developed it but at
some point both the little girl and a
little boy need to separate themselves
or recognize the separation between
themselves and their moms this is normal
natural ego development but unlike the
little girl who only has to separate
from her mom as a an individual a
free-standing human being as opposed to
a oneness with the mother the little boy
has to break the sexual bonds that he
has with his mother and in other words
he has to recognize the contrast between
his sexuality and his mom sexual
in order to do so there is a deep need
deep psychological need primordial
something that our ancestors understood
and that's why they had rites of
passages for the four young men where
the boy has to differentiate sexually
from his mother and in order to to
facilitate that process he has to create
contrast and then he needs something to
follow
right he needs other men to show him
like that what would it is to be a man
mom can't really do that you know
fortunately and we'd like to be as
idealistic as possible but that's not
the case biology reigns over ideology
every day so your desire to break away
from your mommy and the desire to
establish yourself as an independent
free thinking individual in contrast
really that's what you're doing to your
parents and your heritage is normal it's
natural it's supposed to happen so that
the world evolves otherwise we'd be
steeped in superstition Dogma never
really enlightened we'd never grow so I
want to acknowledge your desire to do so
and I also want to give a quick warning
to any of you who or find yourself in a
similar situation yes you need to create
contrast yes it's unfortunate that the
world doesn't provide ritual initiation
for young men but your parents the
religion and your mom in particular
don't deserve resent or disdain that
often comes that that's associated with
creating that contrast and trying to
stand on your own I remember when I was
much younger not that much younger the
amount of disdain that I had towards my
parents for the ideas that they taught
me the experiences that they they they
steeped me in but because they were
doing the best that they knew how our
parents always do the best that they
know how the information that was
provided for them at
that time I don't know how old your
parents are but my parents grew up
before there was an Internet
so yeah they had to take many things at
face value because that's all they knew
they knew the TV said newspapers said
and what the president said when he
addressed them addressed the nation on
the radio or whatever depending how old
your parents are so they only know what
they know because of the information
that was available to them you and I
brah we live in a brand-new day and age
where information is not only plentiful
but it's fucking confusing and that's
why you need core values and your
parents may have even provided you with
some core values one of which is your
religion your link to religion
Christianity in your desire to move
beyond Christianity in your desire to
create contrast between you and your
parents in your desire to grow up and
white mommies tears so that you can be a
big boy you've decided to explore
Buddhism
I took your question because I was in
very similar situation my parents raised
me as a Catholic but my parents were
never very religious never really
pressed us with it but they introduced
the idea that there is a higher power
that there is some transcendent other
that's beyond just me that's just beyond
just us that is um interpersonal and
ever-present you know science has names
for this also but in religion they
called it God and it intrigued me hmm
all the ideas about a God really
intrigued me in college I created
contrast with my parents by actually
becoming Christian at one point in
college I had some friends we're really
into Christianity and I was like boy
that looks that sound like a good idea
that sounds like some pretty cool stuff
I'm gonna study some books they're gonna
teach me a little bit about the
mysteries of the universe and so on and
so forth so I was able to get the ball
rolling but ultimately it didn't jive
well with me
where I was at that time in my life and
ultimately I began studying various
forms of spirituality as you're doing
right now and Buddhism happens to be a
pretty fascinating one happens to be
very resourceful in its in many of the
practices and and if your parents are
truly god-fearing or gods seeking or
spiritual people Christian in particular
they'll recognize various suggestions
even by Jesus where he says look
sometimes you've got to leave your
parents and come follow me
sometimes you got to grow the fuck up
and let the dead bury the dead and come
follow me
sometimes you gotta have to sell all of
your shit and he says this at some point
you're gonna have to sell all your stuff
he says it to the rich man so all you
shouldn't come follow me basically he's
saying in various different ways you're
going to have to fucking die and be born
again you're gonna have to die to your
old self meaning your parents you're
gonna have to die to your old longings
and sense of being meaning your wealth
or your even your ego your character who
you think you are
breakdown completely dissolve be born
again so that you could be born again in
Christ in Christ consciousness do you
understand now your parents raised you
in a form of consciousness that they
label as Christ consciousness but it's
not fulfilling enough for you that's
totally understandable not only you're
creating contrast but you're reaching
now and you can thank your parents for
the impetus for the inspiration to reach
to reach for God and you're finding that
Buddhism is allowing you that to happen
there are those you know we're talking
about soften and blow to your parents
they're not gonna bit look this might
soften a blow or now it doesn't matter
you're gonna have to grow up anyway and
mommy's gonna cry that's just the way
shit is but um if your parents are
thinking people open available creative
intuitive people they might be able to
accept the idea that perhaps you know
I've heard this before in fact uh you
know I'm sort of a a religious slut like
I kind of IIIi bounce around I don't get
tied to too many things and for many
years I was a Baha'i I'm not familiar
with the Baha'i faith it's also an
Abrahamic religion
similar Christianity one of the tenants
of the Baha'i faith is that there has
been progressive realization of the
celestial ideas that burn with
consciousness in humankind
and Jesus just happens to be one in a
long succession of many and many that
will continue to come and Buddha and
Jesus many people believe and there has
been tons of investigation into the
relationship both consciously and
physically between the teachings of
Jesus and the teaching in book of Buddha
there's in fact a book I believe called
Jesus the Buddha but you might want to
you might want to read and invest in and
look another Baha'i idea that I took two
during my stages in that in that in that
stage was that when a child or an
individual a person like yourself grows
in consciousness regardless of what your
parents grandparents or ancestors have
may have said or done your level of
consciousness offers retrospect
retrospective blessings to your ancestry
in fact it's believed that they gifted
you with the inquiring heart to keep
seeking your enlightenment or your
salvation see there's just different
language to describe the same shit
Christians might say salvation Buddha's
might say enlightenment but it's an
awakening that if you awaken my friend
which you are we're all awake we're in
the age of tremendous awakening I don't
know if we all realize this or not but
because of the internet information is
that much more actively available for us
think kind of where we're stumbling is
the UM we're not the age of actually
doing it you know a lot of you guys I
know watch these videos haven't done
shit yet that's normal natural because
you're absorbing but um we're gonna move
to the age of actually doing this shit I
think we're getting close evolution is
rabid anyway my point here is that it is
your responsibility
to die to your old self to die to the
younger immature version of yourself
that needs mommy's approval and it is
very responsible of you to be seeking
higher thoughts and ways of being such
that you can reach enlightenment when I
say reaching enlightenment it's not a
destination it's a process of becoming a
stronger version of you so my man you
can do the good work of empowering other
people including perhaps your mommy
daddy grandparents and seven generations
of ancestors keep growing stronger keeps
brighter keep shining your light done