okay got a great question from our
friend Sasha it's a big puzzle there are
lots of pieces to his puzzle so I want
to shell it out in pieces the very first
thing is that our friend lost both of
his parents when he was 8 years old he
had two siblings one was 16 was 18 his
brother was 18 years old when his
parents died when his parents died all
three of them got a inheritance of over
$100,000 each right so my G was 8 years
old 8 years later when our friend Sasha
was 16 his brother who at this time it
must have been in his 30s borrowed fifty
thousand dollars of that one hundred
plus thousand dollars that Sasha got as
an inheritance right and that money went
to all sorts of dysfunctional things
like paying for partying
bills and just a lifestyle it's just not
resourceful - growing stronger than his
older brother had adopted and and
granted my empathy goes out because it's
a difficult thing to lose both your
parents at such a young age
your brother grew dysfunctional and is
apparently still down in dysfunction
going down a dysfunctional path based on
that trauma or whatever else life has
offered him but you are you sent him
fifty thousand dollars you you mention
fifty thousand dollars and the very
first thing I want to address is the
energy around surrounding the money the
money you understand that money is a is
a manifestation of the service we
provide to the world we that's why we
earn it you earn money because you give
something to get money the money that
you got is sacrificial money the energy
surrounding it is not I worked hard for
this money it's my parents died and this
money fell in my lap so there's a lot of
a negative association with that money
it's very difficult to understand this
because we like to look at things
objectively right like it's it's just
fucking money and your parents died it's
cash bro not so subjectively especially
as a young child the experience is so
with getting that money is a very
difficult one so you probably have a
detachment from this money three to give
$50,000 to your brother is not only a
expression of your love for him right
brother you know he needs some money but
it's also a indication and there are
many indications but it's just a it's
another indication of the pointing to
the detachment that you have from the
money the ill feelings that you probably
have about the money right whether or
not this is conscious is irrelevant I'm
telling you that there are ill feelings
about the money because your parents
don't die when you're eight years old
and you get a $100,000 and you feel good
about that okay so that money is not
really your money and I think you feel
that way as well
so it's a tool now to help you see some
things and help you grow stronger as you
learn how to earn your own money because
that's going to be important because
you've got it you now you have to have
different associations with money
otherwise you're gonna end up broke or
destitute or spending your money on
things like your brother is and
apparently you're much more grounded
child then your brother was but we got
to resolve that right this money is not
your money and it's fine that you gave
your brother fifty thousand dollars the
thing is that his brother now is a
victim of what he's calling attention
deficit disorder right he's got other
problems he's on drugs and whatever the
case may be perhaps he's got a new job
bla bla bla and but it's time for him to
pay the money back right now that he's
got a job fifty thousand dollars and our
buddy Sasha doesn't want to disrupt the
relationship that he has with his
brother doesn't want to be a burden upon
his brother but he wants his money back
right so I totally get it
his brothers our victim right it's like
hot he's got a TD and he's had a bad
life and I'm sure you feel this way
towards your brother the energy between
your brother is kind of like my poor big
brother he can't get his shit right he's
a victim and he's embraced that right
for him to to embrace a diagnosis of any
sort anytime we embrace
the diagnosis doesn't mean that you
don't have what you've been diagnosed
with I have cancer right doesn't mean
that there isn't cancer cells in your
body doesn't mean that the is attention
deficit doesn't have a deficit to his
attention it's how do you embrace that I
have a VD it's mine I have cancer or
there's attention deficit happening in
my body there's a cancerous growth in my
body you see and I'm sure your brother
is the type again this is all just pick
ulation that embraces the victimhood
like this is going to be his pattern
this is going to be his Karma and he's
going to be a drain on you for the rest
of your life if you don't deal with him
in a resourceful fashion right if you
enable his victimhood but he's got a
good job now mm-hmm right how old this
is probably I'm sure he's older than me
right I mean based on the math here what
you've got to recognize and what I'm
gonna offer you is that there's a movie
there's a great line in this movie a
Bronx Tale anybody's watched this you
know if you grew up in New York you
definitely watch the Bronx Tale where
college you know I think is the name of
the kid in the movie he's chasing after
a kid down the street right clothes you
know must be like 15 16 maybe 18 years
old chasing his kid like you
motherfucker
get back here Chi Chi Chi's running and
then his mentor collection hos mentor
comes up to a missus hey stop what are
you doing what's going on here you know
this guy's like a big mob boss is that
what are you fucking doing here kid
that motherfucker owes me a thousand
bucks or a couple hundred bucks me 500
bucks whatever it is he owes me a
thousand bucks he says hey relax relax
pleasure no chill out let him go let him
go
he's like
we let him come in and the older smarter
more grounded patriarch mentor says to
him look that guy's no good you just
paid a thousand bucks to get him out of
your life he won't be around anymore
think of it that way think of it as you
just invested in getting that rat
bastard out of your life right with your
brother it's very different than you
know some rat bastard that owns you
money with your brother you've bought
clarity and understanding on where you
are in relation to him what type of
relationship you have he lost his
parents just says you did and he leaned
on you suckled on you right he's going
to continue suckling on you and if
you're not aware of that right I'm not
saying kick him out of your life but if
you're not aware of the relationship
that you have between the two of you you
will be suckled on for the rest of your
life not only by him but it'll become a
pattern your wife will suckle on you
your friends will suckle on you you know
what you call someone that gets suckled
on a lot a sucker you don't want to
become a sucker and your brother will
suck you dry if you're not aware of the
situation so you paid $50,000 as a kid
right it wasn't your money to begin with
and you felt this way
but you were afforded a pipe pie of
energy and you invested a part of it to
gain clarity on the relationship between
you and your brother and that's very
very very very valuable because if you
do not have this clarity about the type
of relationship you have between the two
of you like I said you will end up a
sucker in many many many many ways so be
grateful for what she purchased he's not
gonna pay you back okay I'm not psychic
but I've got a pretty good grasp on
human behavior right he's a victim he's
just got a job he owes you $50,000 from
several years ago you're not getting
your money back you invested that money
just like collage no did in order to
gain intel as to the type relationship
that you have with him right so that's
it that's done now and he owes you even
more money than that that's fine what
should you do in this situation I don't
want to affect a relationship with my
brother you have to grow stronger than
your brother now this is what you do
next right you already understand the
associations with the money you already
understand your relationship with your
brother let it both go that money's not
yours
invest it get rid of it when I say
invest even in the evening the
investments need to be flittered away
that's not your money that's that's
blood money okay
this is just what I'm feeling about it
and I could be wrong but I'm offering
you this that's blood money get rid of
it the best way you can just like you
did in order to get rid of the suckling
from your brother now clean slate this
is what you need motherfucker you need a
clean slate to start all over again and
this is great you don't have blood money
in your pockets and you have a
perspective you've gained a perspective
on your relationship with your brother
grow stronger now what is Elliott Hulse
this message always grow stronger and
through your strength through the
energetic charge of your positive energy
you will inspire him perhaps to grow
stronger or someone around him to grow
stronger or someone you've never met yet
to grow stronger it is your job now to
take those experiences and any other
experiences that you've had in your life
you've got a great story your parents
died great story right I might sound
objective when I say that but but stick
with me for a minute all of our
challenges are also challenges for other
people we go through shit so that we can
show other people you can get through
shit so you've been through some shit
embrace that story use it it's a tool
now you're gonna grow stronger look both
my parents died at age of 8 my brother
is a drug addict and look how awesome I
am that is your goal
that's what you do now you become
awesome now I don't know what that
awesome looks like you know what that
awesome looks like and I can promise you
it's gonna be a long
our journey of Awesomeness becoming the
strongest version yourself and I'm
grateful for your pains and I'm happy
for you because you're gonna be a big
strong super star badass and you're
going to then in your parents name
inspire others perhaps including your
brother to become stronger versions of
themselves that's your mission once
we've cut ties with the negative energy
in our in our lives which is a process
in and of itself because we all come in
here innocent and the world wakes us
once you've cut ties with the negative
energy your only objective as a human
being living in this day and age and the
culture that we live in is to become a
stronger version of yourself and inspire
others this is how the human race
evolves you've been offered check
environmental pressures if you if you
studied Darwin environmental pressures
create what sparks develop of evolution
you're going to evolve in a way that is
unique and that can serve a purpose in
multiple ways if you have the right
perspective if you're thinking about
this properly you're telling yourself
the right stories so that's it my friend
I appreciate you sending this question
and I am looking forward to hearing more
about your journey of growing stronger
and how you support others as you
develop talk to you next time