got this question from our friend calls
himself DK DK is a young dude who wants
to be a basketball player so he does
what any young man with ambition and a
goal would do gets up every single
morning very early practices his skill
it gets out there and dribbles the ball
before school he's on the fasted State
he's committed he's disciplined he's
hardworking he put in all the effort
that's associated with what it would
typically take to reach success except
he fails it doesn't make the basketball
team and it's not the first time can't
figure it out what's going on here
what's keeping me from reaching my goal
although I put everything that I have
into it
am I just doomed to failure for the rest
of my life and he's falling into the
depths of depression because of these
circumstances because of this experience
one things you got to understand my
friend is that you're supposed to fail
you're supposed to fucking fail because
failure is the stepping stone to success
it's not just cliche you know that
sounds fucking nice you put it in a
Hallmark card right you see a nice
little meme on Facebook that says that
right we put your belly house right next
to it make that mean failure is the
stepping stone to success
fuck that poetic shit you need the
logical reason why because failure is an
experienced it lends to wisdom that
ultimately makes you a stronger version
of yourself right right now you want to
play basketball well it's not in the
cards for you but you know what you
discovered how to be committed how to be
disciplined how to deny the self so that
you can move forward in the direction of
your dreams you've won in that regard
the failure is just a signpost that
you're going in the wrong direction to
understand another one of these cliches
or cliches stories is about Thomas
Edison right when a reporter asked him
you know what is it hot how do you feel
about failing a thousand times and he
said no I didn't fail a thousand times I
just found a thousand different ways
that it wasn't going to work and that's
what that's what's happening with you
but every time he found a way that
didn't work he was adding to his journey
he was growing stronger he learned
something he discovered something you
were discovering something about
yourself and you're exercising your
character every time you get up and try
something move in the direction of
something even if you don't get the
fucking thing it's not about the thing
it's not about making the basketball
team it's not about making million
dollars and it's not about the lightbulb
it's about what you learn along the way
who you become along the way it's that
fucking journey and you're on the
journey and guess what the journey is
hard the journey is riddled with failure
and that's why most people don't do it
most people are willing to get on that
journey because they're afraid to fail
you my friend have failed to
congratu-fucking-lations it's the
greatest thing that ever happened to you
because it shows that you're alive it
shows that you did something and it
shows that you're growing stronger now
go and fucking fail again boy I hope I
hope you guys are watch these videos I
hope you gonna fail a thousand fucking
times keep going in out there and
failing you know what that means
every time you fail it means to me it
tells me that you're doing something go
out there and fucking fail it's the
greatest joy in life because it says so
much about your character and it adds so
much to who you're becoming but we live
in a culture in a day and age where
everybody wants something for nothing
right they see Michael Jordan on the end
day and they see all his money right now
use him as an example because I'm
reading a book where he's mentioned
right LeBron James Rahon perhaps they
see him at the end they see all the
successes at the end they see Steve Jobs
right they see all the great things that
happen to people you might watch this in
fact you know you know what he said to
me right cuz now I'm saying I'm talking
to audience now JK you know what this
dude said to me he said Elliott you've
always been a success at the end of his
email ha Elliott you've always been a
success can you help me out no
motherfucker I have not always been a
success I have so many failures it would
make you crawl under a table and want to
fucking die I felt ISM dude I don't
think I didn't want to go there
I am a failure in and of itself just me
who I am the way I look how do you fail
from fucking birth right I didn't fit in
I walked I walked into school the first
time and it was like okay I don't fit in
I failed at that I didn't have a fucking
hand in that I came out of fucking
failure but I learned something from
each one of those fucking failures dude
that's why I am Who I am today
label it as you wish
call it what you want you might see it
as a success but me I'm still failing I
got four children every day I fail at
being a better dad there's always more
that I could do and I embrace that
because every time I feel failure it
means that I'm doing something and then
I'm growing in a particular way and I
look at the failure when I say how can I
improve or am i moving in the wrong
direction signposts so that's it dude
get used to it
you're young get used to it no don't
just accept it but embrace it it is the
law of nature it is the way it is it's
not harsh right cuz it's because a good
Town Mike you know life is hard no life
is not fucking hard there were laws to
life and that's one of the fucking laws
that you gonna scrape your knees you're
gonna fall down you're gonna fail you're
gonna fuck yourself up just the way it
is love it for what it is because if you
didn't fail you would never be able to
appreciate success done