so buddy Richard uses a really
masochistic form of motivation
basically he psychologically whips
himself in order to achieve particular
goals that he set for himself in
particular fitness goals he's realizing
that this is not a resourceful way to
motivate himself in order to become a
stronger version himself in fact he
feels as if it's making him weaker and
essentially what's happening is he talks
down to himself badgers himself fucking
idiot or whatever the case may be and
that gives him the charge enough to go
and do something about it he goes to the
gym he works but he realizes that all
this negative self-talk that happens to
be giving him the motivation right to go
and work in the gym is also
deteriorating his character he's getting
depressed it's getting worse and worse
interesting thing that he describes also
is that there are lots of other kids in
his village I don't know where you live
but there are other kids guys doing the
same thing right and there's no one to
dad any support or two for guidance I
said what do i what do I do because I'm
walking down a dark path of
self-destruction in order to get
something done that's it that's an ego
contract you know a lot of the times
when we go and exercise and train there
are two reasons to train the body
there's two reasons to exercise the body
and what I'm going to share with you now
there's one that is for pleasure you
train the body because you enjoy the
charge you enjoy the oxygen you enjoy
the surge of blood and hormones
associated with lifting weights and
running and jumping and sprinting using
the body for all it's been meant to be
used for right expressing our our mind
is expressed to our body so your entire
nervous system is enhanced through
exercise that is resourceful exercise
exercise it adds to you that is euphoric
that makes you feel better about
yourself that's it's probably the one
that most people don't do more more than
more people probably definitely proceed
from a place of
masochism it's it there's a there's a
schizophrenic behavior towards the body
it's I'm going to make this body do what
I want it to do so it's like the head is
attacking the body and it's like I'm
gonna grow 20 pounds and there's this
neurotic drive to force the body to do
or to to perform based on an ego a
construct something that the brain
created and usually what the brain
creates is what meat media culture
shares with us and tells us what we
should we should do or aspire to right
so there's this idea of what you should
look like and you know that you could
beat the shit out of your body to make
that happen
okay that's sometimes that's you know
it'll get you what you think you want
but ultimately you end up down this path
of beating the shit out of yourself
literally and and I'm mentally
emotionally right you're and this is
what's happening to your not feeling
better about yourself because you're
beating yourself up psychologically and
then using and then furthering that
beating by going to gym and yeah hurting
your body point is I don't have to place
judgment on it you've already said that
it's a no social thing cool what you
need to experience is good feelings in
your body once again and that's really
where we live we live in our bodies it's
all you really have this is it
you know once once this dies then the
spirit exits and whatever a spiritual
shit goes on I don't know I'm not here
to debate but you're living in this
thing right now right and it's all you
have in order to experience the world
that we live in and in order to have a
pleasurable life you have to experience
pleasurable feelings and the only way
that you can invite or elicit
pleasurable feelings in your body is by
softening it with deeper breathing
that's a very first step you describe
yourself as depressed depression is a
just like it sounds
it is a depression of the
in the body it is a closing in
tightening a pressing down of the
energetic physiological and
neuromuscular processes of the body you
become clenched right what you need to
do is the exact opposite open the body
open the body for deeper breathing and
for pleasurable feelings and pleasurable
feelings will happen when you get out a
lot of the negative feelings that you're
experiencing right so I invite you to
practice the bio-jet bioenergetic
catharsis that I've shared with you guys
in other videos shaking and vibrating
breathing deep using the bioenergetics
tool your best bet is to just begin with
the bow I taught you guys all these
things so I'm assuming that you can go
back and search my channel or you know
stick around you'll learn a little bit
more about it but using the bow in a
fashion that opens up your your
respiratory pathways I'll show you very
quickly again if you want to get open up
your hips you want pleasurable feelings
this is the center for pleasure right
this is where you're your sex center is
open up your hips by putting your hands
on your butt
working your way up to the heart right
love pleasurable feelings of the heart
are here and you see I'm vibrating
already alright and then opening up even
further okay you got to get back in
touch with your body dude your body is
where emotion lies your body is where
pleasure lies maybe take a break from
weight training for just a little while
because weight training closes you up
right it has a tendency especially
bodybuilding type weight training has
intensity to close the extra respiratory
muscles the respiratory pathways
stretching and breathing maybe take up
yoga right that's the first step get in
touch with your body get in touch with
your ability and that happens to your
ability to breathe deep the second thing
would be find a way to get a charge in
your body that's not associated with
beating it right so that means pick a
goal and what I would actually my
invitation if I were if you were my son
I'd say look son go and learn how to
play an instrument let's take up guitar
lessons let's take up piano lessons
let's take up the saxophone or the flute
take up some instrument that allows your
body to express itself through the
instrument and also creates beauty right
so you're now using the head you're
connecting your head back to your body
they need to join each other once again
because I had to beating the shit out
your body they need to join each other
and they need to produce something they
need to create something learn how to
play piano make it your goal to play a
particular piano song you know do some
research but when you get back into your
body when your mind and body become one
again and you're using
as a collaborating means to a beautiful
end creating music as opposed to beating
up your body you will be on your way
back on that journey of becoming a
stronger version of yourself too so
that's it I hope that's helpful I kind
of spoke in circles there but the bottom
line here is get start to breathe deep
open up your expert ex respiratory
pathways getting in touch with your body
your motility right you've got to feel
your body again that happens through
deep breathing and then go and learn how
to play beautiful music with that body
maybe even sing singing opens up the
extra respiratory pathways singing
causes you to breathe into your balls
also so that might even be a better idea
than piano or the guitar but it's your
choice dude I hope that helps