just one thing I noticed with a lot of
people dead lifting and he said how how
you deadlift and it really tells a lot
about the person I noticed that you know
everybody's heads always up everybody
says always love you always want to you
always want to see you want to feel like
I know exactly where I am I know what
I'm doing like the deadlift I'm like
okay I can see in front of me but just
you know you don't have to get that
stimulus 24-7 you don't have to always
see where you're going like just
everything like your feet are still on
the ground you know just so funny now
I'm gonna give up I want to be a little
poetic here I talked about how there is
this restriction what's going to tear
out this portion of the nextel box
accruals sensors and the draw bustles
the mastoid and all the drops is up here
they all act as a physical for principal
expression of psychological castration
from the body the body represents the
part of us that things went out of
having a bank awakens your heart for a
QB time digesting that part of our body
is also that the peripheral nervous
system vegetative nervous system it's
that which does stuff without you having
to do it and when you're describing not
happy being able to see it's almost like
you've got to have courage enough to
trust your body without having to be in
control of it because this is this is
the position of control this is in
position and it's fearful control
because you gotta be courageous to just
go with what trusting your body and let
your body do this you've got to build
courage to do okay so that's either here
no they're much okay now that's
basically what i want to say just I mean
that could either be like a way to
diagnose like what that person might be
thinking about like what what's really
going on their head
choices are making the life that have
that's maybe the kind of personality
like oh I always need to be in control
at all times I need to see everything
like it's always going to be the same
any with you if you look up or down but
what you forget about your heart you
forget about you know being grounded and
all this stuff because you just want to
satisfy this one here we're going off
you're going strong let me by
mechanically or stronger I think you're
even stronger trust your body because
there's an imbalance of strength when
it's all sympathetic when it's all male
when it's all aggressive as opposed to
parasympathetic without female tender
that's the only yeah yeah then I'll
synergize simple is all about that
balance the old this whole thing our
world has become so head oriented
male-oriented penis more into depression
oriented more oriented that there's kind
of work or in vain our dysfunction is
due to that in doubt so it's trusting
it's yielding its softly it's being
tender enough that allows deep grounded
strength