so we have this question from our friend
who also know how he could better
believe in himself
says a lot of your videos Eliot revolve
around how to ignore other people who
don't believe in you but what if you
just don't believe in yourself what if
you don't think you have the skills the
abilities and the technical know-how
whatever that might be to achieve your
particular goal how do I come to believe
in myself well my friend here's the very
first piece of advice that I like to
offer you there is no need to believe in
yourself belief in yourself is
completely unnecessary you don't need it
what you do need is passion and courage
that's how shit gets done you decide
with your head you act with your balls
and you continue to color it with
passion from your heart the head is it's
giving you your wrapped up in this story
about the fact that you need to keep
believing in something belief is
completely unnecessary the head its job
is to help you decide your intelligence
it allows you to calculate based on past
experiences and information but belief
is a compulsion construct that makes you
that means you need to fool yourself
somehow
that's all belief is belief is I have
absolutely no proof but I'm tricking
myself to believe I'm tricking myself
into right this is I mean there are lots
of beliefs out there and if somebody
believes something that basically means
I have no evidence for it for factual
for no factual evidence I don't know
that this is true but I'm going to paint
a picture and I'm going to tell myself
stories that makes me believe or somehow
that it is true it's all fucking mind
games your mind fucking yourself you
don't need this you need to use this to
choose what you want then you need no
longer head but heart and balls
motherfucker that's what takes over once
you've decided whatever it is that you
want good you decide once and now you go
you move
passion and you move with courage you
move with your heart you move with your
balls and regardless of how you think
about yourself you do it anyway
you got courage and passion so you take
action you don't need to believe
anything in fact you could fucking hate
yourself and you just keep doing it
because the thing that you're doing has
to be bigger than you that's one of the
prerequisites right because if you
choose based on greed right I'm going to
achieve this goal so I can have more so
that I can be empowered somehow and
manipulate people
the more narcissistic and ego-centered
it is the more you have to revert to
this part of your body there's no
passion in narcissism and there's no
courage because it's cowardly but when
the thing that you're doing is bigger
than you when it's a service when it's a
way that you can make the world better
your heart will instantly be animated
and your balls will get you through it
passion and courage there's no need for
belief done