the principles of strength training
taught me how to succeed in everything
else the character that I've built
through strength training is what
allowed me to succeed in every other
thing that I do that's why I always use
strength training as a metaphor for
everything else in your life if you're
watching my videos you know that Elliott
house is not just talking about strength
training l is talking about growing
stronger in every area of your life
because it's been my experience that as
you grow stronger with the barbell as
you physically grow stronger you're
developing a character associated with
strength that you can carry with you in
multiple areas of your life and you
begin to understand the same principles
of succeeding in the gym are the same
principles that will help you succeed in
life the biggest one of which in my
opinion is courage you know if you're
too scared one of the things with a lot
of these kids that are not growing
stronger in the gym they don't have a
coach or something is that they're too
scared to timid too afraid to attack the
training with with any type of ferocity
and that holding back in the gym is the
exact holding back from getting the
girlfriend they want getting the career
that they want getting you know all the
things that they want else other things
they want in life we got a good friends
I'm not gonna say his name because he
knows I'm talking about he probably
doesn't know I'm talking about it right
now but when we used to train we would
jump don't be like yo just whatever you
got to do just turn your brain off and
jump over this barrier jump over the
barrier and you would hesitate you get
up to it and it was like I know you
could do it but even if you can't do
approaches fucking jump you're not gonna
kill yourself you knock over the you
knock over the pole who cares
you get all psyched up and hesitate
every single time one day I was like
look dude this is not just showing up in
the gym right where else is this showing
up that same attitude associated with
hesitation in your approach to athletics
I guarantee you is showing up in school
with your girlfriend with your career
with your business with your
relationships and short
you know surely he agreed he said yeah
you know what you're right and he looks
back and we can take a look and it's
like a lot of those areas that I would
like to do better they lack because of
the courage I didn't build when I was in
the environment to the gym it shows up
your character is something that you
carry with you wherever you go
it doesn't just the way you show up in
the gym is the way you're going to show
up in life and the way you show up in
life a lot of times is the way you show
up in the gym