yo Eliot what up y'all question here
from Joshua tiller says in many of your
videos Eliot you talked about how in
order to be successful need to put a
hundred and ten percent is this camera
cook it still crooked I know because the
strengths there we go
some of your videos you talk about how
to be success successful you need to put
a hundred and ten percent of your effort
into achieving whatever objective you've
set aside for yourself right on a
counter point because Eliot always
contradicts himself you could have said
that
and then you contradict yourself Eliot
by saying you need to reserve and detach
yourself from the world and focus more
on the subjective to better manage
stress my question is is it possible to
give a hundred and ten percent of
yourself to achieving your goals yet
still be able to detach yourself from it
to eliminate stress or burning out I am
a success he says I'm 22 years old and I
have a job as a park ranger where I
truly feel I am contributing to making
others happy that's pretty fucking cool
man Park Ranger I love my job and I give
a hundred percent 101 percent hundred
and ten percent and everything I do
however I've been slight being uh I've
been starting to get burnt out I don't
want to sacrifice the effort and
everything I do I'm aware that you went
through something similar
Elliott yes yes indeed so you know I've
also said things like you got to take
care of your game piece right if you're
gonna play this game you want to play
the game as hard as you fucking can
think about an athlete right an athlete
gives a hundred and ten percent I mean
when when the ball is snapped he's going
right when the ball is in play he's
running you don't hold anything back
you've you've ever played sports or if
you ever watched professional sports
do you know that everything is on the
line and they're training year-round
also right the thing is that they're
playing a game they know they're playing
a game you're playing a game we're all
playing a fucking game right as what
this is right if you take it too
seriously then you missed the fucking
point but what the athlete does is he
takes care of his game piece right he
sleeps well you make sure he's getting
enough rest or his coach or the person
that's invested in him make sure you go
you go to bed motherfucker you ain't
staying up drinking you know shooting
yourself in the leg in New York City
right you got to eat well right if
you're gonna give a hundred ten percent
you got to be eating well you got to
Train well meaning in a balanced way so
if you're gonna be training with the
weights you had also be doing your
stretching mobilizing getting massaged
doing yoga right balance training what
else keep your stress low some some
boxers you know in the past it's been
said I don't know if they still do that
because like you can't be with women you
know man hold on hold on to your
vitality no women keep your stress low I
think that's more about just keeping the
headaches low right shit I don't know
why I say that cuz I women in my life
ain't no headaches right I got 99
problems so the key here my man is that
there's game time and then there's
recovery time and as much as you put
into your game time you know when you're
when you're park ranger in it up right I
want to make a park ranger joke about
Yogi Bear but I respect you too much
cause you're making people happy you
Park Ranger in it up when you go home
turn it down a notch turn it down a big
notch Elliott Hulse says get a hammock I
think every warrior needs a hammock to
balance himself out right now you're in
full warrior mode but you're gonna burn
yourself out if you don't go lateral if
you don't go horizontal and get rocked
in your hammock man so go home in fact
like if you could put one up in your in
the tree in the
and the park ranger Hut put up a hammock
man you in the goddamn woods put up a
hammock and every moment that you get
you know you just went and save somebody
from a forest fire right I got back
there picnic basket you go and I had to
do it you go and you lay down in your
hammock you lay down in your hammock
there's rock there dude ten minutes ten
minutes and you're recharged it's really
magical it's like it's better than
anabolic steroids that's not true but it
really helps you become more anabolic it
helps you relax recharge in a very quick
way man that's some about that rocking
something about being being horizontal
right almost like you're dead it is
rocking hmm and you're outdoors - park
ranger man so it should be easy for you
to do so just just to recap you can go
hard when it's time to go hard but you
have to just like an athlete make time
to eat right you shouldn't be skipping
meals you should be drinking half your
body weight in ounces of water every day
you should be getting eight hours of
sleep every night you should be keeping
your stress low right all the things
associated with good health that's why I
can't separate Fitness from life mastery
that's why I put that yo Elliott all
together in this channel because lot of
you guys want to be successful in
business or successful in your
relationships but just your health is
all fucked up you can't be sick sad and
crippled and Wanek I want to meet women
well look at you you you're fat with
zits right it's not a disease it's a bad
habit Society is that is eating that
fast food and not exercising right fact
backwoods it's a in a disease it's dis
easing it don't you're not easy to be
that way but it's a choice bad breath
all these are indicated indications of
your health take good care of your
health everything else falls into place
dead-ass
you know you got these guys who earn
billions of dollars but they sick
they're not happy now if you got a
billion dollars and you're healthy
that's a different story man so keep
doing your thing
lay down rest relax when it's time to
take frequent rest intervals throughout
the day and follow those healthy
principles done