[Music]
so I put myself in a situation where I
openly receive criticism justifiably
from growth both religious and
scientific people on one end you got
religious people who wonder why Elliot
uses the word God will speak so
eloquently and openly oftentimes about
Jesus and perhaps some of the other
figures in the Abrahamic religions but
often speaks very openly about his ideas
on Eastern religions how could somebody
be like could speak that way but still
deny that a man could rise from the dead
come back and hang out with you or walk
on water perhaps why why why won't you
take literally that a man could talk to
a burning bush Bush talks back and then
gives him ways and means to navigate the
world why why can't you take that
literally Elliot no the other end of the
spectrum you've got scientific people
that wonder how is it Elliot that used
to be so scientifically with regard to
the body you use such elephant language
to describe the world in a very
scientific language but yet you use this
word God you refer to this Jesus
character and all of which makes
absolutely no sense
there's one thing about both ends of
that spectrum that are exactly the same
as each other
and when they both fail isn't that they
see the world through the eyes of one
side of a two-sided coin both religion
and science see world objectively now
you might say Elliot that's not the case
with religion right because religion was
born of an objective experience
objective experience right that's why
they spoke in terms of animals speaking
to people in giant floods and all the
stories made up in order to describe the
deeper realities of the world that they
did not have language for or at least
the word the language was in the way we
use it today in scientific terms but
when you start taking those outer
descriptions as literal translations of
what has actually happened like there
was a Noah Ark Jesus actually died and
came back physically like we can touch
him then what you're doing is you're
looking at and you're distorting you're
ruining the beautiful poetic language
that our ancients our ancestors used in
order to give us hints into how to
navigate the external world toward
subjective
understanding the language is pointing
to something a greater reality there's
no need to prove it you see sciency
religious people you would have proved
that these stories are real well that's
where you become scientific and you and
you fall into the same trap that science
has fell in falling into where
everything is about how I can prove well
good that's fine that's great that's
very important side of the coin it's 50%
of the human experience because only 50%
of what goes on in the human experience
is object-oriented meaning that we could
point to it we could touch it we can
prove it we can measure it that is all
very well and good it's very important
it has gotten us so much of the
beautiful things that we have today
because we can see the world in that
reason that way we can be objective see
many animals can't do that human beings
are brilliant in our capacity to be
objective but we have this bias towards
objectivity and we've completely ignored
and demonized the subjective experience
the subjective is the inner experience
and it is not the same as that which
could be measured with tools and pointed
at in tangibly manipulated and navigated
you can't deal with it the same way as
you deal with the outer experience the
objective because the subjective is not
is not an object it's an experience
my invitation is to continue with
whatever way you decide to understand
the world either through the poetic
language of religion or the scientific
way of describing the world because that
even even that is poetic if we don't let
you know we don't like to look at it
that way acknowledge it that way
and get in touch with your experience
the subjective what's happening inside
you not what someone has told you see
both science and religion are based on
what other people have measured or
experienced what other people see or or
or have come to know most of the time
it's not true anyway they've read
textbooks or Bibles they don't know
anything because they've been so far
remove from their personal subjective
experience that all they can do is
personally identify with these objects
language that's really what it is this
fucking language that we've become so
addicted to language is just symbols
that they have no personal experience of
their own most of us have no personal
experience of our own we don't know how
to be in touch with ourselves you don't
know what's going on inside us in fact
inside it's all creepy and weird so we
had better attached to that which is out
here which is clean and neat number of
problems with that being attached to
objects puts you in a very vulnerable
position to manipulation by those who
hold the objects you see that's why
religion has caused so many Wars and
science is causing us to destroy the
world destroy the earth both afford us
beautiful things in their correct
context but both cause us to destroy
ourselves and our planet go in go in and
see feel experience what's happening in
you use the objective world to get a
better understanding or use language
symbols to sort of describe it but see
it for just what it is
it is a tool science is a tool and
religion is a tool and the words that
they use are simply language they're
just different languages but still tools
to describe that which cannot really be
described which is the subjective
because everybody's subjective
experience is completely different
that's the other trap when you become so
attached to the objective you don't have
anything
because it's all out there so of course
I'm ranting and I'm sure I lost a lot of
you along the way there I probably lost
myself but my real invitation is not to
give up your religion not to see it as
right or wrong not to destroy the world
in the name of it or to just be attached
to science my invitation is to go in
experience yourself trust yourself know
that what you're feeling and what's
happening on the inside of you and your
perspectives thereof are good and
they're right and they're true although
they may be diametrically opposed to
everything you've been told have your
own