a question from our buddy CJ who has
conflicting or seemingly conflicting
passions so he's in school and he's
studying how to become a music producer
and he loves it with all of his heart he
feels as if he's in his river as I would
say when he's doing the music production
thing when he's producing his own music
when he's studying music everything
associated with that he loves now he
also started going outdoors and rock
climbing and doing exercises in nature
essentially this is the way he describes
it says that I've been outdoors running
and walking and hiking and I've grown to
love the outdoor lifestyle associated
with doing all the things that make my
body healthy and fit so he's got this
fitness and outdoor passion as well as
his music production passion and he
feels as if they're at odds with each
other and they're really not but in his
mind he believes that if he follows his
his dream and pursues music production
he's going to end up in a big city right
which I don't know anything about music
production but perhaps perhaps he's
right perhaps the situation is such that
in order to fulfill his dream he's got
to make some sacrifices and that which
he would have to sacrifice in his mind
is his ability to exercise outdoors in
nature no I don't know where you word is
that you live but I would assume that
you could probably have both depending
on where you live but the real question
here is right because it goes beyond
just the content here the the context of
the question is how can you have both
right and we tend to live in a day and
age and people tend to tell us and
people have told me that you've got to
choose one or the other in many regards
so for example I wanted a lifestyle
where my wife stayed home with my
children I wanted to have lots of
children I want to spend lots of time
with my family my wife my children and I
wanted to build a business I wanted my
own gym and I wanted to do what I'm
doing here through publishing ideas
through the internet and it would it all
seemed like the people that I shared
this idea of having both with thought I
was nuts well you know what if you're
going to build a big business and you
going to have all these lofty goals with
regard to your career then your family
is going to suffer or if you're going to
be a family man that just realized that
you shouldn't have such high aspirations
with regard to your your fitness
business things of that nature and the
same thing as for you people are going
to tell you what you ought to choose
what I decided to do was take the advice
of Dan Kennedy who's one of the sort of
a mentor to me because I read a lot of
his books and he said the very first
thing you should do is design the type
of lifestyle that you want to live first
thing you do don't figure out what kind
of business you want don't decide what
kind of career you want the first thing
you do is to choose your lifestyle down
to the letter so essentially script your
perfect day what it would look like yeah
what when you have everything as it
should be and for you it might sound
something like this get up in the
morning and walk out into my backyard
and go hiking for an hour come home into
the basement studio that I've produced
that is building remote audiences
throughout the world and artists are
coming to to me through the internet
through this thing in my house that's
located on their mountain in nature
somewhere you see now that may have
never been done that idea may have never
been presented to you but that's
something you can create the problem is
that we when we start imagining the
things that we would like to have done
especially if it hasn't been done before
we don't know anybody who's done that we
start saying out it's impossible that
can't be done right there's no way that
this could happen it goes against the
way it's traditionally done and what I'm
inviting you to do is to ignore that
completely and become so enthralled with
this idea of having both that as you
navigate your life you're going to find
that opportunities show up and you're
going to have the strength and the
courage and the conviction and the
commitment to do certain things and make
certain choices that will ultimately
lead to you having the life that you
want and you know people are going to
say you're lucky people are going to
tell you that you're lucky that you that
you have these things you're lucky that
things worked out the way they did they
is now you have both where most people
have chosen to be a slave to one or the
other or for some reason in their life
they're not fully satisfied you didn't
you're a bit more lucky than those
people what they won't realize is that
you're living on purpose you're creating
a vision for yourself and that vision is
coming true regardless of what other
people say or whether or not it's been
done before you design your lifestyle
first and the design the structure
around which you will bring it forth
good luck