yo Elliot what's up guys got this
question from one of our strength camp
online members Julian since both of my
boys are following in my footsteps I've
been lifting weights with me for two
months now Ali is 15 and Jack is 14
pretty good I'm very proud of them and
they're making some good games but I
want to check to see if I need to be
more cautious with them since they're
not yet fully grown adults you give me
some advice on the matter please so uh
Thank You Julian that's a great question
interestingly enough i began weight
training when i was 14 years old and i
would give you the same advice that I
would give any adult that's training
right now and that is not to get too
caught up into fixed patterns of
training and and this could be with
regard to sports and it could be with
regard to training in the gym because
often times I see these young men come
in here and they've been playing
baseball say for example since there
were seven years old and what I mean by
fixed pattern is that they keep doing
the same movement over and over and over
and over again for seven years they show
up here and they look like this you know
the arm is immediately rotated one hip
is rotated forward and that shoulders
hiked up and then there you know the
parents like well here is he's got it
he's gonna lift some weights and gain
some muscle and I'm looking at the kid
and I'm like.he his biology is a
mechanics or so off because he's been
performing these fixed patterns right
pattern overload doing the same thing
over and over and over and over again to
such a degree that now he has chronic
muscular imbalances he's constantly
getting injuries he's definitely not
performing at his best and I think this
could be averted if all of us should
but the clothes on me if all of us
starting at a very early training age
training age meeting when you start
training integrate and incorporate
multiple ranges of motion into our
routine so if you've got your boys
bodybuilding that's great they should be
building up their muscles getting bigger
and stronger but also include days where
they're doing gymnastics or days where
they're doing yoga that's what I do now
I don't weight train exclusively without
integrating some yoga into my training
about three days a week I do yoga I put
on some yoga videos or some great one on
YouTube and there are some great DVDs
just by a yoga DVD and athletic yoga DVD
fact one of my friends just sent me a
book called real men do yoga and on it
as a professional football player
sitting cross-legged and I think the
reason why real men do yoga is because
it keeps them healthy strong vibrant and
vital without injury and continuing to
progress on their journey without a you
know all the crap that people end up
dealing with in surgeries and whatnot
because of poor training routines so
keep doing what you're doing man I think
it's a fantastic job that you got your
boys training I began training when I
was 14 years old but integrate multiple
range of motion explosive and just
different elements of training into
their routine so don't they don't get
fixed into these these stuff
bodybuilding patterns where they end up
with really tight biceps tight shoulders
and screwed up bodies when they're 25
see what I'm saying man done Elliott's
it what