so what I've got from one of our friends
here is kind of an invitation it's less
of a question but more of an invitation
or sharing of something exciting that
he's discovered I can't pronounce her
name or a young fuck or something like
that but um but anyway our friend goes
on to say that he's discovered what he
has found to be the secret to all
happiness in life and he says he's
studied this is such a great degree with
such fervent excitement that he could
probably write a book on it he says he
searched all the different philosophies
and religions and he has come to this
one thing that would provide us with
great joy and happiness if we could
simply yield to it now when someone
starts talking like that my ears perk up
because these are the things that I look
for because like many of us I struggle
with turmoil I struggle with the monkey
mind I struggle with self-doubt but I'm
always looking for ways and means by
which to avert it and then share it with
other people and and our friend his his
answer is the same one that I've come up
with and that I've experienced many
times over and over again in my life
have used to the greatest of its ability
and completely lost at certain times and
that is silence solitude cutting
yourself off from the noise and the
distraction of the world now I'll talk a
little bit about that but before I move
forward one of the people that I go to
one of my mentors if you will that I
seek advice from when I am feeling loss
is Ralph Waldo Emerson you probably know
this any time I flip open his books I
find peace in his words and this is a
copy of of self-reliance which is one of
my favorite pieces and there's a line in
here that I wanted to share with you
namely our friend who set the question
but Emerson goes on to say that there
are voices in which we hear only in
solitude but they grow faint and
inaudible as we enter the world society
everywhere is in a conspiracy against
the manhood of every one of its members
what Emerson essentially is saying here
is that when we're in solitude we're
allowed to go in as opposed to always
receiving from without and when we can
go within we're allowed to examine the
depths of our heart and our soul and
that's where we'll find many of the
either cobwebs or gems that lie within
so my friend you would probably ask if
it's so if this idea of silence is so
widespread if every religion every
philosophy understands that you need
solitude you need silence you need
moments of prayerfulness and why is it
that everyone's not doing it well there
are a number of reasons first I'd like
to explain myself I found recently that
I'm just way too active and that I need
to cut back slow down and simplifies my
motto for the next several months and
it's simply because I've been so active
in creating that I never allowed myself
the yielding of silence and oftentimes
life just does that to us or we allow it
to do that to us because there are
always opportunities for us to to take
action in directions that we want but we
resisted perhaps the same reason why I
resisted it but to a greater degree most
people resist it is because of the
ugliness they may find on the inside
when you no longer have the input of
society you don't have society telling
you what to do when I say Society I mean
even your friends your family when you
don't have everyone speaking into you
you have no choice but to speak to
yourself and you might find some crazy
shit down there when you're by yourself
and you've got to seek yourself you've
got to speak to yourself because that's
essentially what ends up happening you
might not like what you find you might
start growing agitated irritated
uncomfortable you start looking for
things to do you pick up your iPhone you
start pedaling away at that you go into
the
computer we turn our music you turn on
the television you cannot be by yourself
because the anxiety is a barrier against
the fear that lies within so know that
if you're resisting silence and it is
the elixir for all peace joy happiness
pleasure then it's probably because
there's something that needs to be dealt
with on the inside and the best thing
that you can do is deal with that shit
because if you don't it acts as a cancer
and eat you from the inside out if you
don't go within if you don't seek
silence to go within and you will go
without you will go without joy go
without peace you will go without
pleasure because all those things are
found when we deal with what's inside we
can only deal with what's inside
when we shut off the television shut off
the computer turn off your iPhone stop
talking to people look calling people
we've got to go in and I found that my
most creative work because you'll find
one of two things and usually when I go
in I've gotten past the bullshit
sometimes we have to do that's why I use
bioenergetics it's a way for you to be
by yourself and bring up the cobwebs
bring up the mud so that the purity
inside can be expressed and exposed once
you get past that and don't be afraid of
that don't be afraid of the ugliness
inside you we call it ugly because we're
judgmental we place values judgements on
things but there's nothing ugly about
anger anger is an emotion it's right
it's true let it out it only grows ugly
when you repress it because you don't
look at it
there's nothing ugly about tears there's
nothing ugly about joy sexual pleasure
laughter these are all things that make
us uncomfortable when we see it in other
people simply because we're suppressing
it in ourselves how many times you see a
grown man cry and you feel weird shit
right it's cuz that guy is showing
something that is almost a mirror
reflection of the shit you're holding in
on your own when an adult laughs too
much how many times people get irritated
this bitch won't stop laughing they get
all weird it out she's crazy
no she's expressing she's experiencing
she's
healing she's letting out that which is
within so that she could experience the
purity with it down below that below the
emotion there is a place of calmness
centeredness peace we've got to get past
the bullshit first and in my experience
when you can settle into that peace when
you've gotten out of your own way when
you've dug up the muck the mud and
you've cleared the cobwebs you will tap
into a resource of vast creativity in my
own experience when I can get out of my
own way what I've expressed myself
through exercise or just through
meditation by calming it when I speak
it's not even like I'm speaking because
it's coming from a place that is not
Elliott Hulse it's beyond the
personality it's beyond the character
it's beyond the frustrations the angers
that the things that color my personal
experience as a human being some might
say that it's God speaking through you
you're allowed to say that because when
you get out the way what else is there
so this is really just a conversation
between you and I and anybody else who
thinks it's interesting to talk about
this stuff but yes my friend you are
correct at least in my experience and
the experience of millions over the past
millions of years I can't really say
that because I don't know about how long
we've been here ten thousand million
years whatever the point is that this is
a universal ideal and in the world and
in a time where noise is at a premium
it's everywhere seeking and finding
silence will make that individual a
mastermind amongst monkey minds