Hey earlier today I posted a video on my
other youtube channel where i spoke
about breaking the mold of the older or
weaker version of yourself in order to
allow the stronger version of you to
emerge right and all the resistance
associated with that and i used a
metaphor with regard to imagining that
you were a statue made of plaster or
whatever statues made of and a new
version of you needs to break out of
that and how uncomfortable that might be
physically and mentally and that that's
where most people drop the ball in their
and their evolution towards what they
would believe is a stronger version
themselves one of the things that i
wanted to say in that video that i
didn't was that becoming stronger
version yourself isn't so much about
what you do you know we like to think
that like a stronger version of me will
be doing this or i need to do that in
order to be a stronger version of myself
really which you end up finding is that
a stronger version of yourself requires
that you give things up the hardest part
about becoming the strongest version of
yourself is giving up lower forms of
yourself or weaker forms yourself
whatever that is to you right i'm not
here to judge what's stronger or what's
what's weaker and what that means is
there's going to be a challenge to your
ideologies and ideologies come in very
in many many many different forms
philosophies religions things of that
nature but you have to question if
you've got to ask yourself these
questions and the the biggest ideology
that needs to be challenged is you need
to ask yourself you need to challenge
and ask yourself whether you're willing
to give it up or not is the idea of who
you think you are you say who you think
you are as a manifestation of the
experiences that you've had the things
that you've been told the conditioning
that you receive as a child and the
environment and how they have the people
in your environment respond to you what
they expect of you so when you challenge
Bob or Dave or Dan or Susie or whatever
it is that you're is associated with
your name it's almost like you're your
actual personhood
it is crumbling right the ego structure
that you've developed over the past
thirty years how old you are is being
challenged and it has to break down in
many regards and we become very attached
everyone else becomes very attached to
that version of you and it ends up being
less of a struggle to do more things to
become a stronger version yourself and
more a challenge to give up things that
you believe are an integral part of who
you are especially when those things are
unruly 'its it
you