Wow these are just like tons and tons of
courses and things I've studied over the
years I got rid of like enough to fill
this room I just threw them out because
I just couldn't yeah anymore much to
everything it sometimes this is all of
osho's lectures that you can get on
audio I studied every minute Wow I got a
lot more ocean then I'll show you move
I've got every audio every video every
book every CD or DVD everything Oh show
ever produced they could be bought in
English I bought at all that's fast
studied and extensors and I have been
studying ocean since high school
I Oh shows goodness I just found out the
time you came spent five years with Osho
yeah I've heard that before
here's here's OSHA's books somewhere in
there's all his videos there you go
there's my handwritten notes on osho Wow
really so while watching and listening
these are the notes that you taking yeah
how long have you been studying Osho
probably 7 years 6 or 7 years he's
really delved in and so you
I got about 800 page when I was a day -
you spend studying
I often study while I eat I study while
they train and I studied while I travel
on airplanes so you're listening they're
taking notes yeah when I train I don't
I'm not nearly as aggressive as I was
for a lot of my life just because I
reached the point where I had studied so
many of the real you know nutritious
people mm-hmm
that you just start seeing everything
repeated with its own spin on and run
other words yeah author takes lao-tzu
and chops them up into something else or
you know any of the great writers in any
field right there's only a few key
pillars of knowledge then they get kind
of sliced and diced and so
the Cigna quality gets less and less and
the words get more and more right so you
get further and further away from the
wisdom of the essence and more and more
into the fluff of someone trying to you
know get a pat on the back but
masquerading is you know whoever they
might be but after years and years of
study you just get to the point where
you can kind of like pick a book up and
look at a few pictures and read a few
paragraphs on any topic and know where
that person's act so you end up getting
less and less good books you can read
after a while I realize it's the same
shit over and over and over and over
again so probably by about the time I
was 45 I've reached sort of an
intellectual saturation point and
probably around the time I was 42 I'd
already been really feeling that quite
strongly to sort of started going more
and more into myself right and you know
found myself far more likely to do Tai
Chi or something like that and to sit
there and read another chapter in
another book yeah because I've got
enough intellectual structure and
development that it's kind of like a car
the faster you drive a car the more
horsepower it takes to get another 5
miles an hour out of it right right it
takes a lot it might take 200 horsepower
to go from a hundred to a hundred and
ten but it might only take thirty five
horsepower to go from zero to ten you
follow me go so once you reach to a
certain level of depth of knowledge in
any field you've got to actually work
harder to find the next level of that
knowledge through traditional sources
you have to go right to a master and get
your ass tracked because there's a
certain natural limitation on transfer
from intellectual information to
practical application
right so you can become a coffee shop
expert that can't get anything done
really so once you get to that point
then you got to go out and practice and
do hands-on study but then once you get
to the point where you've integrated all
that really the only thing you can do is
go deeper into yourself and identify
energy flows energy patterns energetic
connections and then look for the
governing systems you know paradoxically
you you actually have to go in to find
the governing says yes you know but
people are so oriented in our culture to
going out something's wrong with my
shoulder Eliot right would you fix it or
what what did I do
right but until you go in and identify
you know what is the the impetus that
keeps leaving a person to have say a
repeated shoulder injury repeated back
injury a repeatedly over train or under
train or over eat or under eat right you
still are really just treating symptoms
right so for me once you get to that
point of intellectual saturation the
next stage you have to go into is
practical application because there
cannot be wisdom without a synthesis of
knowledge and you cannot do that without
experience the only way you can
synthesize knowledge is to experience it
yeah
otherwise it's purely theoretical and
your priors to lost is lost it's just
right
it's like talking about God right it
never gets anywhere because you know if
you're talking about God you're not
talking God you're talking around God
right about things around right so but
once you go into the practical
application and you maintain the
intellectual development then you get to
the point where you can say okay john
doe's ideas about how to centralize the
disc or improve your bench press or
whatever they don't actually work very
well or they only work for a certain
number of people you know maybe with a
certain strength profile or certain body
type
but those are not things or they may not
even be safe for some people right so
you you start finding okay now I can see
what works in theory what works in
practice how it works for then you say
okay well whose also figured that out
and every step you go to whose also
figure that out you see oh you're
climbing a ladder with people that
actually know how to think systems
theory or think you know holistically or
look how things affect each other right
so then you start reading their word
what do you do almost every time if you
follow that trail you end up with
somebody who is sitting in a cage
somewhere and drive a car and have a
bank account who said to stand up tall
bend to bend stand up tall you know and
his name was Confucius from well he just
gave you everything to know about
weightlifting right oh yeah well does
the simplest yes what were we doing that
was I mean it's so funny at such a young
age
I'm 33 I almost feel like it's almost a
waste to spend so much time reading and
studying and not doing and what you do
you realize it is stand up sit down yeah
lie down right yeah well you know you're
it's important for you to follow your
love right but don't follow your fear
button