my awesome friends that watch my videos
you guys are cool so I'm going to go
ahead and open this one up it just came
and I gotta find some scissors maybe
maybe this little keep thinking
hey
I don't use knives anymore to open boxes
because I've got bad experiences with it
huh Oh Mike will spot you yep wonder
what it is hard let's read the card
first the suspense builds thank you so
much so I'm gonna read this later i'll
pick you guys whoa Colleen look at this
unbelievable I just shot and there's
another one in Ralph Waldo Emerson then
I was just saying how much i love to get
more art pieces in fact i just bought a
piece of art from Marvin the guy made
that our friend you want to show that
over there mark I bought a I bought
something way there
for Christmas Wow my friends thank you
so much Manny Cortez art if you got a
website or you guys want to see where he
makes this stuff this is incredible look
as though look dad me and Emerson put it
that mean you're like oh we might have
rain in room bringing a camera and look
real close look at this look how he
decided to make this with like gold
pieces underneath and paint on top
newspaper clippings or something like
wallpaper and marking markers this is yo
you even got your do light color this is
the extreme of creativity blessings to
you my friend lets you see you nanny and
thank you so much for this and thank you
guys for watching this elliott and
filled some really cool stuff that
really cool people send me