so with regard to haters some people are
asking me Elliott what do you do about
haters they see that I've got haters and
they probably have haters also here's
the thing with haters they are providing
a stimulus that you can choose to
respond to either in a resourceful way
or not at all you don't owe anybody
anything but what I would do is to
search your heart first before you
proceed in the rebuttal or deciding how
to go about handling the hate that
you're dealing with because that's the
most important thing and it reminds me
of a story about Martin Luther King
obviously a loved and hated man in
America at one point and he was attacked
in his home someone drove by and shot
bullets into his home and I think he had
about four children living with him his
own children and his wife and people
were shooting into his home haters were
hating and he searched his heart and he
responded by getting rid of all the guns
in his home and his answer for doing
that was that if I'm committed to
non-violence even if violence is
approaching me even if I'm being
violently attacked I want to make my
home my heart so clean pure and free
from the idea of violence that that I
know my sentiment is true I know where
I'm coming from is real I don't know if
I do the same thing but it's an extreme
example of how someone dealt with hate
it's going to happen you're going to get
haters people are not going to like you
for whatever reason people don't like me
for lots of reasons I say things that
offend them make them uncomfortable they
think I'm unqualified to share certain
ideas and that's fine I don't owe them
any explanation I don't owe them a
rebuttal except for times where it may
be resourceful it make clarify you know
there are times when people ask
questions and it's they're just looking
for clarification they're just looking
for
affirmation Elliott are you sure about
this and I responded sometimes people
are just plain rude you know and it's
going to happen to you especially if you
put yourself out there think about
people like Martin Luther King who was
so committed to his mission that even
when violence came his way not just mean
words in comment areas on Facebook and
YouTube bullets flying through his home
and he responded by further cleansing
his own heart these are just ideas
hopefully resourceful to you talk to you
next time
Elliot's it