hey guys just wanted to share real quick
experience with you
earlier this week when I was filming
video answers to the strength training
questions that I get on my Elliot
channel I answered a question from a guy
who claimed to be 700 pounds and he goes
on in his question to describe how
although he 700 pounds he can do full
splits that he's super athletic that
he's in martial arts that he can uh you
know his a boxer and all these crazy
things he's also a massage therapist and
it sounded like a description of a
Marvel superhero apparently there's a
there's a superhero by the name of
jogger not that totally fits this
description so this gentleman sent me a
question that was that seemed as if it
was fake you know that he was
positioning himself as a as a super
villian if you will now I'm not always
the keenest individual you know
sometimes I quite a miss like I'll read
I'd read that question and I thought
nothing of it I had no inkling in my
mind that perhaps this was a joke
question and I'm sure I get Joe
questions all the time I don't think too
much about it I just kind of read the
question if it's interesting I just go
ahead and answer it and that's what I
did and I offered our 700-pound friend
an 11 minute video on all the
perspectives that he could gain based on
the challenges that he's facing in his
life and then I offered him just a few
ideas as to how he may go about to begin
losing weight you know he's had a lot of
traumatic events that caused in the way
to lose gained all this weight and I
showed him how he might be able to lose
it now after posting the video
immediately I got attacked rightfully so
by by many of you were saying Elliot
dude come on did you not know that this
was a troll question which basically
means a fake question did you not
realize like this guy's pulling your leg
there's no such thing as a 700-pound guy
that can do full splits and does martial
arts you know you gave a good answer
Thank You Elliot we all are entertained
by your ideas on health and fitness but
Skai gotcha and I immediately I had to
like think yeah I got got I got got on
this one obviously there's no 700-pound
guide it's doing martial arts and like
kicking people and doing splits right
unless he's a superhero so I you know I
kind of bowed out and said ya guys you
know what I don't always criticize the
questions that I get beyond just trying
to help people when I answer it that's
really all I do is I answer the question
the person sounds like a genuine
individual who I could support if I have
enough the right ideas that might be
able to support them then I offer an
answer I don't know try to judge whether
or not it's a fake question or not well
turns out that our friend actually
exists 700-pound Cain Marko which is the
the actual isn't his actual name his
name's Bobby but that's the name that he
uses and apparently that's the name of
the the juggernaut superhero if you
think I'm kidding let me show you now
there is that's Cain Marko Cain decided
to redeem Elliott Hulse by creating a
video here is when I vomited for 45
minutes three oh my god I vomited so
hard did I gave myself an umbilical free
okay I swear to God I didn't queue it up
to hear about him vomiting out his guts
but anyway that was totally a
coincidence but anyway I'm making this
video just to show you that um just to
share the experience that I thought it
was something cool so that's it I want
to thank Bobby for making the video to
approve the Elliott Hulse is not as
crazy as he may seem and then uh also
just to share a good laugh with all you
guys who thought that the the video was
a troll and and that this guy got over
on me it turned out that it's true
following your balls and following your
heart isn't
risky as it may seem because it's
exactly what I did when I made the video
answer didn't think I just followed my
heart piece