what's up guys today's blog post that
you could read down below is all about
my three steps to guarantee that blind
faith works for you it's not that cut
and dry but you'll see what I mean in a
moment I begin by giving a shout out to
our friend Nick Bundy who watches these
videos reads my newsletter and was
inspired by my non jobs channel that I
created several years ago about
entrepreneurship and helping you get out
of the rat race to start his own
business apparently he's a married guy
or is in the wedding industry somehow
because he makes wedding bands that he
sells on Amazon I know that sounds crazy
but it's because they're not dying
encrusted or you know real hard jewelry
in fact this is what they look like it's
a rubber wedding band now I'm married
and most of the guys at my gym are
married or my coaches and trainers
aren't married so they don't have to
deal with taking the ring on and off
every time they're going to pick up a
barbell and you know it kind of it hurts
your finger or you get chalk all over it
whatever the case may be I always gonna
take my freakin ring off and it becomes
a bit of a hassle so he figured let me
fill the gap in the market place by
creating wedding bands for men who are
athletic if you lift you might want to
run it run rubber wedding bed anyway he
sent me a package containing several of
these different color rubber bands and
by the way you can you can find them on
Amazon like I said just by searching
infinity flex ring but anyway he got it
got me thinking I got this letter in the
mail yesterday and it got me thinking
about a lot of the risks that I
personally took and many of my friends
who own businesses took when starting
their own thing man because it's quite
risky I mean anything that you choose
any adventure that you choose to go on
in life is going to be risky but this
just happens to be one that some of us
choose to throw ourselves into so I
started thinking about how did I choose
to make the decisions that I engaged in
while I was taking those seemingly
calculated but also seemingly
blind risks of quitting my job while I'm
starting a family and all of the
different steps that you have to take
investments that you have to make and
all the challenges you face when trying
to turn some nothing into something
right that's what creativity is all
about so I in my blog post and I wrote
it down here I wrote down my three steps
how to make decisions about things that
you're not sure about how do you decide
on what to do when you've got a vision
but the path isn't very clear right
oftentimes we're chosen with two paths
right you get out of high school you
choose well do I go to the army would I
go to college you you're dating a girl
do I continue to date her what do I
break up with her for this one new one
that I like right there's always these
types of decisions to make and we always
have to go into deep contemplative modes
and engage in activities that associated
that support us in making decisions so
my three steps number one this is where
I kind of bullshit myself it's not
completely blind faith because your
first step is to contemplate yes take
the time right away instantly when
you're not sure what to do the worst
thing you can do is to act spontaneously
in circumstances like this take your
time I say sleep on it and while you're
sleeping on it while you're gathering
data while you're mulling it over I want
you to consider this one question what
is the worst that could happen if I
choose a and can I live with it
and then you ask yourself the same thing
with decision be what is the worst
absolute worst that could possibly
happen if I choose B and can I live with
it I remember when I decided to quit
working at the fitness gym and open my
own why I never opened shit I opened
like my van the doors to my van and
started training people out in the park
several years ago when I begin my
business and I'd asked myself what's the
worst that could possibly happen say
nobody signs up for my classes nobody
hires me as a trainer I've got a home
and I've got a wife and I've got a baby
and I've got another child on the way if
this shit doesn't work out once the
absolute worst that could happen and I
really thought it over you know and I
really decided that the absolute worst
that could happen is that nobody hires
me I don't have any money I will default
on my loans student loans all default on
my credit card loans I'll probably have
to move my family out of my house the
worst that could happen luckily I have a
little bit of a safety net as most of us
do the worst that could happen is I can
send my wife to go live with her parents
or my parents with my baby while I
continue to live in my van and make this
shit work because I wasn't going to give
up no matter what that was the absolute
worst that could happen in fact along
the way a few other steps intervened
there are a few steps that happened in
between and I had to lean on and people
were there to help me make the thing
happen so it never really fell rock
bottom but I set myself up for it I said
what is the absolute worst that can
happen and I painted that picture and
asked myself can I live with that can I
live with my family leaving me to go say
with their family with my parents or her
parents and can I live in my van living
off of rain water and crackers right
that would be the worst then I get
dysentery and have diarrhea that
dehydrates me and my
eyeballs fall out right that might
happen it could happen could you deal
with it the next step after you've
contemplated and dug deeply into the
question whether or not I could handle
the worst that could happen you now have
to choose but you choose with a fucking
sword bang right you do this by creating
a deadline for yourself you say all
right this is enough tomorrow I choose
and when you choose you put your foot
down you take that axe and you chop off
any other options but the one that you
know you're gonna do and that's it no
turning back that's the key once you
make that decision the other half of the
decision the other Appa choices the
other things you could have done you
completely ignore you throw it away you
never turn back and look again because
it'll only make you sick indecisive gray
on the fence and weak you choose hard
that's it they call it burning the boats
there is no back door there's no way
back you jump and then you learn to fly
and that's the third step the third step
is to make your decision right you burn
the boats and you make the damn thing
work right you make it work but there's
a trick to making things work that I'd
like to share with you a magical
perspective a magic wand that you can
wave over the choices that you've made
in order to make them right every single
time without fail successful people
don't make the right decisions they make
their decisions right by always seeing
the silver lining by always seeing what
they've learned along the way by always
gathering all
of the sometimes intangible jewels gifts
treasure that you get when making a
decision and seeing it through so I'll
give you an example a young lady comes
to my gym she moved down from New
Hampshire looking for something new to
do in her life she was very decisive and
decided well I'm gonna move down to
Florida I have some family there there's
the strength camp gym down there I like
to lift I want to get involved in
strength sports I'm gonna make this damn
thing happen along the way I have the
goal of working in a particular industry
this is what her her story isn't it's
what she shared with me and she came
down and things weren't working out the
way she planned right because this is
the thing about making decisions we make
decisions based on what we think should
happen things weren't working out the
way she had planned she thought at this
point you know a few months later she'd
have a career working in an industry but
she loves she was very clear about what
she wanted but it wasn't working out
that way time was running out money is
running out and she's got to go back
home she could possibly and what most
people would do is see herself as a
failure oh woe is me poor me it didn't
work out the way I wanted to do but
instead even though she didn't get what
she signed up for she was able to see
the treasure inherent in making the
decision anyway the fact that she came
down here gave her space to think about
what she really wants in life it gave
her a few experiences to show her more
of herself she engaged in conversations
with new friends was able to see family
and was really able to explore a new
realm of life a new way of being put on
a new hat in order to see is this right
for me
and then she adjusted making the
decision right by seeing the silver
lining so that's it my friends those are
the three steps to guarantee success
through buying faith of course you're
thinking about it do so contemplate
sleep on it number two choose and the
blind faith comes in when you make that
decision and do that turn your back burn
fucking boats and go done