certain we got a question from our buddy
who says that he has no ability to trust
in himself and therefore cannot trust
anyone else he's very suspicious of the
people as if in his environment and he's
also very suspicious of his own ability
to achieve anything
he has no trust and this what he says he
also admits to the fact that he's an
over analyser he likes to call himself a
realist but he's also recognized that it
makes him a pessimist in many ways I'm
happy that you recognize this that form
of self objectivity is critical for
personal development for you to be able
to see that which you hold on to in some
may called a gift is also a curse and
when you're overanalyzing everything and
when you overthink things and you call
yourself a realist oftentimes you're
just a coward a lot of times those who
want to gather more information they
want more supportive ideas they want
conclusive evidence they want research
to back them before they take action are
cowards because Trust has another word
associated with it very closely tied
they're like cousins the cousin of trust
is courage you can't calculate yourself
into trust in the same way that you
can't calculate your self into falling
in love you can't calculate love you
can't calculate an orgasm you can't
calculate trust it's one of those things
you have to yield into you've got to let
go and allow to happen and letting go
and allowing and yielding all sound like
feminine traits feminine qualities and
in our culture and our society we've
been so we're so sexually confused but
one of the things that we've uh that has
damaged the psyche of the man
of the masculine is this rejection of
certain forms of the feminine one in
what in particular is yielding softness
allowing but I invite you to consider
this that it will take more courage more
manliness more effort for you to let go
and yield softly like a woman into the
trust of yourself and others and here's
the thing with trust and it's cousin
courage and I'm gonna I'm gonna I'm
going to lean on that word courage more
because it really is the foundation of
how Trust happens here's the thing about
courage
it is the iron quality for all success
be it personal development becoming the
strongest version yourself relationships
business financial worldly success
success in every regard spiritual
success depends on courage doing the
thing even though you have no supportive
evidence for its path
you have no proof that this man is
trustworthy but you do it anyway you
have no proof that you're going to
succeed in this entrepreneurial endeavor
but you do it anyway you have no
evidence that this is the right woman
for you to call your wife but you do it
anyway and it isn't acting courageously
that you build courage it's a muscle
just like any other you don't get strong
by reading books hoping for analyzing
body building you build muscle by doing
the damn thing I've mentioned this in a
video earlier this week or if you
haven't watched it it's coming up soon
it's called how to get everything for
free it means you got a giveaway to get
you got to do the thing to have the
power my friend so a few things yes I
acknowledge your acknowledgement that
you're way too up in your head and it's
an addiction it's in fact it's an
addiction for our culture we live in a
heady culture we've come to respect only
that which we can tangibly
materialistically reduce here it is it's
a years of here the findings here are
the facts right fuck facts
trust courage now that will take you
some magical places facts will just give
you what someone else figured out
important one
I don't want facts I want experience
because I can carry that with me and
they form virtues like courage
my friend so you've got to get out of
your head and listen you must have some
sort of courage and faith some sort of
courage and Trust because you asked me
your fucking question you must have some
kind of trust in me so trust me when I
give you my advice about how to make
this thing all happen because right now
it's still abstract we're just talking
about it it might be a good idea and
hopefully it touches you at a visceral
level because courage cor cor cor are
the it's the root of our heart our
cardiac system our coronary system the
coronary core courage heart courage
can't be found in your head you can't
analyze courage you can psych yourself
up for courage courage is found in your
body in your heart so you literally have
to get the energy stimulation out of
your physical head you got to stop doing
it and you have reduced attention you
get it back into your body but you got
to drive it that deep down into your
balls gotta breathe into your balls
Eliot tells the answer for everything
because when you soften your body and
you breathe deeply and you get all the
tension out of your head you can access
to something that is of the balls
intelligence
it's called intuition instinct that's
the deepest form of our intelligence and
you also get the courage to trust your
intuition to trust your instinct it's
found in your heart
when you find that you're getting
headaches stretch your neck I'm going to
make I have a video going up on my other
channel on a couple days about
stretching your neck it might be up
already stretch your neck stretch your
jaw these are all muscles associated
with thinking too much
massage your jaw exercise the whole area
in your face so that you can reduce some
of the tension without a little going on
about get looser here you loosen this up
you're all fucking tense when you say
you're in your head it's not a idea it's
not one of those you it's not
metaphysical not out there so where I'm
in my head in something that I might to
think about you are in your head too
much get out of it knock it out ah
physically get out of it massage your
head go get head massages oh you know
you're gonna feel like afterwards oh
also shake your body exercise go run go
jog go walk you've got to move your body
and you got to breathe deeply you should
be sucking wind every single day use
many of the exercises and stretches I
teach you in my videos massage your
belly with the ball lay over the
bioenergetic stool do the bow have
cathartic outbursts where you beat the
shit out of something so that you can
reduce the the anxious tension the
anxiety in your body and in your mind so
you can soften it all up and allow
yourself to be grounded again and your
intuition and in your courage in your
heart it's the way of the world folks
it's the way it's always been done and
we know this because we these ideas not
only show up in our wisdom literature
ancient texts filled with wisdom current
contemporary gurus who share these ideas
but also in our mythology and in our
movies let go Luke
and trust the force Luke Skywalker let
go Luke obi-wan Kenobi says to him
you've got to let go and follow the
force let the force be with you Luke
Indiana Jones in the and the Temple of
Doom I believe he's given instructions
to walk across a chasm a deep chasm an
endless pit to make his way to the other
side where he could receive the goal
whatever he's after some golden fleece
or something the calling is to take
steps across this open chasm but there
are no pathways for him it's an open
chasm but he has to trust he needs
courage to take the first step into the
abyss and if you see him the movie you
know what happens he close his eyes and
steps over the cliff and out of nowhere
a big brick comes up and catches his
foot and he's standing here on one leg
it caught him and then he has to take
the next step
shoot and it catches him it protects him
each step that you take has to be in
faith oftentimes by saying ignore ignore
your ability to analyze but it's only a
part of the puzzle in fact it should be
weighed in equal proportion to pure
courage and intuition do this my friend
because it is the principle because
you're on your way to becoming the
strongest version of yourself and you
need to exercise these things so that
you can achieve that goal
it seems as if it would feel nice to do
these things and in abstract they sound
like good ideas but you must do them you
must become the strongest version of
yourself and you must have courage
do the thing
and you will have the power done