ruined just in question from our buddy
I'm not going to say his name but
essentially he's been probably in the
past he's practiced some really strange
masturbation habits this is basically
says I'm not going to try to visualize
or assume what type of strange
masturbation habits this was but I'm
just going to I'm going to proceed from
a place where I am feeling you probably
jerked off why tomates right and now
you're dealing with a situation where
when you are actually in the presence of
a woman blooded woman his dick doesn't
work now he doesn't have any problem
getting an erection right he gets what
he calls morning wood
he's very sexually excited by women but
when the time comes to lay down the
smack he simply can't get it up or he
goes down and gets it up reaches out and
then recedes and and it's obviously it's
a big problem you know you can't get
into any type of sexual relationship
with a woman because no dick right so
here's here's just a little perspective
for you with regard to how you damaged
yourself right and this may be
resourceful for you or not but when
you're masturbating you're making love
to an image right now you do have your
hand and your hand is warm right you're
you're jerking yourself off but the way
you're able to arouse yourself is based
on a image and idea right either you're
watching it on the screen or you're
thinking about it in your head but there
is no energetic connection there's no
heart-to-heart and there's no real
vagina near you right and the essence of
sexual contact is manifested through a
heart connection that drives itself into
our sexual organs you feel when you fall
in love when you feel sexual this whole
area of your body your heart who swells
up it gets warm
it gets hot you know well that's why a
woman does this oh when she sees a hot
man this hole in your heart swells with
lust with affection and it energetically
and physiologically drives itself into
your sexual organs right these sexual
organs engorged with blood right the
heart brings blood to the organs right
so an engorged palpitating heart filled
with lustful feelings towards someone
aids in the the swelling and the
erections of the vagina and the penis
and and right now your you've been able
to create the hard penis that ejaculate
without the heart connection without
feeling another human being you've done
it with your head so I've often talked
about how you've got you've got three
centers of mind you're thinking with
three brains you got your heart your
head your heart and your balls the heart
and the balls play the biggest part in
our ability to enjoy sexual
relationships with people the head has
nothing to do with sex in fact the
reason why we enjoy orgasm so much is
because the head shuts off and the body
flushes with good sexual feelings right
it floods our entire body Oh
our body gets let go and the reason why
our body can let go and feel so good is
because the head is out of the way you
on the other hand are using your head to
have sex right not that one this one and
and and what you're doing now is you're
carrying it into the situation with
another woman right now so you have
actually have a warm-blooded woman here
which your nervous system is constructed
in such a way that is it it doesn't know
how to respond and cannot receive the
heart the energetic heart connection
that should be available with another
human being right as opposed to the
mental constructs of sexuality so you've
kind of you've twisted yourself up here
solution or an offer an invitation
you're going to have to find a very
empathetic caring woman that is willing
to work with you
right and I can make some suggestions
about how you're going to find that
woman right you literally have to get
out of your head and you got to go and
find a woman that knows how to share
love right and sometimes that's hot
that's that's difficult sometimes the
most loving women are the ones that
fulfill your ego gratification right you
mentioned Long Legs
you really like Long Legs she might be
short fat but if you can receive if
you're sensitive enough to receive the
heart connection with this woman and
explain to her what's going on
and have her work with you as a project
where you're both serving each other
right there are a lot of women there
other people who get off on just helping
people right they like she would feel as
if a she's a mother to you women have
these hormones oxytocin things of that
nature that that made them want to some
women have more of it make them want to
help make them want to help a man
especially a man that's down then you're
down man you're gonna find a half you
don't have to find a woman who is a very
matriarchal woman who has very motherly
feelings that she can have towards you
this all sounds freaking weird dude but
this is this would be my suggestion if I
were you as motherly feelings towards
you and you can yield and soften into
her love and you'll know this is
happening when you're with her dude
chances are she's not going to be that
pretty right she's not gonna be that
gorgeous because it's got it can't be
from your head and if she's gorgeous and
she somehow has a there's a pictorial
connection between what you think is
beautiful and what she she actually is
you're gonna be too tied up in your head
you're gonna get nervous something is
like oh she really needs to be like kind
of homely right and then you need to
yield into her witchcraft of love and
and open up and you got to yield to her
you're gonna have to soften up to her
you're gonna have to become like a
vulnerable little boy in her hands and
then as your heart softens as you start
to get feelings getting problems you're
not
your feelings your open your fucking
head once you start getting in touch
with your feelings right
close your eyes if you have to and you
start to feel her and she's giving you
warm feelings she's sharing her warm
feelings with you you're receiving and
you can give it back to her and you know
you're giving it back to her because
your dick is gonna get hard you'll know
this is happening because you can well
first of all you're Dixon get hard but
pay attention to your breathing you will
be breathing into your balls you'll be
breathing softly you'll be breathing in
a very comfortable fashion take notice
when you're with these other women right
that your dicks just not getting hard
you're probably breathing very shallow
right it's all you you know everything
about what's going on it's energetically
and physiologically based on your breath
breath it's all about fucking breath pay
attention to how you're breathing and
you'll notice that when you're with
these women that you would like to have
sex with but like you mr. happy is just
not working you're breathing pretty
shallow you're not breathing into your
balls but when you find this womanly
woman right you gotta have to go out
there find her bro she's there they're
all there these type of women are always
a must right except they just we don't
see them cuz they don't match up with
our the figment of our imagination but
they're very loving they have a lot of
that oxytocin they want to soften they
want to pet you you're gonna let her
have to let her pet you find her I bet
you she's bet you she's like your
neighbor I bet you she's pretty close to
you but anyway
softened to her and then Harden with her
and you may or may not continue to have
sex with her or you may not have sex at
all but let her have a piece of the
stiffness when it comes up because she
deserves it she's going to give it to
you there's that woman out there that's
gonna give you an erection dude you just
got to find her soften up to her and
then perhaps if you if you can carry
that with you into other relationships
or maybe you just fall in love with her
right maybe that's it maybe you find her
that's it in fact it's my conviction
that if you find the hard connection
with an individual and the dick
connection with that individual right
regardless of what the head says
that's your woman right because you can
you can rest in her you want to find a
woman that you can rest in see these
other women you're trying to be active
with you need to find a woman that you
can rest in and if your heart can soften
and your dick gets hard you can just
rest in her so that's it bro hope that
helps