all right so personal evolution only
happens when there's pressure I mean
even if you look at like cell division
there's always this phase of catharsis
there's always this disturbance within
the organism that is inherent with the
kicking forward and moving forward of a
division the only way you grow is if
there's pressure that's got to be stress
now if weif is really easy for you for
whatever reason if you're living at home
with your parents if you've got a good
cushy job if you're earning enough money
whatever it is that has caused your life
to be comfortable that is the killer of
rope that is the thing that causes you
not to continue to move forward so there
are a number of things that you can do
in order to continue to evolve as a
human being to reach whatever standard
that you've set for yourself right
because it's all very subjective number
one is throw it all away
I've told you stories I may have told
you stories about how artists I think
Picasso would uh was a doughnut Picasso
van Gogh van Gogh would sell all his
shit when he got really comfortable
because when he got comfortable he
wouldn't have the motivation to create
more art so what he would do is he'd
sell all of his furniture he'd sell all
of his goods he'd go live on the street
and then that would give him the impetus
that would cause the stress for him to
go out and create more really really
good art right so one way to move
forward in your evolution is to throw
all the dice just go nuts and just say
boom I got to grow up and then gamble
that's one way it's really uncomfortable
that's a really fast way to do it and
that's a way that's like sink or swim I
do that sometimes or the only other way
that you can do it and this requires a
lot of self motivation this requires
that you are personally motivated enough
to stick with it is to create very lofty
goals for yourself a goal that is
uncomfortable will cause you to evolve
in order to reach it you're going to
do things you're going to have to
participate in things or going out to
give things up in order to reach that
goal so it's only one of two things the
bottom line is you've got to become
uncomfortable you need challenge but
that challenge comes in the form of
throwing yourself off a cliff and then
learning how to fly on the way down or
pointing to the stars and aiming to
reach that shit hopefully you land on
the moon