so our buddy Colton is in college right
now he's 21 years old he's got a
girlfriend
that's 19 they're in the same school
they've been dating for seven months
right and things have been going really
well until very recently Colton is
feeling just annoyed by her now it's
just stupid Seinfeld type shit like you
know the way she laughs the way she
walks the way she talks like all the
shit is like irritating him right your
watch Seinfeld like you can't date none
of them in Moore George they just can't
date anybody without like nitpicking
like the way they eat or their big hands
all that crazy shit so you know what I'm
talking about but anyway all this little
dumb stuff is starting to irritate him
he realizes that this is like it was
crazy why am I getting so upset with her
now he's got some priorities that he
wanted to make very clear through this
question number one is doing well in
school number two is his music I think I
have this in the right order pursuing
his music goals work and then the
girlfriend right this is just you know
where he is in his life you are in this
sprint time of your life right now right
you're going 21 years old like you just
did you just came out the cage right you
just turned 21 you can only just buy a
beer now so the cage is open and you're
ah get out right and there are things
you wanted you're scrambling to get get
together I totally get it I remember
this this stage you should you're
scrambling to get all your shit right
you need money need to get it this
College thing down pack and you need to
develop your hearts calling which is
your music and you got a girlfriend
here's the thing the nature of the sexes
right and and this is what I'm about to
share with you is going to shed light on
why she's she's starting to irritate you
and why you're thinking about breaking
up with her right whether you break up
with her or not
is neither here nor there but this
perspective is going to help you and a
lot of people are going to like this
perspective the nature of this sex is
the nature of the sexes are evident in
the sexual organs the penis is an organ
that
requires the organism to develop a
charge have so much of a charge that it
reaches out right that's what an
erection is you get your body gets
charged up direction right and then
looks for a place to discharge that's
what the penis does and that's what the
nature of men do this is why there's so
many wars and so many corporations this
is why there's so much art and so much
destruction because we can't sit still
we're there looking for life but fuck
these people let's build this right
we're out there just like a gun that why
do you think they call it firearms we're
out there and we're doing shit that's
just the nature of man it's neither good
nor bad it's just what we do then nature
right and that's our priority it's
always our priority I have a large
family we just got a fucking cat another
female right I've got three daughters a
wife a fucking cat and my son and my
priority is still building my charge and
attacking the world not that my family
comes second or there's any particular
order that you know is unrest or school
to me to be being able to take care of
my my things
you know what I've created but I haven't
dampened that like most men dampen that
women cause men to dampen that right you
become less of a man the more or family
you have simply because your
responsibility you're discharging in her
and that's the nature of the vagina
she wants you to discharge in her the
vagina goes in the woman is the nature
of the female isn't to go out right we
built we have a very male-dominated
world where women are taught at very
young age you need to go out be a dick
but the nature of the vagina is to
absorb the nature of the female is to
soften and yield and to bring in and
this is beautiful
this is life creating right once not
better than the other we just been
taught once better than the other
because there's more outward
manifestation of what the penis creates
and destroys as
pose what happens inside the woman but
sexually and energetically women will
suck you dry am I talking about blowjobs
I'm talking about she wants you to not
only insert your penis but she wants a
big chunk of your energy that's what
women want they want a man to drive
their energy into them and she has
become just one more of the things that
you're reaching out towards and it's a
dream female or a dream they'll drain
you energetically physiologically and
physically right if you're fucking all
the time or drained physically and
physiologically and energetically she
wants your time she wants your energy
she wants your love why don't you call
me why don't you look deeply in my eyes
anymore right because she wants you and
your growing resentful because she's
asking a lot the interesting thing about
women also is that they will come to
resent you if you give yourself all to
them right a lot of women are watching
this and you could either agree with me
or disagree but this is just a poetic
stance that I'm offering that I promise
you is resourceful right if you give
yourself all over to them right women
women don't want a man asleep just all
into them right she's too into me women
will say cuz he doesn't have enough of
his own shit he's not playing music like
you he's not creating stuff he's not
getting good grades in school he's not
working women love a man in uniform you
know why cuz that motherfuckers doing
something she wants you to go do
something and she needs to come to
understand and perhaps you can talk to
her about this right other shit that I
tell you guys no one else talks about
and I hope you can then take it and you
can talk about it share with her look
babe I want you to understand that I
very warm feelings towards you I might
even say that I love him but you got a
hang tight while I do my thing I told
this to my wife when I was 16 years old
right I didn't married when I was 16 but
I was like I told her a very young age
when we were badly in love I said look
if you wanna hang out with me it's going
to be a bumpy ride
like I'm not if you marry me if you want
to stay with me for the rest of your
life that's fine but you're going to be
in for a bumpy ride because I'm going
somewhere and I'm doing some shit do you
want to tag along
cool I'll do the best that I can to
support your female needs by helping her
create a family have a home is what
women want women want the family at home
men we want to go out it's our nature I
told her I'll do the best that I can to
support her but I'm moving baby and
that's why we have such a strong sexual
relationship to this day because I'm a
man and I'm out there and I'm doing shit
she wants you to do that if you don't do
that she will grow resentful towards you
she doesn't want all of you she thinks
she does right and she will do all she
can to draw you in to be greedy with you
but if she gets you all did she'll grow
resentful towards me so just be frank
with her Hey look babe and this is going
to come across this not this is going to
be uncomfortable to deal with and it's
just a story it's a perspective that
I've used and it's gonna sound strange
coming from a guy who always says think
from your heart and balls I just invite
you down into your heart and balls but
the three need to be balanced speak to
her if you can if you feel like there
you may have a future with her right I
don't know you know you might end up
with 40 different women or you might end
up with four I don't know you know it's
all about what you want if you see a
future with her sit her down talk to her
like I just offered you about the nature
of the sexes and look babe you know I
I'm gonna do everything I can to support
you but I'm going out right even said
that I go out she can't because she's
sick Almighty look at the metaphors
explain that to her and then use your
head by observing the type of person she
is type of character she is and if she
has everything that you need
or you could foresee as they need for a
life partner later on then you make a
contract with her either you know make
it maybe with it just yourself you think
about it this way but it's like I'm
gonna go out and gonna do my thing but
because you are like Scottie Pippen to
my Michael Jordan I'm gonna keep you
around because I could see how you're
gonna help me build some more shit right
sounds like you're using her but and you
are because she's using you also we use
each other right to fulfill those sexual
roles those pop that polarity we need
the men and women we need each other
right
so you're gonna use her to help you
create what you want to create my wife
watches all my videos so she's watching
this right now and she knows that I use
her because when I started dating her
very young age I realized damn she's
good at taking care of children she's
really good at keeping the house clean
she likes to cook
she likes to support her man and growing
stronger and we have great sex this is a
good move if you see that with her then
use this it's a good move there's
nothing wrong with that you know we like
to think of it as narcissistic no it's
pragmatic it's practical is she going to
be a good wife the type of wife that you
want to help you fulfill your vision of
what a life should be you're the creator
the father father creator male we insert
it to the female that brings life all
right now I'm being too much of a poet
you get what I'm saying dude so that's
it man whether you break up with her
maybe she's just not you know maybe
gotta break up with her but these are
just ideas that you're going to need me
to use for rest of your life with regard
to dealing with women so that's it bro
good luck