you got this question from our 23 year
old buddy Josh my whole life I had
little or no self-confidence never had
an official girlfriend I've only been
with three girls in my whole life
since September last year I've joined a
gym I've lost 60 pounds I feel great I
thought it would help me become more
confident to talk to girls but it really
hasn't helped very much I realized when
I go out to the bar and I see a girl I
want to talk to I can't get the courage
to go and talk to her I freeze up don't
know what to say but by the time I do
grow the balls to talk to her I'm so
drunk I can't say anything haven't I had
more self-confidence okay I've got some
ideas for you before I am before I move
forward I want to give a shout-out to
Tyler RSD who's got a YouTube channel
and and he's it's called real social
dynamics
that's what the rsd stands for Tyler
Durden thinks he calls himself and he's
got some pretty cool videos that are all
about how to build up the confidence to
speak to girls and much of what he talks
about it's very similar the things that
I talk about in these videos and has to
do with the energetic processes going on
within it he calls it the inner game but
you've got like an inner game that you
got to deal with that means more than
the flash on the outside see you lost 60
pounds that's kind of on the outside
there are guys that are 60 pounds
overweight that just chicks dig because
their inner game is solid and and that
all revolves around the stories you tell
yourself the state that you put yourself
in are you using bioenergetics like I
teach you do you meditate the way I tell
you to meditate or using these different
forms of self-talk that support a way of
beating that's resourceful for the thing
that you want to have happen in your
life it's all about the inner game guys
the the body your outward expression is
merely a manifestation of the evolution
or lack thereof of your soul who you are
on the inside and then this gentleman
gets it so I would invite you to check
out some of his videos now the piece of
advice that I want to share with you the
idea that might support you in this
particular situation and that will
support all people who have goals
because that's really what it is you've
got a particular goal 23 years old and
you might want to get laid and you might
want a girlfriend
my I would invite you to think more
about like how can I get a girlfriend
how can I find a woman that that
appreciates me loves me I could share
myself with her she shares herself with
me and we can enjoy our life together
doesn't mean you gotta get married or
whatever the case might be but someone
that you could share your life with we
all want someone to share our lives with
you know be it friends or you know
girlfriends wives male so whenever you
set a goal ahead of yourself and this
has just been my experience there's
always anxiety associated with the
distance between where you are and where
you want to be right there's this space
between your desire the thing that
you've thought of and the actual outcome
and that's riddled with all types of
anxiety stemming from what is the
process going to look like at what's
gonna happen when I say hello and so on
and so forth is she gonna throw a drink
in my face what if she thinks I'm a dork
like all these things associated with
the process the anxiety of the process
what is it going to look like if I quit
my job how am I gonna start up this
business I have no idea how how that's
really big part of the problem we're
very caught up in at how society we
think that how is the most important
thing how is it always always the most
important thing doing the thing is the
most important thing and how often comes
after how is very subjective in many
situations meaning I could give you step
one two three and four but that's my
step one two three and four your step
two one two three and four might be very
different don't ever look for some other
people's house in order to adopt them so
that it's it's the only one now you can
use other people's house to kind of get
the ball rolling but you got to find
your own how that's part of the pain
that you're inevitably going to
experience but too in the process of
getting where you from where you are to
where you want to be I see a hot girl I
want to go I want her to ultimately now
here's where the other piece of anxiety
comes from I want and now you could see
yourself snuggling with her in front of
a fire and sharing presents at Christmas
time
and kissing her and rubbing her body and
having sex with her and holding hands as
he walked through the park and go to the
beach and giggling with one another and
then you know like in TV when you're
both running at each other like this and
she's coming at you and you're coming at
her and you hug like all that all that
shit that goes to our head when we're
feeling romantic ah see now you you
built up a fucking picture
that needs to be fulfilled that needs to
be manifested otherwise as soon as a
part of you knows it that's not that
that's a there's a possibility that that
won't be the case and then there's
anxiety there too so this whole idea of
setting goals or having aspirations in
any particular direction be it with
women or with your business with school
with with sports with weightlifting
whatever it is energizes you but could
also create anxiety okay so what you
will need to do when I invite you to do
meditation helps us also because you're
less entrapped by your thoughts when you
meditate what I would invite you to do
is don't think about what you want when
you see this woman get it out of your
mind completely because it's going to
it's going to dictate to you it's gonna
you're going to become a slave to your
desire talk to her simply because you
want to talk to her and that's it take
everything else off the table completely
don't have any expectations for where
it's going to go begin the process and
then ride the wave the best way to talk
to someone is to ask them questions they
go up to her and you ask you know one of
the best ways to approach people also is
to be completely transparent come be
completely transparent
hey I don't I don't normally do this but
I thought you're a pretty girl and I was
wondering
where'd you buy that beautiful dress
because I want to get one for my sister
ah that's a good one right I want to get
it for my sister's now you're a nice guy
hey I don't normally do this but I
thought that was a beautiful dress and
it all it looks awesome on you
I'd like to get one for my sister would
you get it oh I got it here such and
such such and such at this website oh
really
I like websites I'm being a dick like
I'm totally like making fun here but the
point is continue to ask her questions
how did you find that oh how did you get
into that type of style Oh what do you
do for a living oh do you wear that kind
of dress when you go there oh I bet all
the guys in the office think you're
really hot oh and you get in you you
engage in the process the slippery slope
of the particular process be focused on
the moment be focused not so much on her
because that becomes creepy also you
don't be that creepy guy focus on the
conversation and let the conversation be
the guiding force of your of the
evolution of that relationship with her
it would start if it starts to shave off
like it seems like well we're not
getting anywhere or she's not really
interested in you look you have nothing
invested dude especially your heart you
didn't invest it because you didn't set
up set yourself up with these grand
ideas about running towards her in a
field and hugging her right so there's
nothing to lose whenever you engage in
the direction the journey of a
particular goal you your unconscious
mind knows that there's a particular
goal don't build don't paint too strong
of a picture about what it should look
like don't get so caught up in what you
should do to get there move in the
direction of your dream move in the
direction of your desire be aware as
you're taking each step along that place
don't think too much about the end
result this is crazy right because most
people tell you have goals think about
the end result don't invest in the end
result invest in the process and the
process is revealed as you move along
remember it's all practice Ralph Waldo
Emerson says that all of life is an
experiment the more you make the better
every girl you talk to is annex
ermand right you don't want to take it
is to see many guys will will take it to
such a degree that like you know she's
just a piece of meat you know and then
they're coming from a place of lack of
respect for the human being that's never
good
you understand that I'm being drawn
energetically and physically towards you
let's open up a dialogue and rec don't
be so attached to it that you can't see
that well this is practice because if
she rejects you you're going to try it
again
don't be invested in the result you
didn't get what you wanted
and that's okay but you learned
something you always learn every single
time you do it you learn something till
you get really good at it you talk to a
hundred girls trust me we should make
that your goal talk to my hundred girls
and you will become the type of guy that
can talk to girls do the thing and
you'll have the power done