that's Bob Marley song that I'm
listening to as I Drive my children to
school
I think it's called brainwashing and it
almost brought me to tears not because
of the words of the song but because of
how the melody went hummed creates a
vibration in my heart it breaks up the
bitterness breaks up the rigidity
associated with the pain
holding the heart back the heart wants
to be let free the heart is consistently
broken and imprisoned by
the head which is a tool used by
civilization to control us so if you
haven't figured it out right now I'm
feeling a bit schizophrenic a bit torn a
bit broken off from the connection my
head heart and gut should have maybe I'm
just sensitive maybe I'm just
sentimental but I assume that many of
you go through the same thing you might
not have the words to put to it or look
at it as abstractly as I do we refer to
it as poetically as I do but I know it's
there because we all suffer all of our
hearts suffer the world that we live in
the Empire that we're all a part of
whether we like to be a part of it or
not whether we've chosen to be a part of
it or not damages the heart damages the
soul and we sacrifice ourselves for a
game that we didn't choose to play very
careful with that word choose because a
part of me believes that the spirit
chooses the body and the time in which
the body will play this game of life on
earth perhaps we've played other games
at other times but right now my soul
your soul has chosen to play this game
at this time under the dictates of this
Empire game and when I say Empire a
little literally mean Empire I mean this
world global domination by a small
percentage that you might refer to as
the oligarchy
that set up a system that imprisons the
soul so that the physical body of each
human being can work as a battery to
fuel their system to fuel their desires
to fuel whatever their designs may
ultimately be and again I don't say this
as a victim I say this because it's
important to look at this objectively to
see what this all really is it's just a
game and movies like The Matrix and Star
Wars and even recently The Hunger Games
Movies shed light on this idea of course
in a cinematic way but if you really sit
back and pick apart what's actually
happening here you can see the parallels
and then there's the guts my gut the gut
is the part of the brain part of the
mind if you will that is concerned only
with survival so you've got the head
that's tethered to the game of Empire
success making your way making money
and all that's associated with that we
need cars to drive we need houses to
live in when he clothes to wear food to
eat many of these things are also
considered a part of what it takes to to
have loved because tribal association is
an intrinsic part of what it means to be
a human being at its core according to
Maslow its hierarchy of needs safety and
survival is the only thing that trumps
our desire to be a part of the whole to
be a part of the tribe Association to be
accepted by all and others and none of
us are free from that I often talk about
not caring what other people say and
being yourself regardless but it's not
an easy thing especially when you live
in the belly of the beast
Babylon you live in the Empire live in
civilization
you want to be accepted because tribal
association is a deep human need
and survival is so closely tied to this
human need for tribal association
because if the tribe doesn't accept us
we have the potential to be outcasts by
the tribe and and in many ways that's a
death sentence is to be outs about caste
by our tribe now we can rationalize all
we want about the way things are today
but our DNA and our ancestry comes from
a place where human beings lived with
each other and saw each other not as
separate entities but is a unity as
different cells in a single organism to
be cast out or separate from the rest of
your tribe is a is a death sentence in
many way because we need each other
we've needed each other for survival so
here you have a split between the head
ie Empire civilization the game that we
play the heart which really desires
union community love oneness with one
another
and survival
that is dominated by our body or our
reptilian brain gut and here we stand
and this is what we do and this is where
we are and this is what we have to work
with as we make our way through the game
and know also that we have choices about
how to play this game but it will always
be difficult because there will be that
rejection if you to truly be honest with
your heart you're going to have to break
it because to be who you want to be in
many times pushes away those who you
like to be with there's no answer for
this I have no answer for this I just
share this with you to let you know that
these are the ways that I look at the
circumstances of my particular life with
hopes that perhaps my lamenting my
musing in this way that's some of you
know that you're not alone if you feel
the same way perhaps I can put words to
what you're experiencing but didn't know
that you weren't alone that there were
others
you're not alone and I know I'm not
alone
but we've got to be courageous we've got
to be courageous in honouring ourselves
because as we honor our own hearts as we
trust our own instincts as we rein in
the power of our own head brain to
calculate our ability to proceed in this
world in this Empire in this
civilization from our heart and from our
instinct to me is the most resourceful
way to play at this and it's a daily
struggle it's a battle
but the gut also in its desire for
survival means that it'll do whatever it
has to do to get by and to survive maybe
not always thrive but to survive this
world
perhaps the thriving will come in future
generations because of the words perhaps
that I share the words that many other
poets writers thinkers artists musicians
share that give hope to those who will
come before after us
done