I got a question from our 17-year old
friend here who says he's falling into
deep depression no girlfriends and no
friends there's nobody to talk to
essentially what he says is that he's
been trying for many years since high
school and obviously is out of high
school now to fit in with people and he
just finds that everybody that surround
that he might perhaps fit in with are
not only disinterested in the things
that he's just he's interested in but
they're also interested in a lot of
things that he has absolutely no desire
to do like what he says it's drinking
and partying you know there are people
that find that fascinating to him he's
just like I just can't do it but in
order to yield because that's what human
beings do in order to to deal with one
another to enjoy one another he yields a
little bit and he says okay well you
know some of these guys invite me to go
out and I do engage I drink and I and I
do the things that I need to do but
still there's no connection there with
them in fact everybody mocks him and
calls him grandpa they says he's kind of
like old and meaning that the things he
likes the things he wants to talk about
things that interests him the things
that disgust him are kind of old man
like you're 17 fucking years old
so obviously this makes him very upset
things aren't going the way he liked
them to go anyway he wants to know
what's wrong with him he can count and
he finishes up like this what's wrong
with me I can count on one hand the
amount of people that I can truly call
my friends the thing is most of them are
adult ache the time to know me are
adults and he says this is driving him
nuts what should he do I don't have any
friends what's wrong you know I almost
as I'm reading your question I'm already
starting to think about ways to gain
perspective for yourself in order to see
that it's okay that you don't have quote
unquote friends and I was going to go
down the route of you know certain we're
all born into life with a certain with
very different capacities for maturation
we grow up older and some of us grow a
lot
in this time that we're here on earth
based on whatever circumstances they
were surrounding your birth you know
wherever you came from on the spiritual
plane whatever the circumstances are
with your parents and then you know up
through your early childhood determines
your capacity to a very good agree and
some of us you know me I'm using this
just as an example you know being
facetious are born to mature into wise
old men and some of us are born to
mature into twelve year olds in an old
man's body just what it is and and
you're going to receive that for what it
is and see that we're all different
appreciate people for what they are and
then find those who can be attractive
you're attractive to you and you could
be there's attraction going on but then
you go on and you finish your question
you say that I have enough friends to
count in one hand well my friend first
of all if you have one real friend see I
call you my friend but I'm not your
fucking friend I make videos but if you
can count on one hand the amount of
people that take the time like you said
to get to know you well embrace you and
move through life joyously with you
ie a friend then you are one blessed
brother you are so lucky because it is
rare to find a single person that will
care to get to know you in that
particular way that you can actually
call friend you see we do have
acquaintances and there's nothing wrong
with acquaintances but acquaintances are
in a way like flings just you know like
people who have sex you know we do that
planes you know the sports X as opposed
to people who become your life partners
and I use that term plural II partners
these are people that we embrace each
other on an energetic level our hearts
come together not just our genitals and
in your case not just our hanging out
you know talking in bullshit heart
connection and dude to go through life
and to have found at least one heart
connection with another individual means
that you are so lucky and I will invite
you to look at a few things number one
be grateful for the amount of wisdom
that you have at such a young age such
that it pours out of your character and
what they call the old man they call you
an old man be grateful for your
situation it is it's a good place to be
in a world that is lacking that maturity
that's lacking wisdom because you will
be a beacon on to many and the other
thing is I invite you to take delight
full delight in the one or two
friendships you do have because your
outpouring of aggravation anxiety
frustration and what you call depression
is a leak of energy it is a waste of
your energy that could be going towards
deepening your relationship with the
older more mature people that appreciate
you your character and spending time
with you I'm done