hey what's up guys I'm here in Berlin
Germany many of you guys know that I'm
participating in a 21-day Osho dynamic
meditation camp that's put on by my
friends
Christina Locke and Ali von stein at
their Osho studio here in Berlin and if
you live anywhere nearby anywhere in
Europe I totally invite you to come in
check them out they've got programs
running every month for you to come and
do 21 days of dynamic meditation they do
Kundalini meditation and they do all the
various active meditations that were
brought to us by Osho the thing is that
there aren't too many places in the
world where you can do this and I was
lucky enough to meet Kristin and Olly
over about 15 years ago in New York City
when they had their studio there the
purpose of my newest project grounding
camp is to bring Osho active meditations
and bioenergetics to the world so if you
can't make it to Berlin don't you worry
a grounding camp will be coming to a
city near you
and over the course of the next few
years the intention is to have an
opportunity for anyone worldwide who
wants to participate in Osho active
meditations to do so it's that powerful
and I am a campaigner meaning anything
that I find in my life that is of great
value I intend to share it with you I
did that with strongman training I did
it with corrective exercise I did it
through my yo Elliot videos I did it
through all the advice videos I've given
you my job is to take what helps me and
share it with you well anyway today
during our dynamic meditation there is a
section in the meditation where you are
to steep yourself in stillness those you
who are not familiar with dynamic
meditation there are five stages the
first two stages are about charging the
body with breath and catharsis movement
all kinds of spontaneous movement sounds
dance
shouting shaking whatever it is
that is coming up in your body really
tracking the energy in your body and
allowing these things to process in a
safe contained environment after that
stage the third stage allows you to sink
into stillness and is during this
stillness portion of the dynamic
meditation that often times there are
insights that I receive and one was the
arch of awareness and I know that you
there's a lot of talk about being aware
and awareness and you know these
meditative terms that are growing in
popularity because we are waking up and
people are becoming more aware but there
may be some confusion about where to
begin with awareness what the heck does
that actually mean I'm aware a siren
went off I hear it somewhat there's a
beautiful woman walking by I'm aware of
her well those are all external
circumstances all external stimuli true
awareness begins on the inside now that
can also be confusing because when I say
awareness begins on the inside
oftentimes we go immediately to our head
to be aware of what's going on in our
thoughts is powerful but to be steeped
in our thoughts is a distraction
most of our thoughts are also an outside
distraction because they aren't our own
thoughts if you listen to yourself for a
moment you'll begin to realize that
those thoughts come from other people
they come from media they come from
conversations you've had with others the
place to really begin with stillness and
awareness is which what's going on in
your body take a moment right now and
notice where you may be holding some
tension right we're very unaware most of
us very own conscious of how we are
holding our bodies how oftentimes we
have our shoulders hiked up and we're
not even aware that we're doing it
clenching the jaw not aware that we're
doing it
your fists tight not aware that you're
doing holding the belly in not aware
that you're doing it notice your feet if
your energy drawn up out of your feet
and it almost feels like your legs
aren't there or is there so much tension
in your feet that you're not even aware
that you're cramping your feet up in
your shoes curling your toes up begin to
be aware of how your body is responding
begin to be aware of how you're using
your body in an unconscious way now I
mentioned earlier that the dynamic
meditation requires that we charge the
body first and then release through the
cathartic phase well if you're having a
hard time noticing the sensations in
your body noticing the tensions in your
body noticing where you may have a lack
of energy in your body it may be because
you need to be charged up a little bit
more so if you're having a difficult
time begin with breathing just become
aware of how you're breathing you can be
very deliberate about it by choosing to
lay down on your belly and belly for on
your back and belly breathe by raising
your belly and dropping your belly
thirty to fifty times begin to notice
how there are shifts taking place when
you do that all right you know in the
beginning it might feel sets and cycles
and then over time you might find that
that breath begins to open you might
also notice where the blocks are that
are not allowing you to breathe as deep
as you know you could be if your
muscular system wasn't getting in the
way and you can do things like foam roll
or myofascial self release or corrective
stretching to support yourself in those
areas that things we locked up and
blocked so anyway I wanted to share this
with you today awareness and the art
thereof begins with attention to the
sensations in your body
[Music]