are we glad question from our buddy Gino
who was dating a girl for five long
years and a year ago he decided to break
up with her because he felt that he
needed to grow stronger on his own
without her had nothing to do with being
a bad relationship he just felt that it
was necessary for his personal evolution
to move on this was a year ago he came
to find he says just yesterday one of my
best friends confessed to me that he's
starting to fall in love with Gino's
ex-girlfriend right and this is fan this
it's totally fair play she is fair game
for lack of better terms but a scent and
your friend is being honest with you
he's coming is he confessed and he says
look man I know this is your
ex-girlfriend apparently they've been
talking or whatever the case may be and
he's got more feelings towards her
there's nothing wrong with this but it's
nothing wrong with it here right you
could lovely it's logical okay you broke
up with her she's there they're together
and that's fine here it's okay logically
it's fine this is one of those times
when Elliot the head heart and the balls
have to be aligned and sometimes one
serves you better than the other but you
got to know how to keep them working
together in concert the mind can
rationalize and sometimes you've got to
do that sometimes you've got to tell
yourself a story rationalize the
situation I think you have right the
problem now is your heart and your balls
your heart the heart and the balls are
saying okay I agree I'm pissed off
you're feeling lonely were some of the
descriptive words that you used angry
depressed frustrated and lonely
self-doubt hatred it doesn't know how to
cope with this that's your heart in your
balls that's the animal part of you that
had that that's the emotional part of
you the feeling part of you the part of
you that this guy is somewhat detached
from but he is going to be a better
servant for you in this particular
situation you've got to rationalize and
I'm sure that you can do this here's the
thing now we want to tie the heart and
the balls back into where the mind is
going you see the mind is a very good
tool right now that you need to use in
order to manipulate what's happening
or body this is gonna sound very strange
right may sound strange to some of you
this the others of you have both sound
that strange I'm going to invite you to
number one get out all of your heart's
longings and promptings with them then
go to your friend and say look before I
spill all this out on you we're best
friends right and before I share any of
this with you I want you to know that I
support I support the head-- supports
what you're doing with my ex girlfriend
because it's alright it is alright but I
have some hurts in my heart that I want
to share with you don't ask him to
engage in a conversation about it and
you don't need to engage in a
conversation about it all you need is
the catharsis all you need is to get it
out it's not right it's not wrong but
it's in your heart if he if he starts
trying to help you rationalize that this
is not the time for it it's not the time
for actualization - time for catharsis
he's your friend and I believe he's your
friend he's going to appreciate he's
going to be there he may think it's
weird at first but that's why you
prefaced it the way you did when you
start letting this all out on him
right because you both have to deal with
it you're best friends she's there it's
like a weird love triangle right the the
best way to deal with most situations
relationship situations that we have is
through honesty it's getting it all out
on the table and you're doing just that
but again that purpose is very important
I'm not trying to ruin the situation
with you and her these things are in my
body and I have to get them out and I
need your help in allowing me to do it
with you right and you may I don't know
what your relationship is with her but
I'm assuming at this point you're closer
to your friend then you were with her I
don't know you might want to do the same
with her catharsis get it out with no
intention to manipulate or change the
situation for them explain that to them
I don't want to change what's happening
I just feel I need to get this out right
that way you soften the burden on your
heart you soften the burden on your body
right because right now you're holding
it in your 10
you are growing you're stewing with this
shit and if you don't get it out and you
don't get it at another resourceful way
then it's going to turn into something
ugly it's gonna manifest itself in all
types of physical physiological and
energetic fucked up shit that you don't
want to deal with that's number one
you've got to get it out catharsis
hopefully you can do it in a safe
situation with your friend the second
thing that you have to do and this is
the one that's going to sound some
strange to some people and like dove to
other people you're going to need to
pray for them
pray for their happiness pray for their
relationship pray for their joy bring
good vibes good feelings extend good
energy in their way this way you're not
only softening the burden of your heart
but you're aligning it with your mind
when we pray we literally take the
concrete ability of our mind and we tie
it to our hearts that's what prayer is
prayer has more of a personal
transformative effect than it does
outside of us and really we are the
energetic magnet for what happens
extrinsically
in our lives so this the stronger you
are the stronger the tie between your
head in your heart the better things are
going to show up around you that's the
power of prayer is the fact that it
changes your energy and energy vibrates
and does shit that we don't even
understand outside of us all over the
place right that's that's four totally
different quantum physics talk right
spiritual / quantum physics like there's
this shit that just happens that we
don't understand vibrations and waves
and particles that are just popping and
flipping all over the place right but
how do we manipulate that through our
own meditation through our own prayer
through the alignment of our own energy
and
lining with the type of feelings that we
want which are good feelings and you're
going to line up your head with your
heart or vice versa line up your heart
with your head because the head knows
this is okay the heart is still feeling
line it up with the heads intention
through prayer and extend good feelings
their way whatever happens with them is
up to the universes up to God has
nothing to do with you any longer you
made peace with it you passed on her you
gave her up this is your friend he's
allowed to have feelings towards her
get all the emotional shit out and pray
for their goodness because that goodness
is going to make its way back to you