so our friend Renzi was uh when he was
in high school he was obese really
really fat overweight sick had a high
chance of getting type 2 diabetes and
during that time he lost some friends
good close friend him passed away also
family members passed away so he was
sick
fat depressed sad lonely and what he
calls the laughingstock of his school
this was a couple years ago back in a
2010 I think and he was in the bottom of
the barrel the worst it could possibly
be and he's still a bit you know several
years later and still has a lot of
resentment and ties to those experiences
but an amazing thing has happened he's
transformed himself he's lost 110 pounds
he is getting ready to do a bodybuilding
show interestingly he went from being
the laughingstock of his old school to
now where he's in school and he has a
ton of other guys coming up to him
wanting to be more like him right there
asking him how is it that your muscles
look so good how is it that your body is
developed in such a way that you're
gonna go and compete as a bodybuilder I
want to do that too please what's her
name again
Renzo Reni help me out not only that but
ready is being approached by women all
over the place
fat sick depressed kid that nobody likes
and is the laughingstock and his friends
and family are dying all around him too
now having the admiration of his peers
and women are flocking to his side the
problem is that he still doesn't see
himself as he presents himself he still
sees himself as that big thick fat
depressed kid that nobody likes I
totally understand I know this sounds
weird a lot of people watching this will
be like dude what is your problem man
you're you're in good shape now and
women want to talk to you and you're
still complaining like you're a sick fat
kid what's up
I could tell you and the reason why I
took your question is because I've
experienced the exact same thing now the
context is the same but the content is
different and and it's been a challenge
for me and what I'm talking about is
coming from being deeply in debt broke
like can't put gas in the car
really poor huh right just you know five
six years ago to now where I can
comfortably say that I have the things
that I need I can spend money on nice
things today right but I've had a
difficult road not only in digging out
of the debt and the destitution that I
came from but in accepting it when
things started turning good things
started getting good for me right in the
same way and I'm using this is in
contrast to your story this thing
started getting good for me
in other words like I didn't have to
worry about how I'm going to pay the
bills in fact I've got extra a lot extra
left over at the end of the month
probably about eighteen months ago you
know but a year and a half ago things
started getting good and that's when the
anxiety came in that's when I started
worrying that's when I didn't feel good
about myself anymore I knew who I was
when I was broke but now I'm confused
that or you know about that time I
started getting confused and I spoke to
a good mentor friend and therapist of
mine dr. glazier and at that time I
shared these ideas with him what's going
on with me and he said one thing he made
one statement he said that you have to
catch up with your reality and at first
it didn't mean much to me because I was
like dude I'm asking for help here and
you're telling me I need to catch up to
my reality and he started pointing out
all the great things in my life you know
you've got this you've got that you've
got that you're not broke anymore you're
not destitute anymore you're not that
guy anymore
look around you and I'd look around and
I'm like yeah I mean things are good but
still when is it all going to fall down
when is it all gonna collapse when am I
going to go back to having to you know
for borrow money to put gas my car when
is that going to happen again
and he shakes his head he says look you
got to catch up to what's actually
really going on and the way you're going
to do it is to get very uncomfortable
with spending your money like you're a
wealthy man wait a second so I'm you
know Here I am like I just got a little
bit of money and I'm starting to save it
up a little bit and he says go in buy
furniture for your wife you know I
mentioned that you know Colleen would
like some new chairs around the dinner
dinner table yeah we've got old like we
had like those chairs that you flip open
you know what are you going those
portable chairs you know so we had those
around the table and I'm like our chairs
a good I she was a fine why do I need to
go and spend six seven hundred dollars
on under chairs come on so go and buy
her the chairs and it wasn't because of
the chair than me you know I'm so
against debt and spending for
frivolously frivolously you know and
that was the the old version of me the
version of me that was fearful that when
he's like go spend almost a thousand
dollars on chairs I'm like dude you're
out of your mind and the reason why he
asked me to do those things and what has
been a fruit of me getting uncomfortable
by doing those things is I'm starting to
behave like someone who is living the
reality that I'm currently living what
you've got to do is you've got to start
acting even if it's uncomfortable even
if it feels fake I didn't want to buy
chairs for $700
even if it feels fake go and do the
things that are associated with someone
who has your reality those guys who want
to be like you you know what puff up
your chest and say men I'm gonna take
you under my tutelage I'm gonna take you
under my wings and I'm gonna help you
write me who is sick fat depressed and
nobody liked is now helping other people
yes go and help those guys those girls
that want to hang out with you and talk
to you I know it feels uncomfortable I
know you feel like you're ugly and fat
take them up on the offer take a couple
of them out speak to them do the things
that life is prompting you to do because
life is letting you know that you're a
different person you've done what I'm
always telling people to do
become a different version of yourself
become a stronger version yourself
you've done that physically out here but
inside you're still like I was broke
you're just broke of spirit I was broke
of pocket we've got to step outside of
our comfort zone when the world is
asking us to even though there may be
guilt associated with doing it you might
feel like you don't deserve those
beautiful girls that are talking to you
just like I didn't believe I deserved
nice chairs around the dinner table but
we've got to do it not because of the
thing but but because of who it's going
to force us to become so that's it my
man congratulations good luck step out
there and allow life to give you the
beautiful things that you've earned good
luck