I like being yourself and everything
mystic things
I said earlier that everybody wants that
one thing and really like Socrates
figured out when you get boiled down to
it you lose what we have
right so the easy answer is anything is
the fun of you happiness but you do need
that that's true because this thing will
having sex with lots of women makes me
happy
really so that means it's very
superficial happiness it's it's not a
whore happiness because happiness is a
stripping away of stuff what you're
explaining this properly
it's a simplicity happiness like
children do it brings that you want to
ask if they're happy talking about right
you have that adults are you happy but
you guys before you're already happy
they're like we meet question is that
the thing is tense of the kids because
there's not so much stuff piled on and
yet there's gonna get to there's gonna
be a point where we need absolutely
happy thinking like no or yes because
the world is piled a lot of shit on
heaven at that point you know when you
get 12 years old
you start evolving sexually then you
realize it's no fun as it used to be
when I was a kid playing Legos right now
happiness has tangibility you're four
years old there's no pain there's no
tangible it looks like it is happiness
is but that makes sense
happiness is not is the way happiness is
our natural state when we are completely
unfettered and undistracted
we're not attached when we're free
because that's what you know to do our
tax day anything what we laced up on
that this is what you should think this
one should know I just saw this
yesterday it was a great thing somebody
wrote in to share Facebook in the
expectation it really is the same or
time that reduces reality - reality
happiness is reality happiness is
reality
so what happens is that child grows up
and that child is steeped in reality
which is happiness our natural state but
we start weighing things on that
expectations you need to get good grades
you need to get into this college you
need to be this particular way where you
are not good enough you need to believe
this you do not believe this you need to
do this so we saw lazy stuff on net
right expectations as you get older if
you've got all this shit laid on you all
this shit later on the happiest is just
stuff down you still know what it feels
like it's still in there that sense of
happiness which is associated with
unfettered not being buckland there's
nothing on me
four years old so we start escaping into
circumstances drugs yeah you saw
escaping into food we start skating into
things that bore the shit or carry all
the expectations we believe you're high
and you're happy you're not really happy
because you still have that shit you
just forgot right people would do the
two sets sex pornography turn it off
fucking great you know why just one
second we'll see orgasm tracks for one
second you're in ecstasy you're supposed
to God isn't possibly can when you won't
get to wake up right all the
expectations are still there
so when you say ask your question one
more time
yes it's not so much an avoidance but
it's an awareness that what you think is
making you happy it's just telling you
to the pain associated with all the
expectations
Carrie right so I'm gonna tell you what
you shouldn't shouldn't avoid because if
you're an alcoholic I wrote a blog post
about compassion the other day and say
they have no it's kind of a why do not
the holidays like I know why you're
drinking just got all those damn
expectations lay upon you and your
happiness is buried underneath and while
your trouble you can forget for a little
while so the things that you shouldn't
do or merely but things that are only
going to add to the burden because if
you're not hauling that other problems
if you're a sex addict now you've got a
city problems if you're whatever it is
we want hot asses off just how we escape
in the West go go go go bigger better
more that's the car bigger house whoa
you become addicted to that expansion
you get addicted to that rush you forgot
each new house new body a new bill right
you got a new bill you know that's did
more expectations each the thing that
you're doing is laying more on top of
your happiness in the long run it's
really not happiness is stripping that
shit off letting go of as much as we can
knowing what expectation is not to get
yourself involved not getting involved
with things that lame or expectations
argue is that helpful
you know those kind of metaphor