got an awesome question from our buddy
Jake here he goes on to say Elliot how
can i spread my love he says I know this
might sound sort of strange but after
spending quite some time developing
myself I've come to this unusual
realization I realize that I am happiest
when I'm kind to others and spreading
love so to speak go figure I know it
sounds sorta hippie-ish but I truly
believe if I could figure out the most
efficient and all-encompassing way of
loving everyone I meet that I can
positively influence every life that
comes in contact with mine basically
Jake wants to know how do I live my life
so that I can stay in this current of
love because that's really what it is
you've discovered one of the most
powerful principles of life which is you
reap what you sow you get what you give
and my man if you are overflowing it so
much love that you can't help but spill
over onto other people that means that's
exactly what you're going to get back
don't get fooled a lot of people get
this tricked my diesel get tricked by
this they think that I'm going to give
out loving things so loving things are
gonna come back to me no no no no my
friend it's not so much about get tit
for tat a lot of people want to know
well I did something loving where is the
love and shit coming back to me
motherfucker don't work that way it's
the fact that you are loved your in the
current of love you're spilling over
with love and being filled with so much
love you can't help but feel good love
just wants to share itself so that it
increases itself and you figure that out
this is how I have chosen to live my
life whatever you see in front of you as
you watch the screen and hear me speak
is a manifestation of the overflowing
love in me been able to find out figure
out a way that is allied with my talents
and faculties to do that which increases
the love in me see what I do this isn't
because I want to smooch you and kiss
you and love you in fact if we met I'd
probably be
like weirded out like you you think that
I might want to hug you and kiss you but
I'm like I never met you before dude but
I am spilling over in love because
there's so much in me and in that
increase I feel good so I'm just doing
I'm using these videos as a tool to
increase the loving me and that's really
what you want to figure out how to do
now few quotes Bravo Emerson of course
every action is measured by the
sentiment from which it proceeds meaning
it doesn't matter what you do it matters
who you are you I love my friends so no
matter what you do you're proceeding
from the sentiment of love the soil of
love so anything that you plant in it is
going to be fruitful it's going to
increase your love because you are loved
you are that sentiment every action is
measured it grows it dies it is it lives
by the sentiment from which it proceeds
meaning you're coming from the strongest
place dude so no matter what you do
you've already covered your basis so you
could decide to sweep the streets but
bro when you sweep the streets you're
going to sweep with such love that
you're going to increase the positive
vibrations in that area and people who
walk that road won't even know why they
feel so good when they walk that road
but it'll be because you're spreading
your love you can you can work in
construction you can mow lawns you can
write books you can paint paintings you
can make videos you can do absolutely
anything you could plant trees you can
do absolutely anything and it's going to
be infused with that which is most
powerful and that is your love another
really great quote by Emerson is nothing
amazing has ever been created without
enthused
nothing great has ever been done without
doozy azum that word enthusiasm is
interesting because if you break it down
its root is in Theo's meaning from God
and feels God and you my friend when you
bring your enthusiasm to all you do it
is a work of God you're putting yourself
in the river of love of God enthusiasm
you can't go wrong don't worry so much
about what your actual activity is
because the groundwork has been laid for
you to be successful in whatever you do
retain this love my friend because the
world is going to shit on you sometimes
look it's just the way it is but smile
wipe the shit off and keep going for
those who know how to receive it not
everyone can receive your love not
everyone can receive my love it's
fucking Elliott Hulse thinks he's so
smart so clever but an asshole an
arrogant bastard right not everyone can
receive my love but that doesn't matter
you wipe off the shit and you keep going
choose something that pulls at your
heartstrings because it'll be that much
more powerful see not everybody lives in
a circumstance that allows them to make
and that everybody has the talents
faculties to make youtube videos or to
plant trees i can't play fucking trees
my dad you should cease garden beautiful
my dad doesn't like people he loves
plants and when you walk into his garden
it's just you feel the love right not
everybody can do that I plant plants me
and why are you giggle we can't plant
plants they just fucking die find the
thing that makes you that makes you
vibrate that you enjoy doing and then do
it with all of your love I have a friend
who is a waitress and she's been so
since college and she does not want to
do anything else she's growing old and
people tell her why don't you find a
and she smiles and says I love serving
people in this restaurant I don't know
what it is but I feel good doing it
she's so full of love that she can't
help but to do an activity consistently
day in and day out that most people
think of is inhuman inhumane and hot and
back-breaking don't listen to what the
world tells you is right and true about
what you should and shouldn't do spread
your love through the channels that
you've been given to you I happen to
have a gift with words and talking of
IDEO zai don't know talking to video
cameras but again it doesn't matter
because if YouTube disappeared one day
I'd be doing the same thing just in a
different way because every action is
being measured from the sentiment of
love you've got what it takes go and do
anything and it will be tainted and
fused it'll it'll blossom with the
perfume of the love within you done