I got a question from one of our own
Bray's from LA our own brain is a good
man is a good kid you may have made some
bad decisions and it's put him in a
situation where he's got a son a young
boy probably about four or five years
old and he loves his son with all of his
heart but the circumstances of life are
such that he feels he needs to gain
custody of his son I don't know what the
situation is with the woman maybe she's
on drugs maybe she's in a gang
I don't know but our own brain it's
ready to fight to the death to get
possession of his son that he loves so
dearly with all of his heart and it's
brought him and his battle to the
courtroom he's got to go to court he's
got to go to court with all of this
pent-up frustration anger love and
passion and convinced the people in the
court the judge that he's the right
person for his son to live with this is
a very difficult thing my friend because
for a man to gain custody over a child
over a woman it's very difficult the
child came from her it's closer to her
but apparently the circumstances are
such that you feel you need to care for
your son and I'm with you and I'm going
to support you in this your question the
thing that you're concerned about is how
do I go into the courtroom
with an air of confidence you use the
word alpha an air of confidence and
energy aggression to a degree but not
completely fly off the handle not
completely lose my mind embarrass myself
through the court case away because I'm
so excited about what I want to have
happen I know where you're coming from
you're anything like me you're generally
an ungrounded person my natural tendency
is towards phallic narcissism very
energy ungrounded so I've got to do what
I'm going to teach you how to do so I'm
coming from a place experience a place
where you want to be able to take all
that energy that power that you have
that's like a freaking machine gun
because the machine gun is powerful to
take out 12 people with one pull but
when your energy is ungrounded you're
going to walk into that courtroom with
the power of a machine gun but it's like
putting it in the hand of a
five-year-old you can shoot himself
shoot the wrong people and just throw
the entire thing away the gun is
powerful but it's who is carrying the
gun I hope you follow my metaphor that's
important right you've got to take that
same power and put it into a mature
grounded man's hands so that he can
cause the damage that needs to be done
but in a very practical pragmatic and
powerful powerfully grounded way so I'm
going to offer you two tips because you
mentioned bioenergetics in your question
when you're your post it seems that
you're experimenting with using your
body to as a tool to dictate your
character and your behaviors which is
good is right it's all about our bodies
right because you can have all the facts
right just like the kid has the gun but
they're of no use because they're your
weapons the facts are your weapons all
the statistics or your weapons but
they're of no use if you can't produce
or present them in a grounded fashion so
you're going to do two things very first
thing is you're going to take a look at
one of my videos up here it's about how
to deepen your breath
there are several exercises a series of
exercises in that video that you're
going to do you've got to open up your
chest you've got to open up your belly
you've got to open up your pelvic floor
so that you can bring your energy bring
your breath down into your balls now do
you see the way I'm talking right now
it's because the sound is resonating
deeper within my body I'm a more
grounded person because the energy comes
down into a lower place in my body it's
not up high just notice my behavior if
I'm up high
I'm very energetic and I'm up here and
I'm talking like this I'm talking faster
them talking right from my throat a
grounded man a grounded person a
grounded individual talks from his balls
but the only way you can access your
balls is by releasing the tension in the
chest and the belly in the pelvic floor
whether you know you have it or not I'm
telling you you do we all do because
we're always holding our bodies tight
with tension you're going to need to
stretch those muscles and bring your
breath down load everything and
explained in the video you're going to
need to do as soon as you finish that
and you've breathed I say give yourself
a good half an hour of breathing you
breathe to the depths of your torso your
body brought your energy down low you'll
notice the difference because when you
breathe and when you talk you it'll feel
like your esophagus is bigger
you feel far less constricted in your
ability to bring in the breath and let
it out through deep resonating sound
sounds that resonate deep within your
body so step two you're going to take
your shoes off and going to massage your
feet the same way I show you in this
video or I'll put it down below
whatever massage your feet he's a ball
of massage your feet for a few moments
just a minute on each and then you're
going to use deep sounds and grounding
exercise I'll show you right now to
bring your energy though you're going to
need to do this the morning you need to
do this now but the morning of your
court case before you leave the house do
everything I'm describing to you right
now after you massage your feet take off
your shoes and I need you to practice
this Oh deep resonating sound down into
your balls feel your balls shaking feel
your feet hit the ground flat and keep
that sound below this is going to ground
your energy you're gonna feel like
you're breathing deeper you're going to
feel like you're talking with a deeper
voice this is good you're going to need
to carry that with you throughout the
day the way you're going to do that is
by periodically dropping your jaw and
letting your belly loose to bring in
more oxygen that's it's the air that's
your energy
you get it so that's it my man there's
so much to this there's so much to this
you and your situation and I pray for
you hopefully you use my bioenergetic
exercises and they'll support you and
coming from a place of groundedness
power and pragmatism good luck