so our friend James he's 18 now he
relates his experience with a girl that
he's been dating for a year he says
before they started dating of course you
know you're cutesy with one another
throw glances at one another and blow
kisses whatever people do to flirt and
they got together a month into the
relationship and he's been dealing with
this shit for a year now a month or two
away relationship she says to him now
listen here James haha sorry listen here
James the honeymoon periods over he
tells her that she tells him that James
is like a we just aren't dating and this
bitch is talking about sorry I call her
bitch but she starts talking about the
honeymoon periods over right and uh it
starts turning real weird on him you
know picking fights and so on and so
forth of course in a circumstance like
that he withdraws from her for a
particular amount of time I guess this
whole debate this whole problems was
going on for a year anyway so at some
point within that year he pulls himself
away from her and ends up being with
another woman and he says for lack of
better term she turns out she was
fucking crazy too he withdraws comes
with he says literally his tail between
his legs
and comes crawling back to two old Oh
tough ass right I care how pretty she is
bro she's hard to say to tell you plenty
moons over at what but well for anybody
to say that shit to their partner I was
stupid anyway silly silly silly silly
girl so now he's with her again but
things are only getting worse because
now she is constantly reminding him that
he left her and he was with another girl
and it's the whole fucking thing's ugly
look I'm gonna get straight to the point
here and a lot of suggested what I'm
gonna share with you right now to other
people and I get a lot of backlash but I
just don't give a fuck because I say
what needs to be said at the particular
moment I don't everybody every situation
is different that's why I contradict
myself so often look dude
she's a mess she's a mess from the
moment she told you that the honeymoon
periods over it should have been a red
flag to you that this bitch got viruses
she's got mine viruses so whatever
happened to her between her and daddy
because that's usually where where it
begins for most of us particularly
because particularly girls whatever
happened between her and daddy she's
still playing out a lot of that drama at
some point daddy withdrew love because
you know you're a big girl now
I can't sit on my lap anymore right
because of all the sexual implications
there I hope that my daughters will be
able to sit on my lap feel comfortable
enough to sit on my lap well into their
adulthood right even when they're
married husband needs to know hey your
wife's gonna sit on my lap she's my baby
I'll always be but it not all men had
that form of sexual maturity to allow
shit like that to happen so our dude our
girl who's had bad experiences whereby
she would love what was withdrawn from
her and now she believes that's the
pattern by which the world works and she
falls in love with you you have this
honeymoon period that she literally gave
a name we could call it pre oedipal if
you're a fraud Ian and those who want to
knock Freud look a guy didn't have
everything correct but he pointed to a
lot of shit but we didn't know before so
they would call that pre oedipal she in
her relationship with her father during
the honeymoon period that was the
oedipal period of development when daddy
withdrew love because we all do at some
point it just depends how severe that
withdraw is we call that post oedipal
that hurt
that pain of separation now that's a
pattern she understands and she calls it
honeymoon period maybe her dad called it
that or she heard that term and she said
yeah that makes sense
and she comes and in playing out the
drama with you everything is hunky-dory
until the honeymoon periods over and I
don't know how she delineate it that
outlook she waited a particular time or
had a particular experience with you
made her to create that demarcation
honeymoon periods over
it's her pain it's her problem and I'm
going to invite you not to make it yours
again feel no guilt for falling in love
with this girl feel stupid for staying
with her especially if she's not open to
education okay I mean when you love
someone you try to educate them and
maybe I'm educating you right now how I
love you guys through these videos so
you have some information to go back to
her and say hey you know what maybe the
honeymoon period wasn't over maybe it's
just you acting out a pain that you
experienced when you were a kid and
perhaps we can be happy again
because you really should be naughty
mood should never end now there are
fluctuations in the intensity of
honeymoon but the honeymoon never ends I
had a honeymoon with my wife last night
okay
so maybe if you have it in you and if
you feel it fit and it's not going to
drain you so much because you're still
young you you don't want this to be a
fucking drain on you but I bet you have
a lot of energy you want to do it you
want to educate here you want to move
her in the right direction because you
you generally love her not because you
want her back
in in any way that you can envision but
because you love her so much you'd like
to see her heal big difference there
that means unconditional love we love
her without condition meaning I don't
need to own you after I fix you or help
you we don't really fix anyone or cut
and run brother let's get the fuck out
of there you know I mean it was one
experience you learned something wrong
check her out on Facebook ten years from
now you'll either say wow you know I'm
happy you got your shit together or
you'll save poor ex all that shit coming
done