got a question here from our buddy
Robinson who wants to know yo Elliott
with so much information available out
there and so many different books that
you could possibly read and subjects to
study how do you know what to spend your
time reading studying immersing yourself
in especially when there's so much that
could be a waste of time and you know he
goes on to say that you know in becoming
the strongest version of myself I
checked out your Pinterest profile to
read some of the books that you
recommended already but really how do
you decide what books you're going to
read next
how can one find the right books in this
gigantic pool of literature where
there's so many books that could be a
waste of time as opposed to supporting
you great question and one that I am
constantly challenged with but I do have
a perspective that's going to support
you just to give you some perspective
first as to how I can relate at least
once a week I grab my what is now my
hair I grab my hair and and I shake my
head and I say to my wife I want to know
everything I wish I could know
everything right now I start going down
a vein or down a river of learning and I
become so excited and anxious that it's
like I flip to the references I want to
read all the references I want like the
book to be in my nervous system now
instead of taking my time to read it
then you know that's you know we got to
reconcile this this the difference
between what we want you know the end
result which is more understanding more
wisdom and getting that shit into our
brain so I didn't mean to say this but
I'm going to preface what I'm about to
share with you too with an invitation to
study studying learn how to learn
there's a really good audio program you
know begin with this now you're right
Elliott's giving you more shit to study
but begin with this because it's going
to give you a perspective and it's gonna
give you tools for the things I'm going
to talk about a moment accelerated
learning by Brian Tracy is called the
accelerated learning course by Brian
Tracy and although there's a lot of
fluff in it I'm going to talk to you
about how to navigate
around the fluff also there are some
really useful tools tips techniques that
you can use to increase your learning
ability because that's really what it's
all about how quickly can we not only
bombard ourselves with powerful ideas
but how can we digest and assimilate
these ideas I've done videos on this in
the past so I'm not gonna go too far
down that route but I would invite you
to learn how to learn the next step is
and this is really a this is an
invitation for self exploration and
commitment to a legacy so before I even
give you this next piece that's that's
really what I have my invitation would
be is like what do you feel as if you're
how do you feel you're going to serve
the world with what type of service or
product how is it that you're going to
ultimately take the things that you're
learning and give it back do you see and
that's very important so for me which is
the only thing I could use as an example
based on my experience is anything
related to the four layers of strength
that I call or that I that I say
ultimately culminates to create the
strongest version of an individual it's
taken me years you know thirty-five
years old and I've been thinking about
this very long and it's taking me years
to figure out the four areas main areas
of study that I'm going to to spend my
time studying for professional gain when
I say professional gain again it's my
book use my career my profession how I'm
going to serve the world so the very
first thing is take your time and study
the thing that you love and that you
intend to use as a tool to serve others
my four layers of strength or our
neuromuscular strength I don't I only
study things that are related to
neuromuscular strength you know the
muscular system the physiology of the
human being as it relates to the
muscular system and the energetic
expression of the human being as it
relates to the other three so all the
things that you hear me talk about in
some way involve energetic strength
physiological strength or neuromuscular
strength and that's what really you know
all the ideas that I share with you in
these
are an expression of or grow out of my
desire to learn those three things the
fourth one fourth way of shrink
presentable strength presentable
strength is your ability to like I said
take these stains and serve the world
with it make a place for yourself in the
world with the with the with the ideas
that you've decided to build your life
around okay
there were two more things I want to
invite you to and to consider also and
before I go further these three ideas
your Professional Studies which is what
I just shared with you and the two more
that I'm gonna share that I'm going to
tell you now come from Earl Nightingale
or Earl Nightingale share this idea with
me in a program on audio program called
lead the field
I believe I'm giving you more shit to
study right the second one is understand
your language come to know how to use
your language because he goes on to
describe how the greater number of words
that you understand and can use not only
increase your ability to communicate but
increases your ability to think words
give point to abstract ideas all words
are just symbols to ideas and ideas
ideas our abstract ideas are in the air
ideas are ephemeral if you will
ideas just kind of they're out there and
they're they've not been grounded in
reality yet right you know we thought
about landing on the moon for related
them fucking moon right we thought about
creating this information highway before
we actually created the information
highway all the things that you
ultimately manifest comes from the
abstract down into reality the more
symbols you have for the abstract the
more you can put together ideas see how
magnificent that is so if ideas is this
is this pool of energy words are ways to
grow a point to different areas within
this pool of consciousness as pool of
energy the more words you understand the
more you can learn that goes back to you
know your learning capacity which is the
very first thing I should invite
to do and then finally the third piece
is to understand study and make your
mission in life to also know your
history
it's a crazy one right you wouldn't
think that it you know Elliott how does
that serve my ability to to develop my
capacity as a scientist or as a poet or
as an artist or an architect whatever it
is understanding your history gives you
a frame of reference for where you are
in this dance of humankind because it'd
be nice to say that humankind or life is
linear but there are those who believe
if you study the Hindu tradition that
life is circular and where are we on
this circular dance that humanity's
doing a part of the reason why that's
interim portent to know study Hinduism
they're not even really interested in
history because they think it just keeps
doing this but I find it important to
know and then majority of people that
study this way find it important to know
because it it gives you the tools in
order to navigate your life in avoiding
problems of the past you basically
you're learning from your standing on
the shoulders of giants if you will
right so things like studying the
history of your country Western
civilization Eastern civilization and
then biographies I think biographies are
really important because they give you
the grass roots the grass roots
experience of people during the
particular phases of this you know human
evolution so there you have it though
the three main things I wanted to share
with you in this video
prefaced by learning how to learn are
your area your main area of study that
you ultimately are going to use to serve
the world is the very first one and you
make that your the second one which is a
very tremendous support mechanism is
your language study language but if
you're reading a lot you're studying
language also but study language no more
words and then finally
history know who you are and where you
stand in this struggle
I think that's Bob Marley done