they got a really fascinating question
from our friends Scott Scott happens to
be very very gifted talented 21 years
old he lives at homes with it with his
parents but check this out
he scored the highest in his school on
the standardized test as a kid and then
went on to quit school right so he's the
smartest kid in his class
excuse me and he decides to quit he
starts college because he's a brilliant
kid and I think he got a scholarship and
then he quits and then he decides to
partake of different activities
including the arts so music he started
to play the guitar picked it up in a
matter of an instant got bored and quit
started drawing
became very proficient at drawing also
making websites both of those things he
became very good at very quickly within
weeks he says and then quits the thing
is he finds that he continues to get
bored with all these magnificent things
that he has the capacity the natural
capacity to do he can do almost anything
it's a little weird but reading his his
question it basically has me assuming
that he is a genius but he's bored and
he hates his life he hates living at
home with his parents and he doesn't
know what to do I keep emphasizing that
word do because apparently you have the
ability to do whatever you want and all
the things that you do do you get bored
doing so you're looking for answers
about what should I do
right another interesting thing about
Scott is that he at one point was a very
big Meech a fan Frederic Nietzsche if
you're not familiar with EJ EJ killed
God he's basically the guy that killed
God in his assertion that God is dead
now man is free to do whatever he wants
very interesting story Vijay then kills
himself
you see so he killed the one thing that
he felt and his followers felt was
holding man back from becoming the
strongest version of themselves which
basically to them meant doing whatever
they wanted so the power structure was
destroyed and then he goes and kills
himself because there's nothing left to
do I mean what else do you do wouldn't
you kill God what are you to do right
kill yourself I mean endgame the problem
is that niche a new yourself and it's so
funny that you read Nietzsche because
there's so many parallels there you can
do whatever you want you know what the
fuck to do you know what end up killing
yourself like me J did what you've got
to recognize is that what knee Jay
didn't do which would have been to put
an end to the whole mess and what you're
dealing with right now is reap what is
replace the death of God with something
and I'm going to refer you now to a to a
talk by Osho I don't know if you've been
following me for a while I'm a big fan
of Osho I read a lot of his books a talk
that Osho gave in like 1984 right I'll
put a link down below you can purchase
it for like $2 on the web site you need
to listen to this and he's a he's got an
Indian accent so you know listen to it
closely and bear with it but I'm the
name of the actually I pulled it up here
cuz I was thinking about you man I read
your question and I was like this guy
needs to listen to some fo sho so it's
called uh god is dead now Zen is the
only living truth right and and those of
you who are watching this and you're
Christian or very religious where the
case may be
I'm not making any assertions I'm
referring our friend to listen to this
and if you're smart kid and if you liked
reading Nietzsche you're gonna like what
oh show has to say about DJ because what
Oh show invites you to do not to do
anything and that's it's kind of the
direction I want to lead you being is
where you're going to want to drown
yourself drown yourself in being and
it's a very zen approach to life and
you'll find that happiness is found in
the moment not in what
you create or the goal that you're
striving towards or killing God or
becoming a great artist it's in being
it's in the moment it's drowning in the
joy of existence and that's what Zen is
a lot of these ideas that I share with
you guys it's simply because I am
fascinated with them myself I'm not a
guru of any sort I just happen to be
interested in a lot of different ideas
and because I'm neurotic
I study a lot of shit to help cure my
neurosis so when I find an interesting
dude like yourself who who's neurotic
all hell but it's talented and brilliant
I like to offer you a direction to
continue expanding your consciousness
and that would be my invitation to you I
think that you'll find a wealth of ideas
that are going to support you in
reducing the neurotic drive to do more
things because you've already found the
futility in it and to find peace and joy
in the pure being of life and as
interesting as it may sound I don't know
you but I you've got a monk's heart
you've got a spiritual heart you might
not know it I mean you read Nietzsche
right EJ killed God but it requires that
type of person to reject all that life
has to offer especially when he can do
whatever he wants to finally settle in
the spiritual reality of life and it is
found in the moment it's found in Zen
it's found in your pure being not
necessarily doing so that's it my friend
I'd love to hear from you comment on
this video if you guys see him thumbs it
up I'd like to see with you what you
think and how you proceed with this idea
good luck my friend Eliot sit what