okay my name is Pete my wife Ganga
following your videos for marijuana it
without tremendously I guess my question
would be what guided you to find your
true calling and what advice can you
give for me to help myself find my
microphone okay one of the things that
that makes us one of the most comforting
things is to say here it is that's it
bears like now your your thing is to
call there it is
I got it true calling what my invitation
to you is is to realize that there is no
just that there is a movement towards
infinity that's what that's what that's
what human beings do that's what nature
does that's what God does that's what
the particles in space do they move
towards infinity that's why the infinity
symbol looks like this they fucking go
anywhere in particular but it's just
going you see what you've got to do is
you've got to get in touch with that's
subtle
strength within that tells you where to
go so for example I grew up very
athletic
right it's a subtle strength within me
based on my experiences in my DNA that I
knew that if I did anything outside that
some intelligence would it be that says
sports strength training someone it's so
fun that I would be denying and I eat
you guys nobody's heard of God lightly
but it's to describe that which cannot
be described
within us this guide is that animating
force if I deny that because it's in my
heart to move towards athletics I know
that oh you're moving outside the bounds
of that which is true be okay I'm
standing here talking about truth right
what does it have to do pendant in mind
you I'm still they still say on strength
coach do you see but as I moved towards
supporting fourteen fifteen sixteen
eighteen year old kids with training
barbells they would ask me so in my
heart that's that's so energy that
sensitivity truly towards I didn't say
you know string coach I can't go there
dizzy I've never had it
that's why labels are so dangerous you
want to be able to say I am hey what are
you right now
I'm please home at least you want to say
I hope Elise officer so everyone sure
you have something to snuggle in the
huddle and say when someone when you go
to parties in some what you're gonna do
time while you're in the flesh but they
wouldn't be like killing I got it got
you
we are that animated forcing that become
sensitive enough by the ship that I say
sounds poetic insight hi but it's
because it's an invitation to trust your
body trust yourself trust her senses and
move with it if I was like no on this
record and I listen to people that were
just like Elliot stop all your
philosophical bullshit you're just stick
to it
wait tonight actually let everybody else
say oh yeah don't forget this is you I'd
be denying the service of and confined
to the world and I wouldn't get such joy
out of my life by doing what I do your
calling is a feeling it's a journey and
you've got a sense enough sensitive
enough to move it it's about coming to
stronger version of you it allows your
calling to happen does that make sense
because again this is why what I do is
the make any sense because you want to
be most people when people read a book
it says they give you tests based on
this tests and these answers we've got a
graph here that tells you that you are
such and such and this is your calling
dan that's out like prison my car is
like