we got this question from our friend who
is 18 years old he's been living in the
United States since 1999 so he's been
here for quite some time but he
committed some crimes of sort and now
he's being deported back to his country
of El Salvador now being 18 years old
and having lived most of his growing
life here in the US he's got friends and
family and his entire life is rooted in
his home and now because of a breach
because he fucked up somehow
it's getting kicked out he to go back to
El Salvador he says my life is falling
apart
he's even thought about committing
suicide he says I'm not even strong
enough to do it I have guilt over the
pain I caused my loved ones I'm going to
leave them and I'm going to be hurt my
question to you Elliott is this under
these horrible circumstances what is the
most valuable thing that I could hold
onto mentally and physically now a
couple things very first one is this
this is the harsh reality of life and
receive it but receive it without
resistance
because it is life you make your bed and
you sleep in it all the time what you
reap is what you've sown it's just that
way you did something and this is the
result it was a bound to catch up to you
whatever you're doing there's going to
be an equal but opposite reaction it's
physics motherfucker so you made your
bed now you got to sleep in it just be
okay with that take responsibility for
that don't feel sorry for yourself feel
empowered by the fact that you are a
creator in your life you're a manifester
of circumstances you did something and
you made something happen now there are
unconscious on undercurrents causing you
to do these things that are causing this
circumstance so we might want to explore
what's going on
character-wise cyclist psychologically
spiritually what's going on inside you
to make you
make these choices but take
responsibility my friend whether you are
cognizant of why you make these choices
or not you're making those choices and
eat the pie that comes with it be with
that don't judge yourself because you
because the next step here is going to
be explore yourself I'll talk to you
about in a moment don't judge yourself
because my man you don't even know
yourself if you're making choices that
are giving you results that you don't
like it means you don't know yourself
someone else there's a demon in you
that's making choices and and then
you're like what the fuck happened I
know better I don't know why I keep
making these mistakes I'm so stupid and
then and then and then the bad thing
happens and there's more resistance you
got to get over that immature Mickey
Mouse baby bullshit grow up made your
bed now sleeping it man the fuck up get
deported like a man wipe your fucking
tears and blow your nose right I don't
say that to kick you in your ass I say
that because you need to stand in your
feet you're 18 years old you're gonna be
a man take responsibility bro okay
that's first number two what a lot of
people say yes adults say shit that's
why my videos are so long cuz I would
just say shit
I explained right why are you a DD
motherfuckers can't watch me more than
10 minutes more than five minutes you
don't belong here
I'm not talking to you I'm gonna explain
a lot of adults will say well what did
you learn from the circumstances right
what did you what did you learn from
your mistake they say now that's a very
it's a loaded question but typically
comes from a superficial sentiment and
the answer usually is superficial so
you're gonna learn well I learned not to
sell drugs in front of police officers
well huh then that nice that's something
you did I learned not to carry guns into
government buildings oh that's something
you do I learned not to to beat up my
girlfriend's again that's something you
were doing so
the thing that the person's doing isn't
what they learned they read that now
they may be remorseful for the choice
hey I shouldn't go around beating women
and selling drugs in hot areas right but
that's like stupid logistical stuff
that's that's stupid logistics what you
really need to come to learn or what
your weaknesses are you know I've
learned that I'm very impressionable I
listen to rap music it's all about
beating women and selling drugs not that
it always is I happen to like a lot on
rap music but uh I envision these ideas
of selling drugs and having jewelry and
being a pimp when I hear this music when
it bends itself into my consciousness as
I start dressing and talking and
behaving in this way by golly I learned
that I'm a follower I'm impressionable
that's what you learned you didn't learn
don't sell drugs in front of officers
and don't beat your girlfriend you
learned it you're an impressible
impressionable motherfucker
now that you learned that you're
impressionable cuz it could be a million
other things it could mean that you're a
coward oh you're a coward you won't face
up you you won't stand in the face of
certain challenge there's there's
something that you need to man up to
that you keep powering away from and in
your cowardice you end up making these
choices but then when someone asks you
what you did would you learn it's about
the choices you made now I'm a fuck it's
because you're a coward
always go to virtues always go to
character always go to who you're not
being or who you're being because then
you can work on it because now if you
know you're impressionable
that's one it's very important because I
know I'm impressionable I'm gonna deny
and I own every piece of me I'm highly
impressionable
but that's why I'm very very very
diligent about what I put into my
consciousness certain things I don't
watch certain things I don't
environments that allow myself to get
engage with certain relationships I
don't get engaged with do you see and I
do it not because I judge those things
as bad evil I don't want to be around
but because I'm impressionable and they
gonna fuck up my head I need I need a
pretty strong head for the things that
I'm doing I'm living
gained here gonna be a little big game
you got to figure yourself out and you
got to start dealing with yourself
objectively if you know you're fearful
get very clear about what you're fearful
about why you're making choices about in
your life based on that fear and then
face that fucking fear it always boils
down to fear just different
manifestations of it so baby boy what
are you afraid of right what scares you
because there's something scaring you
this making you making you do the stupid
things that you're doing right maybe
you're maybe you're afraid of lack and
safety and security and you don't
believe that you have the skills or the
character to earn money in a resourceful
way because everybody doesn't like you
the white man is my enemy he's the
oppressor well that's the story you're
telling yourself based on a fear that
you have based on probably no experience
at all
what TV has told you immediate old you I
don't know I'm just making this shit up
but I'm guessing because most y'all
don't have no experiences all your ideas
come from what other people told you for
music you listen to them in the videos
you watching the movies you watch now
you have no ideas of your own you have
no experiences but yet you hold on to
these ideologies you let them rule you
so that bullshit-ass fear it's causing
you not to sack up pay taxes and be an
upstanding resourceful citizen in this
country so maybe you do need to get your
ass kicked out till you start telling
yourself better stories about
empowerment instead of fear mercy now
I'm just making this up but perhaps it
always comes back to your core values
your core virtues get in touch with what
you value see where your virtues are
lacking and build yourself up from the
inside out
done