so after posting a video earlier today
about being willing to do whatever it
takes to achieve your goals I've gotten
some questions about how to discover
what your passion is obviously I decided
to build my life around the idea of
strength helping people get stronger and
and sharing ideas about strength but
Skyfire 11:29 commented on that video
basically wants to know Eliot how do I
go about finding my passion because it
seems like a very hard thing to do so
I'm going to offer you a little bit of
my experience number one you've got to
expose yourself to a lot of different
things to find out what exactly you
really love that means read lots of
books on topics that you enjoy continue
to expose yourself to ideas from people
that you respect that's probably one of
the best things to do look at someone
who you admire and you like what they do
and really pick their brain in other
words read all their books watch all
their videos read all their blog posts
do whatever you can to get inside the
mind of that person and also go outside
the bounds of the typical things that
you may read or study so while you read
is magazines go out and read some poetry
just expand your mind you've got to
really expand your horizon by exposing
yourself to ideas and things that you
did seem almost foreign to you you've
got to go out and and bombard yourself
with new ideas and the weirder the idea
is same the more looks spanned your mind
you've watched my other videos you see
how weird some of the things I like to
expose myself to and then I I add it to
Who I am in it it continues to show me
what my passions are so that brings me
to the next point that think of you
think of your core the most passionate
strongest version yourself as the pit or
the center of a onion right so there are
layers there so you're going to have to
peel back layers and this this is takes
the course of a lifetime so who you are
today and the passions that you have
today aren't going to be what your
passions are and who you are tomorrow
the strongest version of you right now
is the strongest version of you but ten
years from now that's
look totally different than it looks
right now so my advice with regard to
that is don't be afraid to evolve so
because you say your passion is blank
today doesn't mean that next year five
years ten years from now it's going to
be completely different than that but
the only way that you can expose those
new layers those deeper layers that clip
closer and closer and closer to the true
strongest Jew is to continue exposing
yourself to new ideas Eliot said what
[Music]