a lot of female competitors we really
appreciate I wanted to know like when
you because you had a video recently
that was about this guy that lost 100
pounds
shut down but what do you do when it's
like you you've competed in your
Metallica just like shut down feels like
you're drinking water in getting away
you know but I'm also like that post
competition depression that you kind of
go through i don't know if you know
anything about that if I know your uncle
with its hormonal and it's generally
adrenal fatigue both they answered a
boat let's pour down adrenals you've got
a nerve you that become way too
catabolic and you may I mean I would he
tested I told another lady earlier to
talk to dr. kalish actually my brother's
doing tests now a little brother he went
to dr. killers class I would do is
classified that's the appointment but
I'm getting your adrenals tested their
saliva tests and let you know if your
stage 1 stage 2 is the h3 adrenal
fatigue and based on how your adrenals
are functioning throughout their
circadian throughout the day there are
lifestyle nutrition and supplements that
will help rebalance the adrenals that's
really from from all my studying
physiological strength take a live
without percolation learned of all the
guys the Keystone hormone that's going
to like screw with the rest ends up
being the adrenals and the adrenals are
now is also stimulates that we drink by
dieting it's going to affect all the
other hormones that support your animals
or that building muscle being able sleep
at night not being stressed out not
being depressed yeah there's so many
other hormones that cascade off and how
do you go off like you know
showing you really Sony is so much
cardio like how do you get off of that
honey like balanced f2 like how to
explode you know you have to become
anabolic right now it's a hormonal
balance where you spent so much time
being catabolic that you've got you got
to bring it back weight training weight
training in at this farm or a debauch do
you a train yeah you might be overdoing
your weight training might be so in
balance it sounds like your balance and
sounds like you're super catabolic one
of the exercise modalities that support
animalism without a breakdown it's like
chi gong meditation movement meditation
you want to be able to simulate
parasympathetic nervous system to become
more antibody I would invite you to take
your Chico meditation class were you
really focus on your breathing and maybe
even take a break from the type of
imbalance train all it's called you with
all this weight training your breakdown
breakdown breakdown breakdown say you're
definitely instead computer you're
gaining weight and you're draining that
much your adrenals with your death I'll
do yeah you literally have to go the
opposite end of the spectrum and not
doing weight training is enough got the
undo the damage by actively stimulating
the parasympathetic went to the nervous
system through deep breathing and
meditation you have to do the exact
opposite which
because more of the same it's like how's
that term go abuse that you get to a
point of diminishing returns where your
your activities that once got you moving
in the right direction now diminish
diminishing returns that's what I was
looking for you're at the point of
diminishing returns but the more you
keep doing over here the worse it's
going to get and that's our metallic
mentally point the same courage that it
took to go down this journey is the same
goes it took courage to be the type of
athlete that you are we all have courage
we just forget that we have courage
especially when we get what we want are
you really good as an athlete miss
direction everything they got you what
you want to hear all the glory of the
pride associated with what you got here
required some courage so it's hard to
detach from the version of yourself that
got you here in order to recreate a new
version of yourself by doing the exact
opposite which is chill the fuck out
literally oportunidad but you've got to
let go for a time of this character this
character is fit fit and firm and
beautiful and all the things that it
took to get fit for a beautiful are now
maybe you back sick and tired strange
right these all these things got me what
I wanted but now thats the point
intimidation like mentally i find it
makes you so much of a stronger person
and then i think one of the weakest
times of my life was when I was
that's like yeah you went off the
boundary that's why this looks like this
because you go too far this way you're
going to be forced back this way it's
like watering right yeah it needs water
right exactly what you just drownded you
went too far that you what you're
getting is the exact opposite look you
got what you do it right you probably
need to take a whole year to restructure
your lifestyle your opinion by building
up more arrows and you might find that
you get better results you would rather
it isn't forever so I've actually quit
working with athlete with bodybuilders
and finger competitors because I've
watched them completely like ruin their
lives going overboard with it I I talk
almost every female that comes in your
out of doing figure competition I've
seen the complete thyroid profiles read
from years afterwards it's the biggest
paradigm shift if you're going to have
to make sorry I Japanese absolutely
because you're right please you have to
make a paradigm shift you have to
completely switch your mind of thinking
that that on stage presence where you're
at eight percent body fat is the
stereotypical walking model of health
because it's not all it is is you're
looking good one day on stage no I don't
think for me it has anything to do with
that at all I think for me it's like
what where it brings you mentally
training and competing for that when
you're like what yeah like basically how
strongly makes you mentally you know
yeah they're too yet you're too male
strangers that sounds as pre-book girl
you are you got a giant cock better for
your way to penis what is pleasing
walking penis wants to feel hard and
aggressive too much no because you know
what it'd be like really manly man I
don't know sex like this what it's like
but it's like this it's not sexual
energy in that necessarily sexuality but
a very aggressive male woman has a hard
time keeping an aggressive man tends to
be a battle penises can you make them be
manifesting you might not have tested
everywhere in your life who may just be
using this one your body and your diet
as a way to exert all of your control
you might be very very yielding with
your man but you've built up a structure
and a place where you you're building a
giant penis your be very bad so the
thing is you've got it you've got a
softening the best way to stimulate that
that feminine energy is with meditation
breathing deep with
my to do Qigong slow moving body moving
meditation where you focus on reading
teeth balancing your hormones that were
definitely email that you in touch with
my brother Elliott Hulse biz gmail com
I'll save my brother he's actually doing
experiments because he's not talking
very much right now because work at all
probably just by the test itself you had
paid for because he's going through an
internship right now where he's testing
me everybody's adrenals I thought of
humility you spitting vials email it to
you you mail you'll bail back the bottle
to the lab he gets the lab results we
get the lab results you can tell you
what stage we're drinking what stage of
adrenal fatigue you're in and then
there's a protocol associated with that
petite the supplements will help you
instantly with ryan when you start using
you started using the self interstate
your utility go good it helped me
provide okay you know if you don't
change your lifestyle if you don't
change your lifestyle you will be
dependent on what they give you a window
of opportunity to do what I'm asking you
to do that which is to start meditating
start breathing eating foods that not
only support your figure but nourish
your body very important you see the
difference
nourishment and bodybuilding nutrition
good so that's what it is you've got a
balance your hormones anabolic