I just got finished reading a really
emotionally charged email from one of
our friends by the name of a Kay he's 17
years old he lives in Sweden and he's
having some really tough times at school
and that might seem like well it's a big
deal why you know everybody has to tell
time at school to some degree but his
story dates back to when he was about
six years old and his 19th I think then
nineteen year old brother older brother
died in a car accident and then after
that there was a series of other deaths
in the family that led to his mother
becoming very depressed became an
alcoholic his older sister became very
depressed and then they both went
through very abusive relationships
my friend a Kay is still growing up
through all this shit dad really wasn't
there as a father but was there more of
what I gather as a friend and then at
some point early in high school his
father slash friend who was kind of like
you knows his buddy I guess he would say
through all the the turmoil and trauma
was early the early part of his life
hooked up with a woman in started his
own family so now a key 7a K 17 years
old it doesn't have a stable matriarch
and what posed as a patriarchal father
figure
disappeared started his own family is
really you know not that involved with a
Kaden age when boys really need men more
than ever
17 years old we always need strong men
in our lives but you're going through
you didn't have a great foundation and
now you're going through some changes
physiologically psychologically
physically it would be good if you had
someone to lean on and you know I I do
understand when you say Elliott you know
you've been a mentor to me through
through some tough times I get that and
that's why I make these videos but I
know there's nothing like having a man
put his hand on your back until you look
I've got your back I mean that's so
significant that hand right on your back
saying son
I've got your back especially when times
are difficult like you're experiencing
right now so his mother is giving him a
really hard time there you know he's he
failed some classes he's in the second
year he failed some classes he's going
through fights with his mother he's
depressed and frustrated at home because
of that resistance and school is just
falling apart he says also this is very
poignant that he senses a deep
depression coming on in the form of
depersonalization when I use that word
depressed I I mean it literally like you
retreat from life that's what it
depressed means it means to depress your
energy and Toodee personalize which is
the type of depression that he's
describing means that you depress all of
your energy up out of your body and into
your head and a head a head brain
because you know the whole body's mind
but the head brain without its roots
which is the entire peripheral nervous
system right I mean I often use the
analogy of the the cerebral cortex
you know the head brain being the
flowering out of the roots of our
peripheral nervous system imagine
imagine a flower beautiful flower right
which is which is the head brain that's
a beautiful flower it allows us to be as
unique as we are as human beings other
animals have autonomic nervous systems
you know they don't have what we've got
so it's the flower of you know of the
world in many ways but imagine a flower
just like a flower in your garden
without its roots it ain't gonna fucking
last
there's no nourishment there
depersonalization as a form of
depression means that the energy is
depressed or removed from its roots from
the body you just don't feel the body
you don't experience you can't have
emotion you don't have feeling it moves
up into the head brain where it is very
dangerous because a without sensation in
your body there's no opportunity for
love
because the the head that's below the
head the brain that's below this head is
the brain in our hearts there's an
intelligence in your heart whether you
believe it or not it does not just by
coincidence that the poet say that love
is in the heart well how the hell they
figure that shit out love is in the
heart it's not just a metaphor it's a
reality and if you don't have feeling in
your body you don't have feeling in your
heart you will not experience life deep
personalizing from the love that's
allowed in the roots that are that are
brought up from the roots of your
existence your peripheral nervous system
down in your body it's not a life worth
living and in fact our friends the title
of his email a point of no return you're
right dude you've you've gone in a
direction I'm not gonna say you're right
there's no return but you're going down
a scary path I'm going to talk to you a
little bit about some ideas that might
support you but I just want to bring
significant emphasis to just how how
dangerous it is what you're doing and I
say you're doing it not to place
judgment on you because it's a big part
of the problem you had a lot of judgment
placed on you I say you're doing just to
give you a sense of empowerment you see
a lot of people do want to take
responsibility for their lives because
it's it's uncomfortable but at the same
time if you don't take responsibility
for your life then you have no power to
change it that's why I talk to you guys
the way I do
so I sound so frank and blunt sometimes
but it's because we've got to be able to
see the reality of the situation and
it's your doing they call it your karma
in the Indian Hindu tradition your karma
your doing that's what it stands for and
then one step lower and I leave I mean
lower literally and figuratively is your
sexuality you'll have no there's no room
for sexuality if there's no love in your
body because you're too depressed
depersonalized from your from your body
to deal with
so what I'm going to invite you to do
considering the the no roots that you
have in your childhood literally and the
no roots that you're experiencing in
your life right now physically the more
tormentas emotion academic quality
motion thought patterns ideas the more
aggressive depressive ugly for lack of
better terms bad if you will
thoughts that you Harbor give strength
to the depersonalization because it goes
up in your head so my first idea for you
is to boy
you already detached from the situation
and I think my first thing I wanted to
share with you is the idea that you got
to remove yourself from the situation
but you know I thought of that before I
made this video but now I'm going
through you know I described exactly
what's happened to see what that
depersonalization and the fact that
you've already removed yourself from the
situation is the problem my friend
you're going to have a potent experience
and you need to have it right now and
again this is just when I give you these
invitations I make these videos so that
you have ideas to consider it's a tough
thing that you're going to need to do
but you're going to have to feel all
that you're experiencing right now
you're depersonalization is the sin that
is your that is the bad thing happening
right now it is not necessarily at
you're failing school that's what I
originally wanted to get out I think I
just said it the right way
it's not about failing school so don't
and it's not about your mom being mad at
you those things seem like they're the
sin and they can get into your head and
have you feel more guilty about your
life but the real sin the real damage
that's being done right now
the real wrong is the depersonalization
you've got to come back into your body
my friend and you've got to feel what
your hot what's happening in your life
and I know it's not good but the further
depression and suppression and chaining
of the emotion in your body it's going
to make you sick forever it's like
ripping off a band-aid all the pain
associated with it needs to happen
powerfully and quickly in order for you
to experience the peace later on
otherwise that slow ripping off of the
of the band-aid is going to take forever
I hope you guys are following my analogy
so what you're going to need to do come
full circle and get to the point it's a
form of bioenergetics
you could see how sincere I am about
that idea of shaking your body and
hitting your body and going through
catharsis and just going crazy so that
you can feel your body again so many of
us are depersonalized you're
experiencing a very concentrated form of
it and it's happening early in your life
but you know I think it's happening to
us earlier and earlier anyway but you're
gonna have to cry you have to yell
you're gonna have to fucking scream
you're gonna have to get back in your
body allow yourself to have the emotions
that are associated with the anger that
you're experiencing you're angry and you
should be fucking angry everybody left
you when you were a kid your big brother
died and your mom checked out your dad
was never there
you ought to be fuckin angry about they
didn't give you roots they didn't give
you your body and who you've become as a
manifestation of that and the only thing
left now for you to do is get your body
back get your heart back at your balls
back even though you've never been
taught how to use it or it's been
stomped on or ignored
more more likely early on in your
childhood explore different categories
techniques of body meditation body
psychology I would invite you to start
doing yoga that would be a very easy and
soft way to begin bringing feeling back
into your body yoga and deep breathing
any type of deep breathing exercise I've
been using a lot of Qigong recently
because a friend Paul check taught me a
new one and he said Elia do this for a
hundred days and I've been doing it with
the cathartic type exercises you can
find meditations by Osho dynamic dynamic
meditation look that up Oh sh Oh dynamic
meditation and if you can find a
one-on-one person to work with you in
body psychology or bioenergetic coaching
you see I'm not a psychologist I'm not a
body psychologist I just find these
ideas interesting and I want you to
explore them because I feel like they're
the tools that are going to support you
all in becoming the strongest version of
yourself I don't say this shit just
because it's uh it might be entertaining
or or I don't know fascinating for
entertainment but I say it because I
know that they're going to help you and
you my friend need to get back into your
body get your heart and your balls back
you're gonna have to go through a tough
time right now not that you aren't
already but the thing is you are
checking out like your mom did from the
experiences of your life what I'm asking
do is jump right back into it I hope
that helps you I'm done