we have a question here from our German
friend by the name of us Khan he is a
drummer
he's a beat boxer he draws comics they
play sports like table tennis badminton
he lifts there's a lot of really cool
shit in fact here's a video of him
beatboxing I Wisconsin problem is that
he doesn't know where to go in life what
do you see what is his final destination
in fact that's the title of his question
is what is my destination well your
final destination is death because
that's all of our final destination but
he's wanting to know how am I gonna take
all of these various strange loves and
talents that I have and be somebody
right because that's really what we're
all told we need to do we need to become
something or become somebody you know
from the time we're little kids what are
you gonna be right that's the that's a
fucking question that the P that people
ask us adults asks what are you gonna be
as if there is a fight there's a real
fucking answer to that because human
beings are very linear and we end up
somewhere right you know that I'm being
sarcastic here's the thing bro there are
a few different things I want to share
with you number one I don't know what I
am going to be when I grow up I have no
idea what my final destination is and
I'm not attached to it what I do is
follow the beat of my heart and wherever
it takes me is where I'm gonna dance bro
right you understand that beat because
the beat makes you move and if you
listen to the beat you're gonna move and
if you keep moving you end up somewhere
now the point of the dance is not to get
to the end of the dance the point of the
dance is just to dance that's it bro
just like when you're making your music
just like when you're drawing your
comics just like when you're doing all
the things that your heart beats to and
that is life it's not that's where I'm
going and I'm going to do everything I
can to get there people would like to
make you think that that's the way it is
but it's not hasn't been my experience
now
here's the bad news because I made a
video I uploaded a video a couple days
ago called when you follow your heart
you're also going to break it and I got
to tell you man
this world is not designed for people
that follow their heart no judgement not
good or bad but here's the thing if you
do choose to just follow your heart
right
meaning I'm just going to go with the
flow whatever happens is what's going to
happen as long as it's my own beat
you're going to face those who think
you're out of your fucking mind you're
an idiot you're a moron
you're lazy you're unmotivated you're
they're going to give you they're going
to all types of reasons why you are
wrong for simply following your heart so
for the very first thing you're going to
do is you're going to break your heart
because of the bonds that you would
potentially have with the people that
love you because the people that love
you or the people want to control you
the most it's just the way it is then
there's the whole rationale behind well
you need to make a living right well
true you need food you need shelter you
need some of the basics of what it what
it requires to live somewhat pleasurably
in this world right mommy and daddy want
you to be a lot doctor and lawyer so
that you know perhaps you can take care
of them when they're old and broke I
don't know what what is what it is that
causes parents to push their children
into professions that force them to deny
everything that they are their heart
their soul their gut their their their
their passion for success in the world
for what everyone has told you you need
to aspire towards but anyway they're not
going to like this
and he in that conversation that you're
going out till me have with yourself
that is just very rational I need to
make a living it's going to come up well
I can tell you this that you do need to
find a way to make a little bit of money
so that you can put food in your mouth
and maybe have some of the traps ends of
the world but beyond that you really
don't need to strive too hard to make
like I know you mentioned in your email
100 million dollars because you can't
eat hundred million million dollars you
can't snuggle up with a hundred million
dollars and if you sell your soul for a
hundred million dollars you can't buy
the motherfucker back once you sold your
soul money doesn't get it back getting
rid of the money gets it back you know
this is one of those Jesus things where
he's like you know the richer dude can't
buy his way into the kingdom something
of that fact and it's not because
money's bad money's not bad money's a
means by which we trade trade is a good
thing because human beings need each
other but there is a there's another
part of you another intelligence that
needs to be honored and you and you can
ask hundreds of thousands of honest men
and women in their 50s and 60s or so
forth they're going to they no one ever
will tell you at that age that I'm
regretful for following my heart but
they'll always tell you I'm regretful
for spending too much time working
spending too much time in my business
not enough time with the people I love
where does love happen in the heart
doing the things I really love happens
in my heart so one of the things I often
share in these videos is that you know
if you choose to follow your heart
you're damned and if you choose to
follow your head you choose to follow
the world and civilization you're damned
you're damned if you do you're damned if
you don't you're fucked either way I
would just like to be fucked while
owning myself while other people are
fucked while being slaves
it's your choice bro but I will tell you
based on my own experience if you just
listen to your heart you follow the beat
of your heart you'll be okay
study a little bit about how to make
money right I mean it's not a big deal
it's it's so
nevah it's a prop you gotta find a way
to prop up that thing that you love you
see I love talking in this way I love
coaching I love making these videos I
found a way to prop it up by studying
marketing studying business I haven't a
find that there are many different ways
that I can actually art a good living by
making these videos right besides just
the the ad revenue that comes from it
which is pretty fucking awesome so
realize that it's just a prop you got to
find a way to prop up to stand up that's
what it means to stand up to probably
prop up the the product of your heart's
desire the product of your heart desire
is that making noise with your mouth
right which is fucking awesome it's
really cool find a way to prop that up
and there are many different ways to
prop it up depending on how much time
you want to spend on developing the prop
and what type of life you want right you
have four children
I've wanted a life with a like abundance
so I gotta find I got to spend more time
than most I've had to spend several
years figuring out like how to make some
money without selling my soul you might
just want you know you might not ever
want children well that's cool dude then
the prop could be as easy as putting a
bucket out in front of the going in
front of the museum or somewhere
downtown putting a bucket and just
making your mouth noise dude you might
make like a hundred bucks a day that
your bucks today is a pretty good living
for a single dude be okay with that
though don't watch rap videos and think
that you need to drive a Maserati right
you see that's where we get this is
where we get tangled up with what the
world has us wanting to expect you don't
need a fucking Maserati you don't need a
boat you don't need four houses do you
see mean food on your table that's it
man done