everybody evening is a 21 year old
virgin and in fact he hasn't been in a
relationship yet at all and it here's
the thing he's not a bad looking guy he
says this is actually pretty
good-looking and girls like you know
like his body and the way he looks and
stuff like that he's just always been
too shy to be with any girls and I was
21 years old and his problem is not that
he hasn't had sex but when he does have
sex he feels as if he will be an
embarrassment he'll be embarrassed
because here it is 21 most people have
already had sex maybe great sex which
you know again I spoke about this one of
the videos what does that actually
fucking mean and and now here I am a
virgin as an adult and if I have sex
with a girl that I'm trying to be with
you know perhaps build a relationship
with she's going to be she's not going
to like me I'm gonna let her down
because my sexual expression is that of
a boy first time I'm putting myself
inside a woman and and it's probably not
going to be pretty and it might not be
here's what I want to offer you here's
the thing that I think we all need to
understand at a very core level is that
sex is not just a penis in vagina
experience it is a lining up of the
hearts the minds and then ultimately the
genitals the penis a vagina of two
individuals in our culture internet and
probably in your experience the best way
to attract people is up here this is
where we start we start with talking hey
you know hey you're cool I'm cool little
you will be like these things it starts
here so we're making a mind connection
with another individual and a lot of
times most people are just mind people
most people just mind and dick people
head and dick head and dick head in
vagina and vagina most people's hearts
are very closed there they don't even
feel their own hearts expressions we've
closed out our ability to love our
ability to share our ability to
experience other people at a heart level
so my invitation to you is to find
someone obviously that you connect with
here but work
seriously in the beginning to build up
heart emotions with her and put yourself
in a vulnerable place you already are
vulnerable but the more you own it speak
about it and then you to the other
person lean on the other person the more
they will appreciate your shortcomings
right and that's not to say that this is
a perceived short coming it's not a real
short coming but it's a perceived to are
coming in perception is reality so you
need to find a woman that loves you
first you need to find someone that you
love you deeply and truly love that way
the sex that first experience is more
than just okay mr. happy can we make it
work I don't know my dick is not gonna
work because you're gonna be in your
head because you're nervous and you're
going to be expecting your debt to do
something which is kind of like what I
always talk about the head making the
body a slave the pendulum through which
the head and the balls swing is on the
heart that's the apex that's where we
reach people begin with love I know this
all sounds like hippie shit but find a
woman that truly that you can truly
experience love with warm feelings even
when you hold each other bring your
hearts together hug bring your hearts
together and breathe into your heart
with her and visualize our hearts making
love our hearts having intercourse first
and then when you look deeply into her
eyes and you're ready to put your body
inside hers she will accept everything
you give her no matter what it looks
like because the deeper level of
connection has happened that's your
first experience fucking like animals
and having wild crazy orgasm sex that'll
happen perhaps later don't don't try to
be stroking King the first time the
first time unit its if you want to waste
the first time go into it with I'm gonna
be stroking dokie king of the world and
you can you try to do the porno thing
lay chest to chat
with her body to body eyes to eyes put
yourself inside her and she will receive
all of the beauty of the strength all
the power that's within you and that
means far more than how many times a
stroke because