how do you remove yourself the emotions
that you feel when someone's not getting
it but someone like you know they have
it in them and they're just not pushing
through like they're the biggest but
they're their own obstacle course and
we're just they can't get out of their
own way so how do you remove yourself
from that emotion of like and I really
want to help you in like it just drains
your energy how do you stop that how do
you remove yourself when you care so
fucking much we got a puppy it's uh it's
khalil gibran on children the profit but
basically talks about how much parents
begged in order to propel their children
because I mean this is your client that
came in they gave you money they became
from you that's so the emotion
associated with wanting that person all
right is the investment is so much more
great I want you to have I could shit
but so what I'm doing is I'm I'm really
putting your situation about steroids
it's like what happened to a child that
doesn't do what you want it to do I know
you
succeed I want so much for you why can't
you get through your head remember my
dad even saying this shit's me I want so
much beauty would say weird shit like I
cut my hand off you have to just get it
right figure it out why can't you just
do the right thing I can't do the right
thing that's the right thing cuz if
those loops above do all the right
things I would be standing here right
now I didn't have the opposite to what
he wanted anyway within the poem he
tries to gauge the parents understand
that although the child comes from you
the child does not belong to you have
been chosen as a servant to that child
or individual and as a servant do you do
in a detached fashion and you do
everything that you feel is right from
you within you to support that person
without personally identifying the
result I'm giving you everything I have
or whatever happens is completely yours
my dad would even say that to me he
would say you this is funny my dad would
say this all times like I'm gonna give
you 100% everything I got then I'm
washing my hands that's what he was
saying and those you never wanted them
to watch this hand is wash my hands when
I washed my hands I did it all the right
things
let God look at the universe and all
this happened then you happy you plant
the seed
my dad's a gardener
you plan to see you water it but you
don't like spreading seeds someone with
balls on rocky ground some of it falls
amongst to leave some of it is taken
away by a bird right someone we call
them on programming grows into a tree
that creates more seeds but it's not the
farmers fall what happens to the seat he
sowed the seed your putting every if you
could say mister business my daddy he
would say I feel good about everything I
did you could say I feel good about
everything and say this to your clients
I'm giving you 100% I have given you
everything that I have but I've washed
my hands the result you give everything
all you do is you put in and feel good
in your heart that you put in everything
that you've got and then you let
everything you let it happen
let's see what this says actually you're
chipping khalil gibran on children your
children are not your children they are
the sons and daughters of life's longing
for itself they come through you but not
from you and though they are with you
yet they do not belong to you you may
give them your vote but not your
thoughts when they have their own cause
you may have their bodies but not their
souls for their souls
in the house of tomorrow which you
cannot visit not even in your dreams you
make strive to be like them but seek not
to make them like you for life goes not
back their retirees yesterday
you are the boughs this is actually what
I thought this you are the boughs from
which their children as living arrows
are sent forth the archer sees the mark
upon the path of the infinite he bends
you with his might and his arrow may go
swim and far let your bending in the
archers and feet or gladness but even as
he loves the arrow that flies so he
loves the boat but a stable if that
momentum for what I thought