kind of great question for my buddy will
who is 18 he's an actor he lets us know
that he's agnostic and so never really
believed in a god he also has this idea
very intelligent really smart kid and
talks about how you know as primal men
we had the purpose of survival and today
now that civilization has been created
we really don't have to survive anymore
so we end up you know making up all
types of crazy shit to do in order to
occupy our time and he says religion is
one of those things so you know now he's
questioning whether or not he should
adopt a religion because he sees a lot
of his religious friends with a purpose
you know spread the gospel or go to
heaven whatever they Cakes maybe he sees
them with a purpose and he wants to have
a purpose because he believes that since
man has developed all that it's needed
to develop to live comfortably we really
have nothing left like we've already
fulfilled our objective on this planet
this is this is wills assertion well
it's interesting that you're an actor
right and the reason why I say that is
because act in acting is a form of art
and a big part of what may you're
looking at this to scientifically as an
agnostic or atheist might a big part of
the contrast between what motivates men
are is science and art and science is
always moving forward science is always
like what's next what's next dig deeper
deeper deeper deeper deeper think more
think smaller
think small and it's moving in a
particular direction and it could be and
it's futile it's just what we do and it
can be exhausting and you feel
scientifically that we've reached our
pinnacle what else is there to do the
very first thing is that's probably not
true I think scientifically we're going
to we're gonna do a whole lot more but
it has to be balanced with something
that is apparently bubbling up in you
which is art poetry is what I like to
say you're an actor you
because you're trying to get somewhere
you don't act because you're trying to
achieve something right you don't write
poetry you don't sing music you don't
dance because there is an end in sight
it's not it's not a path that you tread
to achieve a goal it can become that but
then it becomes neurotic and it loses
its value you do it because you do it
you do it because humankind is designed
to dance to wiggle to have fun to laugh
to feel to express to create what I
would like you to do is to wrap yourself
in your acting become as many different
characters as you can because you can
because it's fun because it's an
expression of humanity that's the beauty
in poetry and in art it's not that
there's an end in sight you're looking
for an end you're doing because it feels
good perhaps you can find a way to earn
a living with it and that's great
but what's even better is that you feel
joy that you feel pleasure in your body
and that you're contributing to the joy
and pleasure of other people by creating
and sharing your art continue to act
start to dance start to sing start to
gain pleasure in the expression of your
body the way you see if you feel fit
become an artist let the science alone
for a moment if you decide to adopt
religion go about it scientifically
right so you kind of it's a balance
folks it's a balance between objective
subjective science and art religion and
math you see I'm trying to give you some
contrast here go about it as I'm looking
for a new piece of poetry to participate
in because it feels good
you see I you might call me an agnostic
you might call me an atheist because I
don't believe per se the stories that
are told literally by the religions but
I appreciate them I read the Bible I
love reading all sorts of Eastern
literature what they would call
religious literature
I really because the poetry is fucking
beautiful Regenesis I think that's the
best I think that's the most profound
poem that mankind has ever created I
don't believe that there was a big
bearded man that liked that breathes and
it in the book came and it's a divine
book right it's a cool poem though it's
a cool story to tell yourself it's
interesting it's fascinating oh yeah you
know it's a metaphor these are all
metaphors it's artistic appreciate it
for what it is I would say yes explore
religion explore Christianity at its
roots I'm talking like the Gnostic
Gospels I'm talking about the roots of
like what did Jesus actually think and
say that what the church tells us look
into the mystical forms of religion
Gnosticism as there is the is the is the
mystical form of Christianity the
Kabbalah I believe is the is the
mystical form of Judaism Zen is the
mystical form of Buddhism look into the
mystical forms of these faiths
because that's where you're going to
find a true poetry the true root meaning
of the messages that those brilliant men
that brought about the core of those
religions we're thinking you know don't
get caught up in symbols like most
people do with regard to religion so
that's it man I am excited for you
because you are going to now be able to
appreciate the power the potency the
pleasure in poetry peace