so the first thing I want to address in
this video is the fact that many of you
recognize that last night I removed the
video from my channel called my
girlfriend's that is an asshole now I
didn't remove the video because of what
i said in the video I roomed that
because of where I was coming from when
I created it was inauthentic and
ungrounded and for that i apologize but
i would also like to make it up by
creating this video today the content of
the video is that our friend is in love
with a girl they're 22 years old and
they live in egypt and the father of the
young lady does not approve of their
relationship for whatever reason even
though our friend wants to propose or
perhaps has already a pope or propose to
this woman the father has created a
situation where he cannot wear our
friend cannot get in touch with this
girl he's distraught he's wondering how
can he appeal to the father how can he
get through and create a situation where
he can be with his beloved and the way i
would like to see you approach this from
the depths of my soul from my core from
my heart is to see you work on
befriending the father i know that if
there's going to be a young boy that I
approve of in dating one of my daughters
it will be a boy that I have a
connection point with so often I'll joke
even though my children are very young
right now I'll joke and I'll say that
the boy that comes in dates my daughter
had better be able to deadlift or at
least attempt lifting a stone at my gym
doesn't mean that he has to be athletic
or gonna be a big beastly brute like I
am but I have to either try to find or
we naturally have created a connection
point and what you need to find with
this father if he doesn't hate you just
yet that might be the case but you
always can redeem yourself is a
connection point so instead of looking
at what you want look at the obstacle
and how you can get through it
but don't see the obstacle as an evil
see it as something that you can use to
work on your ability of coercion you
know I use that term loosely because
it's not meant to manipulate but it's
meant to figure out how to soften your
approach and allow someone to receive
you so find out what his favorite foods
are find out what his favorite beverages
find out what his favorite movie is find
out the things that he enjoys what's his
favorite sport does he enjoy playing a
particular strange game with cards find
out what really makes him happy but is a
bit quirky something that's a little hmm
it's interesting that you enjoy this
card game go and figure out how to play
that card game and invite him out one
evening and say hey look you know I know
we've had our rough patches I've been
playing card game a for a little while
and I know that you're really good at
that and that's something that you enjoy
doing would you like to meet up at a
place a bar or a restaurant and play
some cards sincerely your preach you
approach him with your feet on the
ground and your eyes focused on his from
a sincere place that you're trying to
reach out and make a really what is a
heart connection with the father don't
mention the girl when you guys hang out
to play cards don't mention the
relationship when you're having that
beautiful meal over some strange tea
that you know he likes don't bring it up
at all just focus on how you can
befriend him and over time perhaps very
quickly he might open up instantly and
say you know what I resisted you because
I didn't know you but you went out of
your way and you are now approaching me
from a level a ground that I'm standing
firmly on not you're not on your terms
but on his terms and you're approaching
him on his ground on his terms he may
very easily and quickly open up
say you know what I I didn't know you
and I didn't like you at first but it
this juncture I think you're an okay guy
I'm banking on the fact that you're
probably an okay guy your douchebag this
won't work once you get through to him
again in a very businesslike and
grounded fashion not ahead in the sky
excited and in love but very pragmatic
practical grounded and businesslike you
approach the topic of his daughter and
you speak in terms of concreteness not
love not poetry you don't want to appeal
to his poetry right now it doesn't sound
like he's a very poetic man to begin
with you explain what your intention is
don't talk about how you feel he's
probably not interested in how you feel
it's probably more interested in your
intention this is my intention with your
daughter and you spell it out like it's
a fucking business plan that you're
selling you're selling to a potential
investor very clear very grounded two
steps first open his heart by
approaching him in an area that he is
already open he already loves this food
he already loves this game and number
two you appeal to his mind by speaking
in very practical terms by your
intentions with his daughter good luck
buddy