yo Eliot what's up guys today question
comes from Andy he posted this on my
Facebook wall and I thought was pretty
interesting he goes on to say that he's
16 years old and he's begun weight
training and he's learning a lot more
about himself and it's been a good thing
but he also notices that he's getting
real arrogant he's self objective enough
to know and realize that his attitude is
changing but probably not for the best
he says that he feels this urge to just
argue with everybody especially when it
comes to the things that he's
experiencing even though he realizes
it's irrational I'm only 16 I only just
started weight training I only just
started having these experiences but yet
I think I know it all and I want to
fight with everybody including my
parents my mother my friends he says
that he's really hurting people because
he's lashing out and and saying mean
things
well first good on you man for
recognizing when you're being an asshole
I mean that's really the first step they
say that the the most pathological form
of ignorance is not knowing that you
don't know there's hopefully you dude
because you know that you don't know and
there's even more vote for you because
you're willing to ask for help so when
you describe your newly found power and
a sort of arrogance that comes with it
you're sort of describing what a Jungian
psychologists would call infantile
grandiosity or inflation you're starting
to feel yourself in traditional
societies when the older men recognized
a young boy starting to feel himself you
know getting too big for his britches
that's when they started the initiation
process that's when they would drag your
ass out into the woods tie you up and
make you jump out of a tree or fight a
lion or fight a bear or do something
crazy to really initiate you into what
it is to be a man rather than just
feeling like a man and we don't have too
much of that in our culture these days I
mean I don't think you could create a
liability form strong enough to support
taking boys out and having them fight
bears and shit but it's we kind of it's
unfortunate because what that does is it
it gives the opportunity well it does
two things that inflation is going to be
deflated whether you feel like it or not
it's going to come in the form of
humiliation right and that's really what
that is it's a form of humiliation which
leads to humility so it's going to be
then and because nobody's facilitating
this for us in our culture it's going to
be one of the other you're either going
to fall into humiliation because of your
attitude and your your complete
inflation someone's going to burst your
bubble let me put it that way you're
gonna walk around with you know all
high-and-mighty
and you're gonna say the wrong things
the wrong person and they're gonna chop
you down not necessarily punch you in
your mouth but they're gonna know a lot
more than you and they're gonna make you
look like a fool and then you're gonna
go home you're gonna feel like an
asshole
or if you've got a conscious conscience
or you'll look back you know I I trust
me I've got a lot of these experiences
look back like you know damn I was a
real idiot I look back at so many
instances where I was inflated and the
choices that I made in that state and
say damn I'm humiliated I feel like an
idiot
because in retrospect you realize fuck I
was I was literally possessed by demon
in some way so there is also the other
end of the spectrum where there is a
process by which you either choose
humility or you have it facilitated by
ritual elders things of that sort so
because there are many rituals and
ritual elders and initiation processes
what we have to do is ultimately create
our own humility by recognizing that we
are not the source of our power this is
where religion comes in as a handy tool
for us when we realize that like a light
bulb is not the source of its power you
are not the source of your power
you shine brightly in the same way that
that light bulb is shining brightly but
the light bulb isn't the source the
electricity is the source so by offering
your gratitude for the source that moves
through you that allows you to have the
power that you're exhibiting brings or
requires humility prayer thank you
humble submission to the Lord God Allah
thank you for making me giving me the
opportunity to be strong thank you for
giving the opportunity to be healthy
thank you for giving me the opportunity
to live in a world where I can increase
my intelligence with information thank
you to all of the all of what the source
provides you that you didn't provide for
yourself you see what I'm saying thank
you for your parents you're fighting
with your mom and dad but thank you for
bringing me into the world thank you for
the for the magnificent love attracting
energy that brought you guys together
that allowed you to have sex and make me
thank you for the food that you guys put
in this put on the plate so that I can
grow stronger thank you to their job so
that they can buy the food that they put
on their on their food on your plate
there's so much to be thankful for
submit your humility to the source that
gives you the power that you're
exhibiting and it's all around us we're
swimming in it the other one is too and
religious people would say repent for
your sins know that you're a sinner born
a sinner right there's all types of
associations with it but if you look at
it practically it's you don't know
everything
realize that you are limited in that
which you can see and we are we can't
all know everything we live in a
space-time continuum and all we can
really say we know is what we're
experiencing at this moment because you
can't predict the future and the past is
dead you know nothing all information
that you think you know and that you're
regurgitating is merely dead form that
you've adopted from someone else all you
know is your current experience so you
know nothing realize your ignorance
understand your sin
and finally ask for help realize that we
need each other and that there are those
who if we are humble enough to approach
should be approached to support us when
we think that we gain all of our power
through our own efforts and that we know
everything and nobody needs to help us
that's when we spiral down into the
depths of depression and anxiety
frustration and a very uncomfortable
life done Eliot's it what