so guys hey we got a question from our
buddy in crypts
he says that he discovered my shunt camp
Channel not too long ago and my best of
yo Elliott videos have really inspired
him to turn his life around and now he
goes to the gym everyday and this is
good because before being inspired to go
to the gym and start training in the
morning he says between 9:30 and 11:00
he was sort of depressed didn't feel so
good about himself things weren't going
the way he wanted to especially
internally you know a lot of negative
self-talk but when he's at the gym and
shortly thereafter he feels great about
himself he loves being in the gym he
loves feeling the burn in his body whew
he loves the transformation that he's
seeing in his body his self-esteem is
growing and the endorphin rush that that
subsides
a few hours after your training I mean
anybody who exercises know-how knows how
a did thing it is to feel your body and
all the hormones and sweating like I'm
sweating right now it's why my shirts
off and I couldn't I wouldn't have it
any other way because it's my body
perspiring leaking water when you can
feel your body you can feel your
brilliance feel the beauty of life and
your body that's why exercise is so damn
important it's less about what you
become physically meaning I'm going to
lose weight or gain weight and more
about the experience of feeling your
body the experience of experiencing your
body now he's got a problem
he says you know I understand that I've
been I've lived a life up until this
point is in his mid-20s surrounded by
negative people and you know it's a it's
a part of the reason why he has a lot of
negative self-talk
and I feels down about himself come
evening time he says you know once the
day is starting to wind down and I'm by
myself he says you know I feel lonely I
don't have anyone because I feel so bad
about myself
I don't extend myself towards people
because I feel bad about myself and now
I'm alone by myself and I hate myself
can't even stay in being with yourself
how could other people stand being with
you if you can't stand being with
yourself and I understand it's like well
I might like myself more if other people
like me but my man the world is your
mirror I love you and this is why I
offer you this
you're creating this circumstance now I
don't blame you for the negative
self-talk because you know we are we're
all offered the challenges that we need
in life all of our pains come for a
particular reason so that we can grow
strong or inspire others however God has
decided for us on this plane but now
listen there's something you can do
about it and in fact you're beginning to
realize that there's more for you in
life and your spirit is about to evolve
my man
you are on the path to becoming a
stronger version yourself let's talk
about being with yourself because that's
the first place you're going to have to
mend the pain nourish the soil and grow
some beautiful flowers here's my
invitation to you you've already
discovered the power of going to your
body for feeling good it going to your
body does a number of things it gets you
out of your head in the head is a monkey
mind you know there's a lot chatter
going on in the head and most of the
chatter
you don't own most of the chatter going
on in your head is chatter that was
given to you at particular times by
people so your mom saying yeah you're
just like you're dead and I hate that
motherfucker well that gets in your head
especially if you're very young and you
receive that and it's my mommy
why would mommy say some shit like that
it's damaging a teacher who told you
were too stupid a girl who told you
you're ugly
my best friend who left you for another
friend because they've got better video
games whatever it is all these things
happen to you and then you turn on the
TV and the TV says you you know you had
ought to be afraid you should be scared
right now because there are there are
threats there are threats to your safety
or other commercials that are like hey
you're not good enough because you don't
drive this car and look at this man he's
got sexy sunglasses on and you hmm don't
even have any do you see so the world is
constantly telling you why you're not
good enough so you have to be very
mindful be very skeptical of your own
conversations be very skeptical of
what's going on in your head especially
if it's unrooted or ungrounded from your
body so go into your body gets you out
of that bullshit round about monkey talk
conversation in your head
and it also stimulates the pleasurable
feelings joy that is experienced in the
body joy and pleasure are not abstract
things you see UK that's why money
doesn't make you happy because money is
abstract when he is a thing outside you
even nice things nice cars nice homes
nice clothing again there's still things
outside you so they may stimulate you
for a moment even other people other
people may stimulate you I got a hot
girlfriend now
they might stimulate you from the
outside but again those things you don't
own because there's no intrinsic feeling
tied to it
joy can't happen if you're not feeling
it in your body it's not joy it's an
idea of joy but it's not joy if you're
not feeling in your body pleasure Oh
pleasure happens only in the body you
can't think pleasure
you can think pleasurable thoughts that
help your body feel pleasurable and
that's something we're going to talk
about in a moment but pleasure happens
in the body so you're going to have to
find and I'm going to teach you
different methods by which you stimulate
joy and stimulate pleasure in your body
that's not just jerking off because most
you guys jerking off ain't even enjoying
the jerk off I can promise promise you
that you're so rigid that you're
probably just like you can't wait to
bust the fucking nut you know true joy
and pleasure take it comes and taking
your time the body takes its time you
understand
so anyway it's for a different video
what you're going to do is this my
friend I invite you to dance now of
course I made a video last week where I
was doing a very vocal revolve tents I
was a vocal a particular spirit because
of the type of video but in the evening
time I'm going to invite you to do this
put on soft music and upbeat music I
like oh Tamar Lea Burt Oh tomorrow o TT
o mor Leibert li e BR
really that's it but he plays good
flamenco guitar flamenco flamenco with
the guitar it has a tremendous ability
to get the body doing this
close your eyes and notice I'm not even
dancing well I don't have the music
right now and I'm a little rigid because
making these videos today but I want you
to get into the flow where the music
just carries you you don't even have to
do any type of fantastic dance and if
you if the energy rises in your body
where the dance becomes celebration let
it become a celebration if you get tired
in your celebration don't judge just
come down and let the dance be a soft
dance to things I'm going to ask you to
do when you dance three things actually
they all support one another number one
be mindful of your breathing never stop
breathing and breathe deep breathe
heavier just like you were running or
you're exercising see how much better
I'm dancing now this is breathing the
other thing try not to let your head get
too stiff so move your head a lot you
got hair whip it around and number two
number three don't get caught in a with
mikhyl rut meaning if you if you're
dancing like this don't stay here longer
than 1015 seconds then do this doesn't
do this don't do this you see you keep
moving keep expanding your range of
motion keep expanding your body's
ability its capacities go down and then
bounce from the round go up go back go
front do the hokey-pokey throw yourself
around getting your body but what you're
doing now is as opposed to weight
training which I of course I love also
which is very regimented and very
restrictive you're just moving in this
particular pattern over time you are
opening up your creativity you're
opening up your spirit you're opening up
your body you're opening up your nervous
system to lots of different experiences
all related to breathing letting go and
pleasure just say do this of course
you'll be by yourself and this is the
process doesn't end there
spend yourself listen to two three four
songs if you want to
some days maybe just one but dance the
whole idea is to dance until you've let
yourself go into the dance this is a
process of learning is going to take
some time because many of you are very
rigid your bodies and your minds are
very rigid if you cannot dance you're
lacking you're lacking you're lacking
and you're also never going to
experience pleasure oh and the pleasure
that's available to you if you can't
dance and sway your hips and move your
hips you're never going to have a full
explosive transcendent orgasm that
should be available to a man oh I want
you guys to be happy I want you to enjoy
life when you're supposed to enjoy it
which is always right life isn't always
the better roses but the stories you
tell yourself and the way you engage
with your body allow you to have a
pleasurable experience most of the time
so you're going to dance my friend spend
yourself to the point where you should
be breathing and then just lay on the
floor now when you lay on the floor my
man just go deep let your body feel
heavy get as heavy as you possibly can
on the floor there meaning all of your
muscles relaxed and you don't move an
inch
let your body grow heavy whoo continue
breathing don't restrict your be it
breathing and then smile smile from your
heart smile in your face and in your
heart in your belly and begin affirming
that the beautiful relationships are
making their way towards me right now
the people I love love me and are making
their way to me right now
even if I don't know their name I'm so
happy and grateful now that new
friendship in love is making its way
into my life
that's it that's the one I am so happy
and grateful now that brand-new
friendship and love is making its way
into my life right now and exhale now
your brain watching yourself
you put yourself into a very resourceful
place to be brainwashed because when
you're in that passive place of deep
meditation your nervous system is ready
to absorb whatever you give it brainwash
yourself my man cuz the world's already
doing it but they're dropping shitty
seeds in you now you're planting
beautiful plants beautiful roses
beautiful flowers and your life will
grow and bud in that particular way
blessings brother done