so the content of today's video actually
comes from a request or a favor that one
of my viewers asked his name is Joshua
and he goes on to describe how a good
friend of his Ashley is a fan of my
videos the favor that he asks is that I
number one say happy birthday to Ashley
he says that it would totally make her
day so I'm happy to make your day Ashley
happy birthday and the other thing that
he describes is the fact that Ashley's
going through some tough times right now
it didn't give me any details but let me
know that that she's having some
difficult times and by having my sharing
the happy birthday wish would bring some
motivation or inspiration to her so
beyond just the birthday wishes I'd like
to offer you a perspective on hard times
difficulty in pain I'll start with a
story yesterday I stayed home in the
early part of the day to watch my
youngest son Benjamin while Colleen my
wife took my three oldest daughters to
the dentist and as I'm sitting in the
living room with Benjamin not comes to
the door and two beautiful women show up
and I opened the door they're holding
their Bibles so I instantly recognized
that there probably Jehovah's Witnesses
two beautiful women who wanted to talk
to me about spiritual matters so I had
to oblige
we went outside and she offered a quote
from Scripture and the point of the
quote that she offered was that there's
going to be a time when God will or
won't they call it God but I'll say God
or Allah or the universe because I'm not
attached to the name there's going to be
a time when there's peace on earth and
there will be no pain to any of us I
listened intently and and try to get
some clarification as to what she meant
by pain
so she goes on and points to my son
who's standing there and said obviously
your wife had some pain labor pains
birthing pains while bringing forth your
son and as she recognized through the
pictures on the wall that I have four
children so my poor wife suffered four
times through labor and birthing pains
so she goes on to ask me if I would take
that pain away from my wife while she
was laboring and giving birth and I
instantly answered with a resounding no
absolutely not that in fact that would
probably be one of the worst things that
I could do because I recognize that
biologically there are hormones and
chemicals that are supporting my wife
and my children as they go through those
pains there are all types of magical
changes happening in the body and in
mind when you are going through pain and
just particularly the birthing pains
that was probably a bad example for her
to use so I stepped in with another
example I described how I've been
bankrupt frustrated sick sad depressed
sleepless nights for months on end while
I'm trying to build a business right and
this was it's not that tough anymore but
a few years ago when that was the case I
had to go through that pain I can tell
you right now that the maturity level
that I carry with regard to perspective
on different parts of life are a direct
reflection of the pain I suffered in
order to get to where I am and my wife
is not the same person that she was
prior to having all the birthing pains
that were associated with bringing forth
our children my point was that a life
without pain is a life without challenge
and a life without challenges of life
without growth so not only do I embrace
the challenge embrace the pain
associated with challenge and growth but
I even look forward to it in many
regards some people think I'm strange
but sometimes I even ask for
send me a challenge God that you think
should rid the world of pain
I invoke please give me some challenges
here because I need to be tested I need
to be stronger I need to grow in my
resolve with whatever weakness is in my
character pain is a beautiful thing
Challenge is what life is about a life
without challenge a life without pain is
a life without growth and where there is
no growth there stale stagnant energy
and that's where most people live
because most people's lives are designed
around treading a path that is void of
challenge the minute they recognize
challenge or pain they move the other
way this is a primal instinct and normal
and natural but a weak perspective most
people are bored if you ask them what do
you think about your life huh same old
same old every single day what it was
the thing same day same shit different
day things of this nature that's because
they're living their lives in a lie that
is shrouded in comfort it doesn't exist
they're not challenged they're not
growing they're bored and they're better
off dead
your likeness is found in your pain
embrace it love it and grow from it
happy birthday and I wish you more pain
Elliott said what