all right I got a question from our
buddy alpha Fox he's 21 years old he
dropped out of college because for
whatever reason he didn't know what he
wanted to do and he didn't want to keep
racking up debt the thing is now he's
back at home living with his parents and
they keep telling him you got to go and
get a job you got to go and do something
and he's rebelling against this idea he
doesn't want to go get a job so he stays
at home you know and he doesn't go to
school doesn't have a job doesn't want
to get a job fears this idea of working
for the next 20 30 40 years doing
something that perhaps he doesn't love
in order to earn a living what he really
wants to do is be a wonder lust that's
my term he says he just wants to go and
travel I want to go and travel this is
what I want to do right so this is a you
a lot of you guys watch my videos come
to expect a particular type of answer
from me but don't expect anything from
me because I'm approaching you from
where you're at and with you my friend
alpha Fox you got to get off your ass
and go and do something the fact that
you've dropped out of college is neither
here nor there that's already done
you've already you've already made that
decision and you're at home we don't
need to approach that the thing is now
but you've got to go and do something
and you had better go and do something
that you can be very good at staying at
home and thinking about and wishing and
reading about what it is that you'd like
to do or trying to escape because that's
really what your whole idea of traveling
is it's this prompting within you that
wants to physically remove yourself from
the situations that you're in guess what
the only problem with traveling no
matter where you go in the world you'll
still be there
the problem is you it's your paradigm
it's your mindset it's how you're
proceeding in the world you are coming
from a place where many young people
come from many Americans many many
people I can't just say young people
because I meet some old people too and
I'm like dude you still feel as if
you're entitled to something you're
still very lazy you don't understand the
principle of hard work the principle of
commitment and discipline
the truth the principle the reality of
sowing and reaping life is work life is
getting up and doing what you have to do
every single day whether you feel like
it or not life is making a commitment in
a particular direction and moving with
fierce intensity every single day making
every single day a success in that
particular direction you don't always
feel good you don't always get what you
want but you keep fucking going in that
direction
the problem now is your directionless
and you're looking for an escape route
okay you need to get off your ass and
I'm going to tell you what to do right
that's one of the things that you said
in this and you're in your question I
don't like everybody telling me what to
do well you asked me the question and
guess what Elliott Hulse is going to
tell you what to do you're going to go
and you're going to get a job but you're
not going to get just any job you're
going to get a job in sales the reason
why you're going to get a job in sales
is because your reward will be
completely tied to the amount of hustle
that you provide if I ever go get a job
or if I ever tell my children to go get
jobs it will be a job in sales because a
job in sales means that you don't get
paid until you become good enough to
make a sale that means personal
development on all levels you're no
longer just a cog in a machine you are
your own personal corporation you've got
to do whatever it takes become the type
of person it required is required in
order to succeed in that profession now
I what you sell is completely up to you
I would say it's better something that
you can become passionate about but
don't go get a job that doesn't require
you to man up in order to get paid okay
so there you have it I'm not going to
make this much longer than that you've
got to understand that life is work life
is uncomfortable life is about doing
what we have to do whether we feel like
it or not life is about becoming the
strongest version of yourself by
subjecting yourself the challenges that
require the growth
your strengths so that you can succeed I
understand why typical nine-to-five jobs
are not very enticing because there's no
risk inherent in it go and risk yourself
with a job in sales risk yourself such
that if you don't succeed you don't eat
move out of your parents house right as
soon as you start making a little bit of
money move out of your parents house
don't save up until you can don't wait
until you have enough you just make
enough that you can move out of your
parents house move into a you know one
of these one-bedroom apartments they
have them all over here you know you
just rent a bedroom one hundred bucks a
week go rent a bedroom and now your ass
is on the line you got to pay that rent
every single week that means you're
going to do what you have to do to get
what you need in order to pay that rent
you've got a hustle but hustling doesn't
happen until you make yourself
uncomfortable realize that discomfort is
the greatest motivator put yourself in
the position of true discomfort true
physical discomfort I mean you can't eat
that type of discomfort not just
bullshit I know I don't feel good about
myself
discomfort if you don't live in your car
that type of discomfort you go and you
become the strongest version yourself
and that will not only lead to your
ability to feed yourself but you'll be
able to take that take you take the
sentiment from which you proceed into
other career paths other endeavors
relationships and things that are going
to make you a fully functional and
successful person in this society good
luck dude