fearing the end of civilization the
world is fucked why bother
this is a question that comes from my
buddy William William is a is a very
active kid apparently he's in jiu-jitsu
he does yoga he wait trains he studies
he's smart but he's no pothead sitting
around dreaming up conspiracy theories
but he has been entertaining the ideas
associated with how perhaps the American
government the American Empire is
staging false flag terrorist attacks the
sadness in his heart that the Empire
that is fueled by our tax money is
killing children overseas the heaviness
in his heart and his body associated
with the death and destruction of where
civilization is going and all the all
the quote unquote bad things that are
happening are waiting heavily on him and
he doesn't he's starting to feel as if
you know like why bother why bother
doing anything if all this is up is
crumbling down around us there's so much
death of so much destruction even talks
about like rape and and all the bad
things that are happening the very first
thing is I would invite you to do and
I'm saying this from a place of
experience and empathy stop watching
Alex Jones or media outlets of that sort
and it's not because what he's saying
shouldn't have attention drawn to it
right I don't know if you're watching
him but there may be other things you're
watching but because you don't need to
fill your mind with the negativity it's
not resourceful awareness is resourceful
knowing having a perspective associated
with reality and that's what you said
here I'm not a conspiracy theorist I'm
just a realist having a perspective
associated with reality is great you
don't to be one of these like the
majority of naive buckets that support
all the wars that were going into and
and really have no clue about the death
and destruction that's going on or or
the the economic games that they're
playing with our currency and all the
bullshit that's going on by the leaders
of the world right to know this stuff is
cool cuz it's like hey look I'm not so
naive to think that like you know Barack
Obama's gonna save us all right I'm not
that stupid I realize he's a fucking
puppet and that there's a way bigger
game going on but once you have that
awareness it's transformative in and of
itself and you don't need to wrap your
mind around it you don't need to feel
your consciousness with all of what's
going on and it doesn't mean to be
callous it doesn't what I'm not asking
you not to care what I'm asking you to
do is to focus your attention on what
you're going to do now what's happening
don't focus on the death and destruction
it's happening it's sad if you wrap your
mind around it you will be depressed
it's horrific I just watched a
documentary about Native Americans and
and western expansion and the death and
destruction the ethnic cleansing the
genocide of the people that lived on
this land by the Europeans is horrific
saddening to the core awareness is
transformative of in and of itself but
now what you do is you get up and you
focus on how you're going to support
people and growing stronger how are you
going to become a stronger version of
yourself and support other people
because if you're not doing that your
mind is going to be left open for
negative influences to drag you down
into the depths of despair and
depression like you're approaching right
now you have to stop watching it you
have to stop turning on the news I don't
know what's going on with the news
people tell me you know I'll go on
Facebook and people be like oh bombs
went off in Boston I didn't get that
from the news I don't want to know and
it's not that I'm not empathetic it's
not that I don't care about my fellow
man it's I'm fucking busy I'm busy
growing stronger inspiring other people
I'm doing the work of good I'm so busy
doing the work of good and this all
sounds very strange because the
good and bad are a story we tell
ourselves what's happening on earth is
what's happening what's happening with
mankind is what's happening you study
Taoism the Taoist would be like it's
just the way it's just the fucking way
we attach good and bad to it people have
been dying this death and destruction
it's not new
that's kind of my point with the Native
American stuff it's not new we've been
doing this you mentioned the Aztecs
killing thousands of people 500 years
ago it's just what we do it's what human
beings do it's what happens on earth you
can call it bad or you can call it good
it really doesn't fucking matter you
decide what story you want to tell
yourself to me the story I tell myself
is this is happening it's a pop it's all
part of the evolution of mankind right
when they're part of parts of it I like
or don't like God or the universe the
DAO is not concerned doesn't really care
if I like it or not right that's my
story we have certain hang-ups and
attachments we become very attached to
the things that we like and don't like
but really the universe does not give a
fuck what you like or don't like it's
doing its thing it we are an extension
of the universe
we're an extension of God we're
extension of the earth the earth is just
it's just doing this thing and we happen
to be a part of it but what gives
humankind our magnificent abilities the
best of time is the worst of the times
is that we can detach from certain
stories tell ourselves our own
resourceful stories and do something
about the image in our head the image
that I that I grasp onto is a world
where there are men in particular you
know most of you guys are men men who
own their masculinity real masculinity
who are wise in the mind developed in
the spirit and strong in the body
come strongest version of themselves and
inspire millions of other men to do this
same thing it's the best of times it's
the worst of the times man look at this
I'm talking to you I'm talking to
thousands of you right now with this
little bullshit Sony camera it was made
in Japan talking to thousands of people
I just sent out my wristbands that the
people ordered last week I said one to a
UH to an island called the Isle of Man
which is like off the coast of Ireland I
sent them to Malaysia Singapore I sent
them to so many countries that I've
never even heard of some of these
countries I've never even heard of I'm
setting this tattoo we live in a time
where good can be spread just as rapidly
although perhaps more subtly than evil
we see the bombs dropping but what we
don't see on the news are the thousands
and thousands of young men 14 perhaps to
24 that are growing stronger through
what I've decided to do with my life not
putting up putting myself on a pedestal
I'm showing you how I focus my energy
I'm focusing my energy energy on growing
stronger myself which means exploring
new ideas trying new things out not
being afraid of experience becoming a
role model that can support other guys
and becoming stronger versions of
themselves because if I don't do that
I'm just contributing to the
fucked-up-ness of the world and you've
got to look at it that way also you're
no slouch bro you're doing a lot of cool
shit and there are millions of other
boys men people that would benefit from
a little bit of insight or wisdom from
you in the way that you choose to offer
it maybe you want to become a coach
maybe you want to build a business maybe
you create a non-for-profit organization
maybe you make videos like I do maybe
you write books maybe you make poetry
maybe you play the violin whatever it is
you're adding Beauty to the world you've
got to keep that balance if you let the
ditch death and destruction weigh you
down you're your
me an anchor to me and to the rest of us
that are trying to do something fucking
good
good they're trying to keep this balance
it's really that's all it is the good is
good can't outweigh bad and dad can't
outweigh good we can't have all having
to know hell there was if there was no
hell you wouldn't know fucking ever
heaven would be like who gives a shit
you gotta have a hell they're good evil
night Dave what's all fuckin day we burn
the fuck up night can't be all summer
you need winter it's just a balance
right as good as much good as I'm doing
for a lot of people I'm sure that
there's a lot of bad happening you know
why cuz every dollar I or I know what's
happening every dollar I earn from the
good shit I do goes to another drone
dropping a bomb on a kid in Pakistan you
can't you can't you can't win this game
you can't have all black you know white
you can't have all day and no night
you've got to realize this is just the
way it is that's that jinyang tai chi
symbol it's just the way it fucking is
okay
embrace it and do what's in your heart
what you've got to do is become more
subjective about this experience
stop looking out at what's going on and
you focus on you you focus on what
you're going to do and if in your heart
you believe that you have certain values
that you will not cross there are
certain there's certain things you just
won't do to get what you want in other
words you won't step on people's necks
you won't rape people you won't take
advantage of people you can't stand to
see your own hands hurting another
person right then you just don't do that
cuz you're you're you're working to
create balance by just supporting like I
said you know your tax money is gonna go
to some shit that you just don't like
hey you need you God needs the devil
devil is divine Lucifer is the light is
that is the angel of light it's all this
fucking mishmash how is the devil also
the angel of light understanding right
seeing cuz it's all one fucking thing
you can't get away from it you're going
to contribute to evil but you focus on
what your heart is telling you the earth
the God the universe is doing something
in you you just have to fucking do it be
very aware of what your body is that
signals your body is giving you if
you're breathing deep you feel good in
your body you feel grounded and feel
good
joyful pleasure you earn pleasure by
doing the things that you do and you
know you're in the right path just do it
you're gonna die I'm gonna die we're all
part of this evolving fucking thing all
right so that's it the most practical
information idea that I can give you
stop looking at what you think is evil
stop looking at the news stop reading
the newspaper get away from people who
are always new things are so bad you
choose what you're going to do what are
you going to do you develop your ability
to do that you go do that and that's
your only job we've got too much fucking
time in our hands we've got too much
information coming across to us get busy
doing something good luck