so yesterday I get a question on my
Facebook fan page wall from our friend
Val you must know what I think about
leadership it's interesting because this
is one of the things I spent a lot of
times thinking about and this is the
conclusion that I've come to because if
you have some form of ideal that you'd
like to share with people you can look
for different methods to share that I
deal with people and therefore lead them
so a lot of books are written on what
the right ideal for leadership is you
know what is the right thing to get
people to want to do right and there are
a lot of books written on methods how to
get people to follow you as a leader I
tend to think that both of these things
fall short and I'm coming to the
realization that leadership is actually
an internal phenomenon first it's
something that happens inside you that
creates a sort of magnetism whereby
people will follow you if you notice
there are many different ideals if you
look at a Hitler and you look at a
Martin Luther King both charismatic
orator tremendous speakers they use
their hands they use their facies
expression to draw people near them
tremendous ability their method is the
same but yet their ideals is
diametrically opposed both tremendous
leaders regardless of your personal
feelings towards the ideal being
presented one sought to enslave one
sought to liberate but yet both
tremendous leaders so we can't say that
the ideal is what's important right and
we can't say that the method is
important because if you consider a
mother Teresa again another tremendous
leader as opposed to a Alexander the
Great
Alexander the Great seeks to expand his
empire take over the world and he does
it with charisma and fortitude and
strength and power and vision a mother
Teresa seeks to give back the world to
give back that which is necessary for
healthy human development to those who
don't have both tremendous leaders both
diametrically opposed and use different
methods we could go all over the place
with this we have a Che Guevara and we
have a Winston Churchill both equally
convinced socialism capitalism equally
convinced you have a Barack Obama and
you have a Ron Paul equally convinced
but both yet as powerful leaders as the
other even if your personal conviction
is diametrically diametrically opposed
to an individual who has just as strong
or stronger conviction you've got to
share respect with that person Barack
Obama clearly is very convinced in his
ideals you know it's been discovered
that he's of a socialist mindset you
could say you like that or you could say
you don't like it but he's clearly
coming from a place of strong conviction
and that affords him the respect that he
deserves
I personally are not enrolled in his
ideals but I respect the man when he
speaks you know that he's speaking from
a place of heart-felt
conviction he's a great speaker look at
her on paul he's been able to mobilize
the hearts and minds of millions of
young people with his idea of liberty
and libertarianism he's old not very
good-looking
frail short small doesn't speak very
well stutters quite often but yet a
leader nonetheless my point here is that
it doesn't matter what you are doing how
you choose to lead and in fact that's a
very neurotic way to go about it how do
I become a leader it shows that there's
that there's ego it shows that you're
you're seeking to manipulate how do I
get them to listen to me how do I grab
them and make them go as opposed to
strengthening your conviction in your
ideal you know because even the ideal is
not necessarily as important look at a
look at a Hitler and look at a Martin
Luther King they both mobilize their
people with contradictory ideals but
it's the conviction that they had
individually within themselves that
matter
it's Kings conviction not how he went
about proceeding to share his ideal to
liberate it was Hitler's conviction not
the way he spoke his aura to order
skills or his idea that was powerful
so the takeaway point home the takeaway
point that you could take home with you
here today is that your conviction
matters far more than what you do or
even what your idea is to be a
tremendous leader means that you first
lead yourself become fully enrolled and
strengthen your conviction in whatever
it is that you choose and then the
method just happens you don't have to
follow a step-by-step formula right you
don't have to grab in control although
that is a method you've got a Jesus or a
muhammad jesus flips tables and tells
you come follow me
Muhammad goes in and breaks all the
statues and tells you what to think and
you've got a Buddha who sits under a
tree and waits for you to come equally
convinced that their ideal is the one so
to cut to the chase grow your own
strength of conviction and the path
toward leadership will be unveiled don't
copy or follow in anyone's footsteps
strengthen your own feet and stop your
own ground Eliot said what
you