his marriage slavery his marriage a form
of bondage or imprisonment that a person
that doesn't love freedom subjects
themselves to it's a really good
question it's a great question that I
was asked and exposed by one of our
viewers he points at me exposes me and
says Eliot you say you love freedom so
much and I love freedom I've come to
love freedom just as much as you but
there's a contradiction in the way
you're living your life and I'm a bit
confused
you say you love freedom but yet you're
married and on top of that you've
decided to have children I have four
children
why would somebody that loves freedom so
much subject himself to the slavery and
bondage of other people right before I
answer that question the way I think
today is very different than the way I
thought when I got married it's taken
some time for me to evolve into this
because I thought the same way that you
thought and maybe what I'm gonna share
with you is just a story I'm telling
myself but it might be resourceful to
you or someone else watching this I'm
gonna share it back in the summer of
1994 I was 14 years old way back in high
school was going into my sophomore year
during that summer I fell in love with a
teenage girl same age as me and it was
good it was very passionate it was a
love affair during that same summer of
1994 when I fell in love with a little
girl little teenage girl 14 years old
just like me I also discovered weight
lifting weight training training with
barbells subjecting my physical body to
the extrinsic force resistance of
barbells to build up my body and I fell
in love with it I became very passionate
about weightlifting and just like the
love and sexual affair that I had with a
girl my age when I was in the summer of
1994 I fell in love and had a passion
for weight training because in the same
way that the sexual relationship gave me
an instant gratification the weight
training gave me an instant
gratification because I started getting
stronger almost immediately
my muscles started growing not only that
but over the course of the next several
decades
I grew stronger became more a better
athlete 1 football scholarships and
today my life is a direct manifestation
of my choice in 1994 to pick up that
first barbell because what I do today is
I teach people how to get stronger with
barbells that's what I do for a living
that summer of 1994 was one of the
biggest probably the biggest turning
point or trajectory in my entire life
because that same girl that I had a love
and sexual affair with at the age of 14
I went on to marry and is now the mother
of my four children during that summer I
was very excited and passionate about
two things that have come to shape me as
a human being and is a direct tool it's
Who I am today my character is a
manifestation of those two things that I
fell in love with in that summer of 1994
now throughout my journey of a weight
trained as a weight trainer or strength
trainer the passion had died off because
in the beginning all I wanted to do is
read books and magazines about
bodybuilding and weightlifting it was
just I was fully immersed in a passion
of weight training that died off that
died off maybe about a year or two later
as well as the results that came very
fast because anybody who knows about
weight training knows that the results
come real fast when you start but then
it levels out but I stuck with it I
can't tell you exactly why I stuck with
it but I stuck with it I kept doing it
and I think it was because of the
passion and the excitement of that first
few months that I knew that if I stick
with this thing I might get that feeling
back again but what I discovered
while committing to the development of
my body through the extrinsic resistance
of weights barbells dumbbells was it not
only was my body growing on the outside
from time to time because that happens
in phases
you don't continuously grow was that I
was also growing character values on the
inside I was growing and developing my
character on the inside as a result of
the extrinsic resistance of the barbells
I learned more patience
I learned commitment I learned
acceptance I learned courage there's a
list about as long as my arm of virtues
that I developed as a direct result to
the extrinsic resistance of the barbells
that manifests itself in me today has
led me to make choices in my life and
develop me in such a way that I am Who I
am because of the barbells when I
started barbell training weight training
my grades got better in school I had
more courage to go out and do things
that I probably wouldn't have had the
confidence to do
had I not started barbell training had
the patience and the persistence to keep
going and the results would come again
because of the barbell training I am Who
I am in a great part due to the force
the the pain the subjection to
resistance of the barbells my life
change I am Who I am because of that
during that same summer when I fell in
love and had all the passion associated
with falling in love with this young
girl time went on and that passion went
away just like I did with the barbell
and as that passion went away for some
reason I couldn't tell you exactly why I
continued to stay with this girl all
through high school college and up until
where we are today and there were been
undulations just like there have been
undulations with the weight training
where things weren't going so well I was
frustrated with it couldn't get
longer these things happened especially
as the passion died off but I stuck with
it and when I realized as I stuck with
that extrinsic force of a person of the
opposite sex right that training myself
to be with this person because the same
way that we train at the barbells we
train in a relationship there's no final
point just like with training you'd ask
any old weightlifter there's no final
point you know 60 year-old weight
lifters tell you they continue to lift
because they continue to grow on the
inside even though their bodies have
grown old the same thing happens in this
relationship I started to recognize that
I was growing virtues on the inside
directly associated with commitment to
another human being the type of virtues
that I started to grow were patience
persistence right acceptance a lot of
the same ones were reinforced that I
learned from barbell training and so
many so many so many more more so if you
study the work of Aristotle he'll tell
you that virtue leads to freedom to be
truly happy
ie free you've got to become virtuous
but you only become virtuous through the
pressures of an extrinsic force you only
build muscle and strength through
lifting the barbells you only build
internal character values and virtues
through the extrinsic resistance of
another human being through the training
of a relationship and it's in the
training that we grow through the
barbell and it's through the training
that we grow through the extrinsic
resistance of that person of the
opposite sex so a lot of people get
married and they bump up against each
other and nobody grows the the the
growth of both individual individuals
character ceases because they just see
it as an extrinsic resistance as the
barbell laid upon you and you couldn't
pick it up you basically give it up well
the same things going to happen that
person lays on you
not necessarily sexually
- but they lay on you and you've got to
find a way to strengthen your virtues to
be able to pick them back up because
there's going to be a time when you're
going to lay on them and they're going
to develop the virtues to pick you back
up and this happens throughout the
relationship and you continue to grow to
where you're 80 years old like that old
bodybuilder and you say to yourself that
I suck with this thing through all these
decades not because I was in love like I
was in the summer of 1994 not because of
passion of any great degree but because
of the personal development associated
with committing yourself to the training
of a relationship so my friend I hope
that's helpful I hope that makes sense I
wouldn't confuse you with that analogy
but the point here is that subjecting
yourself to weight training is a crazy
thing that not everybody wants to do
because it's weird why would you put
your body under that type of pressure
just to get these so-called virtues that
may not even be important to other
people it's the same type of commitment
and craziness he'll be all crazy to get
married that you subject yourself to the
growth of your character through the
subjugation subjecting yourself to the
pressures of dealing with that other
person and as you both yield to one
another and both assert yourselves on
one another you grow you grow you train
you grow not everybody needs to get
married I'm not pro marriage or anti
marriage but the perspective that
marriage is not a love affair but a
training may shed some light on a new
perspective for how you go about that
relationship you grow she grows you grow
stronger through your commitment to
another person Elliot said what