a quick story for you this weekend I
walk into a restaurant with my four kids
so it's just me and my four children
between the ages of nine I got three
daughters nine and my son is three so
you can imagine me walking into a
restaurant it's kind of a an awkward
sight to see this man with his four
little white children I sit them down in
there they're so well-behaved that great
children in fact the music started
playing in the restaurant and two of
them got up and started dancing so they
were kind of entertaining people as well
but anyway I sit them down while I go up
to order their food and I get a tap of
my shoulder and of course I turn around
thinking like who's got to go to the
potty when in fact it was a beautiful
young fifteen year old girl who I could
tell was really nervous by the way she
was standing there looking at me and she
says I know you're Elliott Hulse I watch
your videos and I just want to thank you
so much for many of the messages you
share through your video because they
have been supportive to me on my growth
in my growth and maturity as a woman
growing in that way and I thought it was
fascinating not because someone tapped
me on my shoulder and said Elliott i
watch your videos it happens all the
time
but because it was a young woman not
typical usually it's a boy 15 to about
35 tapped me my shoulder and says Ellie
it's great to meet you thank you so much
for your videos I'm deadlifting Moore
and I don't have problems with my mom
and girlfriend any longer
something like that and we take a
picture and it's become kind of routine
but it was a young girl and and it stuck
out in my mind it kind of was a red flag
there it was kind of like well it's odd
that's interesting I know that there are
women that watch my videos not that I
know that that there are many of them
but probably about less than 10% so to
meet a young girl who's actually shared
the fact that my videos have helped her
was interesting to me
the next thing I know I went home that
day and then I checked my facebook
messages and I got a message from a
woman who I haven't spoken to in about
two years who used to be my massage
therapist but she had a baby and she
moved and we haven't really spoke we
really had no relationship whatsoever
besides the fact that she's my massage
therapist two years ago and she says to
me in this mail email Elliot you've been
showing up in my dreams recurring over
and over again I'm having these dreams
about where I need to go in my life and
some support that I might need in the
next evolution towards becoming a
stronger version of myself that's in my
words but for her basically is you know
making choices about who she wants to
become and you were there in my video in
my my dreams Elliot now of course I
watch some of your videos but it was
just interesting I decided to reach out
with you just to let you know that I'm
grateful for the advice that the dream
version of Elliot gave to me while I was
trying to make some decisions in my life
again you know red flag goes off I'm
like this is strange again not so
strange that someone is thanking me for
ideas that I may have supported them
with but because it was a woman again I
know that there are women out there that
watch my videos but twice in the same
day finally that evening my wife sends
me a voicemail sends me an email and the
email is from a young girl and I want to
read you the message that I read you
parts of the message from this young
lady she goes on to say Elliot recently
I have this thought that I was planning
on sharing with you
I've been holding holding it back but I
decided that it's really important for
me to share this with you please keep
reading and tell me your thoughts
she says Elliot I'd like to encourage
you to direct your message towards both
men and women I feel as though you're
selling yourself short by primarily
making men your audience as a woman your
message has been very applicable to me
in my life both directly and indirectly
I say indirectly because you should have
to a significant extent shaped my
boyfriend's worldview paradigms which in
turn has positively affected me
so I'm grateful for both the direct and
him by indirect impacts your messages
have had on my life and then she goes on
and and and gives all the reasons why
and she's very convincing why I should
broaden my message in order to reach not
just men but women because these words
are very potent and supportive to women
in their growth as well and and that I
shouldn't see men and women is
differently and recognize that world
growing in the same way although we have
you know penis and vagina very
intelligently laid out I mean the girl
knows how to write she knows how to
convince and uh and she just encourages
me goes on several paragraphs of why I
should during this time of ambiguity
where I'm I'm evolving personally
Elliott Hulse to take in consideration
that the next evolution of you includes
a message that is encompassing of both
sexes as she got me thinking because you
know they say when you get three knocks
at the door you should start paying
attention and all within a span of 12
hours I had a young girl come up to me
in the restaurant I had a message from a
woman I haven't spoken to in years and
this young lady sends me a message about
how my words have supported her and her
boyfriend and and that perhaps I should
broaden my message for women well worth
considering well worth thinking about
and something that I had to really
meditate on a few ways I'd like to
approach this conversation the very
first one is that I want you to know
when you see me in these videos when you
hear my voice and when you receive my
message
it comes from my purest authenticity
it comes from my purus sentiment I don't
shape my message for anyone in fact the
way I speak to you is the way I speak to
myself and all of the ideas all of the
wisdom all the paradigms all the tips
tricks and secrets that I share with you
through these videos are the same ones
that have supported me in my own growth
in my own life I don't have a
message that I formulated for mass
consumption I have I'm becoming the
strongest version myself and I'm sharing
that journey with others who are also on
the journey of becoming a stronger
version of themselves I'm just speaking
from my heart and I happen to be a dude
I happen to be a guy I happen to have
been an athlete I played football I grew
up in a locker room I grew up with with
brothers and uncles and cousins was
mostly men in my life a really good
great father great parents professional
strongman again it's just men I own a
gym and in my gym I train baseball
players football players power lifters
strong men mostly men
I began mentoring a lot of the men that
I trained in my gym young men high
school college-age young men in my gym
because they would ask me questions
about life after our workout sessions
its Who I am do you see I never went out
there and said like you know in
marketing one of the things they teach
you is you've got to choose your
demographic and then create an avatar
this is what they say who is your your
the market you're going after and when
you do that right because I don't even
consider it marketing when you go after
your market you want to make sure that
they fit other parameters outside of
that which you just are pleased by so in
other words I'm pleased by talking to
young men but if I want to make money
you know who I should talk to
fourteen-year-old girls because
fourteen-year-old girls are the biggest
most prolific market in the world right
that's why Justin Bieber is so popular
so you got to start considering these
things shit never work for me it never
worked for me to think of it that way I
talked to you the way I talked to myself
and that is it if you enjoy hearing the
things I have to say it good great if
you can't stand the things I have to say
or that doesn't resonate with you good
great doesn't matter I've used the
analogy before with
bird that sings from the branches of the
tree and someone drives bot walks by and
says boy you know what bird your song is
so beautiful I love you the birds just
like whatever I'm just singing my song
you like it great don't hold me to it
somebody hunt comes by later on throws
rocks at the bird and says Burgess
you're so fucking annoying why don't you
get down from there you woke me up this
morning and you're making my life
miserable
when the bird dodges of Rock and says
look dude I'm really just doing whatever
does I say and whether you like it or
not this is what I'm going to continue
doing and that's how I make these videos
so I wanted to make that very clear to
you at first first right I'm not really
formulating my message just talking I'm
speaking in the same way that the bird
sings whoever receives it great whoever
can't receive it you gotta understand it
wasn't ever my objective to create it
for receiving in that way right
everybody the other thing is that you
shed light on something that was that I
never even considered because of course
I've thought you know women would
benefit from some of the things that I
have to say and I'm perhaps I should
broaden my message you know I don't
think it hasn't crossed my mind but you
changed my mind completely and I don't
think you know what you did when you
sent me this message when you sent me
this message you perhaps thought that I
might change my tune and feminine up my
language a little bit right be a little
bit more like dr. oz and be Luke hold
you by your head and be a little bit
more of a gentleman
instead of saying fucking pussy every
other word maybe maybe I could get
through to Elliot he'll do that but I
want to thank you young ladies
specifically young lady who sent me the
email because of this very line in your
email
both directly and indirectly you have
impacted me I say indirectly because you
have to a significant extent shaped my
boyfriend's worldview paradigms the
greatest gift that I can give to women
of the world is to shape their
boyfriends in a way that they find
pleasing right
I'm not turning men into women panderers
I'm showing men how I've been able to
navigate my life also up until this
point to have to be able to produce to
be resourceful in the way that I am to
my wife to my children to my audience to
my craft to my work to the things that I
do and if that supports men in becoming
stronger version of themselves that
means you have more good men to choose
from women the world that we live in is
designed around pleasing women because
women spend more money than men so
whether you look at magazines you turn
on the TV the message is always pussied
up it's always feminine done right make
it so that women can enjoy it I'm in the
fitness market I get it you're right you
you want to create products that women
like to write so make sure you put a
little bit of green in pink in your
sales letter I get it because women
spend more money but my objective is not
to broaden my market so that I could
appeal to those who are not necessarily
of my vibration right I'm vibrating with
dudes
nor is it too broad in my market so that
I can make more money it's to be
completely authentically transparently
myself and if doing so makes men
stronger women will have better lives as
well
we've been gypped in a lot of ways us
men you see women and I want you to
understand that too and this doesn't
come from a resentful place it comes
from this is what I would have liked
when I grew up and that's why I give it
to the men who watch my videos we've
been gypped in so many ways it's sad it
should bring tears to all of our eyes
but our ancestors knew that girls become
women by biology through your biology
you go from womanhood from girlhood to
womanhood right what happens start
bleeding from your vagina
congratulations you can have babies now
you're a woman Nature gives you that
nature doesn't give men a delineated
period to the point in which we become
men but our ancestors created rites of
passages and we had communion of between
men that was that was unique in the way
that men need to be able to work with
each other so that the mad so the young
boy can become a man and so that he is a
resourceful member of the community
he becomes a warrior a brave he goes out
into the wilderness and he has to have
experiences I've read once I think
through Joseph Campbell about an African
tribe where the young man doesn't kill a
lion he's not allowed to mate with any
of the young girls in the tribe we don't
have that anymore as men I would have
liked to experience that I got I got
glimpse of glimpses of it through sports
glimpses of it through just communion
with you know some of the men in my life
and also some of the boys in my life I
thought about joining the military in
order to continue in that growth but
ultimately I ended up where most young
men end up and that is it that's lost in
a world that doesn't honor appreciate
respect develop uphold masculinity and
all that masculinity could be in its
full tenderness
and aggression I spent my life but I
continue to spend my life learning
trying to learn figure out how to live
in this way in a world that's almost
against men of course men rule the world
right you know the Oleg are key and so
it's all men up there pulling our
strings
that's a dysfunctional type of man and
there are all different types of shadow
men living in the world it makes it look
like masculinity is somehow aggressive
and evil and mean and that's why we got
so many feminists but that's not the
case that's not a fully grounded fully
self actualized balanced man and that's
not the type of male orientation that I
that I seek to develop in myself or
those who are inspired by my videos
and I do this for myself because that's
what I want I want to be the strongest
version of the masculine and I share my
challenges and my successes in that path
with the other young men and men in
general who need to hear that because no
one else spoke that language to them to
us so once again for all of you women
who watch my videos and I appreciate you
greatly know that my greatest service to
you is not the direct communication I
have with you and your challenges as
females in this world and I know you
have many and you've got your role
models and you need your role models but
because of what I'm able to do with and
for the men in your lives
done