got a question from our 24 year old
anonymous friend who also happens to be
a virgin so our 24 year old version is
dealing with situation where he has the
moral obligation based on a judgment
that his mother had offered him very
early on which is that sex before
marriage is wrong right and that's been
imparted on him right so now he uses his
head that piece of information to
control the other part of him which is
his dick and the penis wants to move
forward he he bubbles up he feels
sexuality you know he's been with with
women at certain times and the the
moment was ripe and the piece of
information that he received places the
moral judgement on the body and he backs
off things don't move forward I'm happy
to hear that your dick still works
really well because when we use guilt to
control people
we literally destroy the animal nature
in the human being we destroyed the
sexual nature of the human being in
every regard and guilt is not an emotion
guilt is a tool whereby a moral judgment
is placed on a real emotion see
sexuality is a real emotion it's energy
moving in your body so when you feel we
have blown feelings in your heart for a
particular woman and the energy rises in
you you get an erection that is an
actual emotion that's energy moving in
your body
guilt is a concept it's a tool that's
used to turn you on yourself so you
place moral judgment on what's happening
in your own body and then you end up
with this battle this cognitive
dissonance you don't know what to do you
I think the term is ambivalent you just
become like confused and it's like my
body wants to move forward I have these
room feeling but I've constantly
squashed pushed put down what is
happening in my body because a piece of
information that I had been conditioned
to to receive and have personally
received and use now here's the thing
because we can get very caught up in the
content
of this discussion right and I know a
lot of you guys can go way over your
heads and the comment section is going
to be all about like you know fuck that
religious bullshit and have sex because
it's what human beings do and then
they're going to be those that are like
the the moral situation is such that we
were better off not having said that
none of that both sides of the spectrum
whether he has sex or whether you have
sex with this woman or not or whether
sex before marriage or not is not
important it is neither here nor there
that is the content of the situation
what I invite you to do what I write all
of you to do in all of what I offer here
in almost 100% of these videos is to
consider the context through which you
are proceeding I've often quoted Emerson
in a very poetic way by saying every
action is measured by the sentiment from
which it proceeds that basically means
where are you coming from with the
choices that you're making because the
choice that you make is not nearly as
important as the soil from which it
grows and if you are moving from a place
of guilt then you are moving from a weak
place guilt is not a strong position to
move from fear is not a strong position
to move from anger is not a strong
position to move from these are weaker
emotions or they're weaker concepts
through which we approach life but if
you're moving from place of strength
like I am firmly convinced choice I
believe I have personally chosen I feel
strong about why I'm doing what I'm
doing and I can back it up with all
sorts of good feelings about out because
we could talk ourselves in circles we
can philosophize so the Sun Goes Down
but really all that matters is well how
do you feel about that how's that
working out for you how's that
manifesting itself in your body and if
you're breathing deep and you're feeling
good and there's pleasurable joyful
feelings in your body as you make the
decision you're going to make whether
it's having sex or not having sex then
you're you're moving from a strong place
you're moving from the right place
because it is firmly a lot
and with your head your heart in your
balls but if there is a if there is any
kind of dissonance between what's
happening in the head to heart in the
balls what's happening between the head
in the body then you're moving from a
weak place right the context is far more
important than the content so I can kind
of guess the position you're moving from
here actually I've already said it it's
guilt
you're you're using the guilt that your
mom so insidiously and skillfully
injected into your consciousness so that
you will not have sex and I didn't give
the whole story I apparently your father
wasn't around I don't know if he passed
away and grew up without my father my
mother raised me look your mom raising
you without a male role model means that
she was in a position where the best she
could offer in order to control you and
perhaps your brothers or your other
siblings was to castrate you and it
doesn't make her a bad woman but it
makes her a woman who was somehow left
by a man I don't know the situation you
know either he passed away or he just
you know you didn't feel like being
around but even way a man did something
to her a man left her and she's in a
situation where she's growing a man now
and to deal with the sexuality of this
young man growing up in her house is far
easier if you castrate him very early on
and that's essentially what happened
it's moral castration not physical
castration cut off your dick obviously
but in a moralistic way you were
castrated at very young age right and
for anyone who would argue that point
you're 24 years old and that sucks I
mean that's a manifestation of
psychological castration more evident
than absolutely anything else I mean
we're all castrated to a degree but the
fact that you're not having sex is like
look the poetry stands folks so you the
real situation here is the question for
you it's not the question for me because
it doesn't matter what you do what you
do doesn't matter the sentiment from
which you're proceeding what are you how
are you moving
through life are you moving through life
with fear and guilt or strength and
pleasure joy resourcefulness and based
on the answer to that question are you
moving from fear or love right
love love would be the overreaching
broad umbrella emotion associated with
pleasure and joy are you which place are
you moving from and whatever you choose
I'm good with the world will be good
with you will be a very happy person
based on the sentiment regardless of the
the actual action cool so I hope you
understand that dude figure out where
your where your heart is and then be
honest with yourself about the actions
that you take peace