I got this question from Kyle about
leadership he goes on to say that uh he
works for Boeing and it's a private
sector job and and he wants to be a good
leader he just doesn't know exactly how
he spent six years in the Marine corpse
and did just what you did fantastic he
did really well in the military but now
that he is in civilian life style
working in a private sector job he's
wondering how do I go about being a
leader because I can tell you and you
could tell me that being the military is
very different then than being in the
private sector or being in the civilian
world in the military you are praised
for your ability to follow directions
really well you're courageous you're
brave someone tells you go do it you go
do it right I know this because not that
I was in the military but that was the
mindset that I had when I played sports
was you I don't have as long as I don't
have to think you tell me what to do I'm
gonna crush it right a lot of men a lot
of us do that right we could just tell
me what to do and I'm gonna fucking kill
it that's how it was in the military I
assume but what you're experiencing now
in the private sector world and amongst
peers that are not familiar with that
mindset is that creativity and this is a
secret right this is something that not
people know always gonna tell you this a
lot of people notice creativity Trump's
your ability to follow directions in the
new economy no matter where you work or
what you do or what level if you are
creative you're going to be far more
successful when people are going to look
to you as a leader better than being a
drill sergeant or a good private right
someone who shouts and barks orders or
someone who follows orders and what I
mean by this is that you've got to
innovate you've got to be very keen to
the processes of your job or your art or
your craft or whatever it is that you're
doing and look for ways that you could
step out and make the process better or
go above and beyond but in a very
creative way not necessarily work longer
or harder but be innovative be creative
very good book cuz i'm gonna offer I
don't have a job my entire life is based
on creativity I come up with these ideas
I'm gonna make videos answering people's
questions and then I go and do it so
there's no one for me to lead right but
I've read books and and you've got to
get your hands on Seth Godin books Seth
Godin right so many books on
entrepreneurship but also for how to be
a leader in the workplace one that I
would refer you to is poked the box and
the other one is uh and I can't remember
the name linchpin linchpin linchpin is
is basically about how to be a leader in
the workplace through creative means
you've got to get your hands on that and
read that book is a very very very good
book and it's gonna it applies to you
but that's it my man that to be a leader
in a creative world you've got to step
outside the tract of shouting orders or
following orders and you better move
into a creative mindset innovative
mindset that's what the market and
people reward in the unit in the world
outside the military so good luck my man
I need a little help was good seeing you
again hopefully I'll see you soon Elliot
sick what