our buddy max says that he's boring and
uninteresting and he was wanting to know
how they how can he become more of an
interesting person to the people in his
lives apparently he begins speaking with
friends and family and it always seems
like they just kind of glaze over with
boredom every time he starts speaking
and he's wondering like what does it
take to be one of the most fascinating
men in the world right like that beer
commercial how do I make a more
fascinating to other people and the fact
of the matter is in order to become
interesting to others be interested by
others one of the things that is most
attractive to other people is your
ability to speak with them where they're
at so if you want people to think you're
interesting it begins by you first
putting in your interests you first
afford them your interests in the things
that they're interested in and one of
the ways to really navigate that
skillfully is to either have a large
array of different ideas by by
subjecting yourself to many different
you know books philosophies ideas always
expanding always expanding your base of
knowledge at least a little bit in each
area like you should know what's going
on you know and that will give you an
opportunity to sort of like navigate
with someone as they're moving - as
you're moving towards them and they're
bringing you into their world or if
there's someone that you really like if
there's someone in particular a woman or
you know someone else where you're
really wanting to develop you know some
sort of relationship with you find out
everything you can about what interests
that person and you hold conversations
about that with that person I spoke
about this I think last week in a video
where when you begin speaking with
someone and you ask the inevitable
question what is it that you do you
always follow with well how'd you get
into that that's fascinating how did you
get into that well tell me a little bit
more about this tell me a little bit
more about that you go with being
interested in order to feel in order to
have other people see you as interesting
and the more that you
have at your disposal to share with them
in their direction the more fascinated
they will be with you you know we tend
to think that we're fascinating by
having a lot of stuff ourselves and then
vomiting it on people and that might be
what you're doing right now I've got all
these great things I want to talk about
and you spit it up and vomit all over
people with it and that's always
offensive but when you go and you're a
little bit more yielding you say hey
what are you interested in tell me a
little bit more about that oh that's
fascinating oh I once read a book
something about that did you know such
and such and then you you dance with
that person on their ground it's a far
more powerful and resourceful place to
proceed from as opposed to always
asserting and being aggressive with your
language and conversation good luck dude