hey what's up guys today we have a
question for one of our buddies who's
used to weight training he's used to
powerlifting is used to exerting himself
against resistance and becoming stronger
through those types of exercises but
recently he's discovered that he has a
heart condition a disease that no longer
allows him to do the things that he's
used to doing that has given him great
results he's building muscles he's
getting stronger but now because of the
disease and his inability to weight
train any longer he's grown weak and
skinny and fat skinny fat he says and
all he's allowed to do all the doctor
says he's allowed to do it all that he
can even muster up with regard to energy
to exert towards doing anything is light
cardio and light dumbbell work and this
is disastrous this is a complete shock
to his self perception and I think
that's where I want to begin today
because one of the biggest most
difficult challenges to get through is
to have known a version of yourself have
come to appreciate a version of yourself
and the world recognize a version of
yourself
but dissolution sets in especially when
it's traumatic especially when you
haven't chosen it and that version of
yourself is just ripped ripped away from
you dissolves and a new unfamiliar
version of yourself emerges and it's
none of your fault
you're you're going about your life
doing the things that you do getting
great results enjoying yourself and
people enjoying you and boom your whole
world is turned upside down and you're
left with this you look in the mirror
and you don't even know who you're
looking at challenging place to be you
see often times I talk about personal
growth and taking an active
participation in who you're becoming and
being aware of who you want to become
but you my friend have become someone
against your will and that is an injury
not just to your heart not just to your
body but an injury to your ego when I
use that term ego not see many times
people use that word you go like that
ego ego is just merely the story that
we've told ourselves about who we are
based on the circumstances
we find ourselves in and how people
relate to us it's as simple as that and
is a very useful a very resourceful way
to go about life you need ito but when
there's a shock to your ego there's a
traumatic psychological shake-up that
you now have to recover from you have to
rebuild your ego or rebuild the stories
you tell yourself about yourself and
enroll other people in brand new stories
about who you are and who you've become
so the very first thing that I would
invite you to consider is that the old
version of you is dead that's very
difficult for a lot of people to hear
you know even for people who haven't had
trauma people who grow older you know
men who are in their 50s and 60s and
it's just like because their penis
doesn't get as stiff as it used to it's
I want to pull my hair out
women you know their bodies start
sagging and things like that and so they
what do I do it's like I can't be myself
any longer what do you mean yourself
yourself is the saggy boobs and the limp
dick down but instant you know we like
to take pills and get propped up with
surgery and shit like that because no
one wants to come to no come to
recognize and appreciate who you've
become who you become is exactly who you
need to be right now regardless of what
you used to be and right now you're a
skinny fat dude who can't do anything
but jog and play with like dumbbells
great that's a wonderful thing for a
number of reasons the very first I use
that term injury before because it has
come to my attention I've been reading
and listening to a lot of books based on
mythology particularly as it relates to
the emerging male psychology male
psychology becoming a man and one of the
things that the author in this
particular book iron John by iron John I
can't remember the name of the author
right off the top of my head right now
anything anyway one of the things he
describes in this particular book is
that every man receives an injury at
some point in his life usually coming
from a patriarchal
figure now God has been recognized and
has the the metaphor has been used that
God is the father
so the patriarchal injury that's coming
in your direction is from God the Father
or the universe however you want to look
at it you know this is I use this
language because it is mythological the
word God is mythical mythological it's
psychological it helps us understand
something that we don't understand and
mythological stories help us understand
understand things that we don't
understand or we use metaphors to
describe deeper realities right I'm
going to digress for a moment but for
example Jesus walks on water
Jesus walks on water is if you
understand mythology and you understand
symbolism it is that he's a man who
treads on the unconscious water
represents unconscious for water for
Jesus to walk on water means that this
man lives in our world but treads on the
unconscious or understands the deeper
realities unseen by most that guides our
world water is a deeper reality unseen
and recognized by most that guides our
world we're made of water water always
represents the unconscious so it's not a
literal idea that he's walking on water
we know you don't walk on water you
can't walk on water it just doesn't
happen that way right even the
technology we have today I mean if you
take off your shoes I don't care it's
just impossible
you don't walk on water but if you
attach to the literal idea of the
mythology you miss the deep
psychological power of it so those you
get upset when I say God you're missing
a tremendous and powerful connotation
the association with what I'm saying
words are simply symbols and every word
points to a deeper reality you say tree
but that but the word tree is not a tree
you look at a map even a map is a symbol
but the map is not the territory so I'll
come full circle you have received an
injury the most profound part of what
I've discovered with regard to the
injury that men receive either from our
patriarchal
literal father or God the Father is that
it's through the injury that the
stronger version of the man grows this
is fascinating because I've thought
about it for myself and as I was
listening to this audio program the
author talks about different men's
groups where the facilitator will talk
to all the men and ask them where was
their injury and think closely
especially if you're an evolved man
think closely about your life and what
you've achieved and who you become and
who you serve and how it is an outgrowth
of your injury now one of my injuries
because we've got several of them one of
my injuries is that I had been told I
have attention deficit disorder I'm not
smart enough I'm not good I have no
ability
my poor abilities consciously right
cognitively my cognitive skills are poor
and that I have an inability to focus
and concentrate right that's an injury
to my psyche that's an injury to my
character in the same way that your
heart failure your heart disease is an
injury to your body still an injury the
outgrowth of that injury has become my
staunch belief that there's a strongest
version of every single person
regardless of what everyone else says it
should look like you see I make these
videos carrying the sword of a man that
has grown out of the wound that the
world has laid upon him I am a crusader
for all those who have been told or have
come to believe or the world has laid a
burden on them that doesn't allow them
to believe that they are powerful that
you are strong that you are magnificent
that you are brilliant regardless of the
standards that the world has set upon
you you see how I begin talking I become
very excited and very passionate when I
move in this particular direction
because it's touching my wound the
closer the conversation comes to my
wound the more powerful I become
this is what you need to find how to do
you need to discover how to take those
injuries that you have and make them so
nourishing that growing out of it is a
mighty oak tree of your service to the
world your injury your heart disease
your ill condition will be the reason
why your legacy will be long living and
powerful my friend but shall you see it
and that's why I make these videos also
but shall you see it perspective my
friend instead of looking at your poor
sick fat body in the mirror now and
feeling sorry for yourself or comparing
yourself to who you used to be own the
injury recognize it for what it is and
ask yourself how will I now bring a gift
to the world through my injury all of
you watching this consider where have
you been hurt where has the world done
you wrong or where has God done you
wrong where do you feel in your body or
in your psychology that you've been
injured find that spot look at it
because we often spend our lives
ignoring the injury pretending it's not
there suppressing it repressing it and
it only Fester's and grows as a wound
and never allows true growth to happen
look at your injury look at how your
father died you did you wrong and left
when you were just a child look at how
your mother did you wrong and didn't
stand up against your stepfather look at
how your big brother did you wrong and
beat you up so that your self-esteem is
low look at the teachers who told you
we're too stupid to do the work in the
classroom look look at the sports
coaches who told you that you weren't
strong enough are smart enough to play
this particular position look at the
girl who you fell in love with when you
were only 13 years old it broke your
heart for the first time and for the
rest of your teenage days you decided
you won't talk
another girl and now you're 21 and you
can't figure out how to talk to them
everything that makes you sick will also
make you a success
done