what's up warrior chief I don't normally
do this but today I'm going to recap my
daily blog post my grow stronger daily
that you could read down below in this
video because I feel like the answer I
give to the question in the post could
be resourceful to all of you watching
this video now of course yesterday we
were talking about the inevitable
self-sacrifice associated with going
warrior mode towards your destination
and of course there are going to be
times of imbalance in your life there
going to be times where you've got to
knuckle down and go hard in the
direction of your jeep dreams and it's
going to require that we decide on what
our paramount priorities or core values
are and what is complete trash that can
be disregarded from our life because of
course we only have a certain amount of
time and energy so we've got to invest
it wisely when you're on your journey to
building your business furthering your
career developing a family growing your
benchpress reducing your body fat
there's going to be a tremendous amount
of self sacrifice associated with it
you're going to have to give up things
that can ultimately support you and you
know feeling good right pleasure like
you can't eat chocolate cake when you're
trying to to lower your body fat
percentage you understand what I'm
saying right you got to give some things
up but yesterday we spoke about the ill
advice that many have been giving least
in my opinion about sacrificing your
physiology for extended periods of time
or perhaps even as a lifestyle in order
to achieve results or so-called success
right you're going to get a fucking
result either way whether you like it or
not there's a different story
I call success getting the results you
want right this is what I want to share
with you today is how we go about
getting the result we want which is a
balanced destination and a balanced
journey towards becoming the strongest
version of ourselves now
for I begin preaching right because I'm
pretty good at that in fact I had a a
priest telling me the other day that I'm
the best creature he's ever heard
interesting he's in the profession of
preaching and I just talked to this
camera but before I preach at y'all
today
what I want to share is the fact that
everything I explained to you all of my
advice all of my invitations all of
these videos stem from not me gaining
some sort of celestial insight or being
a prophet of God of any sorts as the
words flow through me know I offer you
this advice simply because I've made a
shitload of mistakes in my life and I've
learned a few things along the way so
with that being said I often tell
stories about where I've been where I've
come from where I am now and where I'm
going in fact I believe that none of us
really have anything to offer except our
own experience in order to support other
people right because you could read as
many books as you want note as many
courses as you want it can consult as
many gurus as you want but if you
haven't done it yourself you don't own
it true authenticity means you're the
author the writer the creator of your
life and when that's the case you become
an authority worth listening to
I like to think of myself as an
authority worth listening to so even if
I'm the only one listening I'm gonna
rant today on Elliot
question Elliot how did you seek to
honor your body Physiology or health and
avoid physical breakdown while climbing
out of 90k in debt correct
I was $90,000 in debt raising your
family for children I have satisfying
your wife which she is greatly building
your empire over the past ten years or
so great question my friend and I wish I
could give you a straight answer the
fact is that there were fluctuations and
different versions of myself all along
the way sometimes out of balance
sometimes in great balance but the
equilibrium
brought me to where I am here today
where I can share with you just a sliver
of my experienced over the past 10 years
and developing my level of success if
you will so I figured the best way to do
this was for me to sit down and think
back to a typical day on my journey
while I was building my business while I
was with my family while I was
developing my vocational capacities
right learning education doing all these
damn things at the at the tender age of
24 every single day to get where I am
right now so what I'm going to do
describe a a day in the life of Elliott
Hulse around 2005 2006 perhaps now I'm
going to begin with a contradiction but
you'll see me come full circle
I begin my day at 4:30 in the morning
very early earlier than most people are
willing to wake up which will notice
laters that I go to bed very early wake
up and I'd meditate and I used to listen
to binaural beats on CD back then I was
listening to a lot of Jolla sinc I still
recommend it I think it's really good
thing is with various forms of
meditation or personal development just
like there are different versions of you
as you're growing stronger we use them
as tools to support us where we are at
that particular time that particular
time it was very source famiy to wake up
in the morning sit down and listen for
an hour from 4:30 to 5:30 to binaural
beats totally rewired my brain supported
me in also furthering the mental the
psychological embedding of affirmations
and visualization that I would do about
the same time in fact I didn't write
that in my email that's why I make these
videos because when I start spilling it
all comes out I would wake up and before
I'd meditate I would do my affirmations
I'd write down exactly what it is that
I'm up to and who I'm becoming you know
and write about five or ten of those a
day I'd repeat them over and over again
but visualize them as a reality and then
I'd meditate solely
think in right I can tell you that by
using this practice today my life is
pretty much a manifestation of my dream
at that time works 5:30 I would cook
breakfast and eat Coleen used to
complain about the beef and greens and
fish sometimes I'd cook like salmon and
and red snapper 5:30 in the morning
she's trying to sleep with the kids
sometimes she was pregnant so that she
would get really upset with me about the
nasty smell but look you know is one of
the things that I knew I had to do for
our family we all had to sacrifice
because if daddy's gonna put any bread
on the table he's got to take good care
of himself and that means filling
himself with good food my wife knew that
bad she understands that today today we
work together and cooking and preparing
food in the kitchen and we help each
other in the dishes you know doing the
dishes and whatnot so it's a very
important part of our life as we realize
healthy fuel is essential for success so
uh 5:55 I leaned leave the house to go
train my first client at a local gym
from about 6:00 to 11:00 or noon might
be training clients all day long that
means working in my career practicing my
skills in my vocation and earning a
living I would charge something around
you know seventy-five dollars sixty five
dollars a session when I was training
people at this particular time at eleven
a.m. most of the part most times my
clients would that schedule to run out
I'd have some time on my own so I'd have
two hours that have to make very useful
time up you notice when you wake up at
four o'clock in the morning and you're
you're going full-tilt so late morning
early afternoon it's a good idea to take
a little break and and I think that's
just natural for any and everybody
otherwise you'll run yourself into the
ground and before noon every day you'll
be ready to take and it won't do as I do
take a nap so what I would do is when I
worked at lifestyle Family Fitness which
was on 4th Street in st. Pete there was
a park Sawgrass Lake Park I'd get in my
car and I Drive over to the park because
I knew that
sunshine would revitalize me I sit there
and I'd eat some of the food that I
prepared the morning earlier in the
morning I always try to prepare my food
or cook my food the same day that I eat
it so it's as fresh as possible and I
sit at a bench and I'd eat my dinner or
my lunch and I would either do a series
of these activities or choose one I'd
either read I would do Tai Chi or moving
meditation right Tai Chi Chi gung type
breathing movement meditation at the
time I would either die I would take a
nap sometimes in my car and I spent a
lot of that time goal-setting and
reviewing so I'd sit at this park bench
eat my lunch and I think about my
accomplishments from the previous week
what I'd like my short-term
accomplishments for this week week to be
where I like to be in three months six
months nine months a year and fuck I
didn't think ten years then I didn't
think ten years later that I'd be here
talking to you guys but there are a lot
of parallels between what I wrote down
as my goals back then and what I live is
my life today it works do what I say and
you might have the same results can't
promise you anything but I learned that
one from Brian Tracy to see somebody who
has something or somewhere where you
want to be do what they do and you might
get there years later I would use that
lunchtime to future I put money in my
future bank account right now what that
means is I've engaged in activities that
I'm cashing on later like I'm use those
hours for writing books studying and
creating fitness products to sell before
I move on to what I did after my
afternoon I wanted to make it very clear
that there is no perfect prescription
for what you should be doing with your
time there's only the question what do I
want what am I willing to do right so I
don't want you guys to watch my video
and say oh that's what Elliot did I
should go do it now in fact because I
cram so much into that into my
spheal spheal here I don't want to
confuse you to having you believe I did
all those things every day at the same
time like I said earlier various modes
of self-development come and go during
the seasons of your life right so you
know just for example just to bring you
up to date during my lunch times now I
usually work through my lunch times but
I take about I take like a 15 20 minute
break every half an hour right where I
do some breathing exercise I stretch it
in between my workouts so my lifestyle
is different right if someone gave me
this template today is that Elliott
follow this for success I'd say no screw
you is saying angle work from me so mind
you a lot of times when I share these
stories they're just my experience
perhaps can offer you some perspective
on what you might be able to do with
your time
but there it's not it's not written in
stone you're not going to get what I get
by doing it you know step by step it's
just the idea it's the sentiment 1
o'clock p.m. I screw this up on my
article I'm sure you guys will figure
that out I back in the gym training
clients got to go back to work gotta go
back to the grind go back to do and I
have to do in order to put food on the
table at 3:00 p.m. ish 4:00 p.m. ish I'd
usually do my own workout my workouts
always supported the goal that I had at
that particular time you know even at my
most masochistic when I was training for
professional strongman and I was beating
a fuck out of myself I would still
adhere to many of the bullet points I'm
gonna share with you in a moment with
regard to keeping my health vibrant
vital and buzzing while I move on my
journey so I'd work out 7 p.m.
depending on the phase of my life where
I was when I didn't have as many
children who's just my wife and I
Isabelle I joined sports like rugby I go
rock climbing as I get older as my kids
got older I would join them as I do now
for bath time dinnertime bedtime rituals
right 9:30 p.m. as it is today it was
back then in bed for snuggles and
drooling next to my best friend collie
I get to bed by 9:30 generally between
9:30 and 10:00 and there you have it
that's my that's my typical warrior-king
daily schedule from around 2004 to 2012
and again I share that with you guys
because perhaps a glimpse into my
lifestyle would offer you a little bit
of insight on how you might want to go
about yours
this is already a really long email a
really long time so our video together
to mixed up and and of course if you're
if you're still here I think we're about
ten minutes in you get the bonus of
listening me just recap some of the
bullet points notes and keys to follow
or that I follow during this particular
time there are probably about ten of
them ten of them and eight of them and
I'll go really quickly so those who
don't feel like reading can get a little
insight um keys to follow number one no
alcohol didn't drink alcohol back then
doesn't mean that I don't drink alcohol
but I don't drink alcohol very much now
either alcohol is one of these things
that requires at least for me a
tremendous amount of life force and time
to recover from so I have to ask myself
is it worth it right if I have a few
drinks on a Thursday night Friday
morning I'm not going to be vibrant
vital and ready to make videos like this
and right so you got you gotta weigh the
options there also because I follow a
strict diet now and then an alcohol
never really made its way back into my
weekend schedule most of the food that I
eat is uh I'm on somewhat of an
anti-inflammatory diet if you will and
try to heal some physiological
imbalances I have I drink tons of and I
had drink drank tons of high pH water I
use a kangen water machine now back then
I would just drink tons of Evian I'd
invest my money in high-quality water
what little of it I had went directly to
my physiology my health in my education
number four I supplement it with fish
oil and living fuel as I do today I
never got less than seven hours of sleep
usually about eight hours of sleep
I was always invested always when that
from from before then you know since I'm
Iowa I graduated college
I've always invested in some form of
movement and mind meditation Tai Chi
bioenergetic breathing viral Noro beats
things of this nature and uh number
seven I always invested in and I hired
several expensive private doctors and
consultants look one of the things that
you realize as a mature warrior and his
fullness is that asking for help was
probably one of the most powerful
weapons in your tool belt and and I
recognized that back then because of the
powerful relation to the powerful
experience of experiences I've had with
mentors in my life so I realized I saw
it as so valuable that I would invest my
money I go I part of the reason why I
was so much in debt because I use my
credit card to take to gather useful
information from people who I thought
were were obviously further along on the
journey than I wasn't can offer me
something in number eight although I was
always disciplined with my nutrition
lifestyle and in lifestyle my stress was
high during this building phase of my
life I needed as much energy and
vitality as possible for my clients
growing my family and learning as well
as self mastery I go on to explain how
if you're gonna play this game
this warrior Kings game of crush it and
go hard in life then you're going to
have to at the same time recognize your
game piece as the cornerstone or the
lodestone for being able to carry all
the weight that is required for you to
dominate done