what's up man how you doing today
growing stronger I bet you are if you
read my letter today you're definitely
on the path to becoming a stronger
version of yourself you can read it down
below in that letter this morning I
wrote about how exercise is medicine
right and we take it for granted that
you know an exercise is an exercise but
there are parameters that can be
adjusted to give your body at different
physiological response and ultimately
make you a different version of yourself
very quickly if you take running for
example as an exercise well there's many
different ways to apply running by
adjusting the parameters right are you
running long distances right that's I'm
running right I'm going I'm going to get
a physical different physiological
response doing this then if I did this
right sprinting very simple are you
sprinting or you're judging what are the
parameters associated with it are you
going for long intervals with low
intensity or short intervals with high
intensity right so exercise in and of
itself is powerful but it needs to be
applied appropriately in order to give
us the physiological and character
character illogical or mental response
we bought might sound strange but there
is going to be a psychological effect of
running long distances for marathon tie
preparation versus sprinting you have to
have a different mindset in the body's
the mind so the way you treat train your
body the way you treat yourself is going
to affect how you behave but how you
feel about yourself it's all very
obvious and normal and if you need proof
just try it out see how you change both
your physical body right because you're
applying the exercises differently so
you're going to change physically but
how do you change your gonna be a
different version of yourself all
stimulus is medicine the food we eat is
a stimulus it's medicine try eating a
different food than you normally eat
you're going to different physiological
response
we take it for granted that food is
medicine we take it for granted even
[Music]
that some of the drugs that we take on a
daily basis although we don't think of
them as drugs any longer because we're
so used to taking them things like
caffeine and coffee that their medicine
you take it and you get a physiological
response to changes your character go to
someone who doesn't drink drinks coffee
every day all right that's the best way
to try it out and then ask them not to
have their medicine today and how
they're going to feel we're gonna be
grumpy they're gonna be miserable if I'm
headaches no fucked up because they
didn't take their medicine coffee is
medicine caffeine is medicine exercise
is medicine someone who exercised all
the time you tell them not to exercise
they're going to feel different we need
to recognize this you know medicine
isn't just the chemical concoctions that
pharmaceutical companies have created
and force down our throats to notice to
to fix fake problems like eyelashes that
are too short and shit like that I think
they might even have some pills for my
eyebrows since mine are thinning out as
I get older right so I might have a
problem I gotta take a pill but that's
not the only type of medicine even our
thoughts our medicine right it's a
little different because we're not
taking something so the difference needs
to be recognized between intrinsic and
extrinsic medicine and extrinsic
medicine is a dose of something that you
take and bring into you intrinsic
medicine it's something that you do or
something that you take in which is not
physical in a way music is medicine
right we don't ingest music but be very
mindful of how you're responding to the
music that you listen to if your
scientific about your media consumption
music consumption in particular like I
am you're going to listen to different
types of music to be different versions
of yourself from moment to moment put on
some rage against the machine put on
some hardcore heavy metal rock music you
will feel different now depending on how
open you are to the vibration it might
irritate you and you have to get out of
the
room or it might open you up and turn
you into a raging beast that will either
dead lift more weight in the gym or or
or attack someone on the football field
a little harder since you were listening
to it in the pregame you see them say it
changes your attitude changes who you
are and over time the music that you
listen to you become you start acting
out what you've been putting in it's all
very normal and natural ah I know say
this to point fingers I say this because
I fucking knew it right so for example
earlier on in my career when I was on
behaving I needed to access a certain
way of being for my activities in the
gym and activities business and I
listened to a lot of really rageful
music and it was good for me it got me
through those times and you can see even
in my character that there's a lot of
rage and anger and fury and aggression
coming out in my in my language just my
being I was taking medicine to make that
happen alright not steroids now loads of
pre workout I was listening in music I
listen to reggae music when I'm at home
when I'm trying to contract as opposed
to expand you know I'm hard heavy metal
music is very expanding it gets your
energy out reggae music some forms of a
bike you know Bob Marley I like
listening to Iration and revolution j
boog it's one of my favorites it's more
you know it's more internal it's more
contracting or or absorbing type music
because the rhythm is inside you it's
nuts is like you're not gonna do a mosh
pit to reggae music right because mosh
pits are out reggae music you gonna do a
little sway by yourself and maybe with a
lady you could take it one step deeper
and like when I come to my office when
I'm ready to do some writing or do some
work I put on classical medicine I
listen to classical music because it
sedates me it keeps you even it keeps me
focused and I like the way my body feels
I like the response is giving me the
physiological and character
logical response psychological energetic
responds to listen to the classical
music no so it's with all types of music
I love listening rap music when I Drive
you know I like listen to cube and drake
and meek mill those are some of the new
new artist 50 cent of course ice cube 50
saying you know these are this is music
that's medicine that when you listen to
it you take on the behavior now be
mindful I've mentioned this in other
videos be mindful of the medicine that
you're taking because if you get a
result that you don't want like say for
example you listen to music that saw
that denigrates women it's misogynistic
in a way or you listen to people who are
that way you really absorb and you
engage and you emotionalize the content
the medicine which you know what
normally happens with the physiologic
response you start taking on those
characters you gotta ask yourself hey is
this working out for me or not right if
you listen to the misogynistic music or
listen to music denigrates women and you
can't seem to have a stable relationship
with a woman and every time every time
you you deal with a woman you end up
cheating on her she cheats on you or you
don't respect each other and you're
gonna end up old and alone which you
know that might be okay for you but you
gotta ask yourself is that what I want
if it's not can you take different music
take different medicine okay so this is
my long way of kind of coming full
circle with what I would like this
message to to portray today which is I
want you to look at the medicine you're
taking in your life with regard to the
habits you engage in how you do them
like I mentioned in mentioned earlier
the way you adjust your parameters in
your exercise program are not just going
to give you a physical response meaning
you know you pump you do a high volume
time under tension bench-pressing you're
gonna build big checks packs from sorry
big chest pecks testicles pectic o's
testicles you're in a big triceps you
your shoulders you know that type of
response you're going to get but you're
also getting an energetic response just
like with the music you know you might
be bouncing your body but you're also
feeling a certain way when you subject
yourself to the net
sin of heavy bench pressing over time it
doesn't just affect your chest size it
affects who you are affects your
character effects to your character
structure because your body changes
whenever your body changes with whatever
it is that you're doing beat acute or
chronic there's an acute change with the
music that you listen to you but there's
a chronic change over the course of
listen to the same music for years
there's an acute response to
weightlifting but there's a chronic
response over the years and like I said
before what to do that listen to music
that's misogynistic he might be getting
fucked up in his relationships because
of the medicine that he's been taking
over time if you keep doing the same
thing you're doing in the gym and you're
not getting the results that you want in
your life it's because it's affecting
your character in a way that you that
isn't resourceful it's not helping you
so you ask yourself what's more
important you know the the outer shell
and I don't I don't say that in a way
that makes it that lessens its value I
do find like new there's great value in
aesthetics there's great value in having
a good looking body but if it's at the
expense of other things you've got to
ask yourself is that if this is the
right medicine for me if you're spending
all your time building up a certain
particular body and it requires a
certain amount of time energy resources
and focus in order to make that happen
at the expense of say your career your
school your relationships your life
mastery as a whole or anything else that
you value then maybe it isn't the right
medicine and you've got to check
yourself the only question that really
ever matters is how that's working out
for you and you gotta look at you know
look at how the things that you're doing
the exercises and the habits the rituals
that you engage in on a daily basis
which make the response chronic your
physiological and psychological response
chronic are they helping you only heard
me I think one of the issues is that we
don't believe we've got options you know
or we don't know that there are other
options and
and the benefits are associated with the
other options right so for example it
took me a long time you're right because
i started my exploration with physical
training using a barbell and dumbbells
and strength training barbell training
in my basement for football when i was a
kid i also took it one step further I
said baseball football never played
baseball how that slip came out I played
t-ball it was horrible at it and I'd be
out in the outfield just picking daisies
in the ball and rolled by so my parents
realized and go and work out for him so
I played football was football just yeah
just more my style but I started weight
training then I took it one step further
it was strongman training now boy I look
back in retrospect and that's why I have
all this wisdom that's why I could tell
you guys all these things cuz I just
look back at my life and say that's
funny how that worked out interesting
correlations it might be worth sharing
when I was in my expansion mode when I
was expanding my energy in the world
through my career right expanding my
sexual energy by building my family
right growing children during the stage
of my life I'm talking to you five years
ago or so three even 335 two years ago
too long ago all right but I can look
back it's enough time for me to look
back and say boy I expanded my life but
I also expanded my body I was the
biggest I ever was during my expansion
mode of life creation life mastery
expansion also coupled with physical
expansion the grind and the hard work
and the commitment and the discipline
and the devotion that I had to strongman
training transferred into my being able
to do the same for my family do the same
for my career do the same for my
business do this name from my vocation
do the same for these videos that I make
for you guys as time goes on and life
requires different versions of me my
exercise programs have to change and so
do yours if I am in the stage of
enduring trying to sort things out and
figure that
out and and create some sort of
stability with my life you know my
family my children are getting older my
business then the exercise that I might
engage in our bit more long winded like
that's a good time or it was a good time
for me to engage in Adventure Racing
right because of the commitment to the
long haul overcoming obstacles but keep
going right very different than taking a
300-pound stoning are there like I've
done changes you it changes you not just
physically want to lose weight I have
lost weight but changes my mind changed
my character changes your way of being
has exercise is fucking medicine most of
what I do these days revolve around as
far as my medicine is concerned and I'll
talk far more about this incoming videos
in the coming months and so forth but I
just would think it's very important for
you to know that a day doesn't go by
where I don't do bioenergetic breathing
or Tai Chi energy cultivating exercises
right when they're when you're in a mode
of growth you need to do things that are
anabolic and oftentimes anabolism cannot
be accessed unless there is rest
recovery so in the same way that sleep
is necessary because it gives you that
dose of anabolic juice in order to help
you recover from your activities of the
day you can support that anabolic boost
by doing exercises that stimulate your
nervous system in the very same way that
sleep does parasympathetic stimulation
through
breathing exercises right I mean I
almost change instantly based on the way
I breathe I've done videos you've seen
them and I think I'll have nanny link it
up here somewhere where I'm showing you
how to use breathing to draw your energy
up ah done videos like this well that's
exercise it's medicine in the same way
that slow rhythmical breathing coupled
with slow deliberate movement offers a
different physiological and
psychological response every thought you
have every food you eat every exercise
you engage in and every relationship
that you have is medicine are you taking
the right medicine in the right doses
for what you want in life done
[Music]