what's up guys today we got a question
from our buddy Ben Sasse he says that
he's living in the sea
mediocrity here in Serbia but he ain't
no lukewarm bitch I'm explain to it I
mean he says that he's about to end his
studies in university with a degree in
archaeology now he knows that he
probably won't be able to find work in
archaeology but it really doesn't matter
because he has lots of interests in fact
he becomes obsessed with different ideas
he can work his way around
archery smithing he plays the guitar
musical theory martial arts philosophy
he just finds veins of interest and he
dives deep into it and he says that from
time to time he'll be fully immersed so
much so that he can't even sleep when
he's diving into waters that are
exciting to him and then one day
something else will come along you know
you know change is interesting just dive
deep into these waters and you might
spend months of studying and gaining
experience in a particular direction and
he just absorbs absorbs absorbs but
picks up and then goes somewhere else
now what he's kind of referring to is
the fact that he perhaps won't achieve
mastery in any particular direction
because he's so attention-deficit in
that way it's kind of a genius but also
his tendencies don't match up with what
the the system is conditioned just to be
which is very good cogs in a system a
very good cognitive system is one that
is predictable you are a bang and there
you go off to the races right that no
longer works because the Industrial
Revolution has crumbled they will our
economy is changing in so many different
ways cogs and systems are useless now
even if you have a half a million dollar
education you're a cognitive fucking
system people who are creative agile
thinking sensitive those are the ones
that are going to make this way make our
way in the future and you my friend are
blessed with this entrepreneurial ATD
I'll tell you what I mean
so again oh he wants to know how am I
gonna go about life if I can't become a
good cog
because I'm too unpredictable with the
things that I love well what I'm going
to invite you to do is to add two more
things to your list of interests and
before I go that in that route Oh Shere
with you don't stop feeling guilty about
your your plethora of interests stop
feeling guilty about choosing something
to fall in love with and then retracting
your love and then fall in love with
something else because each one of these
veins of interests are adding to you you
you when you spend six months studying
musical theory and then you go into
playing the guitar you're that much
better of a guitar player because of the
musical theory and it can be things as
broad as going from archery to
philosophy in fact I wrote it I listen
to a fantastic philosophy book that was
based on the art of archery and the
reason why it so it serves you so well
to allow yourself to be seduced and fall
in love with these different veins of
interest is because we live in the age
of the remix meaning there's not too
much new stuff coming about not to say
that there won't be but a lot of what
now tickles us are the blending or the
fusion of things to understand we are
we're coming from a place of
reductionism to expansion we're going to
become become begin expanding in our
consciousness again it's happening
already and a part of expansion is the
ability to see the big picture and how
things like archery and philosophy are
actually one thing right we're beginning
to see the oneness we're beginning to
experience the oneness of humanity on
earth just the Internet itself you live
in Serbia so at my ass off and flora in
Florida and you will watch this tonight
I'm making this this morning you'll
watch it tonight do you see it's crazy
in fact if I want to upload it now you'd
watch this five minutes after I make it
so we're really getting smaller we're
really condensing we're really getting
more intertwined we are reap remix in
our consciousness understand and you my
friend are a sponge for soaking up
different forms of understanding and
knowledge my friend
you are well-suited for the future two
things you need to add to that list of
things that you fall in love with and
you have to force yourself to fall in
love with these two things because it's
the only way that you are going to serve
others with the information that you're
collecting the experiences you're
collecting it's the only way you're
going to serve yourself because you're
going to be a valuable tool to the
future and you had better know how to
serve yourself so that you are not
sucked dry and then grow resentful of
blessing people with your gifts I hope
you understand what I mean
you need to get paid brother okay the
the more of a service you are to others
the more you need to grow your own
resources so that you can serve more and
it's this big exchange of energy you
give energy and an energy comes back to
you but you've got to open up lines of
communication you got to open up lines
of energy to allow the energy to come
back into you
the more people you serve with your
brilliance the more you will be served
and the more you are served the more
money you have more resources you have
more experiences you have because of
what comes back to you the bigger and
more you'll be able to serve this is the
story of my life but you've got to study
these two things that we share with you
right now let me get right into it
number one my friend you need to become
obsessed with marketing don't feel
guilty about studying marketing because
that's one of those lies the world has
conditioned us in order to keep us sick
sad depressed down lowly and fucking
humble their humble means shut the fuck
up and don't make too much noise you're
disturbing the peace buddy you got to
start you got to learn marketing so that
you can pick up your blow horn and tell
everyone just how fucking awesome you
are they need to know how awesome you
are they need your bits of information
because you're going to make them
awesome through your awesomeness and
they're going to make other people
awesome and that's how the world becomes
a more awesome place there are going to
be those who don't like you because
you've got a big mouth and you say the
things that you want and you know and
receive money resources energy back I
agree
yiii for resources to come in my
direction because as it nourishes me I
grow in my expansive capacity my
strength so that I could serve more my
mind just spreads that way you need to
get into the same vein of interest first
place to begin with Dan Kennedy he is my
marketing guru and when I say marketing
it's simply he marketing goes beyond far
beyond just getting your message out and
getting your ideas out and serving
people with your it goes into how you
structure your business how you actually
structure your lifestyle how you serve
people at different levels depending on
where they are and how they want to be
served and Dan Kennedy has just done a
tremendous job in
feeding my consciousness I was a vane
bait of interest he's got lots of books
study that guy the other one dude cuz
you know studying marketing building
your business serving others and doing
all that stuff it's really fucking cool
but you can't do it yourself this is a
big one this is a huge one because uh
and I say so because it's one that I've
challenged I've been challenged with and
I am working on and making great strides
in and that is team building I don't
want to say management because then
you'll go to imagine management school
and a teacher bunch of shit you don't
need to need you don't need to know you
need to understand leadership and team
building because you are going to need a
team of people to help you with all that
fucking ad D you love a lot of things
but you can't stay in love with a lot of
things right I know cuz I'm the same way
say this week you fall in love with uh
canning or pickling vegetables right I
don't know whatever you just become
obsessed with pickling vegetables and
you begin you delve into that stream of
interests you know everything about it
you can really do a great job at it now
what you're going to need to do is
create means by which you share that
information with people products if you
sell products and you sell services
you're going to need customer service
you're going to need people who
and put together the products people
would edit your videos people who can
edit your your writing people who can
build your websites people who can make
your graphics people who can manage your
money you need an accountant you need a
lawyer because someone's going to want
to see you when their canned vegetables
get botulism and the person gets sick
you see so you've got to learn how to be
a leader or a team builder know how to
and really this is your kingly quality
understand right now your your your
dabbling magician if you understand my
language and now you're doing a great
job at it become a magician about
marketing and business building in this
particular way through Dan Kennedy and
then and then become a king who blesses
the people who have blessed him and
managed the realm by putting people in
positions that allow them to fully
express themselves while serving the
kingdom that you have built do you
understand you're allowed to be a leader
you're allowed to be a king but it is
always in service of the other your
court and your kingdom the people who
support you done