so got this question from our buddy
let's call him dusty right here he says
that he's in a love triangle and uh damn
right he is and it's pretty interesting
so I'm gonna read it for you I'm in love
with my best friend her name is Kay we
hang out all the time and her family
loves me but the problem was that I had
a girlfriend I recently left her because
it wasn't fair uh to her but I made an
excuse oh wouldn't sound that I left her
for another girl my best friend
Cole started talking to Kay he doesn't
know I love her weeks passed and she
started coming on to me and in an
emotional response I let it happen
we were secretly seeing each other and
never told anyone about us but then Cole
did some stuff at with K both Kay's best
friends so Cole did some stuff I guess
had sex or whatever with Kay's best
friend at a party and sent Kay into a
tornado of feelings of jealousy Cole
doesn't know about me and Kay but
they're currently trying to reach
closure
I think figure it out kay put me in her
Kate put me and Cole on hold and now I
feel like I'm losing her I'm obviously
the right choice for Kay I make her
happy and treat her right
she's only attracted to Cole because of
his good looks what do you think about
the situation and what should I do okay
dude I think she made a decision for you
and I think it was a good decision and I
think you should allow it to happen she
put you both on hold you and her both
know about everything that's going on
Cole is the one that's in the dark so
you could see yourself and K as the
powder keg right like that the bomb and
Cole is like the the wick so you guys
the amount of information that you guys
have about the weird shit that's going
on is very explosive that's very
powerful shit coal is very intrinsically
linked to it
he's the wick he's that thing that you
like
for the dynamite bursts all that you
need is for a tiny spark of
enlightenment fire to catch coal in
other words he finds out what's
happening and it's banging the whole
thing's gonna go off and it's going to
be ugly fucking bloodbath you know I
mean it's not the end of the world but
you're gonna lose the best friend and
you lose your other best friend and
there's gonna be a lot of feelings hurt
it's just gonna be a an ugly fucking
thing so uh if she didn't back out of
the whole thing just completely remove
her potent ingredients for the explosive
compound you've created I would invite
you do because with the understanding
that you both have you were in the place
of empowerment coal Hill fuck it all up
get out before Cole finds out fuck the
whole fucking thing up okay some
mistakes were made let's end it not say
another word about it that's really the
best bet but here's the thing now she's
tougher than you either that or she's
more intelligent than you because she
says emotion aside love aside this shit
has to end and she back the fuck out
look that's true that's really what
you're going to have to do and coming
from a guy who always tells you that
you've got to feel your emotions and
trust your feelings and go yeah you know
so on and so forth don't let that make
you ungrounded
don't let that control you the us
experience your feelings
yes fall deeply in love yes taste all of
the potent flavors that life has to
offer and deny yourself none but don't
let that shit on you don't let that shit
on you and that's kind of what's your
being faced with right now so you love
her so what so what you gonna let that
drag look it's a powder keg and she's
trying to get out of it so that it
doesn't explode and in your selfishness
again you know another strange thing
from a guy who's just trust yourself I
say be selfish
so reading a Facebook comment the other
day and someone called me uh ego centric
self centered self in something like
that and gays raised right and guess
what
in my belief of self-importance I invite
you to recognize just how important you
are
so anyway I'm sorry I ran get out and
don't be don't let love don't let the
emotion of the experience the attractive
quality of it of it blinds you in your
head brain you gotta that's when you get
back in your head brain right now look
at it logistically be little logical for
a moment rational get the fuck out of
this machine this mess this bomb that's
it dude so it's going to be difficult
for you I can't give you a good answer
or fun answer when it's going to tickle
you and make you feel all warm inside
what I'm telling you like I often say
and sometimes people get upset just
toughen the fuck up just toughen up grab
your nuts and go somewhere done