my name is Jerome France my name's Luke
and I'm from the UK Boulder Colorado
from Birmingham AL back Norway Oscar
says we make school in Washington DC
area from Poland Albuquerque New Mexico
Wichita Kansas San Diego California if
you're looking for to cry if you think
it's quite a little bit if you think you
need to laugh a little bit if you think
you need to reconnect
deep down who you really are I was a
little bit afraid a lot of the
meditations out there you have to
basically sit down and be quiet through
the movement you get out all that energy
you release all that body armor the
connections that you make you Mentos and
the people who are experiencing same
thing as you that is how they I think
that is most important a beautiful place
like if I'm in paradise so it was very
therapeutic like I felt like it was
relieving love and she's in my body and
he's helping me get my head in mind more
clearer as well that's exactly what I
came here for so I'm really happy with
that I got the opportunity to be here
totally something that I would never
have done otherwise like it was just it
was amazing just something I've never
experienced before in my life it's a
best team I've ever experienced in my
life
overwhelming in a sense overpower and
then you come out like feel you feel
alive I don't think there is I don't
think that there is a perfect time to be
ready for this I think anyone at some
point and anyone needs this I mean I
thought whatever I've been good for me
at 15
and it's good for urine at 25 and maybe
that would be great for me to pee in a
couple years again and maybe when I'm
old I think it's almost like a reset
it's almost like if you could press a
button to remove all the bad stuff I've
been accumulating up here on these
stories that just makes you slow posit
definitely recommend it
you