sup guys back in my car again just
because I get bored of being in my
office making videos and I've been
enjoying these car rides with y'all
these little trips in the park and
riding around in my car so I figured on
my way to my office today I'll just turn
it back on rap with you and if you read
my letter today to be down below I spoke
about women girls feminine the feminine
aspect feminine energy right and I made
reference to Paul Young which I thought
I do quite often because Carl Jung is
the guy who basically did the map of the
psyche using symbols you know many of
the symbols that we see in mythology and
in stories come from Carl Jung's mapping
of the unconscious so symbols like king
warrior magician lover but also he used
the term anima and honey must on e mata
a and then honey must like a us event to
describe the masculine and the feminine
energy that resides within each one of
us every human being has both a
masculine and a feminine aspect of its
psyche alright so you know although we
show up physically as masculine right
with a big ol dick or maybe not a big
one but a dick or vagina we also come
from the essence of a integrated
sexuality we're both men and women at
the core at the psyche level at the
level of the unconscious there are
physical manifestations of masculinity
and femininity but we're both right and
that's basically the concept that I'm
trying to share with you right now and
he calls it the anima animus
and we live in an interesting time now
where sex roles are being challenged sex
role the line between what is masculine
what is feminine has clearly been
blurred right and we see this just from
the progression of what would be a
typical 1950s or post-world War two
women's suffrage liberation attitude
towards sex roles which shows up as
women wear business suits you know women
are are engaging in what we're typically
masculine activities masculine jobs
taking masculine roles you know there's
they're stepping up to the plate
becoming career women many of them of
which I am great friends with and I see
them on a daily basis strength train now
my wife is she's pulling almost 200
pounds so these are these are kind of
new to in the realm of things it's kind
of new for all these women to him be
embracing their masculine and stepping
into these roles prior to you know the
Lucy and Ricky days that we knew in
black and white TV where you know the
man was a the macho breadwinner and the
woman was a submissive housewife we now
see a swapping of roles and in the
swapping of these roles of the blurring
of these lines there's a lot of
confusion there's a lot of animosity
there's a lot of fucking confusion right
because as we as we find ourselves in a
world where women are taking on more
masculine roles and responsibilities
right I mean think about how many single
moms there are we have to play who were
forced to it's not even a choice they're
not even like stepping up and saying you
know what fuck it it's a man's world but
I'm gonna do I'm gonna do it with the
woman's edge
they're forced into it they're forced to
be dads you know the men who aren't
stepping up or the men who are I don't
want to say victim I don't ever think
were victims of anything but the men who
are who become a part of the system
right you know in prison and whatnot are
there are there for their children and
the mom has a step up in VO be a soldier
be a warrior the best way that she
possibly could you know biology means a
lot by I said it the other day that
biology Trump's ideology any do any way
and a man can't replace a woman and a
woman can't replace a man but we can
cultivate the attitude or the character
traits associated with one or the other
and we're talking a lot about and we're
experiencing this emergence of the
Divine Feminine when I say divine
feminine might mean like the wholeness
the fullness the full expression of what
uh what the feminine is capable of the
feminine has its animals right and as
it's it's masculine side so it's an
interesting dance it's interesting and
it's beautiful to watch a woman dance
between her masculine and her feminine
I finished my letter describing the
beautifully muscled tender aggressive
woman in high and high heels and a
miniskirt to describe this this
beautiful blend of the masculine and the
feminine that is arising in many of the
women that at least I see in my life i
watch it in my wife i watch out she
stepped into the role of being a leader
with the children especially when I'm
out there I have to work a lot of men
have to work and the women end up taking
care of the children so they have to
step up and be aggressive disciplining
and essentially creating
or providing a masculine framework while
the man is not there while I'm not there
my wife does this right she goes to the
gym she trains
she's got ambitions hopes and dreams and
treatment and things thinks and behaves
in a way that uh is much different than
the girl I married and I see it in the
women in my gym that I see it in culture
and I think we're all pretty much aware
of it now the other half of the story
here fellas which is a little bit of a
mindfuck because culture has given us
these clearly defined roles and what is
appropriate to play and for men
our role which you know by the way we
all kind of you know the roles are
biological but they're also sociological
we also and psychological we are we sort
of we sort of give ourselves these roles
but the masculine role the typical
masculine role or the other traditional
masculine role the way from then to be a
rises out of
a need that men have that women don't
have you know a part of our hard
heartedness and a part of our inability
to see the way the women are evolving by
taking on masculine traits what makes it
really difficult for us as men for men
in general to take on those feminine
traits by the way I'm sitting up like
this because I know the Sun is behind
it's like my fucking head is blowing
it's a little bit it's a little bit more
difficult for us to take on the feminine
traits and of course Society has placed
labels on you know feminine men and you
know if you if you show up a little bit
feminine of course you know you're
suspect over this guy gay right not that
you know it's very cool it's very
interesting now that you know almost
sexuality is pretty much out of the
closet but still we got like you know
there's this there's a sort of suspect
attitude towards femininity in them in
the male character the modern male
character and the reason why like I said
it's out of necessity the reason why
these roles are more trap easily
transcended by women and harder for men
to to transcend it and why they're
suspect with regard to men who adopt any
and integrate any of their anima any of
their femininity into their character
comes from the fact that young men boys
have to I spoke about this in a video
earlier this week or last week have to
have the double work have the extra job
of not just creating ego separation from
the mother which the little girl has to
do also when she realizes that you know
she's not the mom you know this is if
you study psychology especially in from
the development you start to real you
begin to realize or you'll realize that
when an infant comes into the world it
still believes that it's one the world
is one right the ego hasn't been
developed yet so it believes it's its
mother it believes it's the world it's
still steeped in the unification the
Unified Field of God like
thinking right which is inappropriate
for a human being with an ego we got to
separate little hiss you there for you
academics there for you
so as the the ego has the
differentiators the ego has to create
its own identity
the little girl does so by standing on
her own two feet and saying your mommy
I'm daddy I'm pure maja me and I'm I'm
not mommy I'm a little girl but we're
both girls little boy on the other hand
and ain't so easy because you got to
separate yourself as an ego but also at
the same time you've got you establish
sexual identity whoa wait a second
mommy's a girl then I'm a boy so the the
hardwired need or desire to create
contrast between the masculine and
feminine for men is that much more
difficult so for us too we're a little
late in other words in integrating our
own in mind to our character because
there's so much resistance due to the
fact that it's just normal and natural
that we have to sit become separate ego
identities but also establish and and
not just establishing ourselves but be
nurtured by others to be acknowledged by
other men to be acknowledged by your mom
and women that you yes you are a man you
are a man right women never forget that
they're women ah no matter how much of a
man they become right you could have the
most hard-hearted feminist female
wearing uh wearing pants and shoes you
know straight up just like dressing like
a man but they don't forget their women
no one can challenge them that they're a
woman no one can say you know what
you're not really a woman but especially
at that they're in their hearts but then
we get scared what are you a woman what
are you a bitch
ha ha right that's how we tease each
other what are you being a little girl
but you say to a woman you say to a girl
what are you being a boy it's really it
doesn't hold the same negative
association it doesn't hold the same
stain
as stop being a little girl when you say
to a boy I know because I'm a boy and I
wouldn't like somebody just say stop
being a little girl to me right when I
was a kid especially now I'm far more
mature I've learned a lot about myself I
learned about learning more about the
world and I understand sexual polarity
that much more and I realize and I'm
learning and those of you who are
recognizing contrast in my behavior my
attitude my way of being and they're
confusing like Elliott you're wearing
earrings and shit I've got a shirt on
with a with a heart blooming with
flowers and butterflies and I wear this
crystal which represents love and
compassion right the fuck is going on
Elliott you becoming a fag right I mean
that will be the typical imbalanced
immature masculine approach to the
divine masculine being expressed through
another man now if there's any question
about my sexuality
any question about your sexuality simply
because you're integrating or I'm
integrating more feminine aspects in me
and in yourself right first let's talk
about that let's talk about what those
feminine aspects are let's talk about
what the feminine shows up like in a man
you know I talk about my dress
right the way I'm dressing my earring
and my jewelry even my behavior which
some of you notice is far more flowing
far more relaxed far more rounded if you
will meaning that I don't have that
hyperactive premature ejaculating energy
that most young men carry with them
because it's highly praised and useful
too it's useful it's useful to so
sometimes less useful to us personally
and more useful to the warmongers
governments and corporations right for
us to stay in particular roles that they
could use this as cogs in their machine
but when you begin
exploring and integrating your anima or
your feminine aspect you're going to
recognize a few shifts in even your
mindset you know one of the major shifts
in mindset my mindset over the past year
as I am what you're watching me do and I
don't say this out of it blowing my own
horn or anything I'm just like this is
what I'm doing this is why M this is
what you're experiencing and if you want
to know what I'm doing you want to know
what's going on with Elliott Hulse well
shit I have no problem being objective
about it and just sharing just tell me
what I'm doing it Who I am
and and yes I'm becoming more feminine
yes
I'm becoming softer more flowing yes you
will find a Elliott host and any
masculine who design who desires to
integrate his odd Eman become more full
and whole and evolve and divine dancing
you will find us singing you'll find us
wearing jewelry you'll find us creating
art you'll find us breathing into our
balls while we relax and breathe with
our women rather than always trying to
poke them right okay
are you integrated enough with your
feminine that you could have a
relationship with a woman have a
communication with a woman without
actively pursuing the Smashing mmm
actively pursuing the punani right do we
have to every time you're with a woman
can you embrace the beauty of a woman
this is how you know that your your your
integrating your divine masculine with
the anima
can you embrace the beauty of a woman
admire a woman sensuality sexuality and
beauty without having to own it right
when I say that is like oh do you have
do you have to lay it down every time
you're with or on a woman you will find
that as you grow in your femininity is
you become more balanced and whole that
you start to ease up a little bit you
don't feel like you have to but then we
don't want extremes because in this it
and we do live in this age of extremes
we don't want to extremes we're not that
we don't want it but you know maybe it's
not always most resourceful for us and
we need to look at ourselves when we
become too feminine right now I don't
have that problem I don't have that
problem because should I access that I
exercise my masculine pretty fucking
hard for many years like I wrote in my
letter down below I grew up around boys
doing boy things and that was fucking it
even my you know my business which you
know me as look at my youtube channel if
you look at how many people were one of
the people the demographics that I
watched my videos it's something like
90% men right I'm confident in my
masculinity I'm firm in my masculinity
in my madness I have no problem wearing
hearts on my shirt and wearing my heart
on my sleeve and talking about
relationship with women without smashing
does that make me gay I don't know you
decide right because if you see this
part of me emerging and you see the
feminine another men emerging and you're
uncomfortable what is it about your
sexuality young man that you're
uncomfortable about that's my question
to you if you can't become fully
integrated you can't become whole which
includes yes King warrior magician and
lover but also its contrast its
complement its anima
if you can't if you can't access all
that then you've got some questions to
ask yourself and some growing up to do
young man so that's it
that's Elliott Hulse Gaiman is rat today
and these rats are getting longer and
longer but hey people asked me to make
look those you guys want me to make
shorter videos get on my Instagram I've
got I've got my team creating little
15-second clips I get it like I have to
reconcile that myself there are those
who want to learn who are willing to
listen want 20 minutes of information
which I'm willing to offer especially as
I'm driving right now and I could just
rant and those you guys who are still
look I get it - there's ain't too many
videos I'm gonna watch this 20 minutes
long I like those 15-second clips on
Instagram so of course I acknowledge
that I have no judgments against it and
I want to serve the best way I can so go
to my Instagram and you'll get 15-second
clips that are ripped right out of these
little bit these 20 minute videos and
whatnot so anyway that's it man those
you stuck around and watch this entire
video I apologize well I can't apologize
for the Sun and the glory of the Sun
that's behind me the entire time while
I'm talking
that's basking it you might not be able
to see the clearness of my face and in
my eyes cuz the Sun behind me but hey
what's life without a Sun behind us and
that's it y'all
I drove way past my office
you'll make a u-turn and talk to you
tomorrow actually no I'll talk to you
Monday