hello everyone thank you for watching
truth talks TV i am your host katerina
alec along with my incredible
straight-talking guest here Elliot halls
Thank You Elliot for joining me it's
such a pleasure to have you oh thank you
for inviting me this is pretty cool Oh
for those of those are the people out
there who might not know who you are I
think a lot of people know of you out in
the cyber world but you are a
professional strongman a strength coach
speaker father husband all these really
you know awesome roles that you take on
other people have this misconception
right that a guy who like works out a
ton is just you know kind of a meathead
and you've got leaves profound things to
share these insights that you share
along with not just like things had to
do with strength training but like just
these life you know lessons and just
inspirational messages so how did that
all of that kind of start and evolve I
guess well I own the gym and I trained
athletes and did some boot camps and
stuff and that was about a year after
YouTube came about and I figured it a
good way to bring more clients in would
be to film some of the workouts so I put
up my camera and film some of the
workouts me coaching the people and I
realized immediately that whoa I'm
getting comments from Mike Siberia India
from China it's like it was crazy and
you granted the internet is still fairly
new so five six seven years ago that was
like astonishing there was a Facebook
back then so tonight back from somebody
that lives on the other side of the
world was pretty cool so I basically
just started interacting with those
people by asking them questions on my
strength training channel and I'm
answering their questions and it just
turned into we're now I'm uploading at
least one video a day specifically for
strength training building your body and
stuff like that but also when you start
to answer those questions people will
ask you questions about like what do I
do what my girlfriend dumped me what do
i do my dad doesn't want me to my dad
wants me to go to college and I would
rather ride bikes you know so I wanted
to answer those questions I wanted to
offer some ideas so I created a sent a
separate channel where I just offer then
and I don't have the right answers nor
do I ever claim to but just offer
insights ideas that might be resourceful
for mainly young men to navigate their
life and become what i call the
strongest version of themselves so it
goes beyond just building a bigger
stronger body but having the character
associated with living a magnificent
life in all regards you actually just
did a recent one i think i saw where it
was like everything out there you have
all the answers within yourself
everything out there any resources just
pointing you to look at what you already
what you already know yeah i think one
of the biggest there are some core
issues that that seem to come up and a
lot of them can be found in just basic
character illogical issues if one of
them is not trusting yourself i noticed
that a lot of the questions the content
that the content is not nearly as
important as the context where are you
coming from what this question is always
what I want to ask I always want to like
know okay so you're asking this question
about your you know your girlfriend
looks like why do you need to ask me
that question because apparently the
answer is pretty obvious and it's
because we don't trust ourselves we've
been taught to like look for an expert
or teacher or a parent or some sort of
patriarchal figure to grant us
permission to be who we want to be so it
I'm often reiterating in fact that you
guys are powerful you're strong you're
already strong version of yourself you
just got to get out of your own way and
trust yourself strength three leagues
that's what you kind of your whole
message is not just in strength training
in your body but in all of your life
being the strongest version of yourself
what is that really and what how to tell
somebody cultivate that well about three
four years ago I got involved in a sport
of strong man so if anybody is not
familiar with that that's like if you
ever watched ESPN on my Christmas at
midnight you see the giant men flipping
tractor tires and picking up
big cement stones and pulling trucks so
it's a really off the wall crazy sport
designed to express her strength and I
got addicted to it I started doing I was
really good I was winning and I was
slated to be the strongest in America at
my weight class and I injured myself
just a few weeks before going into that
contest and the minute that my bikes
that popped I knew that it was time for
a new version of myself to be born
because I realized how imbalance my life
had become because of this obsession
with building more muscle getting
stronger achieving more and you know my
story is a metaphor for how we all tend
to go about our lives it's more bigger
better more successful more money
whatever the case may be for me it was
just a bigger stronger body that wins at
flipping tires and when I popped my
bicep it was almost like when in the old
cowboy movies when a horse breaks his
leg you literally have to take the gun
put him out of his misery and I went
through a period of pain associated with
killing that character and and and if
you're familiar with like what a Phoenix
does burns and then Rises I think we all
have the capacity to be born again right
and that's also a very difficult thing
to do so I literally had to kill one
character to be born again and I was
born again with the realization i
formulated this over the years that
strength is found in four layers okay
but I call the four layers of strengthen
these four layers all contribute to you
becoming a strongest version yourself
and the first and most superficial it's
really the outer layer of our strength
is what's what's happening here you know
we do you want to lose weight you want
to gain weight do you want what I
typically invite people do is to improve
your posture how are you carrying your
body I pull that normal muscular
strength our body is a physical
manifestation of what's happening at the
far deeper levels so one level deeper
than the physical manifestation you know
how
carrying yourself the look in your eye
the glimmer in your smile is a
expression of the second layer which is
our physiological strength physiological
strength is basically how well you are
taking care of your digestive system
your endocrine system your hormones and
things that are happening internally
these are the internal systems of the
body that need to be considered you know
you can work yourself to the bone but if
you're you're eating poorly not in the
bodybuilding sense of eating poorly like
you know how to gain weight or lose
weight but if you're just feeling your
body with poor quality food right things
that detract from your energy then
you're never really going to become the
strongest versions one step below that I
use a chart below but it's almost like
one step above that is energetic
strength alright really the one that
matters more than anything it's what's
happening here what's happening here
what's happening at a at a root
psychological emotional level you know
if you're if you're if you're mentally
in a boat if you're mentally stressed
it's going to manifest itself physically
physiologically because your hormones
will be off too much cortisol adrenaline
your be burnt out and I've stage three
adrenal fatigue you're going to be a
mess and if you got adrenal fatigue
there's no way that you're going to be
burning fat in the gym so we've got to
consider what what's happening here what
is your life like how are you thinking
about your circumstances and then
finally the fourth layer is what are you
going to do now because really all this
growing stronger can could be kute can
become a bit narcissistic if we don't
realize that well you're going to die
and how many people are you helping
along the way and I follow that
presentable strength because it's a play
on words because it's how we offer
ourselves as a stronger version as a
present to the world how are you serving
others and and presentable in the same
way well how do people perceiving you
because they're make no bones about it
the way you offer yourself to the world
will always you always get a mirror
reflection mm-hmm
hmm so really it's going out it's going
out and serving others right why do you
think you just said about being reborn
constantly like dying you should that
example in your own life like dying to
reborn rebirth the new version of your
sub why are people so afraid of dying
it's almost like we're so attached not
dying like literally dying but dying
like we can die daily right and like be
reborn and born anew every day and it's
just like we're so afraid and attached
to that attached or afraid of letting a
goal it's like wires that come from
because the natural process isn't it to
just be like it's a constant but yeah
yeah we become personally identified
with with who we've been told we are and
I think that's what it stems from I
think it stems from living in a world
where everyone wants concreteness they
want to know they want to know your
katarina and you got long hair and this
is what you're like good i got shit
perfect you the box you know we live
this in this really reductionistic
science has afforded us so much because
of our ability to reduce into pieces
right now we've got atomic science and
you know if you go dig even deeper
you've got quantum science where now
it's like okay shit we don't know
anything we've been able to reduce
things down to such an ability to such a
degree that we we can manipulate our
environment it has afforded us the world
that we live in it's given us the
opportunity to speak as we are from
across the world through bits right
through the computers with the internet
fantastic it's wonderful the problem is
human beings aren't that easy you can't
break us down but we in order to to
navigate the world in order to be able
to deal with people socially we start
creating categories for people we start
trying to break them down your of this
boom gotcha you're this boom gotcha
that's I mean it's really a form of
prejudice you know it might not be based
on color but it's based on boom I got
you I figured out that man who you are
right to make everyone else very
uncomfortable when you step outside the
box that they push you in you put people
in boxes and the minute you step outside
that box your mom goes that's not the
Elliot
I know is everything alright with you
you're acting more like Bobby Orr you
see what I'm saying like that you know
you're not yourself what exactly does
that mean I'm not myself it begins that
early where your parents want to be able
to label you pinpoint you boom I gotcha
and then you go into school and people
figured you're a jock or you're a nerd
or your this or your that but the minute
you step outside of that what are you a
sellout what are you selling it people
give that me give that to me a lot
because I you know I've got very strong
convictions and I'll just change my
fucking mind yeah you're like you're
such a sellout or sellout well cool call
me a sellout the problem is you thought
you knew me you thought you could pin me
down but I changed my mind and we've got
to be courageous enough to deal with
other people's criticisms when we decide
to change our mind when we decide to be
born again we decide to do something
different yeah they're very comfortable
because they know how to deal with us in
that box they know who you are right but
if you start acting speaking doing
things differently you just throw in
their game on hmm I don't know how to
talk to anymore I don't know I can't
expect you to be there for me on friday
evenings when we go and have drinks
right just stop my life right it's that
what you're also showing me how you're
showing me that I'm responsible for all
the dysfunction in my life how dare you
go and change to become a better version
of yourself show yourself because now it
forces me to look at myself and I don't
want to look at myself you're a bastard
mm-hmm that is so I mean it's like we're
just we are this energy this vibration
and we're constantly flowing and moving
if we allow ourselves to write if we're
not so tied to this idea of ourselves or
idea of others but yeah I've noticed
that people are afraid of it's like it
does it kind of threatens their very
belief system or whatever their their
security if you are now Oh today I'm
this I actually just had a conversation
recently with somebody and she was
because I was selling her that I have
the feeling that the the heart
conviction I'm going to be moving to LA
soon and she was telling you okay that's
cool but you know
better move to LA and and you know we're
from Chicago when we drink beer we do
run she's all like now oh I don't drink
beer another and she was making it seem
like because her friend moved to LA now
she's a different person now she's fake
and it's like her and she figures she
just now maybe just an expanded
different version of herself like why is
that a bad thing yeah it's wonderful
it's what the world does you know I'm
sitting here looking at trees outside
and the trees are constantly changing
the colors of the leaves are changing
the way it's growing is changing the
type of water that it's receiving
changes its physiology and the way it
expresses itself nature is constantly
moving we're the ones who have become
rooted in idea it's really right right
right exactly so one of the videos that
you've done that I bet one of the first
ones that i saw that i absolutely love
was you talked about creating a non job
resume and you went through this whole
process and i just thought it was so
brilliant about you said love something
share what you love receive the love and
and you represent it in such a way that
it's very simple and it is really quite
simple right because it's it's so it's
almost like i could feel first of all
within myself but i'm sure i could feel
it for others who would might be
watching that or hearing something like
that and go okay well wait it's not that
easy you don't like how do i actually
implement this how do i actually do this
because probably some people are saying
i am doing what i love but i'm not
receiving the money or I'm not receiving
the love so can you share a little bit
about that and really bright you know
because this is what you've sort of done
right in your own life yeah you know
doing things is always easy especially
when it's presented you know step one
step two step three becoming someone
different that's where the challenges so
it's not so much this is actually more
heart more difficult than it sounds it's
okay now you need to get out of your way
and allow that to happen so that's why
it seems far more difficult than it
really is now not a little wrong there
is a process of Education there's a
process of determination and discipline
and consistency all we
our character virtues are you
disciplined are you committed are you
courageous these are all things that are
there they're not written on the board
which you have to become right I'm
courageous to make this shit work so
it's not that this doesn't work that you
you need to grow stronger did you allow
it to work the mechanics of the
situation the mechanics of whatever it
is that we do is important but really
it's so prevalent so how to do things
there's no shortage of how to do things
how to do how-to books internet websites
what I've committed to do with the na
job revolution and website is to just
show you how because I know that's not
the issue we we tend to attach to the
how like the house like that's really if
I knew how but I know that it's like
look I'll show you have ya issue that I
should everything you need to do the
problem is you right so it's an
invitation it's two things it's an
invitation to grow stronger right and I
use many different metaphors to inspire
people to do this so that they can
support what's happening on earth let me
work we're evolving at a tremendous rate
because of the internet ideas are being
shared and remixed and growing and
growing and growing on such a you need
to be a part of it especially if you
have something to offer so it's an
invitation to become a different type of
person or the type of person that can do
that and it's also a place where you can
learn the mechanics of it the receiving
of the money is always the hardest part
not because it's hard to set up the
construct to receive money it's because
you've got money hangups you don't
believe you deserve it don't you feel
guilty right system for money mmm so the
mechanics of how to receive my not very
difficult very easy actually but the the
character associated with look first of
all you do deserve this because you're
offering us tremendous services people
are you helping people it's a very first
thing that you got to ask yourself are
you putting in yes I'm helping people
the people or the people are telling me
how much they're helping me I am putting
my heart and soul into this good now are
you the type of character but courageous
enough to say can i receive back the
world's not going to say here let me
give it to you the one will suck you dry
if you let it suck you dry you mean give
give and you'll end up nah that's fine
if you want to be that same person but
you're not going to be any of any use to
anyone because eventually you're gonna
grow is that full of it right and do not
have enough food to feed yourself so
that you can keep doing it so you tell
yourself a story which is all I'm doing
is setting up the natural flow by which
i can continue to serve you by you
serving me mmhmm yeah yeah you have to
ask for the money right right yeah
that's all comes down to self worth a
lot of times that core belief an issue
of self worth like you said deserving it
perfect because the whole non job thing
because it's like why really the
traditional as you said the traditional
American path is bullshit why is that I
mean I believe it I see it but I think a
lot of people out there still don't have
you read anything by Seth Godin not too
much not too much I know I know of him
but he's really he's my angel my
favorite authors to read with regard to
entrepreneurship he even goes as far as
I mean he's so poetic with the entire
thing he calls it art you can really
what we're doing is we're creating art
one of the things that he's brought to
my attention and this is not because
he's brilliant is just because I didn't
know is that the the traditionals the
contemporary school systems that we go
through in the Western world really the
world at large but mainly in the West
has been designed out of the needs of
the Industrial Revolution where they
needed man body hours so what you get
what you got to do is you got to create
really good cogs to fit into this
economic system right where you've got
people who are dependent on a paycheck
and are willing to just put their head
down and do mechanical work for a
competence and it really it it reduces
you to a machine it reduces you down to
a cog in a
because human beings are far more
creative than just putting together
pieces on