so I got this question from our our
buddy who wants to know how could he
really come to this place where he
doesn't care what other people think
about him so you seen me mention this in
some videos and stuff he says look I
know how valuable I am I know I'm a good
person
but I still have this this cloud over my
head that doesn't allow me to fully
express myself in hopes that I won't
offend anybody i I really do care what
other people think of me but I want to
be free from that how do I go about it
Elliot you seem to be so free from it so
let me share something with you be a
little ah transparent here with you it
affects me just as much as it affects
you and it affects everyone else it's
the biggest trap
of society is this this idea of
comparison and respectability living up
to what the world and everyone else
expects of you
right I mean we can't help it because we
know ourselves through others we the
world is our mirror so that what we get
back is a reflection of who we are the
thing is that there's a lot of there's a
lot of pathology out there also so if
you start judging yourself based on sick
people which you know we're all kind of
sick in a way you're just getting a
distorted reflection back of who you
really are the world can never show you
who you really are because the world is
fucking sick we live in a sick society
right I think ditch not Han says it's no
there's no mark of health to be well
adjusted to a sick society right so you
don't want to allow that to to shape
your perspective of yourself how's it go
man I can't talk right now I'm busy all
right
so you can't let the world do that to
you what you've got to do is continue
moving in the direction that you were
moving in regardless of what kind of
feedback you get you just keep doing it
it's about doing the thing it's not
about seek like I said before in other
videos you can't change the problem with
the problem that the level of which it
was created
right and this is one of these problems
that are created here how you do solve
this problem is if there are actions
that you would like to take
words you would like to share things you
would want to do that because of how
other people may be responding and
reacting and behaving towards you you
would otherwise not do you just fucking
do it anyway you can't get rid of this
you can't get rid of it I trust me I try
and sometimes it's better sometimes it's
worse you can't get rid of it but you
can keep doing what you're doing in
spite of it okay if there's something
that you wanted to say and it's really
moving up in your body and you're like I
need to say this but I'm too worried
about what the all the people in the
office write this is a good one in the
boardroom right I don't know what the
boss and my coworkers are gonna think if
I say this shit I think I'm an idiot or
gonna think I'm Bubba but you know what
you do it anyway that idea that they're
going to judge you better go away it's
gonna be there but you do it fucking
anyway that's really the gift here dude
I get I get comments and I get messages
to my YouTube and on Facebook of people
who like they're really mean sometimes
yeah I'm like fucking I'm generally a
nice guy fuck you Elliot you're an
asshole ignorant idiot who doesn't know
what he's talking about trying to sound
smart oh they really like they dig deep
Oh Elliot you're a money-hungry green I
greedy bastard all kinds of shit right
so that could very easily make me stop
making videos like magic imagine I let
those comments stop me from making
videos or stop building the business of
what the way that I'm building it
because people think I'm greedy
I'd like that would be slavery I got to
do what I got to do because I feel like
what I'm doing is right now I keep
making these fucking videos even though
there are people that hate me now here's
another thing it's a trick people love
you right that's a trap too so as you
start sharing your ideas and being
yourself in front of people and they
offer adoration good feelings come from
their reflection don't get attached that
either because you're a dynamic creature
human beings change we evolve we're
different from season to season from
year to year
we're always different and what happens
is when you present at a particular way
that people find pleasing
and you don't tomorrow whoa what's going
on hey this is not how I don't know you
this way your slave to that too we're
all if you allow yourself you'll be a
slave to all the opinions good and bad
of other people do what your body's
telling you to do trust yourself
listen to yourself love yourself keep
moving in that direction and not only
will you live free but you will give
other people permission to become free
themselves done