okay so we got a question from our
friend Alice she has a dear friend was
what she calls him who is sick and
depressed so he's got an illness that
could potentially kill him
but he refuses to go to the doctor he
says I'm just waiting till this all just
takes over and brings me to my deathbed
he's a depressing sad downer type guy
and Alice's always trying to tap him on
the shoulder and say hey wake up why are
you so depressed why don't you go to the
doctor why don't you do something why
don't you enjoy your life get out of
this depression Alice is really heavily
invested in his experiencing life to its
fullest right noble cause you want to
see your friend become the strongest
version of himself but he is not just
mediocre he's dug himself into a ditch
mentally physiologically and physically
in many ways you might say that perhaps
he's a lost cause but you come to Eliot
right because he did I tend to give some
interesting ideas that might support you
and your ability to support him because
that's what it's all about right
become the strongest version yourself
inspire others what can I do Eliot to
motivate my friend to motivate himself
so that he could experience life to its
fullest here's the thing I'm not
interested in your friend nor do I want
to talk about your friend Alice I want
to talk about you okay I'm wondering why
you're so heavily invested in pulling
this person up out of their ditch now
I'm not saying that you should be
hard-hearted or indifferent to other
people's pain but there tends to be a
particular type of person you who is
very attracted to victims him he has
chosen his position in life at this
point and he is a taker he's a sucker
he's a victim okay and again it doesn't
mean that we shouldn't do what we can do
to invite him back up out of the
addition to enjoy life but the amount of
emotional investment that you have in it
some unit which is evident through the
letter that you wrote me begs me to
consider that perhaps you
are dealing with a situation where your
self-worth is intrinsically linked to
your ability to help victims and that's
often manifestation of experiences that
we had with our parents of the opposite
sex
so my question to you is why do you feel
that your self-worth is tied up in
saving him oftentimes young women who
find themselves attracted to damaged
boys and when I say damaged boys are
damaged men I mean like those who are
just like the life is heavy and hard for
them they've been a victim they're
victimized he which I do this victimize
because he clearly is creating his
situation victimized by the illness
victimized by the depression and just
all the bad they can't even kill himself
she says that he tried to attempt
suicide but oh it was just too much you
perhaps have experienced the situation
where your father correct me if I'm
wrong was victimized my life also but as
a nine year old 10 year old young girl
you couldn't save him maybe your dad was
fired from his job and you know spent
the rest of his days as an alcoholic and
you just wanted to save your daddy or
perhaps your mom was a bitch and treated
him poorly and you always just wanted to
stand up and save your daddy whatever it
is for some reason you feel that your
self-worth is tied to your ability to
save someone particularly a man I would
invite you to turn away from him in his
situation because it's nothing but he's
nothing but an anchor and if it's not
him let's say he dies he's gone oh poor
Pete he killed himself that's really
what he did even if he doesn't take his
own life with a gun he's killing himself
with the illness you're going to find
another victim and the next man that you
decide to enroll in relationship with be
it sexually or friendship-wise is going
to be another anchor another loser
another person you've got to save now
you can go back there's nothing wrong
with this hey you
the rest of your life looking for people
to save and if that's your if that's the
way the spirit wants to move through you
then that's just fine but I have a
tendency to think that there are
probably better greater more powerful
things that you could do to reach people
who want to be helped
see if he decides that he wants to take
your help and he becomes what he
potentially could be you have now lost
your positioning
you've lost your grounding oh shit he
doesn't want to kill himself anymore he
actually is getting healthy he's feeling
good and then you know what you're gonna
have to do come back home oh he went on
your left at home now with no purpose so
you know you're gonna look for another
loser ah he's sick he's sad he's
depressed I want to help him and then he
either kills himself or you actually
motivate him and then you know what's
gonna happen you're gonna have to come
back home you're gonna have to keep
coming back home so my invitation is
come home now figure out why is it that
you feel that you need to do this and is
there something better that you could do
with your time again I tend to think
that there are things that you could do
that could support people who genuinely
are in a situation where they just need
a hand okay so so that's it I didn't
answer your question because I don't
think your questions do really is the
question behind the question the
question behind the question is why are
you attracted to someone like this and
how can you become a stronger version of
yourself so that you don't fall into
ditches with Downers and you can help
build up people who want to be built up
good luck