an interesting question from our buddy
rock shop here that's his youtube name
essentially fifteen years old and for
the past few years he's been starting to
lose emotion or feelings towards people
and things he goes on to say it's not
that these people have done anything
wrong or the things that he was doing
has lost any value so he's confused he
feels like he's just swimming through
life swimming in circles he doesn't know
what to do and he's becoming more
frustrated he also says that he's been
diagnosed with a form of depression and
I think that you're being diagnosed with
a form of depression is is valid and
interesting but I think a lot of people
are also suffering from this this
feeling of depersonalization detachment
from the world that we live in and you
talked about feelings and I think that
word feeling feelings is very important
because it points to the reality of how
we experience life we experience life
through feeling now in our culture and
in our world the way things are we've
come to conceptualize feelings right and
when I say conceptualize they're more
like abstract ideas as opposed what's
happening in our body and you know this
is true because when you walk through
the street you see somebody that uh that
you know and they yeah some hey how you
doing man I'm great knowing that like
his wife just cheated on him he's a
raving alcoholic and his kids are
failing school he's not feeling great
he's not doing great yes most people how
you feeling pretty good man everything's
great unless they're you know freaking
whiner complete a complainer and those
people it's a totally different that's a
different story all together but most
people are truly not in touch with
what's happening in their bodies it's
like I've spoke about before it's this
sort of schizoid condition where we're
living in our heads and we're not really
experiencing life through our bodies the
way that you're going to break out of
this right and this is just an idea for
you hopefully this supports you right
because your doctors giving you pills
and you know I don't want to cut in in
any way shape or form right I'm not I'm
not a therapist but what I do know is
that when we depress the energies in our
body in order to reduce the feelings in
our bodies and the reason why we do that
is it
it may have been a defense for you as a
child something may you may have
experienced something that's causing you
to shut down the feelings in your body
this is fairly normal and it happens
quite often the thing is it becomes
chronic and then you don't have feelings
to experience life with and then of the
things that used to feel good and the
things that should feel good the things
that should bring you joy and pleasure
in your body no longer do because the
same pathway through which you cut off
bad feelings because of experiences also
allows you to have good feelings right
so you're going through life and
essentially like you can't feel anything
everything is just kind of like in a
blur they call this depersonalization
what do you got to do you've got an
exercise you got to express the energy
in the body you've got to get it out if
you're not exercising right I know you
sent this to my Elliott Hulse channel as
opposed to my strength cam channel so
I'm not sure if you're somebody who's
into exercise but go to my strength camp
channel and start studying but also
really more importantly than studying
forget studying start exercising just
get it out of your body go for runs go
for walks join a CrossFit gym join a
powerlifting gym do something that's
going to get your body moving begin
doing yoga begin stretching and more
importantly begin deep breathing I
talked about this in several videos on
this channel and my others if you're not
doing bioenergetics begin with exercises
like the bow I've shown you this in
several videos just search my channels
and using the bioenergetics tool and
deep belly breathing these are all
techniques breathing exercise stretching
that are going to bring you back into
touch with your body these are things
that you do with your body I am of the
greatest conviction that our body and
our mind are one thing and if we work to
sever them from one another namely by
stifling the energies in the body by
either through neurotic holding patterns
right holding your breath and not
expressing it through exercise you're
going to have mental difficulty the body
is the mind treat it as such so that's
it my friend begin exercising begin
stretching your body
release the neurotic holding patterns
associated with stifled emotion and I
promise you that you're going you're
going to be relieved in some way shape
or form you're going to feel better
remember that word feeling you want to
get back into your body because that's
where feeling happens good luck