what is your take on killing your master
what would you marry me say this yeah
did you read master oh I've had a lot to
say this about us right OH
I'm wrong I try to be right don't follow
actually eat he's a coffee Holly he
likes expresso he likes a lot of things
right under it like some refreshments
okay
person I've spoken about this way we've
had this conversation
in a forward-moving world an aggressive
world in a male-dominated world
especially female oriented which
basically means goal achieving moving
towards right we find that are best
suited by finding someone ahead of us to
support us in moving forward but you end
up in and if you're a very self
subjective person if you know how to
feel yourself you get to a particular
point where the master has done enough
and in order to continue moving forward
not necessarily past him but in your own
direction you've got to create contrast
between him this is what teenagers do
with their parents when they when
they've gained enough and they've got
the strength enough to move into the
world they start looking for contrast
mommy and daddy are Christian I'm going
to be Hindu do you see we start start
trying to figure out how we can separate
ourselves and it's healthy because it
allows us to that field our own identity
outside the umbrella of the master
because you can go one of two ways you
could you can build yourself up to the
master and then you can sit at its peak
but if you do that you're doing everyone
in this service get out early doing
yourself a disservice because it's like
whoa wait a second push it away and
develop on your own a little bit you
needed that you needed mommy you need a
daddy for a little while and we always
need a mommy and daddy I to this day I
have been to work I got I just killed
one of my mentors right and I group up
to him and then I have to pull away from
him but you know what i discovered also
especially if they're good mentors i
found that because i put back to two
mentors that I'm killed I see other
mentors that i'll come back to recycle
but right now I've got to grow so yeah
you do yourself you do the master a
disservice because the maxtor is really
only objective and the measure of the
master is how many other masters has
that's really the true measure of a
master not how many follow where she has
you see a master with a lot of followers
something's not right that's more of a
cult but if you see a master who a lot
of other masters point to and say that
master got me gotten kind of fog go to
this master because he'll help me too
far to let you know that that but that's
true master because he's not interested
in followers he's interested in creating
massive but in the mind of this student
he has to create contrast he has to
separate himself so that he could move
over we do it with our dads none of my
dad the funny thing is with my dad I
gave my own mastery and I think that to
her nights I've had masters that in
different realms of study where I come
up to and then I'm like got time to kill
your ass like crazy and and it's funny
because the mind does funny things and
that's why we have hatred and bigotry
and racism and prejudice because the
more we can create contracts and the
bigger the divided we could create the
more independent we feel this is why we
don't have the love who's asking Bella
because we're costly trying to sever and
be independent really when it all comes
down to it we're together but anyway so
you do it with your father and you'll do
with certain masters but if it's a good
master you find night experience that
you come back and then it's like you're
at a different level of your mastery and
if that guy isn't true master it's funny
you start to see some of the crazy shit
this is fascinating rights like I talk
fucking crazy and then I'll have people
come back I get this all the time and
this is just through the internet I
first heard you and I thought you were
fucking nuts Elliot first video I saw
you I thought you crazy and then a year
later they let me go Elliot and stop
watching your videos buddy here Jesus
and do it to happen again hey he said
that shit I thought you were fucking
great same person you're a fucking crazy
game with you sitting thinking that any
making sense and it was gonna happen
guarantee your later really now I get it
now I see so if my dad with other
masters what do you should I remember
being like you're fucking you know what
you're talking about gonna come back leg
good health really so that's it I mean I
mean that's how we evolve we build up to
the energetic level of somebody loved us
but we almost have to step on them to
continue growing but we will always
honor and come back to that step again
if it was interests