hey what's up guys I'm on vacation this
week so you might notice that I'm in a
different location my appearance is a
bit different I'm actually in Dominican
Republic for the next few days but I
still feel the urge the need to answer
your questions via YouTube so I found a
really interesting one here that I could
not help myself what to answer it comes
from our buddy Steven and Steven check
this out really interesting situation 21
years old he's been dating a woman for
three years now the thing is Stefan is
still a virgin right so he's adopted
this philosophy of celibacy and it's due
to his being a Christian this is what
he's decided to do with his life the
thing is that he's in love with a woman
who has had lots of sex before he
started dating her now the conflict of
interest here is such that he wants to
be a man and every man has a strength of
conviction in some way shape or form and
I talked about the power of conviction
in other fandoms we're going to look at
them but a person with conviction
strength of conviction is a person that
demands or not even demands because the
man kind of means that you're asking for
but commands respect in every regard you
know a man with conviction because his
strength of character precedes him he
walks in and whatever he has to offer
people are willing to at least consider
because of the strength of his own
conviction the way you feel about and
project your conviction influences other
people and how they respond to you this
is very important because when you've
got a woman who has had sex that you're
doing in love with and she has
experienced manliness in the physical
sense in other words sexuality by
physical insertion by another man you
would tend to think that she can't
experience you as a man and that perhaps
you will always be less of a man in her
eyes compared to
man if she's had sex with right this is
the way you would typically look at it
and I can see that this is why you're
having anxiety this is causing you
anxiety a man has been manly with her
right put himself in her whereby you
have not and perhaps in her eyes that
makes him more of a man than you now
this is very interesting very important
sexuality is not confined to penis
vagina sexuality is in energy so you
have a masculine energy and you have a
feminine energy you could be a man and
have a very feminine energy you can be a
woman and have a very masculine energy
there is characteristics of one who
carries themselves with one of or
balance which is the way we should
evolve of the two so for you to continue
to be or build up the fit of masculinity
in yourself and in her you got to hold
very tight to your conviction conviction
strength of conviction and a dogged
determination to live it and project it
is very very manly very masculine for
you to be celibate not because of the
celibacy itself but because of your
shirt that conviction out thousand
celibacy and a woman who's very feminine
a feminine energy woman is a woman that
wants a man who's convicted once a man
was strong in his conviction who has
belief right so you're you call yourself
a Christian so you're familiar with the
Bible and in the Bible I don't know
where you know I'm not a Bible scholar I
just got bits and pieces but it talks
about how men are to love their women
women are to respect their men a lot of
people get that confused they needed
they think it means that a woman has to
yield to the neurotic demands of a male
which is not true if a man loves a woman
he's going to lead her properly he's
going to love her he's going to give
himself to her and move in a particular
direction that's resourceful for the
relate
ship and a respectful woman is one that
has enough trust in her man that she's
going to yield and these words have so
much negative association with it but
it's unfortunate that it does you thing
is very powerful
Thanks it almost sounds like you know
whom it needs to like just be dragged
around by a man that's not the case but
as a unit the male penis drives forward
moves forward a yielding woman is one
that has enough trust in that man she
will allow him to leave if your woman
who has experienced the physical
insertion of another man can physically
or could energetically psychologically
emotionally allow you to insert yourself
into her you see right now because this
is a metaphor for sex but it's still
very sexual for you to insert yourself
via your conviction and her to yield to
it you're still making the strongest
love that you could actually make to
this woman the sexuality that you're
sharing with her through your strength
of conviction and her willingness to
yield and move in a resourceful
direction with you is the greatest of
all sexual activity