hey what's up guys today we have what is
perhaps the oldest question in the book
one that mankind has been asking itself
since the beginning of recorded history
and one that I think every single human
being comes face to face with
individually at some time in their life
and that is why do bad things happen to
good people or another way it's often
put is why is God who's supposed to be
good allowing evil things to happen to
people if he loves us so much then why
all this evil fair fair fair question
and I'm going to begin like this I'm
going to relate a story of a man named
Victor Frankl those who may be familiar
with Victor Frankel's story that's told
in his book that leads to his ultimate
development of his former personal
development called logotherapy but even
beyond all that Victor Frankl was a man
who's a Jew living in Nazi Germany and
like I alluded to before he was a
psychologist so he was a well-read well
studied man he he was a upstanding
citizen and he had a wife and he had two
children and he lived in a suburb
similar to many of those that we live in
in the United States
he wore a suit he had nice watches and
he went about his life building his
profession as a psychologist with a
practice and people that he would treat
and at some point the political climate
of his country turned in such a way that
he and many of the people liked him Jews
in Germany at this particular time were
swept up out of their homes removed from
their family and separated their
clothing was removed and they walked
naked and all of that which they built
up in their life including their
material wealth and for him it was a lot
of his intellectual well
books that he's written were swept away
sold burned and then being separated
from that which is the the closest thing
to life and love for most people which
is your family and to realize that
you'll never see them again because your
wife went off on a train with women your
children were sent off on train with
other children and you as naked as they
were when they were ripped away from you
hop on a train and go live amongst
neighbor strangers in a concentration
camp he describes this stripping of his
dignity and his humanity and being
treated like an animal it's a sick sad
depressing situation but it's not one
that's too unique or rare in the course
of human history I mean it's not been
done to African slaves it's probably
being done today
it's just one of these things that like
you ask is evil in what should be a good
world it's a bad thing happening to
seemingly good people Viktor Frankl is
an interesting guy because he is a
thinker he's an observer and also an
author and a and a server of mankind so
although he felt as if his life was
coming to an end and most people's were
living in these concentration camps he
still maintained his sense enough to
observe what was going on around him and
to take notes as to the the
psychological pain and then the
subsequent downward spiral of those
living in these horrific conditions
his wife was killed and he knew it he'd
never see his children ever again and he
knew it and on a daily basis he would
walk out into the freezing cold not by
his own fruition by by the way but
because there was a gun being held to
his back along with a line of other Jews
in these concentration slave camps and
you may have had on a rag or something
that may have clothed him somewhat but
he'd be freezing fucking cold
and asked to break up the ground which
was frozen you know and imagine he
hasn't eaten very much food and perhaps
months at this point so he's lost about
60 pounds and and they're given shovels
and they're asked to go out into the
frozen ground and dig ditches so that
the their oppressor could use their
slave labor in order to build railroads
and so on and so forth so here you have
a man who once knew what it was like to
live a warm comfortable self-actualizing
life with people that he loves too now
freezing cold and naked digging ditches
and when he's fed because it was very
rare that he would receive food there
would be a big VAT with heated up water
and a few potatoes thrown in and he
relates all this in his book man's
search for meaning so he can read this
story also and you know from time to
time there might be a piece of meat
thrown in this big vat of water and and
then they would scoop it out and
everybody get a bowl and you get a bowl
that's hot water with like some very
sparse nourishment in it if you got a
piece of potato or you got a piece of
meat in it it was like striking the
lotto and he talks about one day being I
think at some point he because he was
punished because of you know some
discretion you know he he why he yelped
when someone hit him I don't know whose
horrific conditions but anyway he was in
in a confinement for those who had
breached conduct
and he was brought a bowl of this soup
if you will and he relates the
experience of looking into the bowl of
soup and seeing a tiny piece of potato
and in observing that piece of potato he
describes what has been called many
different things from through the mouth
through the lips of enlightened people
that have walked this earth and taught
us as a deep and profound sense of peace
Nirvana or heaven if you will in that
moment he felt a deep and profound sense
of joy and pleasure happiness he even
breaks out into laughter and he feels
the warmth of joy in his heart for
receiving this bowl of soup that
contained a piece of potato that was a
good thing happening to him not only in
his rationale because he was an
intelligent man who could say well you
know like like I often do in these
videos I'm just talking there are all
just perspectives their ideas it's very
abstract he felt and you know how often
I talk about the importance of feeling
thinking and talking is very shallow
that's why these videos only do one that
to do one thing but to instill a feeling
in you he felt joy at that moment he
didn't think about it or intellectualize
it like many of you do well I should be
happy right no you're not you're not
happy and that's what it is
he was happy a good thing was happening
to a good person and if you looked at it
say you'd say fuck why is God so evil he
would argue with you in that moment if
you walked into that cellar at that
particular moment saw him naked with
bones sticking out of his skin looking
at a bowl of hot water with a tiny piece
of potato and you said boy why is God so
bad
as evil things happen he'd look at you
and say he would just burst out with joy
and he relates this experience
so why do I tell you this and what does
this have to do with well you know well
why is God or why is the universe or why
is Allah allowing evil things to happen
to seemingly good people because from
your perspective walking into that room
you're going to say evil shit happening
to a good guy he would look at his bowl
of soup and say ah and be overjoyed and
full of pleasure what the fuck is going
on
makes no sense does it you could be
wrapped up in all of your judgment about
what's going on at that particular
moment based on your experiences and the
stories you've been told since you were
a child about what good and evil is and
he's sitting in the shit and glowing
with happiness now you could say well
he's lost his mind because he hasn't
eaten in a very long time and he's sick
sad depressed he's a maniac because he's
a slave who hasn't eaten and is in this
horrific condition you get a chance to
read the book or to study any of the
work of this man you'll see that he was
very cognizant of what was going on
throughout the entire time and that's
why his his books and his interviews
although he doesn't live today but you
know he passed not too long ago was such
a blessing such a gift to mankind
because not only did he just roll with
the punches and make the best out of
things he observed and he he all though
he felt a visceral joy he concluded
based on his years of study
in the realms of psychology and
philosophy so not only does he have the
experience but he has the weight the way
of sharing with you so now I'm going to
back up for a moment and I'm going to
I'm going to share with you a number of
things that have been profound for me in
my life the very first of which is a
part of a poem that comes from a Sufi
poet by the name of Rumi our Umi and
it's very simple but yet very profound
what he says in one of his poems when he
alludes to the fact and invites his
reader to consider that there is a field
there's a place beyond good and evil I
will meet you there
in other words he's preparing his reader
for a conversation where we can set
aside the judgments of good and evil
because they're merely ideas they're
merely judgments they're merely tools
that humanity has used in order to
understand the world we live in much of
our technology is a byproduct of our
understanding of the dualism that the
didactic nature of nature Sun and Moon
zero one digital the reason why you're
watching me is because of a series of
zeros and ones it's this contrast
between black and white is this thing
like just does the assisted I saw two
good evil so we've been able to use this
digital technology to navigate our way
into this amazing incredible time that
we live in where I can talk to this lens
and you can see it in Croatia you can
see New Zealand
so I'm not saying what I'm about to say
preferencing what I'm about to say not
as a judgment again against the idea of
dualism but to share with you how
everything that comes from this field
that Rumi talks about is a unity of good
and evil there's no one without the
other and that's why he says beyond the
good and evil judgments there's a place
and that place could be nothing more
than a unity a unification of good and
evil it's all these things I say yeah I
believe if I keep referring to in the
Old Testament I create good I create
evil I create all these things I create
the light I create the darkness God is
all these things so Rumi shares us with
shares that idea with you Sufi poet
Sufism is a is a outgrowth of Islam
Islam is a Abrahamic religion the
Abrahamic faith or the lineage uses many
ancient texts including one called
Genesis and you know if you're if you're
a Jew if you're a Christian if you're a
Muslim or any variation thereof you're
familiar with the story of Genesis and
those who watch my videos long enough
you realize that I'm completely
objective about all these ideas
I love wisdom I love mythology I love
psychology I love religion but I'm not
religious meaning I don't hold on to
anything I use it right and let it go so
what I'd like to do now is go to the
roots of our psychological development
as a race of human beings as is
described in the ancient poem of Genesis
that describes why we've become cast out
from this garden of good and evil and
how partaking of this tree of wisdom was
our greatest blessing and curse right
the Garden of Eden mankind story goes
that mankind makes his way and he's got
male and female and at some point a and
he's living in Nirvana he's living in
heaven he's living in Eden it's fucking
beautiful things are great there's two
of everything and everything's together
the woman comes from the man right it
does it's not about which came first and
which one's better the fact is that
they're one flesh and all the animals
there's male and female there's night
and day I mean everything's going
smoothly because everything always goes
smoothly but the reason why it's near
vana is because Adam and Eve didn't eat
the tree of wisdom yet they eat from the
tree of wisdom meaning they have no
fucking wisdom they're like pigs in slop
they're happy right and I say pigs in
slop because there's a level of
ignorance associated with that form of
of animal on this earth that we have
transcended because we ate that
beautiful Apple they're hanging out shit
is great good things are happening to
good people and evil things just don't
exist right because there's no
perspective for it it's just the way it
is everything's just the way it is man
the Garden of Eden must have been great
right how many people live their lives
trying to get back to this place right
they live their life trying to go to
heaven
you know what they're trying to do to go
back to where everything was won and
there was no judgment between good and
evil that's what heaven is and all these
people who live their life trying to be
good have lost the fucking point they're
trying to be good so they can go to a
better place as opposed to realizing
that the world is one thing it is what
it is the dow was called the dow it's
the way and if you just kind of go with
the flow and stay as objective as
possible you don't feel bad feelings and
you've also gained a perspective where
you can actually have what are seemingly
evil things turned into some of the most
resourceful things that have ever
happened to you and that you could use
to bless mankind like Viktor Frankl
Tennyson as the story goes a snake now
you got understand the symbolism of a
snake a snake is always represented
wisdom if you look in the Egyptian
hieroglyphs right what are they called
hi other the pictures the pectorals
where they teach it why is there always
a fucking snake on the on the real wise
guys heads like the dudes that their
suitor was like respecting they're
bringing him gifts and shit he's got a
snake on his head because for the
longest time the snake the serpent has
represented wisdom and a part of the
reason why and there are many different
reasons why the snake represents this is
because of the snakes ability to shed
his past he has this ability to sort of
shed himself to be beyond himself and
leave himself over there if you ever
look at a snake skin a snake is over
there but he's also over there
dinner san he's able to shed himself of
the experiences and growth of life and
be objective from it that's one of the
many reasons others are you know the
whole idea that it's it's it's slithers
meaning it's very close it's its belly
its roots are very close to the earth
but yet it could it could stand up on
tail and become almost human-like in its
ability to be erect being erect
keeps standing up is very our biology
it's a part of reason why we have our
psychology your body is your mind I
often say so the snake can bring itself
upright and in doing so it lines itself
up in the same way that an antenna lies
itself lines itself up and the human
being
lines himself up which allows them to
access frequencies right we are walking
fucking antennas right no other animal
does is if there's another animal that
walks around the way we walk around all
the time with his genitals and eyes in
front then it would be a human being
because it would have access to
frequencies that only human beings have
when I say frequencies I mean literally
frequencies but also intelligence and
understanding and it would have
developed in this particular way those
that are close to us like Apes have a
little bit they're a little closer to us
in their psychology but look at their
body also right they can they can be
logical like we can be logical now they
don't have it develop the same way we
have it right we're just little bit more
evolved but they stand up not once
that's why they not only look like us
but they are like us in many ways so
this animal that represents wisdom comes
and says to Adam and Eve who are living
in bliss they're all naked and they're
cool and and being naked is an
interesting thing because although she
has a penis and he has a vagina good
evil black white female female
notice this penis vagina or vagina penis
penis vagina they're not ashamed meaning
they don't recognize that there should
be some sort of judgement placed on
their difference they're just like there
it is there it is great we're awesome he
shows up and I explains to them look now
the boss knows some shit you guys don't
know the boss has had the boss has some
wisdom the boss has some power right
they say he created all this
I tell you this young atom and easily
seduced Eve right that if you eat from
this tree of wisdom notice it's not the
tree of sinfulness not the tree of
damnation the tree of wisdom of good and
evil you too will have the power that
the boss has interesting and tempting
proposition well as the story goes they
say let's go for that ride baby as soon
as they eat that piece of fruit boom
their eyes are opened penis vagina cover
your shit up holy cow
that shit is going crazy nothing changed
but their perspective nothing in the
world changed at that moment when even
and animate that Apple the world didn't
go boom evil what happened was their
eyes were open and they saw and they
were ashamed because they were able to
judge between the differences the
judgment between the differences allows
for our technology like I said before
zeros and ones and you know we use just
the whole digital era as a byproduct of
that wisdom but also it allows us to
make judgements based on the feelings we
have in our bodies now feelings are just
feelings
feelings are just feelings they're
they're they're warnings or they're
tellers of what's going on but there's
no judgment really there's no good or
bad feeling they're just feelings and
there are ones I like a little bit more
of an ones that I like a little less of
but the minute we start saying good and
evil
good and bad
we start attaching all types of
associations to the two different ends
of Abaco you put the coin it's still a
fucking quarter there's not a good side
and a bad side it's all the same thing
just like the Garden of Eden was all the
same thing but now you go like this who
one must be good one must be bad so now
we have language to describe the
experiences in life that give us
feelings that we would rather have less
of the dangerous thing about words is
that it's it's a it's a cycle you have a
feeling you give it a word you give it a
symbol right words or symbols evil let's
use that word evil I have a feeling I
don't like I call it bad it's a bad
feeling if I recognize that my feeling
which really has no there's no judgment
on my feeling but now I call it bad it's
bad it's a feedback loop which says bad
bad bad and you start attaching to the
symbol you know they say don't worship
false idols you know what idols we
thought we worship more than anything
much right the word evil and the word
good we come to worship it bow down to
good and fight against evil we're
worshipping ideas based on a new form of
wisdom that only humankind has about the
dichotomy of nature what does this all
have to do with good things happening or
bad things happen to good people when
you say bad things happen to good people
you're committing the greatest sin the
greatest misunderstanding that Rumi was
alluding to when he said let's go beyond
good and evil and play in this field
you're perpetuating the idea that
perhaps eating the fruit of good and
evil removed us from some sort of joy
that should always should be
ever-present on earth and in our lives
but that's just a judgment it's just an
idea
it's as abstract as anything else you're
playing the game of feeling bad you're
playing the game of good and evil go
back to the Garden of Eden before we our
eyes were opened in this way and guess
what you find Nirvana the Garden of Eden
heaven heaven is an experience of
oneness between seeming opposites you
need good and evil but good and evil are
just words to describe two opposites of
the way it is you see I think it's
brilliant that the Daoists call this the
way they have no word for God they call
it Dao Dao translates into the way it's
just the way it is now there are going
to be those of you who are watching this
and you say Ellie oh that's fucked up
because you know there are starving
children in Africa and Asia in other
parts of the world and you're you live
in America where things are good got oil
you got cars and you got food you got
air conditioning good evil
when you say that you're once again
perpetuating the miss the sin the
original sin associated with the garden
in the Garden of Eden this is where we
were cast out we were cast out in our
psychology and our psyche we were cast
out so I should feel guilty right based
on the way you described it I should be
guilt I should feel guilty for what the
way has created and I happen to be just
a a leaf flowing in the wind of the way
I know I can't take full credit for
being here but I should feel guilty
because the way has also created a way
where there are those who don't have
judgment judgment judgment judgment
judgment Judgment Day Judgment Day is
right now we're living in hell because
we do this now I'm not saying to be
hard-hearted or apathetic about the pain
of others what I'm saying is that the
most important thing for us as
individuals either living in
concentration camps where we were
stripped from all that we experience to
be good that's the toughest way to
experience pain not I was born hungry
you do have no contrast a starving baby
in Africa is not that upset because
there's no contrast it's like this is
Earth this is how I feel I'm dying now
there's no there's no judgment but a man
who knows both will still tell you I've
reached Nirvana I understand the Garden
of Eden
I experienced heaven on earth
because he put aside the judgments
I'd like to finish with this number one
just to reiterate good and evil are two
sides of the same coin
you can't have one without the other in
the same way that you can't have daytime
without night time life does this it's a
part of the reason why the snake is so
interesting because it does this it just
lets go with skin and keeps going we
have pain when we recognize contrast and
attach judgment to the different types
of contrast good sunshine light is good
darkness is evil that's a fucked up one
that gets us into a lot of trouble
lightness is good and dark is evil so
give me all light you know what's gonna
happen to set the fucking bearable
scorch give me all sunshine and light no
darkness that would be a six sad day
because you'd be more miserable than
you've ever been cuz that type of
imbalance will fry you like an egg the
night cools today and it will always be
that way as long as night follows day
there will be things that you judge as
evil happening to what you judge as good
people okay it's just the way it is the
minute you find yourself making
judgments about me and what I'm saying
right now check yourself and go back to
it go back to everything I just said set
aside your judgments set aside your
feelings and the judgments of your
feelings and experience what I just said
even if you have to turn it off because
you can't stay in my fucking face
because you think it's an ugly face it's
your judgment set it aside for a moment
and go to that field beyond it and you
might find something
number one number two in our individual
lives when things happen that you don't
like you might label as evil understand
that within every single bad within
every single evil within every single
pain is the seed for pleasure
one never exists without the other so
when your life sucks recognized right
away use your beautiful brain to gain or
at least brainwash yourself for the
perspective that there is also a good in
there you have to do this otherwise
you're going to be so attached to the
evil that you'll make yourself sick sad
depressing gonna die a fucked up loser
like most of us do and have to come back
and do this again
you're going to hell and you already
live in it so you'll just keep burning
when bad shit is happening to you you
look for the silver lining in the cloud
that's not a hippie saying that's not
just an admonition to think happy
thoughts
it's the way it fucking is the way the
world works its nature its science its
you can't have negative without positive
it just works that way get that through
your head and also when things are going
great make sure you recognize that the
table will turn at some point so when
things are going good I always say this
I quote abdu'l-bahá be generous in
times of prosperity and thankful in
times of adversity you see the dichotomy
it's the most natural thing
and finally this is a long video check
my watch cuz I got a dentist's
appointment I got some bad things
happening my teeth need to be extracted
finish up now and finally you watch
others who suffer who are in pain that
it's described merely by you and your
judgment because many times you go to I
hear stories and I've been in third
world countries and it's another
judgement and I look at people who don't
have a tenth of what I have and the look
in their eye is of joy peace and
pleasure
they have everything much more than many
of us have with our fancy cars and air
conditioning they don't take pills for
being sad they don't have to go to
doctors to tell them and talk about why
they're they can't breathe you don't
have anxiety they have the way they
enjoy it
but you might make a judgement on that
and oftentimes that's when you fuck up
those native cultures cuz you bring in
what you think is good here's all the
good stuff I've got ears big giant cross
because it always begins that way I've
got Jesus Christ is going to save us all
and technology and you begin to tell
them why this is good what I've got is
good poor soul you have no shoes and
then you start fucking their heads up
and then they want Jesus Christ and
technology and then you know as the
world goes right that's just what we do
and then we and then and then we sit
back and wonder why the Amazon is being
destroyed Oh another evil then the evil
of the destroying of the Amazon we just
gotta stop you gotta you gotta stop you
just gotta stop continuing with your
judgement on someone else or another
circumstance that for some reason you
don't need to judge it but you feel
compelled to do something about I feel
compelled to feed starving children then
you just do it without any judgement you
don't do it because you're fighting evil
that's the dumbest fucking thing in the
world because you don't happen when you
fight evil you get more evil so you can
keep fuckin fighting it doesn't add or
because I'm burying fruits of good no
you're not bearing fruits of good
because when you create when you bear
fruits of good guess what with a fucking
basket of good comes a basket of evil
you're not gonna win you do it because
your hearts telling you do it and that's
all I feel as if I should feed these
people you just do it don't judge it do
it I speak to upwards to a million
mostly young men through these videos on
a daily basis I can sit here and say I'm
doing good I am helping people I'm
working to combat the forces of evil
that's oppressor in your minds and
bodies it's all fuckin judgement none of
that is true
I do this because that's what an elliot
does it's just what's happening here
it's just the way done