so today's question comes from our 21
year old friend who lives in Romania
want to read some of his question here
he says I want to ask you one question
how did you start changing your belief
system and turning your life around
finding what you love to do he goes on
to say that he's in college that he
doesn't like he doesn't want to be in
college but he's there because he
promised his parents who'd finish
he's been single without a girlfriend
for about a year now he has no job
self-esteem is kind of low I think I see
here somewhere that he said he played
basketball at some point but anyway it's
not satisfied this question is when you
have so many things around you where do
you start meaning so many different
ability school parents so on and so
forth just need to get a job and what
not education love life money jobs how
do you figure it out really good
question you know the title of his
question is how to turn my life around
and I really started thinking about what
that actually meant and I think it's the
wrong way to look at what you want to
have happen for you in your life my
friend you really don't need to turn
anything around except perhaps your eyes
and when I say that I mean turn your
eyes or your focus inward what happens
is that life like a tornado spins us
around with all of the different
obligations and belief systems ideas
demands that the world places on us
parents school government jobs all these
things spin us around and we get lost in
it just like you could imagine if you
got picked up by a tornado I mean you're
turning upside down flipping around
things are hitting you from all over all
different angles there are tragedies
just imagine this craziness this is the
life that we end up living in but there
is a place where you can come back in
contact with the true you with your
essence with the peaceful calm
Center which is the eye of that storm do
you see and from that place using that
same metaphor that that place of the
peace calm center eye of that storm
interesting that they call it the eye
because from that place you can see
because you're stepping back and you can
see the world wind of school and
basketball and girlfriends and jobs and
parents and grades spinning all around
you as you stand firm in your place of
solitude of peace of non movement you're
being unmoved you're just watching so to
say turn around your life in many ways
people take that to mean how can I alter
change out switch out the different
elements of the tornado that I'm in what
I'm asking you to do is to learn how to
step out of the tornado do you see so
turning around isn't a isn't a switching
of the content of the tornado
it is a getting out of the tornado
moving inward to the eye very different
also of course I'm playing I'm being
very poetic with this metaphor very
different also than stepping out of the
tornado completely stepping out of
tornado completely completely would mean
that you're not in the I you're separate
from the tornado when the tornado is
doing its thing I think that's a less
resourceful way and what that would look
like is basically someone who checks out
someone who's like you know I just can't
handle this I don't want to do it I
talked about the matrix the other day
this is someone who basically says you
know what I just not going to do this
and I don't know you end up traveling
the world begging for for food that's
cool that's interesting I think it's a
little bit of a cop-out
because if we learn how to navigate that
tornado just imagine how much more
powerful you are as a human being
because there are the all the elements I
mean they're good they're cool things
you know making money's cool having a
girlfriend is cool pleasing your parents
is cool getting good grades is cool
those are all cool fucking things you
don't have to put those things away you
don't get away from those things and
step out of the tornado you got a step
deeper in deeper into the world when
of your life so that all sounds well and
good right practically what the hell
does that look like Eliot I'll give you
what works for me but I will also give
you a few different ideas that might
support you wherever you are because
we're all very different there's no one
road to the kingdom there are many roads
and the road that works best for me
every single morning when I get to my
gym before I make these videos I request
that the guys that work at my gym give
me space between 9 a.m. and 1 p.m. and
during that time I spent a significant
portion of it stretching my body
breathing and meditating this works best
for me because I have a very tense
muscular system and that's why I talk
about things like bioenergetics when I
relax my muscular system when I stretch
when I breathe my energy is grounded I'm
focused on in the moment with the
activity that I'm doing
I also meditate in such a way that all
the activities of the tornado that come
to me during that time I completely
dismiss I ignore it completely I don't
let it distract me from that moment of
meditation
that's my form of meditation that's how
I meditate I'm asking you to meditate
it's an active form of meditation very
similar to yoga I call it bioenergetics
there's a lot of deep breathing this
works for me I'm a body person you might
want to try that experiment with it but
really the key is finding that time for
yourself even if it's an hour once a day
another form of meditation that has
worked wonders for me and I still kind
of go back to every once in a while when
I when I feel I needed is whole asynch
audio meditation it's an audio program
you could look it up it's called hollo
hol o sy NC man the first time I used it
it felt like I was so astonished to the
fact that I didn't have butterflies in
my stomach and put it that way I didn't
have anxiety in my belly right and I was
shocked what the hell happened and it
was at two weeks after using these holy
sink this whole sink CD it there's some
technology behind it or they call it
binaural beats where it creates more
comma serial neurons between your your
left and right hemisphere look all I can
offer use my experience
worked I I felt like I was in the comm
center I of the storm of my life and
that was a very difficult time in my
life when I first started that one that
I know that works very well for a lot of
people in fact I'm relisting to the
autobiography or the biography of Ralph
Waldo Emerson and it's journaling right
my friend find that quiet time for
yourself
light a candle be good to yourself light
a candle take a hot bath put on a robe
smoke a joint maybe you're into that and
be with yourself and your thoughts and
it's almost cathartic in your behavior
because you're writing so you're
literally letting the abstract the word
become the flesh if you will you're
letting the abstract purge its way
through your body and you write and you
just write this journal you write about
what happened that day the things you
thought about the things that you're
dreaming about so on and so forth really
what you're doing is you're getting in
touch with that part of you where
thoughts arise see thoughts are one of
those things in the tornado and if
thoughts are throwing us around right
negative thoughts positive thoughts
dreams desires fears they're all in that
fucking tornado and if you let that toss
you around also it really becomes the
root issue because it's really tied to
your spirit Dennis and your thoughts are
tied to the spirit world they're they're
there they're tangible in that they
affect your physiology right just think
fearful thoughts
you're not going to breathe and they're
spiritual in that they're completely
abstract they are nothing thoughts but
they can fuck you up get in touch with
your thoughts
notice if they're resourceful thoughts
also listen to positive uplifting
messages from a myriad of different
sources I used to listen to a lot of
Brian Tracy audio programs Earl
Nightingale you know depending on you
your bed you know you read and fill your
mind with positive when I say positive
doesn't mean that there's a right or
wrong
I mean resourceful that makes you feel
good books and audios so that's it dude
look man you're perfect just the way you
are we're all perfect just the way we
are
it's not a matter of changing who you
are or turning your life around it's a
matter of getting in touch with your
essence getting in touch with the
Magnificent brilliance that is you
appreciating respecting that and then
letting that guide your life when I say
find what you love and live on your own
terms it's less of an activity is less
of a outward activity and more of a
inward journey of self-discovery and
then letting that self as you discover
it as pieces of it emerge and you learn
more about yourself because really self
exploration self discovery is the most
important part of this entire thing you
let it guide you and that's what I've
done and that's what I invite you guys
to do done I hope that helps