so I got this question from our buddy
Nick who is confused about why his life
is great but oftentimes he just feels
horrible he's happy and then it doesn't
last he's upset he's sad about something
but he doesn't even exactly know why he
rationalizes that well I have everything
I need my life is basically good but I
feel horrible I look in the mirror I
don't like myself what's going on here
how can I avoid these horrible feelings
about myself this depression that comes
over me when in reality my life is good
why is this happening and how can i how
can I avoid these ups and downs very
first thing I want to let you know Nick
is that you're not alone I go through
this quite often more often that I'd
like to to admit there are times where
my life is fucking awesome you guys
watch me and of course I've you know I'm
a little bit of a celebrity because I
make these videos so you think that like
my life is perfect and in many ways it
is but there are times when I look in
the mirror or I just wake up oh and for
absolutely no reason in in my body I
feel horrible and I know what you're
saying too because your mind is your
head brain is saying dude rationally the
fuck is your problem but you feel the
heaviness in your body I've shared many
different ideas and perspectives with
you on meditation and looking at
yourself objectively recognizing that
these are just negative thoughts that
come from our environment some even
believe they're embedded in our DNA or
come from past lives I've also shared
ideas about how to free your body from
the tension associated with this so I
wanted to do something different and
share with you a third of multiple
perspectives that you could use when
there are times that you can't
rationally understand why you feel like
shit why does the pression come over me
there's a really great quote by abdu
l-bahá where he says be generous in
your prosperity but thankful in your
adversity and it's a way of life it's a
way of balancing out the ups and downs
of your life because there are going to
be times when you're prosperous and when
I say prosperous
mean they're making $10,000 a day it
means that life is guy feel good this is
there's a sense of prosperity coming
over me things are good and they're
going to be good in those times
recognize that it's happening recognize
it that it's 50% of the game the other
side of the coin and be generous in that
if you feel good give those good
feelings to other people say nice things
to people if you got a little bit extra
change in your pocket buy something for
someone you know a stranger hold the
door open smile say a kind word be
overflowing with that prosperity when
you have it do not hold on to it or do
not suppress it do not be stingy with it
give give give give give and every
opportunity that you have when life is
prosperous when you're feeling good it's
going to set up I've experienced this
myself and I use this technique quite
often and it's a perspective that I have
to keep reminding myself of and that's
why I'm sharing this with you it sets up
when you're that way in prosperity it
sets up a stronger rebound when in in
squalor when you're it was the word I
used when there's adversity now this
adversity might be internal adversity
you're just feeling bad about stuff you
don't know why or it could be that
things are really bad circumstances have
played out such that there are things
that aren't really good in your life
right now things are hard someone died
you failed something you whatever the
case may be a woman broke up with you
you're an adversity in that time now I
mention that you know I mentioned
rebound now you can even help the
rebound even more because really all of
life is about how we choose to feel
about it when you're in that
circumstance of adversity be it
intrinsic or intrinsic or extrinsic
cultivate gratitude it's very difficult
at that time but trust me it's going to
help catapult you back into good
feelings good feelings are a choice but
we've got to know how to navigate the
circumstances of our life in order to
get more of good feelings than bad
feelings and like I said that when you
give during times of prosperity there's
good feelings and Arriba is a stronger
rebound from times of adversity and
during times of adversity when you are
grateful for all you do have it again
brings back good feelings it allows good
feelings all this is subjective because
you know there are people who have
everything but are depressed and there
are people who have nothing and they're
happy it's all about the choice and when
you are in adversity but you're grateful
for the little that you have you choose
feeling it rebounds you back into the
future choose the feeling of goodness
well-being in your body I have a lot of
great things in my life but there are
times when I just don't feel good so I
have to remind myself boy I have a great
wife who supports me and loves me with
all her heart I have beautiful children
who are healthy I mean that's a unique
thing there are children in the world
were born on Helen unhealthy I can help
I can put food in their mouth
not only can I put food in their mouth
but I have a knowledge of what is
healthy for them that I can support them
with I have a car
I am healthy myself I don't have any
chronic disease I have a roof over my
head I'm wearing clothing I've had a
meal today
I can drink clean water there's clean
fresh air for me to inhale no matter how
bad things get there's also always
something it's usually the most
rudimentary thing the most basic and
primal things that you've got to be
grateful for you choose to be grateful
for Beach you choose to be grateful for
the fact that your heart beats what a
magnificent thing that your heart beats
or that you have a shower you can how
crazy is it that we have water that goes
through pipes that just rain down upon
us we have rain to clean our body at our
wit at our whim at our will and you can
even adjust the tempo
of that rain that's magnificent I mean
how that's never happened before the
history of mankind right I mean how long
have we been doing that we've got sewage
you take a shit and it doesn't stay here
it doesn't like linger and create
disease you've got toilet so you can
flush you've got a refrigerator that
keeps your food from spoiling my parents
grew up in Belize and there they had to
eat whatever they harvested for that day
you know or they put it in like salt or
something the refrigerator
more than likely life is good but we
tend to forget when we become too
focused on what we don't have and we
become focused on the bad feelings that
sometimes come out of nowhere like I
said there are those that believe that
they come from past lifetimes something
bad happened to you seven lifetimes ago
and it's showing up in your body you
don't need to analyze it you don't need
to tangle with it but what you can do is
to allow it to dissipate by being
grateful for what you do have right now
be generous when times are good and be
grateful when times are bad