so got two questions here both of a very
similar nature one is from a young dude
who's been dating a girl that he really
loved he's madly in love with her but he
feels as if is imprisoned by this
relationship he wants to experience
other women but he truly loves his
girlfriend what does he do does he stick
with her but feel resentment towards her
and this feeling of imprisonment or does
he just cut it off and go pursue other
women right then we got another question
from a guy someone situation where his
girlfriend they're madly in love they
love each other but she has made it
clear from the beginning that she wants
to be with other men she just wants an
open relationship I have no problem
loving you I'd like to love you I'd love
to enjoy our time together share good
feelings but they're going to be
opportunities that I might want to
pursue there may be other men that I
want to open up to I hope you're okay
with that so we've got both situations
where there is a dude feeling trapped
and another guy who wants to trap with
love and I wanted to approach this video
with a principle or an idea that really
is it's the truth it's that love is not
ownership and it's a very difficult
concept to understand especially in a
the way we've created the society
civilization that we live in you know
with marriage and and and the way we
date it's essentially where we love each
other and that's it love has boundaries
now as opposed to being what it truly is
which is boundless so how do we navigate
how do we go about our lives how do we
deal with civilization be civilized
with one another while obeying the
natural law that love is boundless
you know we've created psychological
constructs to have us believe that when
there's love here there's not you're not
allowed to have love anywhere else and
what that does is it creates guilt in
our bodies and resentment towards that
which we are shackled to so if you're
with an individual and you love each
other and you tend to
drift even if it's just mentally just
your eyes there's guilt associated with
it there's guilt associated with the
fact that I'm just doing what naturally
happens in my body and there's nothing
wrong there's nothing evil inherently
evil with being sexually attracted to
multiple people at the same time even
having warm loving feelings towards
multiple people that were at the same
time but we'll stop ourselves from Laos
to expand itself because we feel guilty
that we're betraying the only one were
allowed to love and if you decide to
move with the guilt and suppress your
emotion in order to fulfill the
obligation with your beloved then
there's going to be which there always
is resentment associated with the guilt
that you have guilt is basically
essentially it's a situation where there
is a moral judgment being placed on a
natural feeling in the body the
expansion of love and sexual feelings
towards other people is natural but we
have to literally beat it down but
through our own conscious activity and
if I know the source of my beating down
the natural feelings in my body is you
my so we supposed to be my beloved then
there's going to be resentment there and
this is why relationships don't work
this is why marriage is you know one of
those constructs that is beneficial for
upward mobility in society depending on
what it is you want your life to look
like I got to tell myself stories too
because I've been married for a long
time but goes against human nature and
we've all experienced it I don't care
who you are how holy you are what
philosophy you subscribe to what
religion the fact is that you're a human
being
you've got human feelings they are
expressed or they're repressed and then
there's secondary emotions associated
with it resentment and guilt it's just
going to happen it's one of those
situations where we really are denying
who we are and if you see God as I do as
the animating force in the universe
and we have to contain God as he's
moving through us as he/she/it is moving
through us because that's what sexual
energy is it's God moving through you
inviting you to expand your energy and
expand love God doesn't have contained
love God moves through you freely it's
free open love and your litter we are
literally stuffing God down saying god
you're it's not a good idea what you're
doing through me God I've got a fucking
boner here and my wife is next to me and
that chick looks hot
stuff stuff stuff stuff stuff so number
of things I want to share with you in
this video number one young dude who has
his girlfriend and doesn't want to
betray her but two I'm young I want to
have lots of sex with lots of beautiful
women right i and you don't even it
doesn't have to be that pornographic you
could merely be I just want to share
love with other people I want to share
warm feelings with other people maybe
just a warm embrace right I usually do
something else but hey the heart is
opening up to other people but I
genuinely love my girlfriend you got
you're going to have to just be honest
with her you're just gonna have to tell
her look babe let's have a conversation
I love you I love you with all of my
heart and soul everything that I have
but I cannot lie to you and have you
believe that there aren't going to be
times where I'm going to want to share
my love with someone else my love is
expansive my love goes far beyond just
the experience that I have with you this
is a law of nature and I refuse to deny
my nature this is not good or bad this
is merely stating it as it is and you
share that with her you say listen this
is just if you'd like to be with me
because I'd like to be with you this is
the way it's going to be right give it a
try and my friend mm a guy he says he's
a mixed martial arts whose girlfriend
wants to and already told you like I
took like I invited our first dude to do
already told you that this is what she's
going to do bro you just here's the
thing you do not own her love is not
ownership
if she decides that she wants to love
you embrace be with appreciate relish in
the love that you have with one another
and when she shares it with someone else
don't look at it as a detraction from
the amount of love that she has from you
but an expansion of the love that she
can create this is radical thinking this
is crazy I know I'm going to get a lot
of heat for this but you don't own her
and she doesn't own you and nobody owns
anybody else the only commitment we have
to the person that we choose to love is
honest and open communication and
support and allowing that person to
become the strongest version of
themselves as we grow stronger through
the purpose of all of life become a
stronger version of yourself invite
others inspire others to become a strong
version of themselves and if you
recognize a grounded sexuality in that
individual where there are practical
pragmatic and simply expansive with
their sexual energy you got to leave
them alone
now there's hysterical sexual energy in
some people and that just manifests
itself as like this person just wants to
have sex with everyone because there
you're personally identified with their
ability to have sex right
their ego construct is is completely
tied to their ability to have sex or to
get people have sex with them this is
this functional sex and this is you know
the majority of us this is what it's
become because we've suppressed it so so
much so if you look at your beloved and
you see like sweetheart you have you're
just throwing your sex all over the
place in a dysfunctional fashion in an
ungrounded hysterical fashion then that
might be something that you want to talk
to without jealousy being a part of it
if he or she is having sex with lots of
people you love that individual you and
you see that it's hysterical ungrounded
sex then you might want to talk to them
about it because you love them and you
want to see them become the strongest
version himself not because you're
jealous this is all very difficult and I
wish I could stand here and say to you
I've got this mastered but it is a
practical rational way of looking at
this whole situation now you say Elliot
you're married what do you do
how do you deal with this here's the
story I've told myself might be a story
that's helpful is some view I being on
the journey to being a stronger version
of myself at this point in my life and
I'm very different than I was when I got
married I probably got married and you
know I've been with my wife since we
were children and I've always been hasty
we've been together since we were 14
years old and when the time came I was
get married I didn't think about it and
I and that do not regret it at all we've
had some ups and downs but at this point
in my life
Who I am what I'm seeking to create in
my life the type of service I want to
bring to the world the type of family
I'd like to build I have to tell myself
a story that doesn't create guilt
doesn't create resentment but also keeps
me tied to my commitment and perhaps I
am merely you know a lot of what I share
seems egotistical self-centered and I
always invite you to become
self-centered because that's where
strength is found that's where beauty is
found if we want to change the world go
inside first you become a stronger
version of yourself and then you inspire
others so the way I stay strong to my
commitments is because the commitment is
mine my commitment isn't to someone else
my commitment isn't necessarily to my
wife as much as I love her and she loves
me and I don't expect her to commit to
me my commitment is that the virtue of
commitment of discipline of endurance of
patience our virtues I'd like to build
in myself a stronger version of Elliott
Hulse looks grounded committed focused
discipline and has endurance and has
patience these are all virtues that I'd
like to build in myself and they show up
they're strengthened they're built
through my relationship with my wife so
when I have to suppress impulse sexual
impulse or to not take my loving
expansion across a particular border I
am doing it simply because I realize for
me to be a stronger version of myself
through
virtue of commitment I'm going to stop
here do you see and it's not always easy
but it's a commitment to myself so I
can't feel resentful towards myself
because I'm doing it to myself but if I
said I'm not going to move forward with
you because ball-and-chain motherfucker
I got a wife god damn she's ruined in my
life I just wanted to share my love
share my sex energy and she just keeps
getting in the fucking way so it's going
to be one of two things it's going to be
guilt why do I feel this way I should
just push it down I'm a bad bad man
because my dick gets hard or it's going
to be fucking bitch is always like
ruining my life neither of which are
resourceful growing stronger choosing
your virtues the things that you'd like
to grow strong in and using the life
that you've chosen ie marriage a
relationship as a field as a tool
through which you can grow those virtues
is the way I see it working at this time
in this day and age in my particular
life and hopefully those ideas are
resourceful to you the younger
generation is you guys are moving up
I've got four dot I've got four children
three daughters and a son
and I've got some of some really liberal
ideas when it comes to social ideas
especially when it's associated with sex
and love and an expression
and it's difficult because we're
fighting against societal condition
we're fighting against civilization
we're fighting against the social
constructs and if you want to win at
this fucking game you play the game and
you follow the rules but I think we're
coming to a stage in our development
where you can opt out of the game
there are more options available to us
than that of the traditional
socio-economic game that we've been
playing up until this point and that's a
big part of the reason why I created the
non job revolution as part of the reason
why I share these ideas because we're
expanding we're rapidly evolving as a
culture and when I say culture I mean a
world culture we're becoming more
integrated our ideas are far more
expansive there's more experimentation
with life style and Who am I and who are
we who is anyone who's made a particular
choice for themselves in their lives be
it actions that they've taken ie gotten
married or traditions that they hold
dear to their hearts
to impose it on a future generation that
is merely doing what God is doing
through it which is evolving changing
life is dynamic human beings are dynamic
this is where it's going and I'm not so
sure that the restrictive traditions of
marriage and relationship as we see it
causing all the guilt and resentments as
associated with it is going to be the
way it's expressed in the future I don't
know what it's going to look like but my
deepest desire for the future
generations including my children is
that they can live in a world where they
don't have to suppress natural impulse
and feeling in order to get by but yet
you can move freely in your life
expressing yourself to the fullest
capacity in a grounded practice
pragmatic fashion not hysterical our
sexuality has become very sexual even
even our liberal sexuality has become
it's it's far too ungrounded it's far
too hysterical I think we need to become
grounded in ourselves first we need to
breathe deep ourselves first we need to
become meditative ourselves first we
need to find ourselves experience
appreciate love ourselves and then
through that groundedness find
resourceful ways to share ourselves with
as many people as we possibly can
and that's all