so oftentimes people say that it's
practical and pragmatic to save up for
the future they buy insurance plans they
save up for retirement they save up for
future catastrophe they might stop pile
weapons and and goods canned goods and
food so in case there's social collapse
they have a exit strategy they've got
some sort of security for themselves
they put their money in the stock market
on real estate these are things that
contemporary people do in order to make
sure that they've got safety and
security for the future seems like a
reasonable thing perhaps it is but I'd
like to offer you just a different way
to look at it in fact it's a very
ancient way of looking at it one that
Jesus talks about in the Bible now if
you've been studying my work for soldier
for long enough you know that I honor
all forms of wisdom literature without
actually having to be personally
identified with it so I invite you to
consider some of the words of Jesus even
if you're an atheist one of the things
he says in his own way is that you're
better off not saving up all of your
goods all of your wealth in this world
on earth and instead invested in heaven
right now what does that mean does that
mean be a good little boy so that you
can make your way into heaven and stay
poor on earth well some people might see
it that way but the way I see it is that
Jesus is inviting us to become a
stronger version of ourselves and
putting stock in that instead of the
stock market build up your character
virtues build up your ability to be
resourceful in the moment because no
matter what happens to your stockpile
goods your stockpile of money all the
insurance plans that will at some day
perhaps disappear because you know stock
markets do crash people can steal your
shit but instead of investing all of
your time and energy into stockpiling
those things which are tangible work
instead on developing the intangible
which could be likened unto heaven see
heaven is a realm of reality that is
intangible your character your virtues
who you are on the inside is a
reflection of the heaven if you will
it's an intangible nobody can can touch
your courage right again you get hold
courage and say I've got courage the
same way that you can hold a stack of
hundred dollar bills investor time and
energy and cultivating your ability to
handle catastrophe in the future
meditate think and consider don't shy
away from challenges when they're small
and you face them today work on
stockpiling your wealth in you in your
character in the heavens as opposed to
grains and dollars and insurance plans
that are inevitably going to be wiped
out and no one can steal that from you