got this question from our 23 year old
friend she's becoming an alcoholic he
says since his he's miserable at work
he's got a dead-end job miserable at
home because his parents don't respect
them and they go through his mail and
shit long story short he doesn't know
what the fuck to do with his life he's
bored he puts things off he
procrastinates nobody respects him he
has no friends hates his job now we
starting to drink 23 years old you know
that that age 23 years old I think
there's something magical about that
fucking age I remember when I was 23
years old and I think I once heard it
said that every 7 years we go through a
personal evolution and if you don't
allow evolution to happen at these
different stages you go through a crisis
so you're either you're you're kicked
into an evolution it happens every 7
years so at the age of 7 they say you
stop growing essentially um your
character who you're going to be the
foundation of who you're going to be is
kind of solidified at the 8th by the age
of 7 so all the experiences you have up
until the age of 7 kind of sets the
foundation for who you're going to be
and then you've got obviously between
there and 14 14 is like I mean that's
when your dick starts getting hard all
of a sudden you notice girls right
you've got a little muscle you a little
bit's testosterone right so you you know
you're playing sports and you're trying
to get laid between 14 and would that be
21 or 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 21 all right
so at 21 now you're sort of officially a
man you're able to drive drink alcohol
you're assured out into the world in a
particular way that says you sir are now
a man see we don't have rites of
passages anymore for men and it's so
detrimental to us in so many different
ways but it's just it's a very potent
topic of interest for me and I'm
thinking of creating something at some
point I have a son that will need to go
to a rites of passage and as I explore
that I'm probably I'm sure I'll have
much to share with you guys at that time
but you need a fucking rites of passage
to know that you're a man and that rites
of passages is is often
a way for you to break the shackles in
the bonds of immaturity boyhood and then
venture off into the the the dangerous
world of manhood at about 21 right say
you're 23 so right now you're in that
place where dysfunction is brewing
because you've you know no one ever told
you that you're a man now and you've
never been exposed to the challenges
that's what the rites of passage is it's
a challenge that destroys your ego
because you have a boy ego and you got
to move into the man ego and at 23 if
that hasn't happened yet you go into it
you throw into a crisis I remember being
there I remember being at 23
that was crisis mode for me it was my
first crisis and I think a lot of boys a
lot of men because you're a man even
though your mom still goes through your
mail cuz you act like a boy and she
treats you like a boy you've ever been
told you're a man but I'm calling you a
man not because you had hair on your
balls but because this is where you're
going this is what you're going to
become you need to become a fucking man
the thing is in our society we've got to
create our own rights of passage right
now you know it's just the way it
fucking is you got to throw yourself to
the wolves because the elders aren't
going to do it for us and you're in
no-man's land right now and you're
beginning to dabble with alcohol to
suppress the pain associated with it I
can tell you right now I'm putting my
foot down with this one
don't fuck with drugs and alcohol right
now I'm not against alcohol I'm not
against smoking a blunt every once in a
while
I'm againt I'm against dependency
especially when God the universe Allah
energy whatever call it is knocking on
your door telling you hey dude you
better wake up we got something
something something's up and you need to
take some action that's where you're at
right now that's why you're having all
this anxiety that's why having all this
pain because you need to go do something
and this is gonna sound buy some of the
worst advice Elliott Hulse is ever given
and I hope you receive it well I hope
that those of you understand it
can receive it well as as well and that
is go and do something dangerous go sell
all your belongings and hitchhike that's
what kids used to do in the 60s right
they were free there are free lovers our
children they go and fucking hitchhike
California or bust right they don't
assign going fucking hitchhike go and
put yourself in a country where you
don't know the fucking language right to
sell your shit and go to Mexico right
might get kidnapped and fucked up and
initiate into a gang whatever you know
like whatever the experience is going to
be it's gonna fucking be don't be
attached to how it should turn out but
you need to throw yourself into the the
dark sea of life you need to go and do
something that is very dangerous and
that's going to challenge you on
multiple levels you may be physically
hungry physiologically damaged and
energetically you won't be depressed
I'll tell you that but psychologically
energetically challenged you won't be
depressed because you see you don't have
time to be depressed when you're in
dangerous situations hungry people don't
get depressed because they're too busy
trying to eat you see you're depressed
right now because you literally are
depressing the energy in your body that
wants to come out and it's only going to
exercise itself so I'm going to come up
as always going to mature when you have
some experiences quit your fucking job
move out of your parents house and see
what happens
I guarantee you figure it out that's how
I get everything in my life everything
in my life was I don't know what's gonna
happen let's see I don't make plans I
don't have orchestrated blueprints or
blueprints that need to be orchestrated
in order to fulfill some particular
ideal that I set for myself I have a
feeling for where things are going and I
throw myself in that direction okay you
have a feeling about where things should
go because you're
becoming a man but you're not throwing
yourself at it you're biting your tongue
while your mommy slaps you you're
drinking alcohol so you don't kill
yourself it'll just grow worse it's like
a cancer bro so I don't have any
specifics for you because specifics
don't mean shit this is all very
subjective if I tell you exactly what to
do then you become then you become my
son I don't want you to be my fucking
son I don't to be your guru I want you
to follow me I want you to throw
yourself into off the fucking cliff and
learn how to fly do it now or forever
hold your peace
done