hey what's up guys elite halls here and
the problem with most fitness programs
is that they don't take into account
every aspect of what it is to become the
strongest version yourself and focus
solely on the body ignoring aspects such
as the mind the soul and life mastery on
the other end most personal development
programs don't take into account the
body you go to most personal development
seminars and usually you're sitting down
having to take notes and listen just
like you did in school and personal
development includes the body but yet
most personal development programs
require that you do the very thing we're
trying to condition ourselves out of
which is to be sedentary week and
unexpressed here at strength camp we
take a holistic approach I have been
making videos for years talking about
the four layers of strength in order to
become the strongest version of yourself
we take into account neuro muscular
strength the physical strength of the
body your posture how you carry yourself
and your physical strength as well as
physiological strength right because we
can't separate the rhythms of our life
sleeping and waking cycles call the
circadian rhythm we can't ignore the
foods that we eat we can ignore our
hormones in our digestive system if
we're going to be the strongest version
of ourselves in the same way we can't
leave out the aspect of the mind I often
talk about how our body is our mind you
want to have a healthy vibrant vital
mind you want to think better have a
healthier body exercise eat well
and of course becoming a strong aversion
to yourself and empowering others is
what life mastery is all about what good
is it to become fit and healthy and
vibrant and vital if you're not using
your newfound power and strength to
support others and make this a better
world well that's what the grow stronger
experience here in st. Petersburg
Florida in November is all about you
will get to learn for myself as well as
several experts in various aspects of
becoming the strongest version of
yourself you'll also get an opportunity
to speak with and learn from various
YouTube fitness celebrities I'm really
excited about this opportunity to get to
meet you to learn with you and share
together and I'm really excited to meet
you here in November for the grow
stronger experience I do have to let you
know that space is limited for this
workshop and a hundred spaces have
already been taken because we've given
spaces we've given seats to the people
that are coming to our strength camp
clinic so all the information that you
need to get started right away and grab
yourself one of those limited seats is
down below I'm excited to see you then
done
you