good routine next question
perspective on like sharing yourself
with other people like how would you go
about it
and how do you get rid of those excuses
of like oh I shouldn't talk to this
person for this reason I shouldn't tell
them this thing that I think is
interesting because greater is some
other stuff and second part is how do
you get rid of just excuses in general
in your life life I have a dude that's
just doing it
respect
so when you say share under people you
actually mean the courage to say what
you think all right and the answer to
both of your questions is really kind of
the same question
thank you Tito is courage courage
courage heart heart and this is just
going to be in my own mind but it seems
that it's fitting for everyone to
recognize courage is not reckless
abandon it's not being arrogant it's not
being right it's having enough balls to
be you unapologetically Auto mileage
ethically you and if there's something
that is coming up in you that needs to
be said
maybe it's catharsis but maybe it's you
feel this needs to be said you know what
a different people oh then you're you're
doing a number of things by not saying
it or not being you not letting it work
through you your dishonor yourself or
disrespecting yourself you're basically
saying what I have going on here it's
not of any value I'm not good enough
it's masochistic you're beating yourself
there yeah doesn't mean like about
saying go around being like
interesting he's flirting out shit does
making sense but if there's something of
meaning that needs to come up your your
be masochistic you're doing a disservice
to that person by not saying so our
friend I'm sorry wasn't even sure if I
want it to be nice to cheer
I wouldn't M pointed out the glaring to
me obvious fact that he smokes smokes up
ordered that it's skin is on that would
be nice
but wouldn't get anywhere with fucking
nice right
nice to get us anywhere so why are you
doing a disservice if I didn't just say
you know you look what and it might not
right I'm not saying you we're like
other situation you look blank and it
might come across like whoa this guy's
an asshole but at the same time that
person is like right there is something
going on here and you should teach that
person you teach you give that person an
invitation to take a look at something
that can be life transforming right
there may be resistance at first but
there's also the possibility that could
be I had people come up to you and say
no you said that one thing I'm so mad
that you said if it changed my life
why should I welcome back I'd be doing a
disservice to those that may be able to
benefit from what they've done to say
and a little esoteric here you're doing
to God or the universe or allow nature
or whatever the hell you want to call it
but that animating force that's bugging
you to do this thing or to say this
thing maybe it's just using their honor
whatever there's an unseen untangle
force it's like it's possessing me and
it this needs to come out you're doing a
disservice so the point is you have to
do it but did you responsibility to do
it and when you do do it you practice
courageousness you become stronger
version of yourself
because now you've got enough the steam
to use that tool and other things
graciousness will help you say what you
need to say but it also help you build
your business it also help you stack out
that girl that you've always had a crush
on it will give you the courage to give
you see what I'm saying
it's a tool it's something you want to
develop and then use it for other things
that help
as far as I'm concerned we're talking
about this our Father hmm it's in my
genetics just never be close now like I
just like I just look if you meet my dad
you think I'm my boy you should be my
dad he'll coming here by you just for
the sake of pissing people off you'll
flip all your tables it would completely
wrong with everything and unapologetic
but it's like he just he loves this
thing like this time let me just fuck
with you and so I know that it's it's so
weird - that makes for the great thanks
- hey it's like your time we welcome to
bloat but I realize it it's like it but
in the same way that like I can did I
can pick up a lot of weight regardless
of what I do is one of the things that I
happen to be I know you asked me my
subjective experience but a lot of it is
like it's just wearing
couple yeah
Oh Lex