hey what's up guys been a while since
I've made a video while driving but I
figured I'd do it today just dropped off
my daughter and son at school heading to
my office and thinking about the email I
wrote you guys this morning or the
blogpost did you read down below every
day five days a week besides making a
video and also write you a letter and
today I spoke about beers but the
position I took on fear is a little
different then you might typically hear
you know when it comes to fears people
say things in terms of ignoring the
fears or overcoming the fears or or
really waiting until there are no fears
I think that myth is kind of dissolved
already nobody waits so there's no fears
I think we all realize at this point
that life is full of beers it's full of
pain it's supposed to be you know that's
like asking for day with no night life
is pleasurable because of the pain life
is pleasurable because of the obstacles
life is pleasurable because of the fears
right otherwise we'd have no contrast we
wouldn't know what good life is we
didn't have pain so anyway Joseph
Campbell has spent a lot of time reading
and studying I loved his work on
mythology and the use of symbols to
recognize the mechanics of the
unconscious and he refers to the part of
ourselves that we basically cut off and
cast into oblivion as the shadow aspect
of ourselves so basically what that
means is those parts of yourself that
have been deemed as naughty or no good
when you were a kid you kind of cut off
and cast into the shadow so a lot of our
sexual repression gets cast into the
shadow a lot of our hyperactivity or
energy or exuberance as children gets
cut off and cast into the shadow and in
the shadow is where these things are
natural exuberance our natural sexuality
our natural energy our spontaneity these
are all things that reside in the shadow
because they're behind us in other words
we don't look at them with the light of
day as we do normal things in our
activity
the problem is with shadows right things
that you cut off or the world
deemed inappropriate for you that gets
cut off into the shadows is that they're
always there
they're always manipulating and working
on you from the shadow world from
underneath from your unconscious so
today we're talking about fears in my
article and one of the things that
allows you to know when you're
approaching your shadow or aspects of
yourself that you've cut off and placed
into the netherworld is that there are
fears right so for example there may be
fears associated with sexuality right
I'm I'm afraid to engage in sexual
pursuits because I've been turned down
before girls don't like me or you know
maybe I've had a circumstance where I
performed poorly in bed and and I don't
want to re-create that again so you cast
your sexuality into the shadow you know
you end up not you never having a
healthy sexual relationship we do this
with our exuberance or our exuberance is
an immature form of personal power and
self-will we do this with our own
personal power and self will by
rejecting our magnificence there in
Australia there's this or Australia in
front of mine taught me this saying
called chopping down the tall poppies in
essence we live in a world society and
and reality we're tall poppies are cut
down and in other words whenever you
rise above whenever you rise above
what is deemed appropriate by the mass
of people and you write in other words
like the poppies grow they stay level
the one that rises up you got a shot
them down so chopping down the tall
poppies means putting you in your place
sit down shut up you're not as special
as you think you are we all know we're
special so that what happens is that
special part of us that gets shut down
cut off and cast into the shadow grows
but in a perverted way it grows in sort
of a either a coward or tyrant
manifestation in our unconscious so
instead of accepting our own power we
we've become a coward by giving it to
other people and then being resentful
when they have it and we don't so there
are all kinds of mind tricks that we
play on ourselves to buck ourselves in
order to continue to live with our
shadows Joseph Campbell like I mentioned
earlier talks about eating your shadow
it's fucking crazy right know what
happens when you eat something you put
it in your mouth you chew it up right
you work on it and you absorb it it
becomes a part of you what if and this
is really just a question I'm posing to
you what if you took those little parts
of yourself that were deem inappropriate
that you're scared of and integrated or
reintegrated them back into your
character what if you got back that
natural spontaneity and personal will
and self power that's associated with
being a suberin
exuberant four-year-old right what have
you brought that back but you brought it
back with a level of maturity associated
with being in your thirties or 20s or
whatever the case may be what if you
brought back your cutoff sexual
repression from the experiences that you
had early on in life with uh with your
parents Society
it's inappropriate to feel sexuality or
to to engage in even sexual behavior as
a as a child now you think that might
sound strange with children like to play
with their genitals and and it's self
exploration before each before you ever
get a chance to explore someone else so
it's sexual behavior as a child you need
to explore your sexuality and maybe even
mimic some sexual behaviors at the age
of three four five six which are quickly
shut down
you know penises vaginas are bad
sexuality you don't want to be a slut
people do this to their daughters all
the time you know daughters is
recognizing and experiencing with their
sexuality and you know the young age
because you do go through a sexual
revolution prior to your homosexual
stage which is new like ages 7 to
adolescence there's a stage where and
we're really curious about our sexuality
and start to notice sexual contrast
between ourself and the parents of the
opposite sex but anyway my point here is
what would happen if you took that took
those things that are naughty that have
been repressed that have been cast into
the shadow and which by the way don't go
away they don't disappear they're
basically just hanging with you and I'm
causing you to behave in a perverted way
anytime something gets cast into the
shadows or gets cast away or gets
suppressed it doesn't disappear it grows
in its pervertedness what I mean by that
is like the term perverted means it's
changed it turns into something else
it's transformed it turns ugly
you know perverted sexuality that arises
out of suppressed sexuality ends up
looking like priests that molest little
boys because they've been built either
they've been led to a lifestyle of
celibacy but they're not mature enough
to handle it so the sexual energy grows
perverted and they end up touching the
peepees a little boys right doing all
kinds of weird shit that doesn't serve
them and destroys other people's lives
one example is just one example look at
your life
where are you suffering and we
there are you facing boundaries that
you're not willing to overcome you will
know that they're arising when you feel
fear when you experience fear fear is
your friend because fear is a
demarcation of your self-imposed
boundaries and those are the boundaries
that we want to get rid of so that we
can become a stronger version of
ourselves so my invitation to you today
friends is to explore your shadow
aspects explore those parts you that you
don't like explore those things that if
we're given the attention that they
deserve instead of being cast off into
the shadow may help you become a
stronger version of yourself and you
know that you're approaching those
things you know you're getting close to
those things you know that you're
wrestling with those things when you get
icky feelings in your body associated
with fear anger frustration sadness or
depression when faced with people's
circumstances and ideas that tickle or
touch that sore spot and that's my
message for y'all today
keep going stronger talk to you tomorrow