yo Eliot what's up guys so we got a
question from one of our strength camp
online members he goes on to say that he
has irritable bowel syndrome and he did
just like any reasonable person would do
he goes to the doctor you go to a
specialist to figure out how to deal
with the the irritable bowel syndrome
right because I mean that would make
perfect sense you go to a to a gastric
doctor a doctor that deals with the with
the with the with the digestive system
and he should have a solution for you
but our friend goes on to say that yea
he prescribed me painkillers right so
here's what happens now he takes the
painkillers now he has diarrhea right so
um first thing is like you should be
able to sue that guy because that sounds
like fucking malpractice but um that's
not what this is about you know I come
in with one problem you give me a pill
that gives me another problem right but
anyway so he says that he he's been
getting some relief when he does yoga
right so here's the thing
he gets the he gets a lot of tension in
his belly when he weight lifts but he
wants to weight lift so that he's strong
and when he gets that tension in his
belly to aggravates the irritable bowel
syndrome but then when he does yoga
which is a lot of stretching and
twisting a lot of mobilizing the tissue
within the or within the digestive belly
region it's somewhat relieved and he
wants to know you know how do I go about
this I don't want to stop weight
training but it screws up my belly so
you've come to the right place my friend
because I hold a lot of belly
tension or at least I used to until I
learned how to breathe into my balls
right and I've got plenty of videos
where I talk about how to relieve the
muscular tension in the belly throughout
the chest up in your all the muscles in
your torso neck face in order to bring
softness into the body and an irritable
bowel syndrome like you said - it's it's
caused oftentimes from your nervousness
and what nervousness is just think about
the term nervousness your nerves your
nerves are all tense and tight so we've
got to relax the nerve tension and and
in which you've already experienced when
that tension is relieved in the belly
the IBS goes away right without
painkillers and diarrhea so if you've
been watching my training vlog videos
I've been beginning with a foam roller
I've described this in many of my older
videos but you you want to give yourself
belly massages right and it's for you
it's probably going to be one of the
most painful things that you experience
it's not a nice thing so you're gonna
have to really ease into it you know and
I'm not promising to cure your IBS with
belly massage but because there is a
link between muscular tension and organ
dysfunction right they often use the
most obvious example which is you know
in the heart you're having a heart
attack your art your left limb goes your
left arm goes numb right right limp what
the hell is your arm have to do with
your heart while they're on the same
visceral somatic loop same thing in your
abdominal region you know if you've got
tension in your so as you got tension in
your deep abdominal wall and the muscles
of your your gut they're on the same
neurological loop as the as the colon
so they affect one another we can often
bring relief to our nervous system into
our organs by releasing tension in our
muscular system right go bigger right
we're all one thing right so what you're
going to want to do if you've been
watching my videos my training vlogs I
often begin leaning on the foam roller
and
to demonstrate a little bit here for you
but I kind of lean on the side here and
then I go across the front I'll often
get to the point where it just digs in
Oh sometimes I bring it up by my ribcage
and I'm you know of course I'm laying on
this when I do it bring it right down
into the pelvis right down here or lay
on it and then I big start on the other
side come all the way across to the
front from the ribcage the sternum right
down to the pubic bone right between the
right between your uh your hip bones you
start to bring a lot of relief and what
one thing might that might happen when
you start to really actually really
reduce the tension in those muscles is
you start to breathe better what I would
suggest you do is foam roll definitely
foam roll the belly you know you should
do some thoracic foam rolling also
because it relieves a lot of attention
across your torso and then do the open
front breathing that I often talk about
in some of my videos where you you lay
flat on your back hands in front of your
belly I'll demonstrate again here but
you know just search my channel or
search my um strength can channel and
Bree belly breathe inhale exhale all
right
[Applause]
and do that for like 20 minutes again
caveat you know can't sue the doctor for
giving you painkillers for that to
exasperate your problems but somebody
might try to sue Elliot for saying that
I'm going to cure IBS with exercise so I
ain't saying that give you some cool
shit to do that might help you and you
don't have to stop weight training right
if the yoga is supporting you well then
you can add it as a part of your routine
but do like I do I'm back to weight
training again yoga has been very
helpful to me
but um but I like being jacked to I like
being strong also and I could tell you
for a fact that it does weight training
does create tension in your belly
because I woke up this morning after
doing a workout yesterday with a lot of
strongman stuff and my gut was a wreck I
immediately pulled out my foam roller
I've got one at home rolled across my
belly I'm breathing better I'm feeling
better I'm feeling fine so you know you
and I are in the same boat there buddy
so I really hope that helps you man done
Elliot's it what
[Music]