hey whats up guys today's daily post was
about how to train with limitations our
friend asked a question about how to
continue to grow his upper body stronger
with bench presses overhead press and
what not but he's got a shoulder problem
that limits his range of motion so I
spoke in terms of how to improve his
physical strength in the article if you
want to read it it's down below but
today in this video I want to talk about
embracing your limitations so obviously
our friend has a physical limitation and
those are unknowable Ryan I mean if
someone pokes my eye on me and I can't
ignore the limitation the fact that i
don't have an eyeball there it's very
evident to me and my performance in to
people around me so we can't sort of
sneak around them but we've got these
insidious little strange limitations
that i'm going to call brick walls and
shadows in our lives that tend to well
get in our way like a brick wall or keep
us ignorant like a shadow or something
that's in the dark so in terms of
limitations i tend to look at them as
teaching tools so in the article that i
referenced down below i talked to my
friend about how although he's limited
in his range of motion he could continue
to get stronger by working around it
right well the same thing goes with the
limitations in our character and our
lifestyle in our career and our
relationships in our being there are
going to be brick walls and they were
going to be shadows and when dealing
with those limitations realizing that
they're designed for our ascension every
single limitation that you have is
designed to make you a bit stronger
either by teaching you how to move over
around or through a brick wall or
shedding light becoming enlightened
about your shadows or things that you're
quite frankly ignoring or rather not
look at right there are parts of us
there are things going on inside us
mentally physiologically that
quite frankly don't wanna admit right
some of us got the weird little
illnesses you know and we're too afraid
to go to the doctor to talk about
sometimes we have a recurring problem
perhaps with the opposite sex I you know
27 years old and I can't keep up a
normal relationship with a woman same
thing with Jeff jobs and things like
that so we tend to kind of play them
down play them off people would say but
there's no way to grow stronger when you
play them off so today we're going to
talk about going through over around
brick walls with the principle of figure
it out a bonus you've got to figure shit
out these walls are set there for you
either physically physiologically
energetically in your life because you
got to figure some shit out good friend
of mine Dave rule says that successful
people bigger shit out don't look at
your limitation or look at that
roadblock or look at that brick wall in
front of you as something to be upset
about something to cry and whine about
something to fucking complain about like
most people look at it as an opportunity
a chance to grow stronger some of the
ways that we could potentially grow
stronger given a limitation right would
be someone who goes blind right now I
have absolutely no reference for this so
anybody who's listening to this who's
blind forgive me but I would imagine
that someone who is blind and cannot see
how is a limitation that forces you to
grow stronger elsewhere right like with
your fingers someone who can't see reads
with Braille I see the Braille bumps on
the wall when I'm at the you know
doctor's office or at an apartment
building somewhere you're supposed to
touch it it supposed to tell you where
you are but fuck I barely can even feel
them they're so tiny and they're
supposed to be symbolic of something
you're like I'm supposed to touch a
couple fucking dots on the wall and that
should
most me know my seventh floor right so
you gotta learn tactile abilities you've
got to create brand-new motor pathways I
say motor but brain pathways I was
talking about the body so I say motor
but pathways in your brain so that when
you touch the button the bumps on the
wall you become enlightened you come
aware right you go from being in the
shadows darkness to light so you're
forced to increase your tactile
sensitivity this is just one very
obvious example of course you know
someone who's in a wheelchair I can't
run well guess what there are guys that
play basketball in their fucking
wheelchairs they played they play all
kinds of games rolling around like this
doing this you know what happens their
arms have to get stronger now if they're
whining and complaining because the
accident took their legs they'll remain
trapped in the level of consciousness
and with the level of lifestyle that
they currently have but if they're at
aware person who is blessed with a
limitation they'll see that it's an
opportunity to grow stronger elsewhere
and maybe that's the best thing for us
right oftentimes the things that we
don't get are the things that are taken
away from us are for our own good who
knows God's plan for your souls
progression right so don't judge just
figure it out the other thing has to do
with shadows shadows are limitations
that we're not willing to look at and
many times or not even aware of they're
completely unconscious their ways of
being in and attitudes that we adopt
over time in order to defend ourselves
from the environment in order to protect
ourselves and in threatening
circumstances in order to hold ourselves
high in an environment where perhaps we
are told that we're low right I could I
could I can admit for example that I
have a lot of shadow magician issues
because when I was younger I was told I
had
ed and learning disabilities so I kind
of grew up playing dummy you know a lot
of a lot of my ears through middle
school in high school I played dummy so
I realized what I know dummy but that
was it was a shadow issue I carried the
shadow pain associated with being
labeled that way through middle school
in high school and it wreaked havoc on
my graves it grades it wreaked havoc
door my relationships and my self-esteem
but I wasn't willing to look at it
because it was something that was thrown
at me and I said okay fine cast into the
shadows I'll walk around like a fucking
dummy till I grew up and realize that
they're the dummies you said that
because they didn't realize my fucking
brilliance anyway my point is that I had
to look at that I had to embrace that
act I had to really wrestle with that
through my adulthood in order to come to
grips with the fact that that shouldn't
be something I carry around
unconsciously I should shed light on it
meaning put it into perspective and
healed the shadows Joseph Campbell has a
beautiful way of describing the
evolution that's associated Anna
nourishment that supports our evolution
associated with eating your shadows
shadows are parts of of the parts of us
that have been put down like if you're a
hyperactive kid ryan told shut up sit
down shut up sit down you're annoying
over in Oregon you tend to suck it all
in and and cast your energy into the
shadow right because it's judged and if
you're going to live peacefully in this
home you better shut the fuck up I'm
saying fuck a lot today so um I get cast
into shadow but it could possibly be
your greatest gift right talking a lot
being energetic and outgoing could be
something that irritates your parents
and teachers but might be something that
causes your ascension to great heights
and fame if you're willing to look at
the shadow and cast the light the
healing light upon it music
so the way we deal with this is number
one by being honest with ourselves
really looking at our strengths and
limitations and looking at our
limitations and asking if they really
are limitations or gifts and looking at
our strengths and wondering perhaps how
they might be stopping us from growing
stronger oftentimes we personally
identify or the ego becomes fixed on a
particular strength and we think that
it's ours and we thinks it will never go
away and we think that we should be
praised for when in reality is just a
passing thing like all things in life so
your greatest strength could become a
limitation and a shadow issue also the
next thing would be in dealing with
these types of issues is to ask for help
when you realize you need it that means
from mentors that means from friends
that means from anyone who's got an
objective point of view about you so for
example aya must have been about 10
years ago I took a took a course
personal development course in
California and up one of the activities
we engaged in was confronting people
with how we receive them right in other
words you walk up to someone and say I
receive you as arrogant and obnoxious
right so for example I was told by
another young woman who was objectively
leering at me and she says I feel I
receive you as arrogant and I said well
tell me more and she was shocked because
arrogant people don't say tell me more
but what it then where is why she was
shocked and impressed was because no
one's ever done that to her before I
call you arrogant or I said receiving it
was arrogant you want to know more
that's because I'm asking for help if
I'm coming across as arrogant if you're
receiving me as arrogant now it might
not be totally mine it may be the way
you're receiving me and that's okay but
I want to know why I want to know how
can you point out some
very specific things activity behaviors
up circumstances we were in that perhaps
I wasn't aware of right sometimes we're
at work most of the times we're acting
unconsciously and if I did something
unconscious to you please i want to know
that way i can shed light on it with
your help and work to heal it the
interesting thing about these types of
issues shadows as opposed to brick walls
is that they're put there and there and
they represent and they support your
souls progression your character who you
are limitations in consciousness so that
says my friends continue to grow
stronger bust through climb over go
around brick walls and shed light on
shadows done