so our buddy David here is dealing with
a situation where his mother is severely
depressed due to circumstances in her
life so much so that she's even gotten
cancer she's made herself sick according
to the doctor the cancer is a byproduct
of the stress that she's dealing with
particularly at work and if she just so
happens to be working for her sister and
her sister seems to be sort of a tyrant
and our friend Brian goes on to say that
it'd be easy to say that she should just
quit but it seems as if she's caught in
this web of dysfunction where her sister
will make her life hell and so on and so
forth so her mom is when he uses term
lightly but to describe the way you're
sharing it with me a victim of her
circumstances and and it's very
difficult for us to watch our parents
suffer it really is
I'm a parent anima child go figure and I
have a perspective based on both so I
understand I mean what could be worse
than to watch your mother your earth the
womb from which you proceeded into this
world suffer knowing also that perhaps
something can be done
Brian comes to this with with this
question as to you know how does he go
about this this is going to be one of
those videos where I say something
that's harsh and a lot of people aren't
going to like or understand that's
usually what it is when people become
upset about the harsh ideas that I share
in some of the videos it's that you
don't yet understand of course I sound
arrogant saying that way but if you
understood you'd realize that life is
harsh in many ways and sometimes harsh
ideas the acceptance of harsh ideas is
resourceful to us and the one that I'd
like you to be with is this idea that we
cannot nor is it our responsibility to
save our parents in fact it is our
greatest responsibility to springboard
off of them to the greatest of our
abilities and not carry any of their
baggage with us there's a great poem by
it's called the Prophet by Kahlil Gibran
and it's called on parenting I'd invite
you to go look at it but basically he
uses the metaphor of parents being a bow
and the child being the arrow and the
objective of the parent in its life of
raising the child is to bend as far as
it can to set forth the arrow of their
children into the future and when I me
as a parent take that perspective it
allows me to recognize that my part in
this evolution of humankind is to do the
best that I can even if I have to break
my back to support my children and
becoming the strongest version of
themselves and not give them any of my
shit now that's almost impossible
they're going to you know they say the
children bear the sins of the parents
they're going to get some of my
fucked-up-ness
and I've got some of my parents
fucked-up-ness but the entire purpose of
this whole thing of having children is
to send your children off into the
future to do better than you have my dad
is a big proponent of this he says this
often he's like I just want you to be
better than me don't worry about me he's
a starch libertarian in that way like
individualist he's like look when I get
sick and old just put me in a split me
somewhere put me in a chair in the Sun
and leave me alone don't worry about me
you go and you become the strongest
version of yourself you go and do the
best that you can of course you know
he's almost he's probably more crazy
than I am in that way so of course I'm
gonna support him and take care of him
and also my mother you know she's had
some difficult times she had a difficult
childhood she had difficult
circumstances in her family her body is
riddled with many diseases that are a
byproduct of the pain that she's
experienced in her in the rough life and
she has bent her body it's another part
of the reason why our parents suffer my
parents in particular because they Bend
themselves in order to support us it is
our responsibility not to save them from
that but to honor it and use it so that
we can do a better job of sending our
children when I say better I don't
necessarily mean of quality
mean in progression moving forward we've
got to move forward
we can't toil in the past with past
hurts for you to continue to suffer with
your mom which is normal but without the
perspective of I've got to take this
suffering and use it as motivation to do
great things in the world in her name as
opposed to taking the suffering and pain
and using it to save her is a very
important place to begin coming from I'm
not saying being be cold-hearted or it
in compassion it you have no compassion
for your mother that's not the case we
can't help ourselves we love our mommies
right till the day we die or the day
they die
we love our mommies but you got to take
up your sword and take action in the
world in their honor
you can't stay home and feed her
you can't stay home and pet her you
can't stay home and take care of her you
can't save her from her circumstances
with her sister okay I'm not saying she
isn't being victimized because that does
happen but I'm also alluding to the fact
that perhaps there's a lot more going on
than meets the eye
you don't want to get tangled up in that
it's not fair to you and it's not fair
to her it's not fair to you because and
it's not fair to the world you're doing
3d services by tangling with your
mothers dysfunction again it doesn't
mean don't love or appreciate or honor
her it means move from a different place
if you don't take this piece of advice
that I'm sharing with you the disservice
is threefold it's a disservice to
yourself obviously because you're going
to be carrying heavy baggage associated
with past pains that aren't going to
allow you to spring forth in the world
and be all that you can be you can't be
the strongest version of yourself if
you're carrying your mom's pain if
you're carrying her baggage her and her
sisters and the drama thereof you've got
better things to fucking do I'm sorry
it's just the way it is you've got to
move forward number two you're doing a
disservice to your mother by coddling
her in this way
she is best served by you becoming the
strongest version of yourself and you
know what create a woman's organization
once you've made your way or make that
your mission so non-for-profit that that
serves underprivileged women do
something else but you can't languish
with her you are doing her disservice by
not moving forward because you are the
springboard from which her legacy moves
forward you gotta go whether she likes
it or not and guess what you also do a
disservice to all of us to God the
universe and all of mankind because you
have a gift we all do you have some way
to serve the world that you are not
serving them with because you're
wallowing in the language of your
mother's pain and suffering with her and
not moving forward what about the ten
thousand women
what about the hundred thousand maybe
million women that you might be able to
support by taking up your sword and in
her honor developing something that will
serve women it in pain for generations
to come
how honorable would that be for your
mother so again I I guess I have to stop
apologizing because you know harsh is
just fucking harsh but I know this is an
idea that's going to support you it may
be a difficult pill to swallow a
difficult one to look at as a child
having parents that suffer and also as a
parent because recognize parent that you
are the sacrifice for your children I
can't see it any other way
I am the sacrifice I am the lamb for my
children's future I bend and break if I
have to in order to send them forth with
the greatest capacity for
self-development and service to the
world that I possibly can
am i doing all the right things did our
parents do all the right things who
knows what the right things are but you
do everything that you can with what you
have right where you are and you spend
yourself as a parent sending your
children forward and you don't look back
done