got a really interesting question a
timeless question that I'm going to
attempt to offer some perspective on our
friend lives in a university dormitory
and he says he lives amongst friends and
enemies he wants to know how to go about
asserting himself and becoming a
respected person he wants people to
respect him when he says things that he
says or so forth but also loved I want
to be friendly I want to have friends
how do i balance this and like I said
this is the timeless question is it
better to be loved or to be feared and
then there's this balance that's
available to us that I often call tender
aggression and it be tender but you also
want to be aggressive tender aggression
happens not in your activities not in
what you do but who you are and where
you're coming from when you're outwardly
focused on what you need to do in order
to be loved or to instill fear you're
manipulating when you have friends and
you have enemies again you're outwardly
focused you're looking to label the
circumstances outside you and manipulate
them like your world is a chessboard and
if you're playing chess you got to go to
your head and that means you've got to
be diplomatic play politics so that
you're not to look love to not to feared
you kind of balancing it this is pure
manipulation what I would invite you to
do is to forget these concepts
completely to forget the concept of
friend forget the concept of enemy
forget the concept of being loved and
the concept of being respected ignored
completely and come home to where you
are ground yourself in your own
energetic processes as you choose to
approach the people in your environment
ask yourself am i breathing deeply am i
calm who collected a we're energetic
available
how are you being and when you are aware
of yourself when you are being with
yourself when you are grounded in
yourself when you're breathing into your
balls which also means your mind is
activated and your heart is activated
right your body is soft enough breathing
into your balls it's the lowest part
portion of your torso means that
everything needs to be relaxed am i
chilling out here coming from a level
place level-headed right notice that
term it's my heart open and soft or my
rageful and am i grounded in myself when
you are all lined up all of your actions
are grounded and they're right and
they're true and there's no need for
labels or manipulations or diplom the
diplomacy
there's here's how I'm showing up and
here's how I am responding from a
grounded place with what I believe is
most resourceful for the circumstances
boy this is a powerful place to come
from one that I wish I could say I was
always moving from but I know that I
make my best choices when I take my eyes
off of the politics and the labels of
the situation and I go to my body and
ask my body how do I respond to the
circumstances because you could have
friends the do shit that should be
labeled as aggressive or mean or enemy
like but they're your friends so now
you've got this mental construct that
this gentleman is my friend I have to
ignore what I'm feeling right now
sometimes your friends are the ones that
need you to explain to them I don't
appreciate your behavior right now I
don't like when you say such-and-such to
me I don't like when you leave your
clothing over here can you please help
me this way what language to use is very
important also and I know it sounds like
a little bit of manipulation but words
are very important because
ground abstraction so it invites you to
read a book called nonviolent
communication I had a copy and I gave it
away and I really wish I did and I
should buy another one because it really
teaches you number one how to get into
in touch with your body and then using
your body to describe what you would
like to have happen in the circumstances
it's very powerful I would check it out
nonviolent communication the thing is
that now your friends can you might need
to be more assertive and aggressive with
them and your enemies might might need a
little bit more love you recognize boy
you know this guy I like to call him my
enemy but because I am so grounded in
myself I can see the pain in his eyes
and no wonder why he behaves that way
and coming from a place of passion
courage and intellect you might approach
your enemy and say something like hey
man I know we've had a few disagreements
but you look like you're upset yeah I
don't know what's going on but can I
just give you a hug whoa that throws a
whole fucking wrench in the circumstance
big wrench in the situation the bottom
line here is that I want to offer you
this take your eyes off of the politics
and the labels come home to yourself
breathe into your balls grow your tender
aggressive capacities and every action
you make will be a resourceful one done