so this video is a follow-up to the last
one where I invited you to begin
listening to at least trusting and
recognizing the voice of your body in
this video I want to go a little bit
deeper into actual techniques that are
going to support you in hearing trusting
and navigating your life through your
body so hopefully I already built a case
around why this is so important there
are two things that need to happen
simultaneously for the greatest effect
the very first thing is that we've got
to end the chatter we've got to close
down the monkey brain we've got to
reduce the amount of activity going on
in our heads you know so many of us
can't even sleep at night because we're
talking to ourselves they're just
there's way too much activity going on
up here
and the imbalance is such that all the
energy is drawn up into your head and
your body has become dead right it's why
so many of you get headaches and
migraines and neck pain I mean there's
way too much emphasis on the head brain
what we need to do is we've got to
reduce the amount of energy fluctuating
and circulating through this part of our
body right and bring it back down bring
that energy back down into your heart
and down into your balls where it can
cultivate the intelligence of your body
and give you a new perspective to
approach your life a more grounded
perspective to approach your life okay
so in my experience if you use
techniques meditative techniques to slow
down the vibration of the head in
conjunction with bioenergetic exercise
techniques to build the energy in your
body you're going to get much faster and
longer lasting results and you'll be a
bigger badder boss in your life if you
listen
my advice head meditation is simply
sitting meditation because it doesn't
require that the body do much of
anything in fact the body should be as
quiet as possible so when you sit and
you see these you know the Yogi's and
like the meditators they sit
cross-legged they've got their hands
across their lap and then they got their
eyes closed what they're really doing is
they're slowing down the thought
processes of the mind by observing them
and not attaching to them and keeping
the body still because the body is how
you respond to the thoughts in your head
so you begin to gain mastery over the
conversations in your head through
sitting meditation sitting meditation is
probably well I can't say this because
we've got yoga which is also a body
meditation and Qigong which are also
body meditations and there's thousands
of years old so in fact I think our
ancestors knew that they had to be there
to work together
but sitting meditation is one that most
people considered on
consider meditation you know they often
see someone sitting down and they've got
their eyes closed but recognize too that
it's it's not just that even in many
Western traditions you know a lot of
Christians and Muslims you know the
judeo-christian the Abrahamic religions
there are chance there's lots of
chanting Muslims still move their body
in prayer the is to go to bar mitzvahs
and Bat Mitzvah as I grew up in Long
Island with a lot of Jewish kids and
we'd go to Temple every once in a while
and they would rock they would they
would be saying there their prayer or
whatever and there was a lot of this
going on like I can't even really do it
because it was like they come up on
their toes and rock if you're Jewish or
you're Muslim you know what I'm talking
about there's that there's movement
associated with prayer so it really
isn't that new but anyway I digress
to come on back the technique that I
found that's most supportive to my
ability to shut down the chatter in my
mind using sitting meditation is with a
technology called binaural beats
binaural beats are sounds that go into
your ears in certain with certain
frequencies that literally cop it's like
anesthesia for your brain right I've had
to come to use this technology because
I'm so neurotic that I can't just sit in
meditate and I'm sure a lot of you know
what I'm talking about
yeah sit there and meditate Shh poor
sorry so many interruptions today sure
yeah I'm just going to sit there and
meditate not going to happen but a
friend of mine introduced me to a
product called holistic hol o sy NC I'm
not an affiliate for them because their
affiliate program sucks otherwise I
would be but their technology their
product has changed my life
revolutionized my life I wouldn't be Who
I am today if I didn't discover holistic
meditation and it literally is just you
it's their CDs you order the CDs I think
you can get them digitally now and you
put it in and they're like there are
levels of them you start with the first
level obviously and just sit there and
you listen
there are so many stories I could share
with you but you know I want to keep
these videos as succinct succinct as
possible with how my life has changed
because of sitting meditation but it is
not the only piece of the pie because
I've discovered that the body has to has
to be honored also you can't do one
without the other and if you want to get
a double impact and give you a really
good metaphor in a moment for how this
double impact works you're going to have
to include bioenergetic exercises in
your in a part of your daily routine and
if you see me do these crazy videos of
course I'm a I'm eccentric and I don't
mind being weird in front of you on the
camera but this is very serious stuff
and I'm going to share with you just one
exercise and an exercise progression
that's going to support you in reducing
the neurotic holding in your body that
doesn't allow you to breathe deep so
that you can't tap into the intelligence
of your heart in your balls I've made
very extensive videos on the technique
I'm going to share with you right now if
you search my strength camp channel you
will see videos on how to create a
bioenergetics tool and how to use
bioenergetics also deep breathing I've
got videos about deep breathing where
I'm using some techniques I've got one
called how to breathe into your balls
like a boss if I remember I'll link some
of these videos down below there these
are all on my other channel and I'm sure
I've made more on this channel but you
know I I want to share these ideas over
and over again because of that important
the bow is an exercise that puts a
stretch on your respiratory muscles the
ones that become very tense due to
stress it puts a stress a stretch on
them it stretches them and when you
stretch a muscle you tell you you open
up the opportunity for it to relax
coupled with deep breathing and this
brings vibration back into your body and
that's exactly what you want you want
life you want your light your body to
become vibrant again that's where that
word vibrant comes from vibration you
want to bring vibration back into your
body so I'll demonstrate for you very
shortly here watch the
other videos but this is the the other
end of this two-pronged approach to
becoming the strongest version of
yourself on the energetic level okay
those of you who are new to my videos
when I use these terms like energetic
level and so on and so forth sign up for
my newsletter I give away a free book
where I share the four layers of
strength I'm talking about the third of
the four layers of strength and
ultimately how by encompassing living a
life that encompasses the development of
all four layers you become what I call
the strongest version yourself back to
our show the bow looks like this this is
the way I would invite you to do it
there are three different positions that
you can do it the first is with your
fists at your the top of your hips here
let you your back this way the other one
is with your hands behind your head and
then finally this one based on how tense
you are and where most of the tension is
in your body you're going to want to use
a combination of the three or focus on
one more than the other you tend to be
very closed up in your shoulders and
just this one and this one is going to
mean a lot more this one especially if
you've got tight hips like I do and you
put your hands on your butt this one
really opens up the lower portion of
your torso down where your instinct
comes from your balls this is more heart
this is more balls you're going to stand
with your feet straight when you
straight ahead slightly bend your knees
choose the position where you want to
put the stretch then you're going to
open your mouth as wide as you can also
open your eyes keep your eyes open as
wide as you can it's going to feel
awkward and it's supposed to feel
awkward because it's putting stress on
your mask
we wear masks our face is probably the
most tense part of our entire body but
we don't recognize it because the way we
approach the world is through the facade
of our face fake smiles that's one of
the worst people around there's big
smiles can't stand it but that's all
really that's just nervous
the fucking face so when we stretch the
face with the wide mouth and eyes we we
begin to lessen the neurotic hold on
those muscles coupled with the deep
breathing and then you start to that
anxiety that you feel it awkward
awkwardness you feel is really energy
rising in your body and it's okay and
you want to go with it and as that
vibration and awkwardness happens yield
into it allow the vibration to happen
I'll demonstrate briefly
I don't know if you notice but I'm brief
I'm vibrating a lot you might also as
you feel the energy rise in your body if
you were in an environment that it's
conducive to as your energy starts to
rise and you come up out of it allow the
energy to continue to you go with this
vibration oh and different sounds sounds
a vibration also sounds create vibration
in your physiology your organs in your
inner tune that was a pretty cool bike
there's a scooter shop over here these
guys like they wrote my behind the rear
dismiss scooters that was like a bike
with a motor on it
[Music]
sounds deep sounds Oh chanting it
vibrates your inner tube
you could have an inner tube you know
from your mouth down to your asshole
there's an inner tube and there is
tension in our inner tube also MA it
vibrates all that I mean I do then I
feel it right down into my perineum
right down into my pelvic floor Oh
different sounds give you a different
massage in different portions of your
inner tube make those sounds and vibrate
the vibration reduces attention in your
outer muscular system or your outer tube
and sounds release tension in your inner
tube hope you follow me so the
combination of mind or sitting
meditation to reduce the energy in your
head and the bioenergetic exercises that
I teach you these are very simple
bioenergetic exercises that I'm teaching
it because there are some really there
there are some that are far more
advanced that I only do with people when
I'm coaching them most of my personal
coaching has basically become
bioenergetic coaching but these are ones
that you can use for experiment and for
maintenance and it's going to keep
you're going to feel better instantly by
using these exercises and and getting
over the dissonance the cognitive
dissonance that does that doesn't allow
you to do the weird shit that you see me
doing you just got to like be fucking
weird so the analogy that I use because
people often ask me like Elliott how
quickly am I going to yield results I'm
going to get results by using these
techniques that you teach us get back in
the camera so I can talk how quickly am
I going to see results this is the way
I've described it imagine if
our neuroses and we're all neurotic
we're all fucked up in some particular
way we're all we've all got unique types
of fucked up in this but we're off uncle
is a block of ice that you're frozen in
your body is frozen in this block of ice
from your head down you could just
imagine you're like in a cartoon like
you know and they fall into the water
and they pop up in a block of ice you're
in a frozen block of ice bioenergetic
exercises work to free you from that
block of ice that petrification of your
body almost like someone came with a
sledge hammer and started breaking apart
all that ice that's around you that's a
very quick you're going to get instant
results I already feel different from
doing a little bit of the vibration
right here for you you're going to hit
instant results but just as quickly as
the results come from the bioenergetic
exercise it's instant and if you do it
every day it compounds you just get
better and better you feel better and
better it's as quickly as it goes away
this has just been my experience I
haven't done research on this but I'm
all I can really do is offer you my
experiences in these videos and and I
invite you to try them out so that you
can have your own experiences and say
yes Elliot that makes sense no that
didn't work for me Elliot as quickly as
you get the results from the
bioenergetic exercises as quickly as
they go away so if you do it for a week
straight and then you don't do it for a
week you'll start feeling not so good
again you need to do it it's like a drug
you got to continue to use it to keep
that high so you become dependent on it
and by the way you'll be dependent on
all this stuff forever if you're on a
journey of becoming the strongest
version yourself you'll always be doing
some form of body and mind meditation
but if you couple the bioenergetic
exercises with the holistic or any type
of sitting brain quieting meditation
imagine now that that block of ice that
you're in you set it out in the Sun and
the warm Sun is melting the ice off of
your body now it's going to take a hell
of a lot longer
you know the sledgehammer broke up the
ice within
is the melting of the Sun might take
days right it might take several several
hours for that melting to happen but the
effect is that much long-lasting so if
it took you three weeks which is usually
what it takes
in my experience again to really get the
benefit of sitting meditation after
three weeks you start feeling like hey
you know I feel pretty damn good I'm
making good decisions
I feel grounded and you stop it'll take
about three weeks for the results to go
away so the longer you've done it the
longer it lasts I often make the mistake
you'd think I would know better and I've
been doing this for like ten years but I
often make the mistake of meditate doing
sitting meditation for you know two
three months and then feeling so good
then I don't do it anymore well then I
get neurotic and then I get back to it
so what like I said before if you're on
this journey to becoming a stronger
version yourself it does not stop and
body meditation and mind meditation shit
that I'm teaching you right now will
always be a part of the journey I'm
pretty sure I'll be 90 years old doing
chi gong or yoga or some form of
mind-body integrative meditation I've
given you a segmented means by which you
close down the activity of the mind
because it becomes an enemy to the body
and how to bring life back into your
body I hope this helps done