we got a question from our friend who's
16 years old he lives in Australia he's
been in foster care since he was nine
years old and now he finds himself in a
pretty tough situation basically the
woman that cares for him is foster
parent is a 68 year old woman she
provides all of it for all of his needs
but she's a negative woman not
constantly picking fights with him and
making him feel bad our friend goes on
to describe that he's a good kid he
seems to get all of his schoolwork done
he doesn't get in trouble you know that
he spends most of his time studying and
exercising he feels that he's doing the
right things but yet he's constantly
being persecuted you know and beaten
down by the poor attitude and energy of
this woman and he doesn't know what to
do being a senior in high school he
still has you know studies and he's got
a past test he's really busy and he
can't see how leaving the home would
help him because he'd have to swim on
his own he'd have to live on his own and
still be able to perform in school and
stuff like that so he is in a bind he
does not know what to do he doesn't know
how to deal with the situation such that
he could continue to be a good kid but
still deal with a lot of the pressure
that he's getting from this woman so the
way I'd like to approach this with you
today is bear with me I'm going to throw
up some Jesus quotes for you basically
Jesus is always describing in the New
Testament he's always describing this
place called the kingdom he's always
saying in the kingdom it'll be like this
and the kingdom it is like that the
kingdom is closer to you than your
hearts you know the blood in your heart
he says things of this nature there's
always these metaphors about this place
the kingdom and on the Sermon on the
Mount he says you know love II systems
crazy stuff to the people at times says
love your enemies right love your
enemies he goes on to say that if
someone slaps you turn and give your
other cheek what some people take that
to be our
Commandments Jesus is saying hey you
want to get to this place which is the
kingdom which by the way the kingdom is
a mindset it's a type of consciousness
it's a unity consciousness a
peacefulness a joy the reality of life
is found in the kingdom and when he says
these things like turn the other cheek
and love your neighbor people think that
those are Commandments those are steps
that you're going to have to take if you
want to get to this kingdom place so
this you know they say well that's crazy
why would I have to follow these steps
by turning my other cheek and loving
nape and loving uh enemies in order to
get to this kingdom place that I've
never even seen just forget it so the
whole thing does it make sense to them
but if you approach it and read it the
way i read and approach it from this
perspective you see that what Jesus is
doing is he's again describing what
happens when you're a person of the
kingdom when you're a person who is
truly at peace when you're a person who
has found joy and has come to realize
the unity and all of earth and in life
and that type of person is a type of
person that can love his enemy that can
turn his cheek it's not that he's doing
it so that he can be from the kingdom
it's that he is a man of the kingdom so
he does that stuff and what that means
is that he's detached from the physical
world in a way you know in other words
he's not so attached to what other
people are doing or saying to him
because he's found peace in his heart
and no matter how much someone slaps you
or how much someone poses themselves to
be an enemy of you they can't reach the
inside they can't reach the kingdom
which is inside you the kingdom is deep
within and you can detach yourself from
all of the trappings in the world that
will destroy the kingdom within you now
I know this is all metaphorical and
spiritual and religious the point is the
take-home point is for you is you're
going to have to live with the slaps in
your face for a little bit longer you're
gonna have to live with your enemy a
little bit longer but if you decide to
go searching for that kingdom right
finding inner peace
go looking for inner peace what you're
going to find is that you're going to
love your enemy you're going to turn the
other cheek not because you have to but
because it's going to be who you are
some of the ways to help you approach
this place this kingdom this place of
inner peace is through meditation
through prayer through mindfulness
conscious awareness these are all things
there are techniques and there are tools
that you can use to help bring this
about meditation is one of them is that
there's absolutely meditations like
medicine and if you decide to start
studying and paying attention some
places you might want to begin with is
is Osho's dynamic meditations which I've
showed you some of them on this channel
but even just conscious mindfulness
where you're just being aware on a
consistent basis throughout your day
noticing the emotions that bubble up in
you when someone is approaching you in a
negative fashion just being aware and
then obviously they're sitting
meditation where you sit for 10 20
minutes a day and you just count or
recognize your breathing your breath
inhale exhale and just as thoughts come
you just see them and watch them go by
practice meditation study meditation
prayer fulness is like walking
meditation it's like living your life in
a meditative way so these are all
different ideas that might support you
look my friend I feel for you you seem
like a really good guy seems like you're
in a tough situation but always remember
that all the challenges that we face are
only there to strengthen us and the
reason why you're facing these
challenges and so that you can grow a
little bit stronger so that you know how
now have a tool that you can carry with
you and use in tougher situations later
on in your life and you can go back and
share with others other young guys you
know 10 20 years from now we're in
similar situations you could share your
experience with them and show them how
you got through it so that's it dude
good luck Elliot sick what