so the physical manifestations the
physiological manifestations of fear are
exactly the same regardless of what you
fear so it could be a huge fear or could
be a small fear but regardless if
there's fear there your body responds
the same way so I'm what I'm about to
share with you might not totally relate
but battling fear is battling fear in
all of its manifestations so anyway
yesterday I took my oldest daughter took
all my kids to a waterpark and my oldest
daughter wanted to hang out with me
while the younger kids hung out with
their mother and I told her I said look
you're gonna hang out with me we're
gonna go on the biggest scariest rides
first otherwise you got to hang out with
the babies so she's like I knew she was
shocked the minute she heard me say that
she was scared just like you might get
scared if you're going out with your
friends and there's a girl you might
want to go up to and talk to or you want
to quit your job because there's
something else that you some other
venture but you'd like to go on but
either way it's fucking fear she was
scared and as soon as we walked through
the gates we saw this giant slide I mean
it was I can't tell you how tall it was
Boone was fucking tall even I was a
little shook you know in a manly way but
anyway so I'm climbing to the top as
we're climbing I could see she's create
trying to create courage in her head
she's trying to will herself to take
each step up that damn ladder and trying
to will her self so go over that cliff
of the slide just scary as fuck couldn't
even see you go to the end of the slide
you can't even see down it was just it
was just a straight shot but anyway I
had to explain to her that battling fear
on the playing field playing field
through which fear is born is futile you
can't will yourself away from fear you
can't use your mind to battle fear
you've got to use your body to battle
fear acting behavior breathing all
physical behaviors contribute to the
elimination of fear and the one thing
that I shared with her as we were
climbing up that ladder that she was
able to implement immediately that
to soften resolve and melt away that
fear was to breathe into her belly you
know you're scared because you stopped
breathing deep into your body you stop
using your body to produce energy and
you start reverting to your head
so you'll get headaches they get like
all anxious and should there become
ungrounded so I taught her as we were
walking up the ladder to breathe make
her belly big really I was teaching her
to breathe into her balls now but that's
just one way to describe the reality
that stimulating the body through deep
breathing instantly eliminates fear
anytime you're scared anytime you're
worried anytime you're anxious anytime
you're hesitant towards doing something
big be it climbing up a giant ladder to
jump off you know not to kill yourself
but at an amusement park or taking a
leap of faith in a direction that you
believe deep in your heart will
transform your life in a positive way
and you start thinking too much go to
your body breathe
shake vibrate dance turn on some
crazy-ass music and dance shake your
body jump up and down scream yell pound
your chest ah that's how courage is
built that's how fear is resolved you
can't think it away