got a question for my buddy Aidan who
has been dating a girl for about a year
and and they recently broke up here's
the thing though he thought you would
come to her house when they were dating
and hang out with her family so much so
that the family is basically integrated
him into their familiar construct they
would even take him on vacation and shit
like that so he has a great relationship
with her siblings her mother and in
particular this girl's father who he
sees as a second dad right but now he
broke up with her so a year of adopting
a new family or family adopting you and
then you guys are breaking up and the
problem is he go he still goes her their
house to hang out with the dad and hang
out the siblings and stuff and he sees
her coming and you know they'll glance
and like smile at each other but she'll
go about her business and he'll die kind
of be there he still loves her still has
more feeling towards her but comes to
the house because the family invites it
invites him over and and wants to hang
out with him n he really enjoys their
presence so the question is should he
just like cut out completely because of
the pain associated with seeing her
every time he goes there knowing that
he's also losing a second family and
knowing that these people actually care
for him as well right the reason why I
took your question is because I have had
the same exact experience except I was
on the other end of the spectrum my
now-wife right so I'll get to what I
think is going to happen if you haven't
figured it out already when we were
dating in high school in ecology we were
very young were 14 and my family
basically adopted her as one of our own
you know I've got three brothers and
sisters and my parents like she was at
our house like every single day and she
really became a part of the family and
there were times when I was just like I
was fucked I was done with her I was
like I fustrated I was just like I broke
up with it I wrote with so many damn
times was ridiculous but she still kept
coming over she came over cuz my sister
wanted to hang out with her they go them
all together or her and my brothers
would do something together you know and
watch movies and you know she'd go my
mom would like take her
the salon to get her hair cut and shit
and like I be home I'd be like why she
here and she would just like she's
smiling and wave and I don't know if
it's good or bad I don't know you know I
can't place judgment on it but the
reason why I tell you this story the
reason why I took your questions because
in my experience you guys are just gonna
get back together I know you have pain
when you see her if you say that she
giggles and smiles and his flirtatious
with you when you when you walk by and
shit I think the break-up is going is
temporary right and I only say that
because of my experience I don't have
any like practical advice for you here
or paradigms I'm just giving you hope
because because I was in a very similar
situation and this is the way it turned
out my family adopted Colleen and I
married her several years later and I
mean you know I'm very happily married
with a more so than I think then like
ninety-nine percent of the people who
say they're happily married you know so
dude I think it's going to be a long
beautiful healthy vibrant vital
passionate relationship between the two
of you is just yeah you're going through
a moment of separation it's normal
you're young too we you know that's what
happened with me so I think that's
what's going to happen with you good
luck bro