hey today's video is a little different
in that I am going to answer our friends
question but I'm going to answer in such
a way that this video is a call to
action for all young people and that
means between the ages of 19 you know
high school or getting out of high
school to about 35 all young people who
are trying to find their place in the
world what should they do when we're
brought up in a world where the system
dominates and our hearts are left to be
squashed and ignored in order to climb
some sort of an imaginary ladder in the
corporate world so our friend goes on to
say that he titles his question the
system my life and my future in a
nutshell he's in college and he decided
to start studying business just off of a
whim because you know he's 19 years old
and didn't know what else to do and I
don't blame him business is probably a
good one to study but he realized that
he's just not that interested in the
things that are being taught in his
class so he searched his heart and
realized that he loves architecture he
must have an artistic mathematical type
mind for him to choose architecture you
know that's a unique thing to consider
so he wants to now switch majors to
architecture right and in switching
majors he realizes that he needs to
change schools in order to change
schools he needs to take certain
prerequisites and they're all classes
that he could give two shits about so
he's sleeping in now due to the anxiety
and depression that he has because of
this dilemma he needs to spend another
two years studying things he doesn't
like in order to finally do the thing
that he does like and it's causing him a
lot of grief he's young and most of us
are young that I'm watching these videos
and he feels like he's wasting his time
I'm wasting my time and he's stuck now
the ambiguity is just growing thicker
because he's not even sure if
architecture is what he loves but
there's something in his heart that's
telling him that he should do it he
know what to do he wants to escape the
system because this is what he's calling
a he says that this is a crazy system
why do I have to do this there's
something that I love I want to go do it
but yet I have to go through all these
jump through all these hoops we're gonna
go deeper into debt I've got to spend
more time doing things I don't like and
how do I get out of this trap so I'll
first begin by describing my life okay
what I do right now right I have what I
am going to term a non job I don't have
a job I don't create jobs what I do is
search this is literally I this is what
I do and the reason why I'm telling you
this is because I want to share the
steps to be able to do what you see me
doing for the thing that you love
I searched the depths of my heart on a
daily basis to see what's in there what
do I love what do I love what do I love
I'm 33 years old and I still don't know
what I want to major in right just like
yourself I studied uh Healthcare
Administration I think right I don't
remember a single class but yet I had to
go into debt just like you I still
search my heart because I'm
ever-evolving as you are ever evolving
you're always growing and the thing that
you love grows as you grow and this is
normal and natural so if you ever
actually find out what you want to major
in you're a lucky lucky lucky person
because chances are as you evolve that's
going to evolve that thing is going to
change right
I searched the depths of my heart I
discovered what I loved I immersed
myself in the study of the things that I
loved meaning I read lots and lots and
lots of books I attend seminars I attend
workshops and I hire mentors I speak
with people who are really really good
at the things I love this includes
strength training philosophy psychology
things that you hear me talking about
the other thing that I do is that I
share that love I share the love with
you through these videos I share the
love with you through a newsletter that
I write I share the love of strength and
philosophy and psychology and physiology
through
books that I write DVDs that I make
workshops that I do I share the love and
I know how to I've learned how to and I
will teach you how to receive the love
back associated with sharing what's in
your heart because when you share what
you love and what you're good at
with other people you will open the
channels for receiving what you need to
put food on your table
right because really that's all we need
is food a roof and some clothing and if
you can get that through your head
that success is not measured by things
then you're going to have an easy time
doing what I'm about to share with you
and that's creating what I call a non
job and I'm really I'm going to relate
this to the idea that you love
architecture and use architecture as an
example the system has told us right the
machine and we gotta realize the machine
is imaginary the machine the system is
imaginary it is not who we are it's not
what must happen it's a choice you can
choose to participate in the game of the
machine and the system which says go to
school go to college get a degree get a
good job get benefits get a retirement
funds and die this is this is just an
idea
this is a machine this is the philosophy
that someone's created that is very
advantageous to the bigger machine which
is we need really good tax payers so the
government can continue expanding at
them pockets empire doing whatever crazy
shit it does you don't have to
participate in that you're free enough
there was a day when we weren't that
free there was a day when you decided to
opt out of the system that they would
burn you at a stake it's crucify you
there do all types of weird shit because
you were defiant of the system today boy
we live in the greatest time ever
because you don't have to participate to
any great degree still gonna pay taxes
but you can choose to play by your own
rules never before has this been the
case so I am I'm already prepared for a
lot of ranting in this video so bear
with me a non job means you don't get a
job you don't need a job you don't need
a career you don't need to create jobs I
have people that make money through me
at my gym but I don't they don't have
jobs here I teach them how to have non
jobs they helped me in my non job but
they're not employees because I don't
own them okay
a non job the non job resumes which I
created here because there are no rules
to the non job but there are
requirements for building a foundation
for the non job that you're going to
have in architecture the very first
thing that you want to make sure happens
is that you love something you've got to
love something you don't necessarily
have to have a name for the thing that
you love but there's a feeling that's
moving you in a particular direction
that is driven by your love so you say
architecture so architecture is just a
name it's a symbol but there's an
artistic mechanical inclination within
your heart that's why we put the heart
symbol there for love because it's
coming from your feeling it's coming
from your heart there's something there
explore that feeling you can call it
architecture because perhaps
architecture is the physical
manifestation of the feeling that people
have had over the course of human
history that is similar to the one that
you're experiencing right I love for
artistic mathematics right I'm not into
it so I don't know for sure but explore
that love so read books attend courses
there are free college courses that you
can attend in architecture right now you
can begin starting start studying
architecture today I know Berkeley I
believe Berkeley has online free online
courses free online college courses you
can literally sit there and study a
course just as if you paid 150 thousand
dollars for it and you didn't have to do
the bullshit prerequisites all you have
to do is log in you don't pay a dime and
you could study the thing you love there
are libraries there are websites there
are seminars there a workshop
there are associations all dedicated to
the love of architecture you can begin
that now all you're doing is exploring a
feeling in your body it feels good when
you see you having a problem getting up
in the morning like you described
because there's resistance between the
heart and your brain your brain has been
conditioned by people saying you need to
do this you need to do that you need to
go through the drudgery associated with
it being something in the system right
and I'll tell you how you can beat the
system altogether be on top of the
goddamn system in a moment and your
heart saying I just want to study
architecture I just want to explore
architecture right so just do what your
heart tells you to do you know why
because if you love something you're
going to want to get up every single
morning you're gonna beg to wake up
you're not gonna want to sleep I do what
I love so much so that I am reading it
to the last wake of my eye before I go
to bed and I wake up at five o'clock in
the morning you know what I do I put on
headphones of somebody else talking
about the shit that I love philosophy
psychology physiology and I go for a
walk so the minute I go to sleep at
night I'm studying the shit that I love
and I get up in the morning and I listen
to it I go for an hour walk I'm studying
it as I'm going to sleep and I'm
studying it as soon as I wake up because
I love the thing I can't get enough of
it if you love architecture or the
feeling bringing you towards
architecture because it might not be
architecture it might evolve like I said
but as you explore the thing in your
heart there's going to be a peace or joy
and enthusiasm a passion that is going
to rise up out of your soul and not you
will not be able to hold it back
everything in your light is going to
revolve around that particular love
because you've given way to it you let
go into the ocean of the love of your
thing right don't grasp it don't hold it
you don't need a degree about it
need to manifest it tangibly in any way
shape or form you don't need a
particular trophy that says I am this
the trophy which is the degree it's just
a fucking piece of paper it's an idea it
means absolutely nothing in the real
world in the realm of things it doesn't
mean anything
it means you went to school and decided
to partake of the system and you got
this piece of paper that says that you
probably know something about this but
you know what someone who loves truly
loves the study of something doesn't
need to prove it because it's oozing out
of his pores right that is you with
architecture begin now because you're
growing it apathetic towards it because
there are all these barriers in front of
you fuck the barriers there are no
barriers except the ones that you've
decided to accept ignore the barriers
it's a game they played that they're
creating a game they've created a game a
machine you don't have to participate
begin studying now rant over part to
share the love I make these videos
because I can't help myself but make
these fucking videos I cannot help
myself but to share the thing I love I
love this so much and if you're on my
Facebook fan page you know this I love
it so much and as I'm reading books I'm
highlighting stuff taking pictures and
uploading it to my facebook wall because
I'm like I got to share this shit when
you love something so much you're going
to find a way to share it and that's
what we're supposed to do right there
are no channels for sharing in fact the
channels for sharing have been
democratized because there was a time
that unless you were on Oprah unless
you're on TV unless you can get a spot
on the radio unless you had a published
book in Barnes & Nobles you couldn't
share your ideas you couldn't reach out
to the world today that's those lines of
communication the ability to share is
more open than ever before I have this
$200 camera and a connection to the
Internet and I share the thing that I
love every single day
you can do this with architecture right
study the thing and the way you feel
like sharing it because it's all
requires creativity or requires
sensitivity the way you feel like
sharing it begin sharing it immediately
do you like talking in front of the
camera it's easy for me to do so I do it
do you like writing start writing a blog
start writing books doesn't matter if
you have the degree or not because the
other people who love this thing don't
really care about the piece of paper or
letters next to your name they love the
thing and if you can share the thing in
a really really entertaining
enlightening helpful way the piece of
paper doesn't mean shit the degree
doesn't mean a goddamn thing
degree the degree only means something
if you intend to continue playing the
game continue participating in the
machine but you don't have to that's
okay if you want to be a part of machine
there's nothing wrong with that realize
that you're being a part of a machine
but you don't have to be in order to
impact the world with the thing that you
love you love architecture you've
already done what you needed to do and
you continue to do it in evolves in you
and you share the thing make videos
write about it speak about it create a
club about it create a fan page about it
share the thing share it because you
love it so much when you love something
so much you have to share it not because
you need that because of some law you've
got to share it now you don't share
because you need to make money although
that will happen you don't do it for any
other reason except that you're so full
of the thing that it spills over like it
says my cup runneth over my cup runneth
over with the love for this thing
whatever it is that you love whatever it
is that you love is okay it could be
building chairs it could be climbing
rocks it does not matter what it is you
immerse yourself you share and then you
learn how to receive because the better
you share the better you'll be able to
receive so for me I make these videos I
recently discovered
that after making about 600 videos that
I can get paid just for making the
videos that's why I've been making a lot
more have you noticed
because there are commercials that run
before my videos and I get paid quite a
bit I mean most people can can live very
comfortably off of what I earn just from
sharing my ideas through these videos
it's a little crazy I almost feel like
I'm cheating but I realized the laws
here are in effect I love something I'm
sharing the thing so I'm open to receive
it right
so there are ad networks that send me
checks big checks for making more videos
helping you doing the thing I love and
what I love doing is helping you do the
thing you love I get paid a lot for it I
write and I create PDFs PDF reports it's
just digital books and I sell them I say
hey I give lots of free stuff away but
if you want a little bit more for 19
dollars you can have my book I've
learned how to receive see this is a
tough one for a lot of people but you've
got to get over this you've got to learn
how to receive the better you serve
people the more you will receive and you
find multiple ways to serve them so for
example I'm holding a workshop in New
York City I am nobody by the way I'm
just a guy who has a video camera that
talks in front of the camera I'm holding
a workshop in New York City in a in a
few weeks and I invited people 30 people
to pay $75 to spend four hours with me
talking about the things that they love
and I love together I mean it's crazy
it's crazy and I'm not a thief I'm not a
gimmick
chicanery dude I'm not trying to rip
anybody off I just realized that I'm
sharing so much that I need to open
channels to receive I'll fly to New York
City and talk about the things I love
and people will pay for it and I love
them and they love me and this is how we
make love we share I share my time I
share my ideas I share the things I love
they share their money so they can get a
little bit more of
from me in a different way in a special
way face to face you can do this with
absolutely anything you can create a non
job with absolutely anything if you've
watched this video this long if you've
listened to my my ranting you know and I
had way too much coffee today so so I'm
going nuts here if you've listened this
far and you're fully enrolled in the
idea of having an on job creating what I
just described there are logical steps
there are steps there are steps to this
there are concrete steps a path that you
can tread to make all this happen and
because I love this just as much as I
love physiology philosophy and
psychology and body building I would be
willing to continue making videos like
this about how to make this happen we
really make it happen not just talk
about it think about it right because
this could seem like a good idea and the
only reason why I'm I invite you to
realize that this is not just a fucking
idea that happens is because this is the
life that I live I literally live I make
a great living you know a really good
living justice way I will show you how
free of charge all I need is for anyone
who's interested to share this video
with other people that you think might
be interested and comment in the youtube
comment section below
just say Elliot this is crazy dope I
want it show me how and I'll either
create a series on this channel or a
separate channel all about non jobs and
how you can create your own on job and
live a free life a life that is free and
allows you to do the things you love to
do because that is reality reality is
you work hard you work diligently you
work insistently incessantly but that
work is a manifestation of your love for
a particular thing you do it because you
love it's not about being lazy is not
about four hour work weeks it's about
getting up at 5:00
in the morning and and jumping into the
ocean of the thing that you love sharing
the thing that you love to the minute
you go to sleep at night sleeping well
because you have enough money to put
food on your table I have four children
I put food in their mouths and passing
on that legacy to other people that's it
my rant is over let me know if you like
this idea if you want more of this
comment below and share the shit out of
this video Eliot what