in the sport of powerlifting an athlete
will choose one of several different
movements to maximize his strength
potential in so let's use the bench
press for example for those you who
don't know the bench press is an
exercise where the athlete unwraps a
barbell loaded with a certain amount of
weight a lot of weight enough that he
can only possibly do it once he unwraps
the weight brings it down to his chest
and then extends it back out the entire
sport is designed around maximizing your
potential in that one particular
movement so you would imagine that as
the athlete finds that there are some
weights that he cannot push you know
it's too heavy what he'll start to do is
break down the spectrum of that movement
so once the bar leaves the chest he's
going to recognize that there's a
spectrum between the chest and full
extension and along that spectrum there
are sticking points a really good power
lifter is going to do all that he can to
discover his sticking points and then
use specific exercises to strengthen
himself in such a fashion that those
sticking points are moved beyond so that
ultimately when he adds more way to the
bar he becomes stronger by overcoming
sticking points now in your life there
are also sticking points there are you
know you might not be making as much
money as you'd like you might not be
able to hold a serious love relationship
you uh there's so all sorts of things
that you want to be able to achieve you
can't lose weight no matter what I do I
can't lose weight you can't stop smoking
or other addictions those are sticking
points and in the same way that the
power lifter is very appreciative of
these sticking points because it
develops his strength in that movement
you're sticking points are you should be
appreciative of because they show you
weaknesses in your character sticking
points in your character and the
spectrum for you is not from point A to
point B but from the weakest version of
yourself or the you you would rather not
be the version of yourself that you are
not proud
and the version of yourself that I call
the strongest version of yourself so
you're moving from week aspersion
yourself strongest version yourself and
along the way you're going to find
sticking points but how do you
strengthen those sticking points like
the athlete you know he goes ahead and
discovers that well Mike for example my
triceps are very weak so I can't extend
fully at the top so he goes and does
exercises to strengthen that particular
part of the movement that muscle for you
it's going to be different you know you
can't exercise your muscles to
strengthen your resolve and your
character in life but what you can
strengthen and what you should
strengthen or what are called virtues
virtues lie along the spectrum of the
strength of your character there are all
sorts of virtues I'll even put a link
down below to a website that has a list
of virtues that you could study that way
you can see for example if I'm not
making enough money with my new business
it's not working out you might look at
that list of virtues and say which one
of these virtues do I need to strengthen
which one of these muscles do I need to
strengthen so that my business can be
successful do I need to be more patient
do I need to be more consistent do I
need to be more courageous do I need to
be more accepting do I need whatever it
is like I said there's a broad there's a
long list of these things take a look at
them down below instead of just saying I
need to get better I need to be good get
very specific about what it is see the
bench press her is not going to say I
need to get better the bench press very
good bench presser is going to say I
need to get better at my lockout and
there's a whole list of exercises that
strengthen the muscles associated with
the lockout if you need to get better
with your persistence per se you know
that strengthening that virtue is going
to get you a better business or perhaps
a better partner in life a love
relationship that you can actually
participate in a long term whatever it
is that you want now i'm not here to
tell you what's right or wrong or what
you should or shouldn't want or what
virtues you should strengthen what I'm
offering you as a tool a perspective a
way of looking at your life finding the
things that you're not happy about the
discovering the sticking points and
strengthening them by getting very
specific about the virtue that you need
to work on talk to you next time Eliot's
it what