hey whats up guys one of the things I've
been reminiscing on recently is the
timeline that it took from me when I
first moved down to Florida and started
my own business to where I am right now
and I got thinking about that because
last weekend I spent a lot of time with
brand new business people entrepreneurs
people trying to come up in their life
even through fitness it was interesting
to meet some people who have lost over a
hundred pounds so got me thinking about
the time perspective or timeline with
regard to achieving your results in any
realm of your life success in business
success and fitness success and
relationships takes a particular
gestation period to bud and become so
one of the questions people typically
ask is how much how long they want to
know what is the time frame between when
I get started on my journey of weight
loss or building a business or trying to
find a significant other to have
relationship with and then start
comparing ourselves to those who are
already there and I think that's one of
the most dangerous things that we end up
doing it's not fair to ourselves and
it's not fair to the person that we're
comparing ourselves to comparing is
never fair to the person you're
comparing yourself to of course it's
very obvious because for yourself
because well why should you compare
yourself to someone who is experiencing
life different than you they come from a
different circumstance have different
environments they're different DNA
they're just different for us to compare
ourselves is silly for ourselves but
it's all so silly for the other person
because when we compare ourselves to
other people we hold them as an object
right everybody's very objective to us
but this person in particular we hold as
an object there they are there's where I
want to be and then we begin analyzing
them as if you know somehow there's a
hidden trick to them being where they
happen to be well they're exactly where
they need to be because the universe
works that way God decided upon it and
you're exactly where you need to be
because the universe has placed you here
right here right now at the exact
perfect time for you so one of the
things that I wanted to share with you
today is how to take a practical
approach to achieving your goals with
regard to time line now I am one of the
first people i'm in aries by the way and
if you know that I kind of pay attention
to astrology and Aries is a fire sign
fiery people want shit fast we burn with
desire we want to go full speed ahead
immediately and we want the fucking
thing now of course that's a cultural
idea everybody in the United States or
in Western culture or just in culture at
large in the world is wanting things
faster now but it's deeply ingrained in
my DNA I don't have patience as an
inherent virtue I want things now I want
things fast and I'm willing it to tear
my body apart tear my mind apart to get
it in fact it's kind of what I did I've
injured myself and by being impatient
but I wanted to share my experience with
you I happen to be a little bit older
than most of the people watching these
videos the median age is between 17 and
27 I'm going to be 37 in April so I've
got a little bit of time on you and time
is what offers wisdom you cannot have
wisdom without experience 10 years of
time over someone who's 20 or 20 years
you know someone who's 1727 to me whose
37 there is a little bit that I might be
able to share with you because I can
look back and see where I was when I was
you now of course I want to warn you
that just because my timeline took five
years you'll see the graphic that
Danny's going to put up either in the
corner here or somewhere where I can
Danny put it over here so I can kind of
have it all spelled out so people can
see what i did was i graphed one of the
various aspects of my life with regard
to success now in my blog post down
below I talked about a few others you
could click that click
length after this video and watch that
what what you see here is a gap between
when I started making YouTube videos and
about five years later if you notice in
the graph there's a long period of very
low subscriber activity what you're
looking at as a graph of daily
subscribers five years I made videos
from 2007 2 to 7 2013 sometimes daily
sometimes a few times a week sometimes I
would skip a week or two but
consistently made videos for five years
building my business building my family
growing my relationship with my wife all
along that time but ultimately it took
five years of hard work grinding to hit
that critical point where it seemed as
if it was overnight success if you look
at 2013 it seems as if where the hell is
this guy come from overnight success
well it was an overnight success then it
was a five-year night that took me
through before the Sun rose I think this
offers a little bit of perspective for
those of you who are trying to gain
results in anywhere any area of your
life and the reason why I share this is
because during that five years I
literally had to transform who I was you
see this is the barrier between what we
want where we are and what we want it's
who we're being it took five years for
the universe to mold my character to
change me into the type of person that
deserves a million subscribers on my
youtube channel the type person that
deserves wealth and abundance you see
the elliot began first making youtube
videos or the you who begins on your
weight loss journey or your muscle
building journey or your your career
journey you're a relationship any
freaking journey will not get the result
until you become the type of person that
deserves the results and that's what the
work is all about the work is
about your grinding the work is about
the discipline virtue that you create
the work isn't about what you do the
work is about who you're becoming over
time and a change or character takes
patience dedication devotion and daily
discipline in all areas not just the
making of YouTube videos for me not just
the exercising in the gym for you or
whatever it is that you have to do on a
daily basis to get your result those are
activities what really matters is the
character that evolves the virtues that
you gain the discipline the insight the
wisdom the objectivity the compassion
that comes with growth personal growth
over time that ultimately lends to the
physical result the manifestation the
worldly thing that you're after since
the beginning continue to grow stronger
and remember it all has to do with your
character it takes time done