so I'm out here just wrapping up my
workout for the day right and the
typical scenario happens where a man of
middle age with her body marked by
decades of neglect passes by wants to
peer in and starts going on about what
he used to do how he used to look how
strong he used to be they're not too
many things that pissed me off more than
that bullshit-ass conversation about
what you used to do and then what comes
up next is or but when you get my age
that's when you put the dagger in the
heart of all sensibility you are exactly
where you are because of the choices you
made and you make choices based on who
you are so you never used to anything
you were always now your body may have
been able to withstand neglect abuse
pollution twenty years ago and now you
know the abuse has been decades long
20-30 years long and now you look like
shit but you've always been shit do you
understand see I will never look the way
you look right now and then talk about
used to because I'm not like I am not
currently making choices that will move
me in a direction to look like you look
so that I would have to say what I used
to do and then use the excuse of O age
now of course I sound arrogant that
point is not to sound arrogant my point
is to point out the reality you are the
way you are because you are and have
always been right barring injury due to
accident or acute illness chronic
doesn't count because you created cry
most of the times but if you got hit by
a fucking bus or you caught malaria a
different story your body is just not
going to be strong but 90% of the time
especially
my culture in the good old US of A you
look the way you look because of the
choices you made and you were never what
the figment of your imagination is now
trying to portray for others through
your bullshit conversation someone comes
in with that shit