so our friend Ben is about to get an
athletic scholarship to an Ivy League
school
he has great aspirations of becoming a
computer engineer and he knows that he
could fulfill that vision for himself
through the immense opportunities that
are being afforded to him in a football
scholarship but I'm not sure of a
scholarship or not but he was gonna go
play football for an Ivy League school
that has one of the greatest programs
for him to fulfill his dream of becoming
a computer engineer now he's conflicted
though because he's heard crazy dudes
like Elliott Hulse rant about the ills
of being a part of the economic machine
and finding a way to fulfill your life's
purpose without subjecting yourselves to
the will and whisp
of this machine right anything he wants
to know what to do you know he's torn
now because my ideas sound good
but this is my dream and it's going to
well I make me have to subject myself to
this Elliott what do I do well the very
first thing is ignore me ignore most of
what I say because because I offer you
guys ideas that are simply there to help
you command your own I never offer
anything in in a way that would make me
right or what I say true these are
merely ideas
some have been resourceful for me and
hopefully they can be resourceful for
you now what the way I'd like to
approach this for you in particular is
with a very popular quote it's been said
that this was found in the Bible
somewhere but I couldn't find it that we
are to live in the world but not be of
it and it's been restated in many
different ways by many different people
but anyway this idea of living in the
world but not being of the world
essentially means that we do the things
that the world requires for us to
navigate peacefully as a functioning
part of the community of civilization
but not be personally identified with it
see that's the difference what you do
and I say this all the time what you do
is not nearly as important
as who you are many people their sense
of value their personal identity is
wrapped up in their job it's wrapped up
in what the world has labeled them as in
the position that they've taken in the
world they actually believe they are a
computer engineer what you're doing
computer engineer stuff but you're not
actually a computer engineer you're
actually far more than that I mean
you're you're brilliant on so many
different levels you're so much more
than even the flesh and bones so to do
the things of the world to participate
in the things in the world to reap the
joys and feel the pains that are
associated with being a part of the
world is one thing but being personally
identified with it is a completely other
thing so my invitation to you is to yes
take your football scholarship yes join
the computer engineering program yes
fulfill your goals by subjecting
yourself to the Beautiful Mind you
economic machine we live in right
Elliott Hulse always contradicting
himself this is a pretty damn cool
economic machine where by you can earn a
tremendous living by doing what you like
to do within the constructs that have
been designed by other people who have
created them you can really just rest on
the system a lot of people see the thing
as a lot of people lazily rest on this
system and then personally identify with
it
you on the other hand are just merely
taking advantage of it while also
retaining your search for your true
essence for your core while retaining
your uniqueness without getting lost in
it so my friend enjoy enjoy all the
fruits that this world and our
incredible civilization has to offer
it's like it's never been done before in
the history of mankind we are living in
the greatest of times but also the worst
of times right so take full advantage of
all the beautiful things that
has to offer just don't lose yourself
good luck