I got this question here that sounds a
lot like many questions that I get it
goes a little bit like this I'm 26 years
old I've wasted the past five years at
dead-end jobs and now I want to start my
own business right and everyone start
their own business but I'm afraid I'm
scared I don't have the courage to do it
where do I start so on and so forth just
from reading this gentleman's question I
got a sense that you and then many of
you really don't want your own business
and I'll tell you why your own business
is very similar to the same type of
slavery that you get when you work for
someone else because you're always going
to work for someone else you're always
going to be some sort of a slave to
something what you really want is the
freedom to choose the type of lifestyle
you want to live you want the freedom to
choose what it is you will do see a lot
of guys go into their own business and
of course you know right have
perspective on this not realizing
there's a shit load of stuff that you're
going to have to do that you don't want
to do and it's sometimes I remember
having these conversations with myself
boy I wish I could just go back to a
fucking nine-to-five because you know
what happens when you have a job you
wake up you don't give a shit about
what's going to actually happen unless
you're you know commission-based or
you're a CEO you go you do your job you
show you right off and just get the
fucking thing done and then you go home
you have a beer and you watch TV
I mean sometimes that sounds like a
really good fucking gig especially when
you're up at 6:00 in the morning and
you're scratching your head at emails
that are coming in about people who
didn't receive their products and then
you've got letters from the IRS coming
and then you've got oh you didn't pay
this bill on time and then you've got
all man there's a leak in the roof and
then then all this other shit on top of
that how do I find time to create the
things that I want to create to make my
business better right there's a whole
lot of shit
that people that don't own their own
businesses don't realize you have to
fucking think about and it's not a
nine-to-five it's 24/7 all day every day
long and you just want to start your own
business because it looks so fucking
cool number of things that I would
invite you to do beef
or you embark upon that journey because
you know it's it's a journey also
starting here it's it's been seven years
for me and I'm still learning shit I'm
still patching up shit that doesn't work
and I'm still restructuring things I'm
still having it's it's not as easy as it
looks guys but have you know it's more
than anything it's a form of personal
development because you wherever you are
weak
you've got to strengthen in order for
your business to be strong right and
that might mean hiring the right people
and so on and so forth but anyway that
it's a whole different conversation one
that I should probably talk about on my
non job channel that I haven't made a
video for in several months which I
probably will be again soon decide this
first number one regardless of what it
would take to have this happen just
imagine for a moment just play
make-believe what would I like to wake
up and do every single day if I had a
hundred million dollars what would I
want to do now something constructive
not fucking eat bagels and play video
games and scratch your ass all day what
would I really love to do or you know
what I like talking to people I like
making these videos personally ever my
life revolves around making these videos
I thought you loved it and you know what
I'm gonna be making videos till the day
I die because I just I get a kick out of
this
right what do you just get a kick out of
doing that's the very first thing now
how you're gonna turn it into a business
now how you gonna make money out of it
what do you really get a kick out of
doing and if you can't answer that
question you're fucked you've got to be
able to sense where there is joy and
passion pleasure in your life what do
you get pleasure out of doing and if you
get pleasure out of doing nothing if you
can't answer that then you're going to
be a slave to what you think you should
be doing forever it's got to come from
your body bro what do you really really
really love and what could you do every
single day get in touch with that first
then number two ask yourself what kind
of lifestyle do I want to live do I want
to be able to get up and go wherever I
want whenever I where I want whenever I
want do I want to spend time with my
family do I want a family
see for me I wanted a big family I want
to spend time with my family or do you
want to live in a big city somewhere and
you know hustle and bustle and rubbing
elbows with people and go on a happy
hour right that's a particular type
that's pretty cool to some people well
it doesn't matter what is it that you
you wake up every single day and script
your day this is what a lot of you know
success coaches teaching script your day
now that you know what you love and you
know what your perfect day looks like
then start thinking about monetizing it
because that's true freedom freedom is
living a life that comes from your heart
and doing what you want to do when you
feel like doing it freedom and that's
really what you want you want passion
and you want freedom you don't want your
own business I don't want my own
business there are pieces of this thing
that suck and it taking me a long time
to figure out how it works and every day
I still feel like a slave to certain
things certain parts of it I got emails
I got thousand emails I got to answer I
don't want to do that I wanna make
videos so you got to find you got to
create systems you got to do things to
to leverage that and that's all about
the second half of the equation your
lifestyle do you see
what every man wants is freedom I've
just given you a few tools that I've
used to create some level of freedom
because you know when I'm writing checks
to Obama I really don't feel that free
some level of freedom especially with my
time my time is my most valuable asset
but every man wants freedom every person
wants to be free but freedom is a choice
and it's a demeanor you could be a
streetsweeper and be far more free than
Donald Trump
it's a choice it's how you feel about
the thing that you're doing and that
brings us back to the first part your
heart if you get if you have a sense of
passion in sweeping the street then
you're you're reaching a level of
freedom and a lot of people don't have I
slept that I dreamt that life was joy I
woke and saw that life was duty I acted
and behold Duty was joy done