so today we got a great question from
one of our friends about taking life a
bit more seriously although he fulfills
all his obligations as a student and as
a son his parents and teachers are
concerned that he doesn't take life
seriously enough meaning that because he
is so happy go-lucky he tells jokes and
laughs and he's generally light-hearted
about things that it's going to impede
his ability to become a success in life
and he better start taking things a bit
more seriously if he's ever going to be
somebody yeah this is one that we're
always we're all hosed with this you
know some of us end up having to take
medication because we're just not
serious enough you know and adults and
successful people and they look like
this because they're they're serious
want to teach us the right way you know
if you're going to be a success you had
better carry yourself with the posture
of seriousness and success or at least
that's what they're telling us because
this is the face of winning seriousness
you do it right now let me tell you what
it is put on a serious face what does it
look like right yeah it's all furrowed
it's all contracted right you got to got
to do that because your body is your
mind so the first place to begin is with
your posture get serious brother the
exact opposite opposite of that is
expensive and that's joining pleasure
and there's no room for joy and pleasure
in the world of success because if you
walk around looking like this smiling
laughing telling jokes and being
light-hearted about things you're going
to be a loser right don't I look like a
loser success loser winner loser
interesting let me tell you a quick
story about being serious about shit but
it's a strange one because the posture
of this serious person although it's a
child I'm going to share the story about
and children possess a form of wisdom
that is very untouched their uncarved
blocks so oftentimes by watching
children we get a better
understanding of human nature where let
me get serious about this serious story
about a serious little girl who's my
five-year-old daughter Simone i watch my
children because they teach me shit
about my own nature smells very serious
every single day when she comes home
because she walks in the door drops her
bag jets upstairs grabs plates and cups
puts them in a basket and she's tiny so
it's the funniest thing she's carrying
this thing she's like lugging it down
the stairs she doesn't want anyone to
interrupt her and she goes out into the
backyard where I have a tree house she
climbs up and she starts setting up her
cups and her and her and her on a little
table in their cups in the plates then
she comes down climbs down a ladder and
then she starts collecting all of the
chair cushions in the backyard and
bringing them upstairs and setting up
her house she does this every single day
and then afterwards she takes it down
but she's very serious about engaging in
this building process and she builds it
all out then she there's a long-term
project here right it's not just this is
he cute day-to-day work but long-term
vision she has she has crayons and
markers and she builds murals all over
the walls in this thing right she's
really taking a serious approach to
developing this make-believe home and of
course we call it make-believe because
there's no money involved and you know
the only serious thing in life is money
in paying taxes she doesn't engage in
that so it's all yeah we can laugh at
her the thing is now I'm going to show
you a strange contrast and children do
this all the time I know she's serious
not only by the archer by the the sense
of urgency in her activities but when I
stop to ask her a question about it or
interrupt her in some particular way
because I'm fascinated what she's doing
she goes stop daddy I'm busy leave me
alone
whoa I just back up excuse me sweetheart
I look at my wife and I and she's
serious the strange thing about her
seriousness is that her face looks like
this the whole time and she's bouncing
and she
breathing deeply and she's daddy get out
of my way I'm busy ah and she laughs
very serious the activity what she's
engaging in the actual fulfillment of
the creative process and the
manifestation thereof and she looks like
this Brian Tracy once said in one of the
audio programs I listen to that in poker
just like in life or in life just like
in poker the winners are laughing and
telling jokes while the losers say shut
up and deal that's a strange thing
because a few moments ago I showed you
the face of success and if you look at
most adults who are successful well this
is sort of the way they look their very
contracted hmm this guy's serious this
guy ain't that serious so how is it that
the winners are laughing and telling
jokes and the winners and the losers are
saying shut up and deal now you might
sit there and say well Elliot of course
the winners are winning that's why they
look this way that's why they're
laughing and telling jokes because
they're winning and the losers are
losing so they look like this that's the
easy answer that's the that's the one
that most people will grasp at because
it's like well that's the way we've been
conditioned to believe that our
circumstances create our behavior that
our circumstances dictate our character
that our circumstances control us that
were victims of our circumstances I'm
losing so now I'm getting serious I'm
winning and so now I'm getting happy but
if you've been watching my videos long
enough there are a few concepts that you
need to consider introduced of already
considered number one is that the body
is the mind and that the world is your
mirror and if you carry yourself like
someone who's joyful having fun
pleasure right it's your character it's
who you are how you carry yourself your
posture you posture like oh like a
winner
and the world is your mirror guess what
you're going to get back winning if you
posture yourself like a loser right hmm
guess what you're going to get more
losing and just look at my body and
consider the energy that moves this
world is it expanding is the universe
expanding is the universe winning is it
getting bigger when a seed is planted
what does it do does it contract because
it's serious about growing right you
plant a fucking seed in the in the dirt
is it gonna get serious or is it gonna
experience the joy and pleasure of
growth of winning fruit and guess what
it does is what winning does winning
creates fruits that drive fruits that
create more seeds that keeps praying
spreading winning is expansive ah this
is the look of winning so most adults
have it all backwards they better all
fucked up and they're telling you to
become a success you in order to become
a success you gotta become more serious
and you look at their bodies look at
their faces this is how you know people
this is how you know what's going on
behind the words the associations and
the idols behind the bullshit
is what you see and when you look at
serious people and they tell you about
success and they look like this they're
losing dude you don't want to look
successful because it's an ugly fucking
face and the world is your mirror you're
just gonna get back more ugly shit smile
laugh and tell jokes and your life will
be that much more pleasurable
you see expansiveness is the nature of
abundance and growth plural poke
proliferation joy pleasure all looks
like that I don't care how they choose
to define success if it's a million
dollars if it's a mansion if its power
over millions if they look like this
they're not winning if you have but
little you have but a morsel for your
mouth and a rag for your back and you
look like this you're winning
do you see circumstances again we become
so addicted to what's happening outside
us what we have what we don't have and
the things that are happening here as
opposed to the Creator we are
co-creators in this thing we create our
world in many ways it's 5050 I like to
think but if you're 50% looks like this
then that's what you're going to get
back in many ways by 50% looks like this
you want to know why I'm so successful
why I love my life Wyatt Elliot is so
lucky about being able to do what he
loves because Elliot is having fun the
whole fucking time I don't take any of
this shit too seriously I I see the
significance in it that's very
significant just like my daughter is
very recognizes the significance of
developing our home in that tree house
even more so because I realized that
this is an innate necessity it's an
expression of this of the feminine
energy in her body to want to decorate
the EUC
my son won't do that my son just picks
up swords and wants to stab shit fuck
shit up so it's very significant it's
the exercising of
deep primordial need and desire in her
body
but she looks like this so my friend
I'll end this way
the world is your mirror and your body
is your mind if you give the mirror a
crunched down depressed constricted body
mind you're going to get back just that
those people aren't happy those people
don't experience joy those people may
get shit done and have nice things and
created circumstances but just look at
them and tell me do you want that I
don't want to have anything to do with
that I judge people by the way they look
right Ellie's fucking prejudice I judge
what's happening by what I see little
crazy right don't judge a book by it's
cover I do that shit all the time
I judge books by its cover because I
look for certain things the look in
someone's eye tells you everything about
them I don't care if your face is burnt
I don't care if you don't do an accident
and a part of your face is ripped off
and or you or you got jaw cancer from
you know just the life happening and
your job is off all right if I can look
in your eyes and I see bright vibrance
vitality life expansiveness I judge that
person as happy healthy vibrant vital
and successful just look in their eyes
watch their body language how they
express themselves you see are they
constricted and afraid to express
themselves many of you are attracted to
my videos and you might not know why
oftentimes it's less about what I'm
saying but who I'm being in front of you
you're seeing energy explode in front of
the camera I'm successful I give success
and I get success the world is my mirror
continue to practice joy continue to
practice pleasure continue to laugh and
tell jokes because that's what winners
do
seriousness is a disease significance
joy and pleasure are the driving force
the map and the energy from which you
want to proceed in order to truly live
and enjoy life and be a real success
that shows up in your eyes done