reaches into the real purpose of life
so you're right
[Music]
not bad not bad at all
good grab it and the way you just didn't
stand tall and just stay in the top it's
not bad at all cleaning up a little bit
how much do you Dylan oh I got 375 when
I get I don't know if it's because it's
too heavy and I do this thing we're sort
of use your legs and your back yeah
there you go good keep the bar such that
it is touching you at the top of your
head here and then your butt now just
follow my lead
you're gonna make sure that that stays
the way it is then journeys about 20
degrees yes yep right there good fix
your head remember that house Nick needs
to be okay good now imagine you have a
hinge right here yeah all right keep
your nothing fall keep everything lined
up here I just want you to tip forward
up that hinge stop tuck your chin tuck
your chin in good I need to be able to
get my hand in here I need you to fix
this up again so that you're only
touching it three spots it's now you're
touching here
good feel a difference there you have
that's hop hop fix it I don't want I
won't be able to touch you I want to
take leave good there you go much better
good stay there and now just past your
knees a little bit more good fix this
again good really good you're strong
dude
now SiC your hips yeah just bring it
right down good but look you're not the
same here yeah okay yeah also I have a
hip flexor probably my left side mm-hmm
this way oh so few of my friends when I
squat I can't wait right there I feel
bad anymore especially with heavy weight
I put plates on the bottom of my heels
your down position turn your palms up
yeah yes supinated eyes seek your hips
for that position
I want you to speaker as I make this
really exaggerated like this really
exaggerated I'm not too worried about
your head too much just just make that
really said if you can you might just
not have the flexibility but try alright
remember how this felt when you were
standing up tall and it should feel the
same way here underneath but you watch
the video that I did with Omar a yes so
I think that demonstrated myself in that
video I had to do it for me but
essentially you've got to be able to
maintain that extension in your low back
thoracic extension and cervical
extension the entire time that's like
when you see me dead lifting it's
because I'm maintaining that the entire
time you you're good you're good you
you could boom you lose it at about 45
degrees and it's happening at your low
back hip area take your hip stick your
ass out and I want you to try it now
tuck your chin in make this so that I
can get my hand in in yeah there you go
a little bit more strength a little
better flexibility you think it's your
strength your business right yet but
let's get just a little bit higher if
not you're just going to copy it you're
not going to do that those from the
floor anymore then you're gonna need to
just reverse
you all will take your shirt off
you almost look like you guys yeah this
is a restaurant
look straight ahead yeah it almost look
like you're more built up over here you
are built up over here tonight yeah you
must much more muscular Stern here and
over here your body works in in swings
look good achoo yeah very good your body
works in like it's called a serape
offenders where it crosses these work
together this glue this latch you get
your money
you do have a lot and this girl's my
lips I can always get a few more and my
left arm is about what you have I've got
almost resting so I'm looking at you
well screwed up what I have to do in
order to maintain his balance
oh geez we never got it done but
basically a great situation with your
nervous system distributes energy the
nervous energy throughout the muscle
injury even on the left the right side
and it's out of this chicken everyday--
situation but because of the
overdevelopment switcher on this side
which is crossing around you could knock
your atlas out that will just further
facilitate the imbalance because now
the nervous system is now acting weird
for your nervous system was acting weird
and created the muscular balance and
this is very easy to pass not that you
watched any of my videos we're talking
about that it's Allison okay so
Visionnaire don't be so fast
no no no idea if it's something like
that like if I define messed up but then
that's when I'm going heavy I for about
two or three days after right like when
you said to the left of the spine
because we're for a while if I like
what's my little bit my lower back
because that's the one that's working
yeah the other side's not working the
other side is dormant while what sighs
with other works of course it gets
painful and then you're creating torsion
then you've got one side of the
musculature working the other side not
you literally twist and you're twist
see so I would have my atlas
but I mean but in the meantime we can
work to help create extension especially
in your lumbar spine that helped bring
it down let's try it again you're going
to have to do more of what are like rack
pulls or yeah I wouldn't bother going
down very low until I had this checked
and then I'll give you some isolation
exercises that you need definitely needs
to strengthen especially the plank above
right here yeah right in there up here
is more like your lower left good and
this is your new favorite exercise okay
stop probably start with 25 and get a
friend to take leave okay you should be
able to get his hands in through that
spot put that down you should be able to
always get his hands
right you should be able to do the
holdup and maintain them
but you get a friend that can spot you
and go halfway through the deadlift hold
that build up to 30 seconds a minute if
you can and then you will be able to
lower yourself with that of extension as
well as technology so that's why we have
the dowels and yeah that's all you can
see right away you lean over your hand
was literally average is further down we
have a boy in the room you don't have to
bring you know
pretty messed up Matt I don't know if
that's causing this but you might break
really close together yeah they're
they're trying to make up for the
liability right here wherever there's a
lack of mobility you're going to find it
those flex more there is excessive
mobility so you're really resting on
these two vertebrae that you're having
there's a lot of work to do before you
number one is atlas and find the
neuromuscular therapist that will do
soft tissue work on you literally saw to
do some soft tissue and then find nearby
these guys know about exercise you know
that's why these aren't sexy ideas this
is like you sometimes up say shit like
this on YouTube you'd like you just
fuckin on you Atlas neuromuscular
therapy and corrective exercise