we got this question here from our buddy
who says he takes really good care of
himself he eats extremely well he
exercises three or four times a week or
actually four or five times a week I'm
sorry he's in pretty good shape
but he can't seem to shake the old habit
of grabbing a cigarette a few drinks and
gambling on the weekends when aimday
says to himself look I do the right
thing five days out of the week when the
weekend comes I can't seem to shake this
there a few times right I skip it for a
week or two weeks but then I just go
right back look la what's going on here
I seem to have my shit together but I
can't seem to shake these bad habits
having a drink of cigarette and playing
cards with the boys whatever the case
may be
you know I'm going to quote Alan Watts
in this video this is this is a
beautiful thing that Alan Watts talks
about and if you're not familiar with
Alan Watts he talks about the the
philosophies of the east and he has a
fantastic way of sharing these ideas cuz
yes such win and there's one element of
becoming whole or becoming the strongest
version yourself through the eastern
philosophy and the way he describes it
is as such that every master always
seems to have an element of irreducible
rascality that's what he calls it and he
says you'll watch and it's very zen-like
and if you're familiar with it with the
zen and the art of Zen and how it comes
about it's very much where if something
is too perfect it's nasty it's like oh
it's too but it's just not nice so a lot
of like Asian art will be like
everything is perfect except the thing
will be slightly cracked it will be like
a little light be like a nice Vaz but
will be slightly cracked or the painting
will be great but it'll be slightly like
a sloppy or the garden will be beautiful
but there'll be leaves in a certain
place it and it's those leaves it's a
crack and it's too strange swipes on the
on the piece of art that actually make
it beautiful and this is like this is
just a but overreaching philosophy this
is like a principle of the philosophy
and
the men who or sought as sought for his
master's also - they would present
themselves with great wisdom and and and
Wonder and they're great guys but
they're always smoking a pipe or they uh
they've got a bad temper and guys
brilliant he's wonderful
when he begins speaking he does
everything right but he's got a bad
temper every once in a while or always
gonna addiction - women like the guys
great man is he's healthy he's strong
he's smart he really but he's got that
man he just he loves women and he would
call this the element of irreducible
rascality because it's irreducible it's
a part of the construct for you to be
whole there has to be a whole do you
understand I hope you I hope you can see
that that element makes the thing
beautiful because it makes it human it
makes it natural a lot of the ideas and
art and philosophy of the east comes
from just studying nature and nowhere in
nature are there straight lines mankind
loves straight lines we've created
straight lines wherever you see straight
lines or grids it's because mankind is
using their linear thinking to create it
Lena here you guys would give me a hard
time that last video I said linear
listen I got it I got accent so nothing
in nature is linear if you look at trees
they're they do this if you do if you
look at anything in nature there's
always these elements of imperfection
and the philosophy of sin and many of
the possibilities of the East come out
of imitating nature in that this tree is
perfect but it's got this weird nodule
on it this pot is perfect but it's got
this weird crack in it and it's just
that nodule in nature imitated in the
art that makes the art freakin beautiful
and it extends itself into the way the
person carries himself in life and if
you my friend are doing things there's
something called the 80/20 rule the
Pareto principle if you're doing things
80 percent right 80 percent of the time
you're eating the
well the way you're supposed to eat
right maybe let's say when it comes to
diet you're always eating the way you're
supposed to eat you're exercising as you
should you meditate as you should you
are an advancing man becoming the
strongest version yourself in every way
that you deem necessary for you but come
Friday night I'm having a smoke and I'm
drinking some beers I'm gonna play cards
with my friends do it it's your
responsibility to do it to be completely
whole in this particular in this
particular philosophy so that's it my
man bust your ass go hard do the thing
with all your might but everyone's not
even every once in a while you owe it to
yourself to have that element of
irreducible rascality done