got a question from one of our friends
who hates himself I was 23 years old and
he says that basically he's got
everything that a 23 year old would one
he just graduated college is looking for
a job he's got a good-looking body he's
got his own apartment things seemed to
be alright on the outside but he's so
much in his fucking head that he can't
get over the story about why he's not
good enough and it's sort of screwed up
his his social life and the reason why
he hates himself is cuz he can't make
friends he can't date women he can't do
the things that a normal 23 year old kid
who has everything that they should have
you can't live a life that that's
indicative of it so he hates himself and
I told you get it you know it's not kind
of like a stupid little depression it's
the fact the fact is that you just are
not content with yourself you're upset
with yourself and the more that you do
the things that make you upset with
yourself the more you become upset with
yourself and then you become upset with
yourself without being upset with
yourself and then it's just say a dirty
nasty spiral down to the depths of
depression and maybe maybe you never
come out of it so the thing you need to
do so the very first thing is you've got
to understand that you can't solve this
problem at the level by which it has
been created in your fucking head
you're too much in your head and you
even said that so thank you yeah I'm Way
up in my head I can't even talk to
people's I'm Way up in my head I can't
do things since I'm always up in my head
I'm always up in my head you've got to
get out of your head and when I say you
it's really your vital energies you're
spending way too much time up here
thinking and shit you need to get into
your body so the shit that I share with
you guys might seem like fun and
interesting and weird Elliot health
stuff where he just kind of shapes and
vibrates and acts crazy huh
entertainment well you know maybe
there's a little entertainment factor
there but the fact is that that is
therapy for becoming a stronger version
of yourself so that you can get into
your body you can get into your heart
you can get into your balls and out of
that slave master that you're using to
shackle down the full expression of the
beauty within you
we're all fucking amazing will you all
have great capacities for living a
joyful pleasure full of life but if you
spend too much time in the one area of
your body that cannot really express
anything you could only chatter then
you're never going to experience life
life is experience in your body so the
very first thing I would like you to do
is turn on some of your favorite fucking
music and dance like a maniac
it might sound real strange or you know
sixties smoking pot type shit but I
promise you you turn on your favorite
music music that just gets you I don't
get too excited but music that gets you
fucking excited hardcore rap music or
heavy metal or the Beatles it does not
fucking matter you turn that music on
and you let go everything you have into
that song it's better if you know the
words of the song - cuz you can sing and
you can get excited go crazy with it get
your body moving and you'll take all the
energy that's up in your fucking head
and bring it down into your balls bro
shake it out jump scream ah turn happy
music turn on angry music turn on all
the music that elicits all of the
emotional responses in your body cry
laughs scream what you're doing is
you're bringing your body your energy
back down into your body into the primal
roots of your existence and then you'll
be free to breathe into your balls where
you'll access your true vital energies
all your vital energies boyar or your
sexual energy comes up from the bottom
of your belly and if you're holding that
tight because you're always thinking and
you're not in your body then you will
never be able to reach your full
potential you always hate yourself who
is this self that you're hating you're
heating a fact you're heating it you
know what
know yourself you're hitting a behavior
that you're doing you're eating the fact
that you can't get it to your body and
inviting you to get into your fucking
body
that's the therapy turn on music and go
crazy go nuts
then breathe do that once a day find
some time to do that then start
experimenting in public with expressing
yourself any way you feel fit as long as
it's not against the law do weird shit
go out it go to the mall and just start
jumping and screaming and making loud
noise uh-huh if there's music on even
better go to like one of these clothing
stores I know that these clothing stores
in the music's like I got a fucking club
just start dancing in the club just
start dancing in the in the store you
got to do stuff that completely
contradicts that which the slave master
has conditions you with you got to do
stuff
completely opposite you got to be like
opposite George and sign so you got to
do the opposite of what you've always
done if you see a girl that you want to
talk to but you're scared to talk to her
you must talk to her
you must express yourself you must get
out of your head get into your body get
into the roots of your existence if you
look at the nervous system it looks like
there's a flower with roots the flower
dies it goes against itself if the roots
aren't watered well get down into the
roots of your body your peripheral
nervous system breathe dance yell scream
laugh cry hug people
Thoros hugging people you mean do some
shit like that like when you meet people
for the first time and you know it's all
awkward because everybody's up in their
head and they're still like scared and
they're not show off they wonder how you
doing how is it buddy
I guarantee you'll feel so much fucking
better it'll be awkward for both of you
will not for you because you'll get over
it and you've been happy energetic
loving caring creative awesome human
being that should we actually really are
you just getting over your bullshit and
then you'll open that person up when you
open up your energy you open up other
people's and
and people are gonna love to be around
you dude she'll be so much fun because
there'll be a dancing around you and
people will join you in your dance piece