hey what's up ladies and gentlemen
Elliot halls here once again today I'm
downtown taking a walk downtown downtown
st. Petersburg cuz I just got back from
the dentist come on T thought me see
that or check that out hi you might also
notice i had my silver fillings removed
during my hiatus from youtube as in
dental work done i take dental work
pretty seriously mainly because my
father grew up in Billy parents lead
third world country third world
conditions man my dad would always talk
about how you didn't take care of your
teeth like the people in this country
we're basically there was no it wasn't a
lot of dental care and even if you could
afford it you were in a minority so he
grew without dental care and he
remembers seeing adults even himself as
a kid growing up teeth would go bad
teeth will rot gums will go bad and and
when your teeth go bad your mouth starts
to rot your whole body begins to rot
people don't think about it that way but
your mouth is the gateway to your
digestive system and your digestive
system is key to your immunity right
from the Rooter to the tooter you got to
take care of people think you know your
digestive system is just your belly in
your gut you know we started thinking
about our intestines recently in regard
to the bacterial content and probiotics
and the immune system but everything
from your mouth to you what hole your
anus your the health of your rectum is
linked to your prostate health your your
rectum is right there by your prostate
so my point is that we take for granted
what health really is but we leave
certain things in the shadow like our
mouths and our rectums those are those
are key gateways to our help right we
can't ignore it a lot of noise down here
today
if you look around you can tell them in
a different part of town right now it is
a little different than where you saw me
walking yesterday yesterday I was out by
my office today I'm downtown where I
like to walk when I'm just gonna go
meditate or I'm gonna do my daily walk
when I was doing my daily walk I would
come down here and as you can see why
it's fucking beautiful apparently
there's a fire so hot he's coming our
way sirens that's one thing you could
expect when you live in society right we
live in civilization we live in society
I'm going I'm going to keep walking down
here by the Salvador Dali Museum you
guys not familiar with the art of
Salvador Dali go check it out the guy
was eccentric anyway so we're talking
about the health of the mouth we're
talking about how it links to your to
your digestive health and how if you
have a nasty mouth with has a nasty look
dudes like don't take it personally the
fact is that nastiness means that you
don't brush regularly you don't floss
regularly you don't get regular
cleanings and checkups and you got food
from last week stuck between your teeth
and if you ever floss go like a week or
two without flossing and then floss and
then you put those little strings
through your teeth the smell that comes
out is like putra fication it's nasty so
yes it stinks you have a nasty mouth and
it makes you sick if you have a nasty
mouth so those you guys suffering with
health or if you're not a great making
gains you want to make it right think
about it you might not think about this
people don't think about this work
you're not getting the gains that you
want in the gym the healthier mouth
could be extrinsically link to that your
digestive system is compromised the food
that you're eating is not being digested
properly you've got overgrowth of
bacteria in your gut because your mouth
is full of muck so I think I've made my
point today take care of your teeth kids
take care of your mouth
another thing I wanted to talk to you
guys today about is I got a question
here from one of our friends he sent me
a facebook question or YouTube question
and in the question he he kind of
relates to some of the things I've been
talking about our I spoke about a few
weeks ago regard to dress and how when I
first moved down to Florida I shit much
less having money for getting my teeth
fixed I never got my teeth and taken
care of when I first moved down here it
took me about five six years before I
had enough money to go to get make sure
my teeth were taken care of what my
father kept reminding me he said when
you get a little bit of money the first
thing you do is go get your toothpicks
go get your teeth taken care of take
care of your mouth so as soon as I got a
little bit of money instead of spending
it on closing cars I'm spent it on my
help like I tell you guys all the time I
take good care of my health so I spent
my money on on getting my teeth fixed it
might be clean taking care of health is
a priority health is a core value I make
health rituals a part of my day part of
my lifestyle but anyway our friend
relates to what I spoke about a couple
days ago with regard to you know not
spending on clothing when you when you
when you're serious about your core
values when you're hard corn your
mission and when you're doing your thing
you got to take care of your health and
got to take care of your mission my
family is my mission my health is my
mission my work in my mission but at the
same time you got to remember we do live
in society look and I and our brother
look at all these people look at all
these things look at all the nice things
civilization has to bring us so we do
want to live here and our friend who
sends a question and about going cheap
on his clothes and wearing bummy ass
clothing he says the I recently I've
been wearing real bummy closing knocking
clothing and not really giving a fuck
he's in college man is beautiful he's in
college and he's getting ready to go to
grad school I believe for neuroscience
so he's a pretty brilliant dude he's a
smart dude look how beautiful that is
apparently they're doing some kind of
event here behind me I can't walk that
way but that's the direction of his son
so I'm just going to stay in here and
talk to you I don't want to here's the
thing i got my stick if i reach it over
the water i'm scared of my fall into the
water so he says yeah I go pretty nasty
on my clothing because I realized it's
not a major core value of mine I really
you know it's not something I care much
about especially since I'm college I'm
starting to go to grad school so fuck it
but then he realizes that people are not
treating him right and somebody says
he's like I wear baggy sweatpants and
whatnot but people are you know not
giving me the respect that I think I'm
do women are not paying attention to me
do is no respect me the way you know a
neuroscientist should be respected so
he's like yo how do i reconcile that how
do i reconcile you know realizing that
fashion clothing is not a core value of
mine but still get the respect and
admiration love that I deserve for being
an awesome dude so you know I stand here
in the downtown area of a nice small
city where I live and it reminds me that
we're not alone it reminds me that there
were people that got here before I got
here it reminds me that all this beauty
all the nice things that civilization
can afford iPhones right that I'm
talking to you on this the paved streets
the cars the building's the boats that
are on the other side of the camera they
all come from other people right so the
attitude that I don't care what anybody
thinks I don't care what anybody says I
don't care what anybody does it's great
for protecting yourself from when you
should be protecting yourself you know
there are times when you've got is you
got to be a staunch self-reliance
libertarian you got to see things fit
for yourself and you got to do what's
right for you and your mission but at
the same time we've got to balance that
with the fact that we've chosen this day
age time in place it's my conviction we
choose our circumstances by which you
become born into circumstances that we
show up in this stuff is life with you
chose to show up in civilization that
means you're going to have to play by
some of the rules and if you choose not
to play by the rules you're just going
to simply pay the price and if you want
to have the luxury of people looking at
you a certain way you know with
admiration and respect you gotta dress
respectfully that's really that's really
the long and short of it and now it
sounds shallow because it is but people
can't see your depths people can't see
how beautiful you are people can't see
the your heart on the outside all they
can see is your eye out you're outside
and you got to respect that unless
someone is sensitive enough to feel your
vibrations which most of us are not to
feel your goodness to sense your dignity
the sense your self-esteem rather than
see it on your clothes or see it on your
face unless that was the case what kind
of trapped our outside sends vibrations
into the insides of other people people
judge you you will be judged by the
clothing that you wear like a part of
successful living also is uh deciding
what kind of judgments were willing to
accept right people when people judge me
when I was 250 pounds with a mohawk and
wore nothing but black strengthcamp
t-shirts and carried a scowl on my face
ten years ago when I was being that
person and people judged me accordingly
I had to be all right with it I had to
be like yes I get it I know I can't go
into this building I can't attend this
function I can't speak to these people
because they're gonna have a hard time
receiving me the way I look but I was
okay with it you see you got to be okay
with it you're dressing like a fucking
bum and you okay with it and that's fine
Hey look if you got a nasty mouth full
of rotten teeth and you okay with it
then that's fine that's really the only
question that matters to be completely
honest these videos are actually like
kind of stream of consciousness rants so
am i contradict myself or talking
circles but it's really just me thinking
out loud so dealing with other people
and civilization means dealing with
people in the peripheral level dealing
with people on your on your outside
because that's really where you show up
and that's really where you receive
people you regardless of how righteous
you are in your judgments of people or
you believe you're gonna judge people by
the way they look you do it I do it
human beings do it it's a survival
mechanism we did it so that we could
judge whether or not a person place or
circumstance is safe for us so you got
it you have to be with that be all right
with that and then you gotta check it in
yourself to you got recognized like you
are judging your judging machine I am a
judgment machine we're a judgment
mechanism so recognize when judgments or
snap judgments based on past experiences
and prejudice or or is it a deep sense
judgment of someone right I don't like
this person like I spoke about yesterday
some people who had the judgment I just
don't he irks me hurts my feelings when
I see him and that requires that we take
a look at our self
it's always about ourselves so my man I
don't know if this video's have any of
any help I enjoy making these videos I
don't know if that's of any help my man
I'm gonna walk this because the Sun is
this way what let me wrap it up this way
when I'm walking with my camera my silly
snick here thoughts aren't as
concentrated is when i'm in the office
or the gym just still wrap with your
camera so hope you guys don't mind let
me see if i can wrap it up for you this
way bro you're going to dress like a bum
that's okay as long as you're okay with
that other people are going to judge you
based on the way you judge the by the
way you wear your dress and you got to
be okay with the way they're judging you
because they're going to do it if you
want to get a different response from
the people you might have to ask
yourself what can I do to get in
accordance with what their expectations
of you are and am I willing to take that
step am I willing to be what they want
me to be in order to get what I want
sometimes requires a tremendous amount
of humility to get what you want you
might have to quote unquote sell out
right what does that actually mean hmm
you know that word sellout is funny
because you're wearing a uniform to go
to your job at the supermarket are you a
sell out cuz you're wearing a uniform
that the mad spected you to wear right
all you guys who like to talk about
people who sold out because maybe they
got on a different uniform maybe they're
thinking different thoughts maybe
they're doing different things well hey
when you get that new job at the office
right you got to put on a suit and tie
did you just sell out right you would
like to wear your shorts with the holes
in it and your and your favorite
baseball team t-shirt but now you gotta
put on the tie are you a cell up that's
all about how you look at it it's all
about your the way you choose to wait
you should again so you can sell out
right you can call this out people tell
me I'm still outlook because I'm not
wearing a strength camp camo t-shirt in
the world I still have my trunk and camo
legend I sleep in them I got on I got on
kitty shirts I like fucking kitty shirts
that people judge me well my kitty
shirts and my short shorts like we're
short shorts and kitty shirts and people
judge yellow judging me right now people
watching the video you could walk
watching me to shrink a judge but I
don't really care
we need each other I learned to respect
each other and through manners dress and
good Brett we allow people to receive
our best energy by showing up in a way
its digestive or then
[Music]