we got this question here from our buddy
Dan he's got really poor self-discipline
and it's it's really creeping into all
areas of his life so bad that even if he
has an important meeting to go to or a
class to get to
he won't get up in the morning right I
mean that is simple as just having the
discipline to get his ass up in the
morning it's it's difficult for him he
says that he's tried you know this is
something that it is bothering him he
just hasn't found a way to get over
himself
because that's really what it is in
order to do the things that are
associated with the life that he wants
to create for himself how does he build
self-discipline the very first thing I
would ask you to do and I'm gonna give
you multiple different steps here is to
get very clear and what you want in your
life if you don't have something to
strive towards if you don't have an
ideal to reach for then there really is
no reason to get up in the morning right
I mean most people go through their
lives just to get to the next day right
and if that's the case if it's just to
get up so that you can play video games
or or eat peanut butter and jelly
sandwiches or whatever the hell it is
that most people do with their lives
then you're going to have very much
motivation you want to create a
situation where there is something so
extraordinary that you want to achieve
in your life on the far end of things
the big picture that you can't stay in
bed I'm excited to get my ass out of bed
every single day I get up and I can't
wait to get things going and it has to
do with the fact that I've got a big
vision I've got a big picture create a
big picture for yourself right getting
up and going to school is irritating to
you but you see it as a step towards a
bigger picture that which would be the
ideal life for you create something
extraordinary that's the other thing
create an extraordinary vision for
yourself right don't let anybody tell
you what you can and cannot achieve
create something huge
no matter how ridiculous it is because
it's going to get you up every single
day and when you get up you're now going
to start practicing the strengthening of
your will power spoken about this in
other videos but you begin with one
thing a tiny win get up every morning
don't worry about making breakfast don't
worry about
whether there's gas in your car don't
worry about don't worry about all the
different things associated with what it
would take to be a successful person
just begin with one thing just build the
willpower build the character associated
with doing one freakin thing
set your alarm clock five o'clock or six
o'clock whatever time you get up
shouldn't be getting up any later than
that
and get your ass out of bed no matter
what it takes even if you're sick and
you got snot dripping down your chin get
your ass up
blow your nose brush your teeth and if
you're going back to bed cuz you're sick
go back to bed but make that a habit
every single day right so now you've got
two things you've got a huge carrot at
the end of the stick that's drawing you
towards a big vision that you can't help
yourself but to be excited about
achieving every single day of your life
that's huge and the second thing is
you're building the methodology by which
you will become successful which
requires structure getting up every
single day be like a machine
pretend you're a machine sometimes when
we you know you put on a Superman cape
you feel like frickin Superman pretend
you're a machine pretend you're a robot
and when the alarm clock goes off you
get up no matter what it doesn't matter
you're just a machine isn't about what
you feel like at that moment right
listen Elliot host contradict himself
you want to be very feeling but you also
want to be very realistic and a reality
principle dictates that if you structure
your life you create discipline you use
willpower to create virtues associated
with big pictures and ideals for your
life you're going to be a successful
person they're said so begin with that
why are you getting up and then build
the willpower associated with getting up
every single day everything else don't
matter I don't care what else you do
with the rest of your day
because it's not going to matter what
you do is not nearly as important so
you're becoming through that practice of
getting your ass up once you build that
discipline I guarantee you'll take it
into other areas hmm I've got a
self-esteem and the verge
you of Discipline I can extend that into
other areas of my life you're going to
have better relationships you're going
to make more money hell you might even
start brushing your teeth more and have
better breath who knows you know I don't
know that's it good luck