got another question from one of our
buddies who's 24 years old right around
that particular age where you're kind of
kicked in your ass to become a man I
usually say 23 but anywhere between 21
and 25 there's this call to action call
to adventure if you will if you study
the hero's journey that happens I think
at around 14 and then again around 24 23
but anyway the story is very typical my
man and you know who you are you're your
initials are B D he knows who he is and
I don't want to make light of your
situation and not have you feel as if it
is potent and important because I know
it is it's very important to you thing
is that it's out it reads just like so
many other that I've read long story
short he broked broke his wrists he
healed so he said he stopped going to
the gym when he broke his wrist so you
know that's out the question and slowly
over the past year or so he's been
losing friends his girlfriend just
dumped him two weeks ago he you know
every situation is bad schools bad works
bad the whole fucking world is crumbling
down on you what do I do
well I'm gonna give you you know how
many of you same advice that I've given
multiple people through this these
videos and I think the reason why I keep
answering the same fucking questions is
because of just how critically important
it is to get this message through all of
your minds to where every man or
becoming man's mind that there comes a
point when you've got to throw yourself
off the cliff and learn how to fly not
so much for what you're going to get
when you risk yourself in that
particular way and of course I'm using
metaphors bear with me not because of
what you're going to get but because who
you're going to become when Eagles are
teaching their babies how to fly as I've
learned this from watching National
Geographic when the momma Eagle teaching
her baby on a fly what she does is she
pushes the the bird off of the out of
the nest
and the bird just
it's plummets plummets plummets plummets
until it like you know the wind kind of
catches under the under the wings and if
it's lucky enough it starts flying and
the momma bird comes down and like they
fly together if the wings don't open up
the babies sit means you just weren't
you're just not ready to survive in this
fucking world right you know the nature
of man isn't very different if you can't
figure it out you're kind of just
wasting oxygen and space here I think is
gonna have to come back and do it all
over again eventually you have to learn
how to fucking fly but we all we all end
up in these situations where the world
has made it so cozy for us that we never
have to become a man in it we never have
to become an eagle that can fly right
because if the mama just starts giving
you the mama the mama Eagle says you can
stay in the nest and not you know I'll
keep bringing you food even though
you're growing you're getting bigger and
bigger
you're becoming a physical man of an
eagle but the model is gonna keep
feeding but then there's no need for you
to to go and learn how to kind of how to
fly you don't develop the wings of
virtue that a man needs in order to be
self-sustaining self-reliant in the
world and in the same way I wanted to
make this point the same way that the
mama kicks the bird out of the out of
the bush out of the nest it's not
because the bird needs to feed itself
it's not because the bird needs to learn
how to build nest it's not for the bird
to be stable and safe in the world she
pushes the bird out so the bird becomes
something else the bird goes from being
a little you know impotent thing to
something that can sustain itself it can
take care of itself
it's not about the thing that the birds
becoming that the Eagles becoming it's
about who the bird is becoming right
instead about what the bird gets the
bird gets a good fucking job or a degree
a good-looking girlfriend a nice car at
a nice neighborhood the fuck and none of
that matters of course birds don't give
a shit about that stuff but it's not
about the worms at the birds gonna eat
through out the fact that now this
the bird has wings so Mama's good I
probably could die right now if the
burgers could fly how many 24 year olds
live at home with their parents I
empathize with you because I know that
it's not your fault no one's posed a lot
of these ideas so you know and share
these ideas with you but I do grow angry
I feel ill towards you because it's it's
it's a perversion
it's disgusting you're fucking man all
right and you're all depressed now
because you haven't exerted yourself
like a man you get all the things you
fucking need but the world crumbles down
around you because a part of you knows
that this is a fucking sham it's a big
show Hindus call it the Maya and we're
very personally attached to it and
you've you're attached to this show and
you have no wings you have no tools to
stand on your own two feet then you know
you're a loser and you're and you're
sensing that that's why about this age
you start realizing like am I going to
be a loser and deny myself in my heart
the growth that it's it's necessary for
my personal evolution for me to become
the strongest version of myself or am I
going to pretend like that shit ain't
there I'm just gonna get a job I'm gonna
do what I'm told
but that catches up with you eventually
they call that midlife crisis so you're
having a crisis right now that if you
don't deal with you'll be 50 the only
problem is when you're 50 you're weaker
you're less courageous because you got
25 years of fake stability under your
belt right that's all the Wall Street
crashes right until until the housing
market crashes oh shit is gonna catch up
with you anyway no wonder it happened to
this generation at this particular time
that generation that lost all its
savings in in the stock market no eight
you're not gonna like me saying there's
some you older guys with you're a bunch
of fucking pussies the bank's raised you
and then was taken away and you're all
cried and so many people committed
suicide during the crash of oh eight
because you built your castle with sand
I'm teaching that building on a bedrock
and that means your character comes
before your stability comes before what
you gain in life what you get and you my
friend if you want to get out of this
depression just think about this do you
think that bird dropping from its nest
towards the ground plummeting at a fast
rate has time for depression no there's
no time for depression there's only time
to figure this shit out and grow some
wings you need to jump off of a cliff
you need to create your own
circumstances I don't know what it is
I've given you guys different examples
of things that I these are just my
examples but there's so many of them go
and be a mercenary of some sort I don't
fucking know go to Haiti go to the
poorest country in the world and and and
and work to help children there or put
food in people's mouths or construct
buildings right of course you might get
killed somebody might come with a
machete and take your fucking head but
that's an experience that's life yeah
that's life's not trying to be so
fucking safe all the time go out there
and do something dangerous that forces
you to become a grown man you can't
think about it you can't read books
about it you can't listen to me all
fucking day about it you got to go and
do something I don't know what it is
maybe your heart knows what it is and
you just need to get in touch with that
but go and fucking do it and you'll have
no time for depression only growth done