hey I'm making this video as a part two
to the my girlfriends orgasm face video
that you probably just watched maybe
yesterday as i finish that video i
wanted to further elaborate on what it
means to recognize negative thoughts and
when they're attacking you and how to
turn away from them one of the things
that i fail to mention in that video is
that you will know if automatic negative
thoughts like watching your girlfriend
getting boned in your head watching are
getting boned by another dude is
happening or if it to know if it's
affecting you because you're going to
feel it in your body you're going to
feel it in your physiology you will know
immediately that you are being affected
netic negatively by a thought by how you
breathe i want you to recognize this so
although it is the abstract thought is
coming and you turn away from it it's
very difficult sometimes to know if you
are actually entertaining it or not you
know because a lot of times what we
resist persists so it's the fact that
you're trying to push the thought away
you're actually engaging with the
thought right to really cut off means
that you don't feel it in your
physiology when that idea when that
negative thought no matter what it is
because we have them you know the orgasm
face one is just one example but we have
them in all types of you know all areas
of our lives you know I remember dealing
with this big time when i first started
my business and I just the idea that I
will always be broke was it would come
into my mind that my family would fall
apart my wife would leave me because I
don't have enough to provide these types
of ideas came to bite in my head we all
get them they all come especially when
were you know we're trying to do big
things we're trying to move on with our
life these automatic negative thoughts
some people would say that it's like
demons or like the devil is talking to
you come you will know that you're free
from the automatic negative thoughts
from the negative visualization when you
are breathing softly when you are not
affected physiologically when your belly
is relaxed when your chest is relaxed
when your jaw and face is relaxed you
know I I didn't bring it up because I
spend so much time talking about body
cycle
gian and bioenergetics and things of
that nature but I really think it was
important for me to to bring this up
again and to let you know that there is
a physiological and neuromuscular
response to negative thoughts you will
know that it's happening because you
will feel it in your body I'd like you
all to become that much more sensitive
and familiar with how your body out your
physiology how your posture how your
neuromuscular system your breathing is
affected by negative thoughts don't
entertain them don't fight them don't
wrestle with them right don't analyze
them don't try to give your try to fight
them with rationalization ignore them
completely and you know that's happening
because you will feel yourself breathing
deep you will feel soft in your muscular
system you will feel relaxed you will
feel at peace a lot of times I think
people when I say things like you know
don't entertain negative thoughts people
then decide to rationalize themselves
out of the negative thought the problem
is that the conscious mind the ego right
the ego is creating the negative thought
and then you're also trying to use the
ego to fight the negative thought you
can't I signed I think said once that
you can't solve a problem from the level
from which it it's created you can't
solve a problem from the place that it
was created right with the same
technique that it was created the
technique that's causing you problems is
your mind creating automatic negative
thoughts for you to wrestle with it on
that same level is not going to work you
literally have to turn away you
literally have to shut it out ignore it
completely like it's not there you will
know that's happening when your body
feels good good luck