that's why I made my videos that maybe
that's what it was when i started my
straight up like I someone I got a big
mouth don't tell everybody everything I
know free I'm sorry logical if you
follow your heart first that's right
it's all you are first and then bring
your brain along which I've been doing
this is like since I was a cinematic and
like this you know I'm doing this stuff
oh la isn't it just ways to monetize it
I think one of the problems is with
people who have obscure passion and I
say it was coo or simply because they're
not the traditional path of
professionals right not to be a fucking
accountant right you knows it I
listening this is on you and you know
what you should be able to do this to
rest your life you should be 60 and
teaching people how to climb on
buildings or whatever it is that his
druggy off is drawing your heart this is
like a lesson yup seems to work required
that be like mom coming sideline 95 to
look back
oh my god Sam point now where r is ethyl
know what they do they make a lot of
money doing shit they don't want to do
and then they sew Oh with all that money
you can't do shit there what I do the
beginner yeah I don't we got a little
bit of time you can get yourself you
killed parts of yours your soul guys you
know when your soul died so now that you
have a money you don't even have the
vitality it's got your ring driver fun
things you're reaching your soul or yeah
that's been my dream since the bag get
him Presley the owner Burton crazy that
my buddy you know when I got that guy
you're so generous he's so wealthy what
he's so happy because he's so generous
yeah you know saying that's what it is
if you could be a conduit or well
especially through your heart you is not
about enriching yourself it's about
bringing well to the world you know and
the first people I think about is is
alright but really thanks bye by putting
yourself out there and serving the world
through your heart your enriching
hundreds of thousands of people with
ideas with inspiration motivation you're
changing people's lives the fact that
you started this idea we've put it on
internet
Corner processors spreading across the
world to the Internet you're lighting
fires individual fires in the hearts and
minds of millions of people that will
alter the trajectory of their lives
their children's lives and great
grandchildren's on to something that's
the power fucking ideas as a power
internet to get out there is nice
nothing is ours so it's up to us to be a
condom spit it out there watch it grow
like wildfire you enrich the world like
that you'll be enriched