that are really interesting and
sensitive question from our buddy
beyond spectrum he's 26 years old he's
been dating a woman that's 34 years old
right the problem is that she was raped
several years ago this is before they
started their relationship and ever
since they've been together he loves her
with all of his heart I mean the the
depth of conviction for his love that I
received through reading this message is
significant you really love this woman
but for two years that they've been
together they've never had sex they
never had intercourse because of the
trauma associated with the pain of her
experience of getting raped several
years ago so we're in a situation now
where she is so physically tense and
rigid that even approaching the the area
of the physical area of sex or the topic
of sex brings up tears that she
immediately stuffs back down or leaves
the room in order to clear about our
friend the on spectrum is not only at a
loss because he wants to
obviously commence forth with the the
act of making love to this woman but
because of his care for her he wants to
see her heal and he knows that the
situation is dysfunctional it'll only
grow more dysfunctional if it is not
dealt with she wants help he wants to
help her what do you do so I'm not going
to approach this from a I'm gonna
approach this as a I'm going to point
you in a direction right because this is
really sensitive this is stuff that
therapists would work with you on and
I'm going to point you in some really
good directions the type of therapy that
I think would be very resourceful to you
I often talk about bioenergetics and
basically how the body takes on the
physical manifestations of the
psychological character be a trauma or
chronic behavior patterns in the body
you'll notice and you may or may not
notice this but if you look
her that your inner thighs if you look
at her hips if you look at her the
vagina area she's probably very clenched
she's probably very tight she probably
retracts her hips she probably closes
her knees down this is all a response to
being invaded as a human being you know
the thing is with women is that they
open themselves up and the world comes
in now this is a situation where someone
ripped her open and went inside now she
literally has to protect herself right
and this is something that for men it's
difficult for us to understand because
we don't open ourselves up we go in she
has to soften in order to allow in but
it shoes taken advantage of physically
emotionally morally and it's hurting her
Peter Levine I'm going to invite you to
read some books and move in this
direction because there are therapists
that you might be able to find that are
bioenergetic offs in sort bioenergetics
is one branch of body psychology and
body psychology therapy somatic somatic
therapy is what they would call it I
tend to have taken a liking to just that
branch bioenergetics because I happen to
be living in the same vicinity of one as
one of the best bioenergetic therapists
in the world but it's just one branch of
what they would call me or Reiki in
therapy or somatic therapy Peter Levine
is one of the best in the world at
dealing with trauma release specifically
trauma release things that have happened
to you and how they get trapped in your
body and their exercises associated with
releasing the trauma but it needs to be
coupled with psychotherapy psyche
psychoanalysis awesome she needs to talk
to someone also someone that is not just
the talker you could talk talk talk talk
talk hug but it still remains very
abstract what she needs is physical
healing this is what we all need right
that's why I'm such a kook but such a
I'm always talking about using the body
to express the emotions getting it out
of your body whatever the case may be
because we are physically holding
ourselves through neurotic holding
patterns in the prisons that our mind is
creating for us a couple books I just
pulled up
- like it the names of some of the books
or I don't if you can see it here but
Peter Levine is the author of in an
unspoken voice which is a book that I
would invite you to to pick up it would
give you a foundation for what this is
all about you know some of the science
about behind mind-body healing you know
it's all one thing and you've got some
brilliant guys like Peter Lorre being in
and a lot of the books I've read by
Alexander Lowen and Wilhelm Reich
obviously who is the the founder of
these ideas in the West and also healing
trauma pioneering program for storing
the wisdom of your body both of those
are good books to start with but again
it's ideas wisdom I'm sorry ideas and
books you know reading are still very
abstract that's why a lot of people read
a lot of shit but they're not that smart
you know it's like well boy you read a
lot of stuff but why are you still so
dumb because reading doesn't really
educate experience educates experience
affords wisdom so overall I'm doing here
is pushing you in a particular direction
you're going to have to get her to
participate in some physical healing
either with a practitioner yeah look in
this direction a practitioner or
together the two of you I you know I
don't know how what type of relationship
you have with regard to that it may be
difficult for you but she needs to yield
into someone specifically with regard to
releasing the tears that she keeps
holding back she needs to sob she needs
to let it all out she needs to express
the anger associated with the violence
that she experienced I mean she needs to
throw a temper tantrum she needs to hit
beds with the with the tennis rackets
you need to do all the things a bit
physically associated with getting that
shit out of her
she literally needs to exorcise the
demon hey we do you think that term
comes from it's very fascinating that
that's a term of exercise you literally
get out of your body
that neurotic holding pattern she this
is this is another form of a neurotic
holding pattern that she's experiencing
it's cycling her physically because she
can't open up right her legs she cannot
open up you can't blame her
she'sshe's sucking it in every time she
wipes those tears away she's got to not
necessarily rheic spear Ian sit mentally
because that's still very abstract she
needs to go through therapy that will
let her express all the anger the
sadness - anguish the depression
associated with the horrible experience
that she went through dude I believe you
when you say you love her with all of
your heart you've been with her for two
years and you have endure the pain with
her and you I know that you want to have
sex with her and that's really that's
what it's all about here you know you
want to be able to merge with this woman
but the only way that she'll be able to
you'll be able to merge with her as if
she softens to someone and she's lucky
that she has you because she's going to
eventually soften with you and this is
that you're someone who she can come to
trust I'm saying she could come to trust
you right a part of her still she can't
she can't because everything associated
with sex is tainted with disgust and
distrust you see so that's it my friend
I'm pushing you in the right direction
that's I mean there's no question about
it I can't give you the exact steps to
as to what to do obviously I don't know
you and I'm not a therapist but you can
move in this particular direction and it
will be very resourceful for both of you
I wish you the best my friend I know
things will work out just a consistent
and keep loving her peace