so our buddy young pawn obsesses about
everything so he comes to me first with
a description of how he goes about his
exercise programs and routines
he is very calculated with his tracking
of the programs I mean total letter and
and he's also very calculated with his
form and he's heard guys like me if you
watch my other channel talked about how
it's important to have very meticulous
form when you're doing a lot of
exercises especially thoracic extension
exercises where you're your aim is to
improve your posture and he puts all his
focus and energy on being straight and
narrow when he approaches these things
it spills into other areas of his life
with his studying with his other things
that he's doing and what happens is as
he goes really really hard straight
narrow in his approach to these things
later on he ends up obsessing over the
fact that maybe he didn't do it right
maybe it wasn't good enough maybe I
could have done more it wasn't as
perfect as it should have been so he's
putting all his effort into being
straight and narrow and then obsessing
over the fact that it wasn't straight
narrow enough without going into how you
develop this neurotic pattern of
behavior this obsessive compulsiveness
that he calls it and you know it being
anal retentive these are his words
without going into it it usually happens
because we're never good enough for our
parents yeah when you're not good enough
for your parents you're not good enough
for yourself you didn't do it right you
didn't do it well enough can never
really satisfy your mom's way of wanting
things done what you've been taught that
right so but that's neither here nor
there what are you going to do right now
so the very first thing I want to do I
don't do this very often is but I want
to share with you a interesting old Zen
story of a one of the greatest gardeners
in all of the province wherever they
live now perhaps somewhere in China and
and he had the most immaculate gardens
in his home and he would often serve the
people in his his neighborhood you know
neighboring homes by developing their
garden
and he was paid very highly for this all
the days of his lives because he was so
good at it
the Emperor heard of this man and the
Emperor had his own garden but it just
wasn't right the Emperor sent for this
man to come to the to the castle and
asked him if he would design his garden
well the old man the gardener walks
around the the Emperor's garden when is
like well it's not bad it's okay what
did you do how'd you get it like this
and he said well I I drew up plans and I
had all of my workers designed this
garden to the letter so he had a perfect
blueprint and they executed it perfectly
the old man says well show me your your
blueprint he looks at the blueprint and
he looks around and he's like well they
surely have done the exact job you ask
them to do it's really a perfect job
what is it that I can do for you Emperor
the Emperor says it just doesn't feel
right the old man stops for a moment
thanks looks around 20 says I know
exactly what's wrong here it's just not
right King agreed oh it isn't right what
are we gonna do the old man goes and
grabs a basket and starts picking leaves
off of several of the bushes and walking
around the garden just picking up
different types of leaves then as a big
gust of wind came he took the basket of
leaves threw it up in the air and they
went everywhere littering the entire
garden with leaves scattered randomly
throughout the pathways and whatnot and
then he stood around he studied he
looked around and said perfect and the
Emperor was pleased the point of this
story and what the story wants to share
with its listener is that there is more
beauty in a little bit of wiggle nests
as opposed to everything being straight
and narrow in fact the beauty in nature
is Wiggly its wiggly nature right you
can't pin it down you can't pin down
clouds you can we really can't pin down
too much of anything in nature nature
curves and wiggles and slimes and
swerves and when we become so human so
neurotic and our
our need - for exactness straight lines
only human beings like straight lines if
you look at the the globe from above you
see where civilization has taken over
there are straight lines everywhere we
just mark everything off in straight
lines human being
the ego loves straight lines lows
exactness and then if you look at the
undeveloped areas it's just like all
Wiggly leave you ever see somebody
wearing whether it was a like Hawaiian
t-shirts with like leaves and patterns
all over each other all over the shirt
the reason why that shirt is so pleasing
it makes you feel like you're on
vacation it's because it's more in tune
with nature it is more Wiggly I've
spoken about this in other videos but
it's a bit again it's this dualistic
nature of the world
there's the head and the balls there's
yin and there's yang there is this
tenderness and aggression and if you're
all too aggressive you're way too hard
you're way too exact you're way too
straight line it's not going to feel
right you're gonna have anxiety and
you're going to be as depressed as you
are right now even though you're
following all the rules to the letter
okay so what are you going to do well my
invitation is to get back into nature
get back into that which we come from
and is Wiggly and the way that looks is
and again you know I'm an exercise
specialist I begin with the body you
know I believe that all personal
development begins when we develop our
bodies get back into the peripheral the
silly Wiggly peripheral nervous system
right the vegetative nervous system
that's another name for the peripheral
nervous system vegetative like
vegetables right like the vegetation the
nature from here down we're all roots
from here up we're flowering the roots
of our human existence extends itself
out into our peripheral nervous system
it literally if you look at the nervous
system it looks like a bud and the roots
get back into the Wiggly nature of your
roots and that's why I am always showing
you how to shake and wiggle in a vibrate
do all this weird silly stuff that you
know what children do
children don't have that type of anxiety
children don't have that need for
exactitude unless we make them neurotic
children put on music and they dance
they dance silly they don't have to
dance perfectly they do whatever happens
in their body the music happens and they
just do this I have children
so I know and kind of a kid myself I do
that all the time as well the type of
exercise I'm showing you to do right now
is wiggle dancing just shake vibrate and
wiggle probably your favorite song close
the door because the door is open and
you think someone's watching there's
this tendency to want to do it right
there is no right way to dance there's
no right way to dwell there is no right
way that nature expresses expresses
itself it all happens very Wiggly so
who's my breath they're all virgins from
or some wiggly dancing when you work out
reserved for yourself a time where you
get a little Wiggly get comfortable with
doing things wrong get comfortable with
not always doing the right thing let
loose go play in nature go play in dirt
practice forms of art that are
completely subjective learn to play an
instrument but don't learn how to play
it just play it start painting with your
fingers just your hands start painting
and don't have numbers that you need to
paint by just let it all out let it all
happen see what happens in your body and
see what you can express it's always
beautiful it's subjective but it's
always beautiful but because it comes
from the depths of your being from your
roots good luck