got a question here from our buddy Rob
who wants to become a physical therapist
he has aspirations for becoming the
strongest version of himself and he
realizes that study has to be a big part
of that there are things that he wants
to read in multiple areas he's got a lot
of passion for different ideas and would
really love to spend his time sitting
down and reading so for his career for
pleasure and for personal growth the
problem is he hates sitting down all he
wants to do is fucking run so he also
runs marathons so he's got this conflict
between his the desires of his cultured
mind which says I I'd like to read for
personal cultivation and his savage body
which says I just want to run well my
friend you've come to the right place
because I used to give me pills when I
was a kid because all my body wanted to
do is run all my body wanted to do is I
get active and do things that's why I
made a living out of exercise but notice
also that I have the same desire for
higher learning that you have I want to
read lots of books I'm my wife laughs at
me and this is probably a phrase that
I've used more times than any I'm
sitting in the living room and reading a
book or I'm looking on the internet and
I just say Coleen I want to know
everything I want to know everything had
this deep thirst for knowledge but then
my body wants to get up and I got to go
run and and I have a difficult time
believe it or not right Elliott House
has a difficult time sitting down and
reading
it's arduous and I have sort of I really
do have a sort of an attention deficit
thing if I especially if I'm not
meditating often I start drifting my
mind will start drifting and I'll get up
and I'll have to move and it becomes
very difficult for me to get any real
solid learning time done few things I've
learned that have supported me in the
cultivation of my learning my education
while still honoring the intelligence in
my body that says get up and move one
which is the easiest one that is
a part of my daily life a habit that
I've instilled that I will be doing till
the day I die
and that is I walk every morning you
don't have to walk you can run I like to
walk and listen to audio programs audio
programs audio books are like gold dude
I the only problem I have with
audiobooks is that not every single book
in the world has been transcribed into
audio or or turned into audio just yet
because I would list I can listen to
audio all day long while I do other shit
I'm learning while I'm exercising when
I'm training in my gym sometimes I'll
have on audio books books about all
kinds of stuff that I like to listen to
all kinds of things and I don't limit
myself to anything whatever like is
coming up with me and I want to learn
about like right now I'm really into
history for some fucking reason I don't
know why or how or what it'll do is
support me in my greater vision but it's
like my heart is saying dude history so
cool so I'm listening to lots of
biographies and books too associated
with civilization in history while I
walk in while I exercise the other thing
is that traditional school doesn't work
for me but what I have found is very
resourceful in allowing and cultivating
my education or workshops I have no
problem spending the thousands of
dollars I spent a lot of fucking money
on going to workshops to learn from
experts College I did okay elementary
school I did horrible high I just I was
a bad student I wasn't very good because
they require you to sit in these rows
and listen to somebody at the top and it
just didn't appeal to my learning style
but I but I can't learn believe it or
not and the best way for me to learn is
hands-on so I go to workshops that are
very hands-on workshops workshops where
there's not very much sitting there's a
lot of doing right and I look for these
especially if they're related to my
field of interest and I invite you to do
the same thing you say you want to be a
a physical therapist but you couldn't
sit through classes well I tell you what
don't you know you know what this is
gonna sound bad and maybe like I'll get
sued for saying shit like this but you
know what you can be a physical
therapist without going to fucking
college right you might not be able to
get insurance companies pay you and you
can't call yourself a physical therapist
but I guarantee you if you go when you
take Paul check courses I love Paul
check courses I love Paul check you go
and you take his exercise physiology
courses and learn how to do hands-on
exercise physiology hands-on physical
therapy and then call yourself a
personal trainer call yourself you know
you don't need to sit through classes be
a personal trainer and you do the same
things that a physical therapist can do
just don't you know just don't blow your
horn let the world know that you're
you're saving people you're helping
people because then the professionals
they get all upset the people that did
spend hundreds of thousands of dollars
in eight years of school to get degrees
which don't necessarily mean anything
except they were really good at sitting
down in following directions they're not
going to like it when like your patients
start getting better results than theirs
so don't blow your horn but you're doing
what you love to do and you've learned
how to do it in a hands-on environment
that the world doesn't necessarily
respect but who cares what the world
respects respectability is not nearly as
important as honoring the intelligence
in your heart and serving people the way
you feel you need to serve them dinner
Stan don't take this the wrong way don't
go cut people open and shit you're
really get in trouble but physical
therapy is one of those things that
there's a great there's a gray area
between personal training and physical
therapy go and learn through your
learning style most universities are
going to afford that but there are
plenty of workshops I know there are so
many of them I like I said I I'm a fan
of Paul check and I just I like him he's
become a friend but there are others
plenty of others that you can learn from
and you'll enjoy the type of learning
environment the workshop affords
so that's it dude you can do this don't
let the world have you believe that
because you can't sit down shut up and
pay attention and regurgitate bullshit
that someone at the front of the
classroom is telling you that you're
stupid that's one way of learning learn
how to learn that's one of the most
important things to learn