what up guys Elliot's back and we got a
question today from my buddy Colton who
was just so freaking awesome that people
can't stand him he begins by letting us
know these 17 years old he's done
extensive reading and research into
meditation Buddhism breathing techniques
etc he says he's an intelligent man one
of the top-ranked students is an entire
class he's a vegan he'd like to think
that he's an attractive guy he's
athletic he plays water polo
I have lean muscles a clear complexion
and I'm relatively tall I'm extremely
focused in goal-oriented and even though
I do have a bit of a DD I have a deep
voice I'm extremely expensive and when I
step into the room eyes tend to be drawn
to me but with all these characteristics
I have a problem so Colton is extremely
awesome and we've all figured that out
he's made it very clear in the first
paragraph but the problem is that he
can't seem to have any real friends he
goes on to say that well with regard to
men male friends I'd like to have more
but I only seem to have one or two and
they're childhood friends that kind of
stick around because we've always been
friends but when I try to develop and
deepen relationships with other
potential friends it just doesn't seem
to go too far and people just sort of go
away that's my situation with dudes and
that's quite painful but even more
painful is that now that I'm 17 years
old I'm becoming a man and I'd like to
develop and deepen relationships with
women and it seems that it's not working
out either he says that he hasn't had a
girlfriend and those that he do he does
try to develop relationship with sort of
come into the fold and then quickly
scatter
I mean talks about girls that he's he's
tried to talk to and develop
relationship with who then just go and
have sex with other dudes basically
ignore him they go away and it just
doesn't seem to be working out well for
him and he wants to know what the hell
is the problem I mean I'm awesome these
people must be out of their minds or
perhaps there's something I'm not seeing
thank you for sharing that with us
Colton
so here's the thing you are awesome the
problem with your awesome is that it's
an awesome that has been fabricated
based on the stories the world has told
you about what awesome is so it's a
heavy awesome meaning you do lots of
research and reading into meditation
research and reading all very heady you
don't mention that you actually meditate
he researches these things he's
intelligent he's a top-ranked student
meaning I do as I'm told because the
world believes that awesome means being
top ranked student I'm a vegan now no
knock against veganism but at 17 years
old if you're listening to your body you
decide to be a vegan I guarantee it's
more of an intellectual choice than
listening to your body I'm a fan of
listening to your body
he has lean muscles the world loves lean
muscles I mean it's on TV and magazines
all the time
he's athletic and plays water polo I
mean water polo those are the sexiest
guys in the Olympics right
he has clear complexion he's relatively
tall right he's extremely focused in
gold oriented this is all shit that's
happening in here I mean you're doing a
fantastic job at being awesome in your
head and that's really what I want to
get to here the awesomeness is all in
your head bro and it's evident because
it's not showing up in your world and I
often say that the world is your mirror
and the people in your world are the
most clear mirrors as to what's going on
in your soul
and the thing is that your awesome is
not grounded and you can't keep people
on their feet in front of you
do you see your awesomeness is
completely fabricated it's a it's a
construct of your ego and it is your
persona if you're familiar with the term
persona it comes from a terminology used
I don't know exactly the roots of it but
its side it depicts a mask whereby the
sound can be projected into the audience
during days when there were plays being
I've heard at stadiums that were too big
and we didn't have sound systems back
then so someone would wear a persona
which is a giant mask that would that
would project their emotions it would be
like a big mad mask or be a big happy
mask or a silly mask and then it'd have
a sound persone per sound for sound
that's what the said word persona comes
from when I say I don't know the root I
mean like what origin what country but
per sound right must be Latin BER and
it's this big fucking mask your persona
with a big horn bur this is what I am
the world world world that's your
personas your mask it's your projection
of a particular piece of what makes a
human being a human being a person who
can never hold on to everything that you
are what that what actually is is behind
the persona who's the person holding the
mask and projecting through so that all
the audience can hear what's going on
dude you're very intellectually attached
and emotionally attached to your persona
which you've pretty much done a great
job of making awesome but it's not real
that's the problem my friend you're
suffering because people develop
relationships with people not personas
and your persona is very when I say
shallow it's not a knock on you as a
person but it's a knock on the construct
of a persona it doesn't go deep into
your heart it is way up into your head
right your head is shallow you don't go
you don't go very deep you know if you
consider that whole concept of the of
the iceberg right and they say that
you're you're under your intelligence is
about 10% of the iceberg because just
the iceberg shows and then there's
everything else also underneath a lot of
you guys who think you're scientific and
smart trust me you don't fucking trust
me be entertained by me for a moment
that there's a significant amount a
significant amount tremendous amount of
intelligence below the surface right all
right I don't need to prove it the fact
that you're watching this video is proof
right your heart's beating and you're
not doing it you're digesting food and
you're not doing it you're real placing
cells and you're not doing it your hair
is growing and you're not doing your
teeth are falling out you're not doing
all the shit is happening and you're not
doing it because there's an intelligence
that guides you but also makes you
sensitive to the energy vibration
frequencies of the sea that we live in
with other people and if you're very
shallow when you're focused on the
persona the the the mental constructs
these are all very abstract right it's
all very paper-thin if you're focused up
here you will never delve into the deep
ocean of frequency that human beings
really operate on we really operate on a
level of deep frequencies when I say
frequencies I mean divides vibrations
feelings emotions that move from the
level of the heart your gut your body
you've got to get out of your head and I
love the fact that you're meditating
because meditation if you're not just
researching and and reading into
extensive reading and research extending
there's no need for extensive reading
and research into meditation
there's shut your brain off in fact the
more you read about meditation more
you're fucking up meditation get away
from the reading and intellectualizing
and get into the body sensations
associated with integrating your mind
and your body
meditation happens in the body it's a
mindfulness of bodily sensations and you
my friend are probably I guarantee if I
met you they're probably pretty tense
there I say you're a tight ass right
because your body is probably very rigid
and you I think you say you have a DD
boy you know of course a lot of this is
character ology character structure
stuff and in that none of it is in exact
science but I guarantee if I met you
your eyes would probably be bitty very
big and you probably be very very
skittish and your body would probably be
very tense you know you say that you're
lean and muscular well you know are you
a soft supple tender aggressively nor
you a dense tight rigid lean and and
that tense tight rigid lean doesn't
allow for
soft tender frequencies to be received
by others and their heartfelt feelings
and for you to give yourself from the
heart a lot of the stuff we'll forgot to
the heart I've I've been doing research
into the heart math Institute innate
they these people are very scientific
about their approach to measuring heart
frequencies and how we operate on an
emotional level I am and you know if you
want to do some research and reading
look into that heart math the hard math
Institute heart frequencies the
vibrations that emit from our body that
is really what attracts people to us
it's not our you know it's a shame
because most of us dare I say a good
percentage of us are so shallow and when
I say shallow I mean not in the body not
in touch with your unconscious not in
touch with the vibrations in your body
and in your surrounding you're all up in
your fucking head many of us are so
shallow that the shell of who we are and
the shell of other people is what we're
attracted to big boobs small waist long
blonde hair big blue eyes I mean it
sounds like it like an alien to me but
this is what we've discovered - this is
what we've chosen to tell ourselves is
beautiful about a woman they did they've
done some magazine articles I've seen or
Bob post where if a real human woman
took on the figure took on the actual
figure of a Barbie doll she would look
like a freakin maniac she would look
sick she would look deformed you
wouldn't be attracted to her because our
idea of what's attractive is is very
much it's an ideology they'd say it's a
it's abstract it's not real it's not
gritty it's not dirty it's not smelly
it's not sexual at all
so that's the very first thing I want
you to get in touch with the idea that
there is a paper you and then there is a
sweaty stinky salty you there is a body
you and then there's a abstract to you
you're very attracted to the abstract
abstract to you in the persona
associated with it now my invitation is
this the barrier to you and all of us to
coming into the raw realness of who we
are found in our body and and how that
root system as its here in earth and the
vibrations associated with other people
and ourselves intermingle the biggest
barrier between your head and Ranas
sexuality really all this is sexual
energy are the stories that you've been
told and that you continue to tell
yourself about how ugly and how guilty
you should feel about the real you right
and when I say to term ugly I mean
there's a story ugly but there's also a
very sexual ugly there's a very raw and
smelly I mean human beings are supposed
to smell right we're supposed to be
hairy ma'am but we you know we wash all
that shit away so they're stories told
about our sexuality and there's stories
that have been told to you about who you
are and what you're not and what you're
allowed to be what's acceptable and
what's what's uh what's praiseworthy get
in touch with the ugly get in touch with
the ugly you get in touch with the part
of you that you've been denying for very
long and in fact if you don't even know
it's there I invite you to really
meditate because you'll find it
especially if you participate a lot of
the active meditations and bioenergetics
and protect perhaps yoga that I often
talk about in these videos get in touch
with that nasty emotion that you've been
holding back for so long and it makes
your body so rigid that is the blockage
between your objective point of view
knowing yourself from an objective place
and the magnificence that's really in
you the subjective brilliance that's in
you look at your anger I'm a I'm I'm
imagining two things that are very
prominent in your in that blockage
between your your ability to see
yourself and who you really are that I
see anger and I see sadness get in touch
with your anger explore your anger look
at the roots of your anger who are you
angry with most boys at 17 years old are
angry with their dads that's a big part
of it you know and you could have the
greatest dad in the world but you're
supposed to be angry with your dad
because at some point a boy it needs to
become a man and the easiest way to
become a man is to create contrast
between what has been told to you as
what what a man is your father and what
you'd like to see for yourself
and evolution happens that way so you're
mad at your dad but explore that explore
your frustration with your father if
it's a father that didn't stay with you
the father left explore that also
explore your relationship to the
masculine that's a very first one and of
course that is going to your
relationship to the masculine idea which
is portrayed to you through your father
is going to show up in your relationship
with men with boys and part of the
reason why you probably have a hard time
dealing with boys because every time you
deal with other men who would
potentially be your friends you're
you're suiting up all of your awesome
armor like you're proving yourself to
your dad your dad left now you gotta
prove yourself why you're worthy of
being a man and now you're doing it to
your friends or if your dad was just
really a tough guy or your dad was super
awesome you have to prove yourself to be
just awesome as or awesome other than
your dad and then you go to your friends
and it's like you're still playing the
daddy game you're brought your boy here
for your friends your boyfriend's not a
homosexual way shame that I have to
apologize for that but your boyfriend's
don't need you to be so fucking awesome
because they don't want you to prove
anything to you to them they want your
heart your boyfriend's want your heart
too and your girlfriend's the
relationship that you have with the
femme
is probably also showing up and there's
deep sadness associated with it so
you've got anger from your relationship
with your father
you've got sadness associated with
relationship with your mother and we all
do we all have sadness associated with
our mothers because our mother is our
root as our earth and when we become
unearthed through the very first
heartbreak generally the very first form
of Unruh ting from the mother from the
earth is when she stops nursing us if
you were lucky enough to have a mom that
nursed you with her body
you know coz then it goes deeper when
she removes you from her bodily
nourishment there is a deep and profound
sadness that strikes every child at that
particular age this has been thoroughly
researched and then usually there's a
second heartbreak that's associated with
a deeper pain when you realize that your
mother is not your lover your mother is
your father's lover and this all goes on
during what Freud called the Oedipus
oedipal complex where you know the boy
realizes that he loves his mother but
his mother can't be with him because of
course that's weird and uh an incestuous
so anyway my friend is my friend my
point is friend explore the roots of
your anger explore the roots of your
sadness realize that you're using
awesomeness to cover it up get over the
awesomeness delve into the ugliness of
the emotions that are blocking you from
being your raw true awesome self which
is gritty raw nasty smelly and likes to
give hugs
done