it was up guys so we got a question for
one of our buddies who recently broke up
with a girl that he had been with for a
year everything went well just you know
they decided to break up for whatever
reason the point here is that he's now
with another girl's with a brand new
girlfriend they've been together for a
few months and although he likes his
girl a lot he can't help himself but to
keep comparing in their relationship to
his old relationship
he's even chronologically looking at it
he says you know after two months with
this woman it's very different than two
months with that woman and he's
constantly comparing what happened in
the past with what's happening now and
he's he's not enjoying this because he's
not getting what he got before and this
is a very common addiction
they say it's it I've once heard that
it's most common in the oldest children
of a family so if you happen to be the
the oldest of four children like myself
you have a tendency to look back
whatever reason if intensity to look
back at the way things used to be the
problem is that when you're looking back
when you're constantly doing this you're
looking back you have no energy to be
available for the moment and each moment
offers its present its gift and if your
eyes are busy distracted with what used
to be or what could be then everything
that is slips by you and every moment
offers its brilliance its beauty if
right now I could snap a picture and
take a picture of me doing this right
now regardless of how I feel about the
circumstances right now ten years from
now I could look at picture look at the
picture and say oh that was a sweet
moment because it captures the
brilliance of the moment and you've got
to be in the moment each time you're
with your your girlfriend and each
season has its beauty each time has its
beauty each each layer of who you become
has its beauty each layer of who she
becomes has its beauty many of you know
that I've been my wife since we were
children she's
the same woman but there's a brand-new
beauty I fell in love with a different
type of beauty 20 years ago then the
beauty that I fall in love with each day
today it's an entirely different thing
but if I look back and say boy when you
were 14 those tits were nice and
succulent and perky and now after 4
children and nursing them they don't
look the same way I won't be present for
all the beauty that's available in my
wife's breasts today and they're far
more sensitive and sexual than they ever
were when she was a young budding but I
found the beauty by being in the moment
instead of thinking about what it used
to be or what it could be boy you know a
couple thousand bucks we could throw
some silicone in there babe and you'll
be perking up like you did back then
right and that's a silly conversation to
get into because today isn't what it was
back then and why would I want yesterday
into the future I want now dude people
do this all the time the children this
is a weird one and children think the
same thing because well I think adults
do this you know uh you're lucky cuz
you're a kid and his kids want to grow
up and then when you're an adult you say
boy I wish I was a kid again no
motherfucker I don't wish I was a kid
again I don't want to by telling you
what to do I don't have I tell you what
to eat when to get up where'd it go when
you're a kid people always tell you what
to do I want to be free as an adult it's
better on my kids I say yeah it's better
to be an adult but then it sucks being
adult coz I have any taxes I got to pay
bills I got to take care of their little
snotty asses I'm wiping their noses and
butts every moment comes with its yin
and yang every moment comes with us
light and dark every moment comes with
its good and evil the idea is to be
fully present in the moment so that you
can experience it all in its rawness in
its intensity in its purpose each moment
its purpose is itself each moment with
your new girlfriend coming back to you
each moment with your new girlfriend be
with her you'll start to notice
beautiful things about her you'll start
to engage in the circumstances and be
grateful for them because you'll never
have them again they never never
happened before and it will never happen
in the future because what's going to
happen is gonna break up with this girl
and you have another girl and you look
back and say well shit this ain't the
same as it was with my girl two times or
going one time ago
you might you know you might miss this
whole season with this new girl because
you're still looking so back on the
other one that when you have your third
fourth fifth and sixth girlfriend you
still thinking about the first because
you had no experiences in between
he's just been daydreaming the whole
time about your old girlfriend what a
shame that would be no two years from
now after five more girlfriends you're
still thinking about that old one
because he had no experiences because
you were thinking about her while you
were doing stuff with the other ones be
with her now we are dynamic life is
dynamic the people in our environment
are dynamic things are constantly
changing be with the circumstances as
they are I make these videos watch
videos of me this is a good one listen
up watch videos of me from a year ago
two years ago well you didn't have to go
that far that back cause I'm constantly
changing I'm an emotional wreck watch a
month ago two months ago three months
ago six 1224 months to just go back I'm
not the same I'm never the same it's the
same Elliott of course same general idea
but sometimes he's more emotive and he
does weird shit sometimes he's more
angry sometimes he's really just
laid-back and talks slowly with a big
beard right January sometimes I stare
off in my videos sometimes I make my
videos and I make my entire video
staring off sometimes I go like this a
lot but each time if I'm to judge my
current performance with my last
performance or let people's judgments
about my current performance compared to
my last performance I'll never be
available to the brilliance that's
happening right now this is brilliant
shit happening right now enjoy it hey
you're watching my video right now and
you're saying hey Elliott I don't like
the new you I used to like the way you
were but I can't stand you now Black
sucks
not for me cuz I'm gonna keep changing
I'm gonna keep doing what
do because I'm present to the moment but
sucks for you because you're attached to
old shit that guy's dead that happened
yesterday that happened six months ago
I'm here now making love to you receive
my love look at what's available now I'm
speaking faster I'm sweating because
it's fucking hot because the seasons
change I can't keep the seasons the same
that's a best thing that's the one thing
that pisses me off why can't I keep the
seasons the same
it's nice when it's cool in Florida
because I'm more cool when I make the
videos now it's hot hot hot hot headed
god damn season we think we can control
everything right well we'll make air
conditioning
let go of the desire to control
manipulate to recreate past or project
into the future be available so fully
for what's happening right now that it
has to be brilliant it's only ugly today
is only ugly she is only ugly in
comparison to something else or sometime
else every moment is beautiful this is
beautiful right now you're watching me
on your couch or at your office while
your boss is thinking that you're doing
books whatever it is it's a beautiful
moment be fully present to it have no
guilt about it that's the other thing
right we have our we're carrying old
shit from the past projecting in the
future or feeling guilty about now
that's I would say that guilt is the
biggest ugliest most damaging sin of all
guilt because you carry it into the
moment you can't even enjoy this moment
does he feel guilty about it for
whatever reasons whatever stories you've
told yourself I should be doing
something else more productive that's
one that I usually feel that fills me
with guilt at this moment I should be
doing something else so I feel guilty if
I'm laying in my hammock just chillin
looking at the trees that's exactly
what's supposed to happen because I'm
most productive in the moment doing just
that don't matter what you're doing how
dumb it may seem you're jerking off and
you feeling guilty about yourself
cause you you want to ejaculate it feels
good but you're looking around can't
even enjoy yourself jump off and fully
jerk off enjoy the masturbation right
everything everything that you do be it
judged as good or bad based on the
experiences of other people and how they
have conditioned you to believe about
this particular moment drop it
completely and fully engaged be fully
engaged with your woman matter what
she's if she's sixty pounds overweight
and cross-eyed man make love to her like
you've never made love to any woman
before even if her breath stinks fully
engaging the experience of her nasty
breath cuz you're gonna laugh you'll
crack up you can have such a great time
because you meet big in yourself boy her
breath fucking stinks and I can't wait
to nut inside her whatever it is fully
engaged in the moment be fully immersed
in the moment experience all of it if
you're in pain indulge in the pain feel
the pain you've got a broken ankle just
feel the fucking pain hey this is I
learned a lot of this from training my
my first channel is about strength
training when you're working out you
just like you want to die feel the death
happening in you feel the pain happening
in your legs as you rep out one more
squat because it'll be all the more
pleasurable when you reach the
inevitable other end of the spectrum
where you're laying in your hammock and
sipping on a protein shake boy I really
went hard I really went hard on that set
I really went hard in that chick I
really went hard in that relationship I
really went hard in school I really went
hard in my career I really would hard in
life go hard and die hard
done