so our buddy shorty dude is in the
friend zone oh boy this is the tough
situation man so he's been a friend
yours is not so bad I've seen it worse
but he's been a friend with a girl since
middle school up through high school and
now he's starting to have warm feelings
towards her like you didn't before but
he wants to take it to that next level
the problem is they're just too friendly
so I'm going to approach this from a
broad perspective with regard to this
idea of getting into the friend zone
because it's a bad place you don't want
to be in the friend zone and the way you
end up in the friend zone is by lacking
the aggression associated with that
which would take the relationship to
that intimate level that really is what
you've wanted from the beginning you
weren't just friends you just didn't
have the aggressive or assertive
capability to take action when it was
necessary during the early stages of our
of your relationship and what that does
is it sets you up in a in a very awkward
place where now she no longer respects
you because you didn't assert yourself
when the opportunity presented itself
and this is a situation with all men and
women if you end up in the friend zone
she no longer respects you and that's
why you're a friend because you never
really manned up when it was time to man
up and there's always a window of
opportunity where the the woman opens up
and it is your job it's your
responsibility to dive in to take action
to assert yourself in the direction that
she's yielding towards for you if you
don't do that you not only have lost
that opportunity but you've lost other
opportunities because there's going to
be a lack of respect for you she's going
to resent you right but she can tolerate
you and then you know you end up
shopping for shoes together and shit
like that
so the first thing is to avoid the
situation altogether if you have warm
feelings for a woman and take this to
the bank this is very important it is
better that you overly assert yourself
and become rejected and get rejected
then be too soft and never assert when
the time is right there's a really good
story of friends of mine who are now I'm
married and in high school I remember
they sat next to each other one was a
really beautiful girl and kind of a
geeky dude but he had just this audacity
about his attitude they sat together in
in a in science class and every day he
would ask her out he knew what he wanted
and he just would he buggy bugger and
she just be like Oh leave me alone leave
me like hey when are we gonna go out hey
when can I take you out Hey he just
started asserted asserted asserted that
was a bit awkward for both of them or
her actually but because he asserted
himself like a man because he knew what
he wanted and he was constantly little
annoyingly always pecking at her in many
different ways he was looked upon by her
as a assertive man now you know there's
a difference between being assertive and
being annoying so you know that's up for
debate but anyway today they're married
this was like 10 years ago and today
they're married and he's still the
geekiest weirdest looking dude and she's
as beautiful as all hell but no other
man has sorted him a person himself in
the same type of way that he did for so
long and that's what afford him afforded
him the prize so you're better off
getting rejected rejected rejected
rejected rejected and finally received
then never pursuing to begin with you
see so now that you're in the friend
zone
you've got to regain that the type of
respect that's associated with being a
assertive man and the only way that's
going to happen with this particular one
is if she sees you asserting yourself
with other women now it could work that
she sees you asserting yourself in a
form of art or sport she sees that
you're fully focused directed willing to
take action in a courageous fashion
towards the development of
athletic ability towards the development
of a particular art or skill if she sees
you really moving forward in a male
aggressive way towards an inanimate
object or idea that might help but what
will help 10 times more is if she sees
you asserting yourself towards a woman
because the number of things is gonna
happen a bunch is gonna question herself
she's gonna wonder wait a second I
thought he was a friendzone kind of guy
and here he is over asserting himself
over these other women and he didn't
assert himself like that to me maybe I'm
not beautiful enough maybe I'm not soft
and female enough maybe I did the wrong
thing and she's gonna grow jealous she's
gonna want to find out why you didn't
assert yourself and right now she's
thinking you didn't cite yourself as
your pussy but when she sees you
asserting yourself with other women
she's gonna wonder what happened why
didn't he come to me like that and she's
gonna want she's gonna be looking at all
you know dazzled and beautiful when she
approaches you because she's gonna like
waiting like what about me and she will
respect the fact that you have the spine
to do this right you know right now she
just doesn't think you have the spine
because you were offered the opportunity
because we always are and you didn't
assert either you were just too blind
you didn't you didn't know it was Aryan
just kind of like ignorant or
you just had cold feet spineless right
you just didn't have the strength of
character to dive in when it was when I
was afforded to you so she's gonna start
questioning her her the way she thinks
about you in that regard you know she's
gonna be like huh you know what maybe he
is I'm seeing parts of him that I didn't
recognize before parts of the character
traits that I didn't recognize before
and she's going to be intrigued so
that's it really the only way in my mind
that I can see you getting out of the
friendzone is to have her see
consciously make an effort for her to
see you being really manly with other
women and if your intention is to be
with her then you do it a little while
just to kind of regain the balance and
then you come back you're like hey you
know what I messed up or just assert
yourself and be like
you know it's a brand-new situation
brand-new opportunity but you're not
going to get it with her just like that
you if you try to assert yourself at
this point and you're a friend it's
going to be awkward and strange it
probably won't work good luck