yo Eliot what's up guys today we got a
question from our strength camp online
member meat hall who goes on to say that
he is madly in love with a young lady
they've been dating for about a year and
he's leaving for university next year
she's staying home so of course that's
going to cause a little bit of a problem
do they break up clean brave you know no
hard feelings between us you go your way
I go mine but we love each other and
it's gonna hurt so much rip that
band-aid off or do we try to work it out
and risk potentially drifting apart and
having awkward feelings towards each
other
thereafter so so this is one of those
you can't win situations so get that out
of your head you know you're damned if
you do you're damned if you don't I've
made videos about this I hope you guys
understand that principle of life you
know successful people don't make the
right decision they make their decisions
right the only thing I can offer you is
the potential stumbling block that
you're going to come upon with each
situation and potentially you could
avoid it what you're really going to be
wrestling with regardless of what choice
you make is resentment right and you've
got some pretty good insight on where
that resentment will lie depending on
what decision you make if you guys make
a clean break you're going to
potentially stumble over resentment of
the choice you will resent yourself or
you resent the choice but there won't be
much resentment towards her you know
even if she goes out maybe she gets
another boyfriend
you really can't logically listen you
know and love is not logical at all so
there goes that logically be resentful
towards her because you made the choice
bro
right so the the only issue there is
misplaced resentment because you're
going to have it it's going to be
towards you and it's a matter of
wrestling with yourself and wrestling
with yourself is often a lot easier than
wrestling with someone else and if you
decide to stay together
the resentment is
going to be outwardly placed so let's
say you stay together and you go to
university and there's a perfect girl
for you right I mean you could be in
love and still find a perfect girl you
know what I'm saying and in every way
it's like I wish that I could
potentially be with you but I can't and
you know what the resentments gonna be
towards your girl back home man mmm
too bad I got a girlfriend oh and then
when you get on the phone with her
you're gonna be kind of like a little
annoyed she gonna be like what's the
matter you need like nothing but rely
but realize like now you're is unfair
because you're placing resentment on her
and she's kind of like an innocent
bystander
you guys both made the decision to try
to do the thing and I'm not saying this
is going to happen but this is kind of a
natural tendency this is a pattern that
you often see where there's going to be
opportunities presented to it to you
they're going to present themselves
beautiful opportunities will present
themselves and the the tendency
oftentimes is to be righteous about your
choice make the right choice you know
I'm not going to do it but then carry
resentment towards the person who you've
made the choice to be loyal to and then
it rots there then you then you really
lose because you lose the potential
lover the new lover and you kind of
start having strained between you and
your woman and then it can go the other
way around also where she starts you
know kind of drifting whatnot like you
said and you're going to resent her for
the choices she made so you know there's
no right answer here there's usually no
right answer to the half the questions
that you guys ask me it's just a matter
of kind of looking at things and in what
you're going to potentially wrestle with
it's like I think it is probably easier
to wrestle with yourself than to wrestle
with other people's emotions you know
it's like the stew just gets a little
bit more complicated when you're dealing
with other people as opposed to having
that clean break I married my high
school girlfriend we went to separate
colleges right we made it we made it all
the way through but I can't say that
there weren't opportunities that
presented themselves and caused us to be
resentful towards each other
on and it was a part of the struggle
that we had to go through in order to
grow as individuals and as a couple
right I mean we're grateful for every
challenge that we had and we're here
today and our bonds are stronger than
ever before I'm so happy that we
attempted to try to stay together
through college she didn't go to
university across the country we saw
each other almost you know once a month
or whatnot sometimes twice a month
because it was just about a three-hour
drive to go see her but it was that
training we chose to chose to battle
with resentment between each other and
ultimately make it on the other side a
little bit stronger so there you have
that you know there were times where we
were at each other's throats we fought a
lot but it worked out so it can win that
way also man I don't know what you
should do but it can work either way if
you make it done
Elliot's in what
[Music]