hey what's up guys so if you've been
watching my videos for quite a few weeks
months years or whatever you probably
heard me use certain words over and over
again in one word that you probably
heard me use most recently in a
repetitive fashion is ritual the reason
why I use the term ritual as a
substitute for habit is because there's
something a bit more powerful to the
rituals in your life whether you know
you're doing ritual performing rituals
are not if you're cognizant of it and
you can infuse your habits with ritual
power it takes things to another level
so what am I talking about the
difference between a habit and a ritual
is as simple as looking at the things
that you do every day without having to
think about it habits are things that
you do without having to think about it
so when you get up in the morning you
brush your teeth you probably don't
think about it you probably just wake up
get to the bathroom brush your teeth
habits are things that you have trained
yourself to do or others have trained
you to do without you having to think
about it it could also be as simple as
getting in your car right when you get
in your car you've got a motor n-gram
from your head to your hand that
automatically jams at Quillan turns the
ignition that's a simple one but you
recognize when it's not properly
accessed when you get into like a new
car right into a new car you have to
look for the keyhole so on and so forth
so it goes from being something that
some novel and new that's something that
becomes habit habitual you just do it
over and over again it becomes a ritual
when you infuse it with conscious power
so some things that well you can really
you can really infuse anything with
conscious power and make it a ritual
things as simple as being completely
focused
and present with your meal when you're
eating a lot of people set the stage by
or set the tone by saying a prayer of
gratitude or grace before they eat this
turns you're eating this turns your
habits of eating most people eat
completely unconsciously you know we
just we're just stuff including our
mouths driving eating fast food and shit
but if you pause for a moment just pause
for a moment and offer 10 seconds of
gratitude thank you to the animal that
you're eating thank you to the soil for
producing the plants that you're eating
thank you for to towards whatever you
want to offer gratitude for the
nourishment that you're about to get
your meal becomes a ritual the powerful
thing about being fully fully present
and concentrating all your mental and
spiritual effort on an activity like
eating or any other mundane activity is
that you become more fully aligned with
the
energy is available from the activity it
goes from being a rote activity to
something that produces more than just
like when you eat it produces more than
just nutrition for your body but it in
live-ins your spirit right when you put
that food in your mouth and you're
thinking about the gratitude you're
holding gratitude with you while you're
eating that food or you're drinking that
water you've turned that simple act into
a spiritual act you turn something from
profane into sacred a lot of these ideas
come from a book in fact called sacred
and profane by Mercer le a day if you're
interested in these types of ideas so
look at your life look at when you're
making love to your woman for example I
mean there's an entire practice
associated with bringing spirituality
bringing focus and concentration turning
your sexual act turning your lovemaking
into art turning into prayer turning
into spirituality they call this Tantra
so you know a lot of people there their
relationships go pretty boring
especially their sexual relationships
get pretty boring because you know sex
becomes a habit you know every night or
every other night or whatever your habit
is it's like you know you go and you
poke your girl what I'm inviting you to
consider is to turn your love Act into
an act of prayer by ritual izing it so
you would do things like perhaps light
candles turn on music clean the sheets
take a shower these are all ways to
prepare your mind prepare your spirit
and prepare your body for the thing
you're about to do you're gonna go make
love man we want to be fully present we
want to get the most out of it we want
the experience to transform us not just
our body right we bust a nut but
actually to walk away feeling
invigorated enlivened like you've added
something to the world you've added
something to yourself and you've
contributed to the to the blossoming of
your woman's energy when you make love
to her
and of course everyday things that we do
can be ritualized and infused with
spiritual power just by being conscious
of it so I remember when I was in high
school and I was never really a good
student but I was a really good athlete
I love strength training and I took good
care of my body it became the thing that
I centered all my discipline around you
know school was kind of the thing that I
had to do training and taking care of my
body is the thing I wanted to do but I
started doing really well in school when
I began ritual izing the healthful
practices associated with studying and
doing my homework what do I mean by that
before I would engage in my homework
practice I would ritualistically go into
my kitchen fill up a big cup of ice fill
it up with water set it by my next to my
books I lay everything out take a few
breaths and the begin working I didn't
know what I was doing at the time but I
quickly realized that uh that I started
falling out of good patterns when I
stopped filling up my health full glass
of water might help full cup of water
and doing a deep breathing taking a deep
breathing moment before doing my
homework I hated homework but because I
ritualized that I was able to get myself
into the flow into the energy into the
frequency of getting that thing done and
enjoying it letting it be come a gift
so so of course we can turn our entire
lives into a sacred experience we can
turn our every profane moment into a
ritual we can turn everything that we do
which seems mundane boring and wrote
into an act of Prayer if we infuse it
with our full consciousness intention
and love a Japanese tea party or tea
ceremony which I had the luck though
that the the joy of participating in in
fact my daughters and wife we're in
England they did a they went to a tea
party an English tea party interesting
that the east and west both have
versions of a tea party which require
now to the tea party ain't just tea
party if you've been to Japan or England
and AHS we sit sitting down and pouring
some tea at least you know the
experiences I've had and traditionally
it's a big to-do I mean every with a
jacket Japanese tea party every moment
every movement every where you set the
cup how you pour the thing how you toast
it how you sip it the whole fucking
thing is infused with full consciousness
it's like a prayer in motion like yoga
tea parties brushing your teeth eating
your meals and making love to your woman
will bring ten times a hundred times a
thousand times more power and joy to
your life you infuse it with the power
of ritual
don't