I got this question from one of our
buddies here who is sort of having a
relationship with a girl they both
really like each other they talking to
fall and things are moving smoothly in
their relationship but there is some
room feelings between the two of them
and they know this is there there are
seniors in high school neither of them
have even kissed someone you know of the
opposite sex just yet he's never kissed
her she's never kissed him and this is a
brand new thing
how does he as a man assert himself in
this sexual way
knowing that neither of them have any
experience you know and getting past the
awkwardness knowing when to make that
move you know it might sound silly a lot
of you guys where you're so tough or
watching this video and you know it's
are for you to empathize with that first
that first kiss but you know being a
senior in high school and moving moving
in this way it's you're breaking the ice
not just for the relationship that you
have with this one woman but also in
your ability to to assert yourself and
move forward with everything in your
life absolutely everything your life is
you're going to meet this resistance
this this high charge where you either
break through and take action do that
thing or you let the awkwardness or the
the anxiety of the moment have your
energy retreat to your head and you
tiptoe around you dance around and you
never get anything done you just stay
with the anxiousness the anxiety the the
ungrounded energy of the moment this is
a perfect opportunity and what I would
do is I would invite you I know this
sounds I'm gonna sound either really
cold and detached from Rome at from you
know your your opportunities with women
between men and women sexual
relationships or I'm going to sound
overly romantic that's a little bit of
both everything that happens in the
concrete everything that is manifested
is the fruit of an abstract idea it's
something that you've thought about
right you've thought about kissing her
right and just like we thought about
landing on the moon these were ideas
before they came into reality you're
gonna you're gonna do this over and over
again there's this there's a cycle of
dreaming and creating right and there
are multiple steps in that in that cycle
that you're going to experience
you're going to go you're going to deal
with for your entire life but there are
segways there are little steps that you
can take that will smooth the transition
between what you'd like to have happen
kiss her and the actual thing you know
the idea of the thing and the actual
thing and one of them if you study
success is to write down what you want
to have happen this is this is almost
like a you know no-brainer when it comes
to the whole idea of goal achievement
but it's like if you want to have a
Mercedes Benz you write down that I'm
going to want to have a Mercedes Benz
you write it down as a goal I'm going to
earn a Mercedes Benz I'm gonna earn them
out enough money to have this thing
whatever it is and you write it down on
a piece of paper you visualize what you
think about it you you you come up with
all the details about the experience
itself in your mind and then you share
with other people it's a very powerful
way is by sharing with other people so
this is sort of a success technique that
you can use as many different things but
now on the romantic level you and this
this young girl who you know there's all
this awkwardness and you being a man
know that you should assert yourself in
this particular way used what our what
our ancestors have used use without
grandparents Jews you didn't have to be
a certified poet or musician to pour out
your hearts longings for another person
on a piece of paper or through a piece
of music be romantic romantic in that
way
bring back romance because romance is
the bridging of the gap between our
natural impulses and the actual activity
of kissing and having sex and it really
sweetens the experience so much more
because now you can together envision
and work out and play with the details
of what will ultimately happen all the
love songs love sonnets and love poems
poems that have been written were
written by men who wanted to have an
experience with a woman but yet is
there's the the ache of distance
between the moment and the actual
activity all of our most beautiful poem
love poems and songs is a bridging of
the gap through communication between
the abstract what we want and what we
want to have happen I will tell you man
and of course I sound corny and you know
a lot of people say like don't listen
Elliot for dating advice look don't I
happen to marry a girl that I dated in
high school so I you know I I didn't
whore around in that particular way I
use that term loosely I don't
necessarily mean more around but you
know what I'm saying I haven't been with
lots of women but I truly believe that
if we cultivate as men if we cultivate
this idea of romance once again bring it
back into our relationships it'll color
the potency of our experience with the
opposite sex to such a great degree of
course there are people there will be
people who laugh at you and reject you
in that way but there's so much power to
it if you find a woman who knows how to
receive your love sonnets you're right
or a love letter bro writer a love
letter that says I would like to kiss
you and here is how and you describe how
you want to put your hand in the back of
her head you you're going to look into
each other's eyes and then you'll tilt
your head slightly and press your lips
against hers and hold it there as you
both inhale and exhale and then be
poetic about it and then through the
inhalation and exhalation we are spirits
blend as our bodies make contact be a
fucking poet poet the power of the poet
and the musician in this way is to
bridge the gap between our natural
impulses and longings of the heart and
the actual event and like I said it
brings so much more pleasure to the
actual event she'll read that I promise
she's a woman who's in touch with her
body she'll melt
and when the opportunity does arise and
the moment the climax comes which you're
going to increase the climax by writing
the damn poem it'll be that much more of
a beautiful experience so that's my
invitation dude it's my invitation all
you guys a little romantic sometimes
done