what's up guys today we've got a great
question from one of our friends he's 25
years old he's made a great many of
accomplishments in his life he's an
award-winning athlete he's won a
scholarship to college and now he's in a
place where he's looking for spiritual
enlightenment and he's been reading
books of men like Eckhart Tolle and
exploring this idea that perhaps I
should set aside the ego because there's
more to life than these worldly
accomplishments the things that I've
been able to achieve with regard to
school and sports no longer gratify me
they no longer bring me pleasure because
they're all ego seeking goals and maybe
I'd be better off setting aside goals
because it's all icky ego stuff or so
he's been led to believe or so you've
been led to believe because you've been
reading the books of and listening to
the lectures of gentlemen like Eckhart
Tolle who I happen to respect greatly
and I've listened to all of his audios
and I've read all of his books and I
happen to think that he has an
incredible understanding of spirituality
but at the same time I think you're only
hearing what he's here at saying with
one ear there is a second half of the
story and for Eckhart Tolle to have
reached you with his message means that
he must have some fucking goals the
dude's been on Oprah you don't get on
Oprah by letting this spirit carry you
because you have no goals because goals
are evil and of the there of carnal
desire passion and instinct passion and
sexuality have no room in higher
consciousness and spirituality or so you
would believe if you only hear what the
man is saying you got to look also don't
ignore what you see because you hear
beautiful language because you hear
beautiful things I often tell you look
with your eyes before you judge look at
someone's body look at Eckhart Tolle he
writes books that are New York Times
bestsellers he travels the world to give
you a mission a message
about not achieving goals because it's
all ego he's an egomaniac I'm an
egomaniac
Jesus was an egomaniac you need the ego
because the ego gives you the sword and
the shield to approach life with it is a
powerful manifestation of it's a
powerful fruit of a balanced intuition
balls sexuality and balance passion
communion community love carnal desire
and passion you can understand that the
neocortex the new part of our brain the
one that gives us this idea that perhaps
there is a spiritual world and allows us
to analyze and be intelligent and to
consider the afterlife simply because we
have the ability to look in the past and
see into the future it's a double-edged
sword mind you we begin to think that
it's somehow better than our passion and
our our carnal our sexual desire because
those things are ego right passion
passion passion agitates the body it
makes you anxious right because you want
to achieve something because I'm so
fucking passionate about it and those
get me started in our third and and
really our first our most base form of
consciousness if I were to go back you
know I mentioned the neocortex is that
one that spiritual one that one that the
ego
might want to get attached to and say
that I'm going to transcend the carnal
desires and the passions of the body but
we also have the mammalian brain that's
of the heart it's an older brain than
our Eckhart Tolle brain that are
spiritual floating on clouds
woowoo brain I have no desires I'm going
to sit here and write best-selling books
and appear on Oprah it's all bullshit
we're all bullshitters he had a seat to
the bullshit Eckhart Tolle bless his
heart
I love him bullshit okay I'm a
bullshitter
Jesus was a bullshitter we use these
tools to reach people so that the fruits
of our passion the fruits of our
understanding the fruits of our
intuition might reach the lives of
others you've got the understanding of
the heart which is oneness community
communication love passion and you've
also got the understanding of the
reptilian brain found in the body with
our intuition our sexuality you know
they say that reptiles don't feel love
they just it's all about safety survival
and sex for them but we have that in us
too in fact that's our oldest brain it's
completely egotistical full of passion
unbridled passion and foolishness
foolhardy fool heartedness to think that
we can somehow live a balanced life on
earth and you've chosen to live here
you've got to eat and shit but somehow
we can transcend and become spiritual
and have no passions and ignore our
sexual desire and intuition I say I
speak like this because that's how I
could totally dogs
I'm gonna put it this way I'm gonna I
want to be egotistical with you for a
moment I'm gonna share my idea about how
this whole thing works right cuz that's
all we all are like I said we've all got
our own brand of bullshit back at all
these brand of bullshit is to sit down
and just meditate and write best-selling
books don't forget mine to get inside
your body feel your body recognize
appreciate your sexuality breathe deeply
open up the passion that resides in you
and express everything that is bubbling
up inside your body in such a way that
we empower inspire embolden and support
everyone in our world balance our
passion with
intelligence and intuition and you know
what the game looks like when you play
that way because that could totally will
tell you that if you play his game like
it's always about the deathbed it's
always about when we're gonna die
because we're all fucking die and guess
what
whatever you accomplished or don't
accomplish mainly the way you feel at
the moment of your death there's a good
chance you're gonna carry that with you
in the afterlife or wherever you go
right that energy that animates us
doesn't disappear when we when our body
dies right it it sort of makes its way
into the higher consciousness so the
collective consciousness do you want to
carry frustration for not accomplishing
those goals those passions not
fulfilling those desires in a balanced
way they're got to be balanced when you
die and say but I was a nice guy and
smile off knowing it's really didn't do
shit or and here's my invitation here's
the way I'd like to see it done here's
the way our warrior ancestors would move
forward carrying the phrase today is a
good day to die boys I want to be spent
I'm going to give all of my passion room
to be expressed I'm going to use all of
my sexual energy to fuel my journey
towards fulfilling goals I'm gonna set
lofty goals and I'm gonna kill myself
every day to achieve them the goals will
be of the heart passion meaning my
family my work my deep desire to share
the messages and the words and the the
feelings in my body with those
you can receive it I have big goals
about this expressing my sexuality I
want to scream I want to yell I want to
trust my gut when it tells me something
I want to enjoy sex with my wife till I
die my last day I want to fuck her like
I did when I was 16 all of my body all
of my energy that's why I exercise I
want to give it all to the day I die and
I want to use all that passion and all
that animal Carnot sexual energy to move
myself in the world in such a way that I
achieve big goals coz when I die I'm
leaving a stamp
I'm leaving ripples ripples that are so
far-reaching that on the outer edges
they don't even know where their
inspiration came from and my soul will
smile I want to go out with a bang and
that means I'm going to infuse you ego
passion and balls sexuality and
everything I do I'm gonna play the game
really fucking hard
but
there's a big butt
very important but a balanced but right
not like one cheeks the same size as the
other but a but that makes the yen
perfect because of the yen the Acker
totally perfect because of the Elliott
Hulse the Zorba perfect because of the
Buddha but it's all a fucking game dude
who cares it has no meaning
there's significance a tremendous amount
of significance to it look around look
at a fucking leaf I'm looking at trees
right now look at the leaf look at all
the intricacy associated with the goal
that that acorn had to make these
fucking leaves what about a tree that
bears fruit that's the dropped in the
soil and all the nourishment associated
with the Mother Earth and the Sun
beating down with all of its solar
energy to bring forth that fruit and
that tree its desire its ego to want to
branch out and create fruit that the
tree can't even eats the ripples of the
trees ego desire to produce that fruit
lives on in me because when I bite it
I'm infused with nourishment that fuels
my passion that stimulates my sexuality
that sharpens my mind so that I like the
tree can bear fruit as well my friend
don't sit and meditate don't sit and
wait for life to go by while you smile
at the clouds
do something worthy produce fruit you
use meditation and you use objectivity
and you use detachment and you use deep
breathing so that you can have the
energy to move forward with your ego
gratification
we need more egomaniacs
we need more balanced egomaniacs
don't let the game carry you away don't
get carried away with goal achievement
in that you don't bring the heart
meaning passion and also the golden rule
we're brothers and sisters if you stop
on someone's face and are in just to any
one of your brothers on your way to ego
gratification on goal achieving you're
imbalanced try again you're going about
it the wrong way if you suppress your
sexuality
if you ignore your gut you will not have
the deep primordial instinctual animal
Holy Ghost power that has gotten us to
where we are as a race of human beings
go set some goals kill yourself
achieving them and smile when you let it
go
done