guys today we got a question from our
buddy Brad who says that he's at a fork
in the road in his life now before I
begin the very first thing that he
wanted to bring my attention is that he
took the call to adventure he watched
one of my videos and he found that he
was moving down the path towards loser
ship he was kind of stuck at home
playing video games smoking weed and
generally being a nobody so what he did
was he packed up and moved across
country and took a job in sales and and
and that's a great choice because the
job in sales forces you to sink or swim
when you work in sales you don't have
the luxury of a salary and someone there
to catch you all the time even though
you're fucking up in sales you got to go
out there and you got to bust your ass
otherwise shit doesn't happen so if many
of these many of you guys were watching
this if you're looking for a career
you're not exactly sure what you want to
go do going into a career in sales
because it is a form of personal
development you've got to develop a lot
of character traits a lot of virtues in
order to succeed in sales and and what
our friend has discovered as he packed
up moved out and took a job in sales is
that the field of salesmanship offers a
lot of mentorship and this is true some
of the greatest mentors that I've had
have been in sales in fact Brian Tracy
who I listen to almost all of his audio
programs is a sales coach and and our
friend has met many sales mentors one of
the reasons why this works so well is
because the mentors usually benefit from
having their new salesman do well but at
the same time these mentors have become
sexist successful themselves they offer
great benefits to young salesmen it's a
fantastic profession
and our friend is doing really well
specifically because he's met so many
wonderful mentors men older men who have
become successful he says not only in
finances but also in their family and
their men that he would like to emulate
and he's doing a wonderful job the thing
is that he left behind him many good
friends who he had already started a
business with
the business hadn't made any money and
it still hasn't made any money and in
fact when I friend packed up and left
the business kind of falling apartment
when he left his friend called him and
said hey what about this business that
we started and and our buddy Brad said
look guys you know I'm gonna moving on
in fact doesn't seem like things are
going any further and all of a sudden
his friends are mobilized and excited
they're like whoa whoa wait a second no
we're gonna do this business bro you
can't leave us we're gonna do it
meanwhile they had been pot heads and
lazy bums just like Brad was previously
but now they're energized there's they
see Brad doing big things and he left
them I can understand you're at a fork
in the road and uh and there are few
things that I want to offer you you had
an interesting crossing the road uh fork
in the road ah and I'll say it like this
the fork in the road is between your
immaturity and maturity boyhood and
manhood
you've already stepped on the road
towards manhood you're on your way to
becoming a man you're doing wonderful
things but you've made some decisions
and you've got some baggage left over
from your boyhood that you're going to
have to squash now I don't like to offer
advice too much in these videos I like
to offer perspectives or a way for you
to get to look at the question behind
the question that's really what I want
to offer simply because I truly believe
that you're damned if you do you're
damned if you don't
and that successful people don't make
the right decisions they make their
decisions right so whatever you choose
it's not about the circumstance this is
about how you choose to approach the
circumstances that will make you a
success and you've already made some
pretty significant choices in a
direction that I believe is the better
choice but you still got this baggage
with your friends
so what do you do a part of Brad's issue
is that he he knows he wants to be an
entrepreneur and he doesn't want to work
for someone for the rest of his life and
being in sales although there's a ton of
autonomy associated with it your your
your selling products or services for
another company and Brad says I'd like
to be an entrepreneur meaning I want my
own and don't we all it's an idea that
is very pleasing to most but I don't
think most of us understand what's
involved there and I know for a fact
that I didn't know what was involved
there when I began as an entrepreneur my
name was go into entrepreneurship for
the wrong reasons I know I did it worked
out for me because of some of the good
things I got going up myself but my
reason for going into entrepreneurship
and I'm sure many of you will this will
resonate with you
is because I just wanted to say fuck you
to everyone who would have been my boss
or my patriarch in some way someone who
is above me I don't want anybody telling
me what to do
I don't want anybody making decisions
for me I don't want anybody guiding me
and directing me in my life and making
me do things that I don't want to do see
so for me it's a lot of selfishness and
fear fear of of the designs of those who
might be above me right and this is all
this is covered in a very interesting
book that I mentioned last week called
iron John and why so many men become
distrustful of the patriarchy has a lot
to do with their relationships with
their fathers but regardless I wanted to
say fuck you I'm doing it myself and
many of you might say the same thing
because you don't want anybody telling
you what to do
I'd really like to go down that route
with regard to what happens in the home
with the father and why that creates
this distrustful niceness in us but
maybe for another video but otherwise
you know listen to the audio program
iron John it's all about becoming a man
so resonates with many of you so I took
that adventure into entrepreneurship you
know it was easy for me to cut off ties
with my friends because that's the way I
do things I couldn't run I don't have
very many heavy attachments to people in
circumstances from the past to any great
degree I'm a visionary I move forward
but you have you got your hands tangled
you've got your hands tied up now I'm
going to tell you to chop off your
relationship with your friends but what
I can offer you some perspectives on
what you're actually asking for if you
decide to be an entrepreneur especially
with these guys who happen to be their
losers versus the wonderful world of
sales and all of the advantages of
having mentors you see when I started I
didn't have any mentors and I remember
day after day really even praying for an
older man to come and show me his wisdom
I really wanted a mentor badly I
remember sitting in my I could see
myself now in my in the townhouse that I
lived in when I first moved here sitting
at my computer trying to figure out what
to do I'm reading audio or reading books
and I'm listening to audio programs and
I had very many virtual mentors but I
wanted someone here to say Elliot let me
help you Elliot let me show you what I
think about what you're doing right now
Elliot let me give you some advice based
on the experiences that I've had I wish
I had that I begged for that I pleaded
for that I paid for that one mentorship
program cost me five grand and it was a
weekend long I can tell you that it
changed my life but I didn't get a
mentor is called the mentorship but it
was really in a way for me to learn some
new things about the profession I was
going into internet marketing then I
signed up for another mentorship program
which was virtual I spoke to the mentor
one time I paid about five grand for
that one
also and to this day I still pay for
various mentors I pay I pay out of my
nose for many mentors but I didn't have
one that just wanted to work with me
because of the pursuit because we had to
say we were pursuing the same goal as in
sales or as in a coach and athlete
relationship which I missed greatly you
know I really I really relished in
having a coaches when I was in college
in high school didn't have that out in
the world I was lucky that there were a
few men that I met at some of these
mentorship programs that were bit older
than me and then they just took a liking
to me and they we exchanged email
addresses and one guy in particular Bob
Bob Hess Bob watches my video sometime
he said you got a kid there's something
going on good with you I think you'll
beat you're well on your way let me help
you out here and he sent me some
information and resources to that really
actually taught me how to meditate he
got me into meditation he got me into
visualization and an affirmation he
taught me about goal-setting he taught
me about a lot of things that like I had
only read about but this man through
email and phone communication out and
out of the kindness of his own heart he
lived in Wisconsin I lived in Florida I
mean we couldn't be more opposite
decided to help me and serve me and I
was grateful for him I share these
stories with you just to give you some
perspective on where I am and how I got
where I am and some of the struggles
that I have had in hopes that perhaps
will help you make a decision about what
you do henceforth again I don't want to
help you make the decision that I don't
want to tell you what to do but if I was
in your shoes and in a way I had been I
would say take the mentorship not for
anything more than the fact that you'll
get to be able to be nourished by the
wisdom of older men we need this man we
need this tremendously our world has
fallen into the grips of anarchy
in and pain and dysfunction for many
different reasons one of which a
significant one of which is the lack of
male mentorship even if you do have a
father in your home many of our fathers
are so busy working outside the home
that the boy doesn't get to see what the
father actually does that's where the
distrust comes from daddy leaves daddy
comes back I don't know what the fuck he
did for eight hours things seem to be
going well and every once in a while he
disciplines me I don't know what this
man is doing there's a sense of distrust
that comes when a father leaves the home
for many hours and the son doesn't know
what the father is doing one of the ways
rectify that is to bring our children to
our work or let them see our work but
that's you know now I'm talking about
restructuring Society but you know what
society is structured by people and
people make choices about how they're
going to live so my friend Brad of
course this is a long I'm going on and
on and on in this video about various
different things and hopefully you can
pick some gems out of it here in a place
where you get an opportunity to be reef
honored some of these men will be father
like figures to you and you need this
and you will be working with them on a
daily basis you see what they do and
they're they're fully transparent with
you about how they go about earning
their living and at the same time
teaching you how to do what they do like
our fathers used to do in our ancestors
days I'm also going to finish this video
with a call to action to all fathers
with sons but although you're a good
father I'm sure you are I had a good
father
III do my best to be a good father
myself one of the things that we weren't
taught one of the things that society
doesn't value nearly as much as it used
to and one of the reasons why things
don't look the way we would potentially
like them to look especially with our
sons is because they grow a form of
distrust towards us because they don't
know exactly what we do
I meet boys on a daily basis that come
into my gym and I say what is your dad
do I'm not really sure
and not only are many of them not sure
what they do but they're almost ashamed
sometimes their dad does some shit that
their dad doesn't even believe in I
sells insurance or something but he
fucking hates it and complains about his
boss every day no wonder why you don't
bring your son to work because you don't
believe in the work that you do how
could you believe in the work that you
do and you if you grew up in a home
where you didn't even know what your
father did it's a sick sad cycle of
dysfunction that spirals down he'll make
it an effort that's my only that's my
only offer here I don't want to tell
anybody what to do once again and of
course I'm talking to many different
people in many different ways in this
particular video
find a way you see when you know what
your values are this is very important
one of the things that we forget about
very often our values what are your
values what are your values what are
your values what do you value look at
that question deeply spend a lot of time
on that question question that question
when you've answered it you should
always be considering your values
now when you figured out what you value
and if you have children and a son in
particular because that's what this
video is about I guarantee you that one
of your values will be to grow this
young boy into a well-adjusted
contributing masculine man that I could
be proud of someday every man who has a
son feels this way about his boy
of course there are fathers who have
left their boys that's a totally
different story and I make no judgments
they're up I'm talking to those who were
still living with their sons who are
fathering their sons find a way that we
can bring our boys up not just in our
shadow but with our light live a life
where you shine a light and help your
son shine his light with you of course
he's going to have his own ideas and
he's gonna have his own convictions and
values too but let him see your light
and if you don't know what your light is
come back to the original question what
do you value and when you align your
life with your values your light will
shine and the future generations of men
will grow your legacy will be powerful
and potent if you consider this one
thing done