we got this kind of funny but pretty
serious question for my buddy Zach he
goes how do you put alpha males into
perspective by this I mean that there
are men who are taller stronger funnier
better-looking better fighters some all
the same package what does it help the
alternative to view these people instead
of looking at them as people who could
potentially be fucking your girlfriend
oh yes sir right I mean cuz there's
probably a good chance he's fucking your
girlfriend well I mentioned this before
and I want to bring it up here once
again because we need to go in before we
go out in other words we got to figure
out what our alpha is now the Alpha that
you describe is a evolutionary alpha I
mean they're just bigger stronger
better-looking men genetically there's
nothing you could fuckin do and the
worst thing you could do is compare
yourself to him because you're gonna
resent him and you're gonna hate
yourself and that never works right
whatever he's doing whoever he's fucking
that's fine that's great that's his gift
to himself and gift to the world that's
the way the the great alpha energy right
that's the way that's why that's why the
universal cosmic cosmic Alpha is working
through him I am different words for God
was working through him and that's fine
dude
you know don't hate congratulate that's
fine about him fucking your girlfriend
hey look you know it's women are
attracted to there are particular types
of women let me let me rephrase that
because this gets to my point there are
particular types of women that are that
have no choice but to buckle at their
knees when they see him I mean he the
minute he walks in the door they know
women know who they're gonna fuck with
in two minutes
the minute he walks through the door it
doesn't matter if she's married or not
or like it's he has a fucking hypnotic
trance on her and whether or not it
actually happens the energy is there
she's open right what are you going to
fucking do but know also that that is
just one type of attraction and that if
you go in and you develop your
gifts which are not so obvious which are
not so extroverted you know maybe you're
maybe you're an incredible poet maybe a
writer
I mean think about think about these
artists that write music that are really
goofy looking goofy looking ugh little
guys with I think about um Dylan Bob
Dylan Bob Dylan's a weird-looking
motherfucker
I mean with his hair and that fucking
nose and the way he plays the guitar
it's it's like he's singing the songs of
music that draw women's hearts and and
wetting their vaginas you know and he
and he's a quirky little he's not alpha
you know I'm just using his and him as
an example I mean look at Michael
Jackson lovin - Alpha about him except
for the fact that he's got an incredible
inner gift a muse
if you will that causes him to predict
what caused him to create incredible
music you know whatever your position of
your opinion of him he could probably
have sex with almost everything
anybody's girlfriend if he wanted to
back then so what you got to do is you
got to show your potency do you see
women are attracted to potency and
potency doesn't always mean tall
handsome strong it could also mean what
does he produce because potency is a
term that describes your ability to
reproduce right and some reproduction is
very obviously physical he's tall I mean
he's just physically dominating with it
makes a woman swoon but there's also
spiritual potency well he writes such
incredible poems or he he builds he's an
architect that creates hazing elaborate
buildings I'm he sure see his blueprints
or he plays the violin with such
intensity that it's that it literally
moves me physiologically you ever listen
to music as why music is so fucking
amazing
it moves you physiologically like you
can you can pull a woman's heartstrings
and wet her pants by playing a
particular piece with us
saxophone right the sex affirm do you
understand the key here is not to go and
find something that you can get bitches
with cuz it could very easily turn into
that oh you know if I learn to play the
saxophone bitch is gonna be knocking at
my door that's not the case because the
play where you're coming from with that
is manipulation where you want to be
coming from is a true sense of your
potency what can I produce that is a
pure byproduct of my masculine energy I
often say how are you having sex with
the world
what are you producing in the world how
are you dropping your seeds into the
world in order to create something
brand-new and when a woman can see a man
who's due does that she becomes very
attracted let's go to our man shit yeah
I'm just making videos right now give me
a second I'm almost done yeah so she'll
be very attracted to that because it
shows your potency so I'm going to talk
to a friend right now but essentially
figure out what it is that you can offer
as a representation of your potency of
your masculinity she will or other women
will recognize that and in that they
will be attracted to you don't measure
yourself up against anyone physically
more dominating than you discover your
strengths develop them create something
that is a value and people will be
attracted to it done