hey what's up guys in today's letter
that I wrote fresh this morning just
like a dozen donuts you could read down
below I spoke a little bit about the
fiery fury enraged it rises up in my
body when I find myself in certain
situations that elicit anger all right
and I describe it as a fiery rage in my
body in my chest because emotions are
physical I've spoken about this before
and when you find yourself being
confronted with a stimulus that causes a
spontaneous response it often happens in
our lungs in our belly and our muscular
system our ability to breathe even in
our head headaches happen jaw clenching
it happens in our body first the first
spontaneous response to a stimulus be it
anger frustration sadness confusion is
usually physical as always physical the
videos that most people aren't aware of
the physiological changes in their
bodies and they get carried away by the
emotion anger grips them and hypnotizes
them and they get carted off into some
crazy world where teeth are lost lips
are busted and paddy wagons are cutting
people off to jail cells right because
you let anger get the best of you that
physiological response well oftentimes
end up in fucking somebody up right so
my letter and my story for you today
revolves around an idea that was shared
to with me by Stephen Covey in one of
his fascinating books where he says
between stimulus and response there's a
space and in that space you'll find self
mastery today we're going to talk a
little bit how to find that space so
that you don't file off the handle no
end up doing stupid shit that you really
will regret later on and honestly it
doesn't have to be just anger you know
if you find yourself in a situation
where you're being seduced by a woman
and you're married or with someone else
you know there's a stimulus and there's
a spontaneous response a rock-hard one
that if you're not aware you're not
standing on your own two feet and your
own greatness
we haven't ascended the throne to alpha
groundedness just yet then you can get
carted off right so you end up having a
situations where you're beating people
up and you're committing adultery if
you're not aware of this space the
physiological response and how to
respond in a resourceful way so um that
word respond you know I slowed down when
I said it because we've got to
understand that there's a there's a
there's a big difference between a
response and a reaction and what most
people do is react right someone steps
on your toes someone says something that
really pisses you off or does something
mean to someone you love whatever the
case may be the the ungrounded
uninitiated will fly off the handle and
in either a lash out or in many cases
turn inward and it eats them up on the
inside because they don't say anything
right I spoke about you know some people
having low charge some people having
high charge high charge people will
explode people like myself and many of
you watching this one something will
happen in will fly out the handle
explode low charge people interesting
they're either too ambivalent to get
angry right this is the case sometimes
when we suppress our emotions shit that
you should be angry about you don't get
angry at that and then there's also
those who the response the reaction is
physiological it's always physiological
but you instead of allowing it to
process allowing you to blow off the
steam you bite your tongue and you suck
it down into your body where it grows in
its physiological turmoil all right I
should have said this I should have done
that who is he you start you start
sieving on the inside and that's just um
that's a recipe for all kinds of
cancerous disorders and pain stress
disease within your body right
unresolved unexpressed
emotion so today let's talk about that
space between stimulus and response not
reaction but response Stephen Covey says
that you know that's the space that
allows us to cultivate our self mastery
life mastery and it's for a number of
reasons number one when someone
confronts you or Scituate you're
confronted with a situation and you
pause for a moment you might want to
find an anchor for your pausing and then
breathe in order to you know assess the
situation right assess the person many
times a person's attitude is a
projection of how they actually feel
about themselves so a lot of times you
know you can go and punch him in the
mouth but at the same time like he
already feels shitty about himself
anyway and that has nothing to do with
you so now you've tangled yourself up in
his negative karma and it's usually not
worth it so an anchor like I say is
something like you know oftentimes what
I'll do is when I find myself in
situations where I would normally
respond because of the changes in my
physiology and the ultimate and the UM
and the way I would risk going act
because of it right fire in the chest
fire in the chest means
ah I simply put my hand on my chest and
I wait hmm take a few breaths now you're
totally control when you don't say
anything whenever you catch yourself in
a situation where you know especially
someone's really Jabberjaw anxious or
someone's really uh attacking you
verbally I'm not talking about you know
they're coming at you with her with a
weapon over their fists I mean in that
case you just you gotta fuck them up but
if they're talking action and they're
really trying to get at you I placed my
hand on my chest and that gives you not
only control of your physiology it not
only gives you control of the time but
it has a subtle remote control effect on
the other person because now you're
taking the wind out of their sails
they're expecting you to
Spahn but if you pause and put your hand
on your heart in order to consult with
your higher intelligence that person is
confronted with a pattern interrupt and
they have to pause too sometimes I'll
put my hands in my pocket because if I
don't I might choking bark ah so I put
my hands in my pocket hmm and pause when
you pause you allow your physiology to
relax you get a lot of the other person
to remote control to relax and you also
get an opportunity to think for a moment
the first thing I try to think about is
where is this person coming from try to
understand what's going on
what is the at what is the real
situation here right now is the real
situation that this should turn into a
battle physical fight or the situation
such that I think you misunderstood
something or maybe I'm not understanding
something that's for clarification not
exactly sure what's going on right now
but maybe you can help me understand or
if you can see very clearly that this is
not your problem and that this person is
wrestling with something on our own
offering compassion sometimes is the
kings thing to do it's a very stately
and royal attitude of blessing when
someone comes to you and they were there
ready to bark you down but you pause and
recognize their hurt and say hmm I can
see where you're coming from I totally
understand why you're upset let me see
if I can help you these all sound like
passive weak yielding responses
especially compared to the fiery fury
fists clenching teeth grinding that is
typical for many of us but I want to
also point to remind you of Sun Tzu the
author of art of war and one of his
ideas in this book that revolve around
bloody victories and although you might
be able to destroy the person in you're
confronted with is it really worth the
bloodbath Sun Tzu talks about going into
battles that uh that you know you will
ultimately win but will lose too much
blood and says that perhaps you should
really eight you might be able to win
the battle you might be able to verbally
confront the person in other words have
that clever thing to say that smashes
them in their mouth verbally but is it
worth the blood is it worth losing that
person's friendship that person's
respect is it worth losing your own
poise is it worth losing your own
grounding is it worth losing your own
liver your own physiology your own
ability to breathe I don't know you need
to ask yourself because like I said
before sometimes they're typing you just
need to fuck someone up but I'd say that
a good 75 80 maybe 90 percent of the
time if we look for that space between
the stimulus and our reaction or
response we will find that we can draw
energy back down into our bodily
intelligence take grounded control of
ourselves the other person in the
situation and respond like a true king
by offering either space inquiry or
compassion
standing in your greatness means making
your feelings your groundedness your
ability to navigate circumstances number
one and the need to win the need to beat
someone they need to be right and
righteous subservient to the stronger
version of yourself
done