question from our buddy William Dean in
Norway really good question because it's
one that I have dealt with personally
he's trying to build his business right
and right now he's broke he does not
have very much money to to invest in his
business much less invest in healthy
food right and he knows because
obviously if he's come here through my
fitness channels and whatnot
that your performance in every area of
your of your life is contingent upon
your health if you are eating crappy
food you're thinking poorly you can't
perform well in business and
relationships in school right if you're
tired if you're weak if you're sick
you're sad you're depressed everything
that you do is going to move from that
place so focusing on the things that
you're going to do matters far less in
the Elliott Hulse model of success then
focusing on strengthening you becoming
stronger version of yourself absolutely
everything so when I first started my
gym and the various businesses a diamond
and I was dead ass broke and racking up
credit cards I told the story the other
day I would drive my wife and I would
drive right an hour to a wholefoods
that was in Sarasota when we lived in
South st. Pete to get healthy food and
put it on our credit card because we
were Deborah I didn't I didn't have
money for for gas much less you know
organic healthy food but I went into
debt and drove you know several miles
almost an hour once a week to get really
healthy food because it wasn't available
in my city at the time you know it's a
couple years ago as I was building my
business and the reason why I did that
is because I knew that if I could think
clear if I was healthy if I was vibrant
if I was vital I could approach I can
attack the things in my business with
that much more veracity I was that much
more better at doing the things that I
had to do now that did take away from
the resources that I would be able to
allocate towards my business but it did
not matter because I was stronger so I
was able to make do with being more
creative do you understand
this this is one of those things that I
just Intuit intuitively felt even when I
was in college like I remember a lot of
kids would stay up to like three four
o'clock in the morning cramming for a
test so they could wake up in the
morning like after were like not sleep
at all but get up in the morning after
like maybe half an hour of sleep and
like they've got crap and crusts in
their eyes and then I go into the
classroom and they crammed I don't know
what the fuck that actually means I mean
your brain can only hold on to so much
you can't cram your fucking brain but
anyway and then go into the class and
they're like oh fucking tired and stupid
and shit but they crammed all night long
me on the other hand I'd stay out till
about ten o'clock I'd read what I can if
I wasn't prepared I'd say fuck it at
least I'm gonna get a good night's sleep
and I'd sleep when I wake up I go to the
classroom and I'm bright and vibrant and
vital and I'm willing to do whatever it
takes to perform so that I went in that
test or so that I passed that test this
dude he stayed up all night but he looks
like shit and you can't think and you
asked them a question and you're like
kidding spells own damn name you gotta
take care of yourself first you will be
a better performer in everything that
you do if you worry about yourself if
you take care of yourself first even in
building your business your resources
have to be allocated in such a way that
you are providing for your health and
strength first even before the other
people in your life even before your
business even before school even before
training even before all the things that
you want to do or take care of our only
reflection of you in your health and
your strength your vitality save your
money buy healthy food you don't have to
buy lots of it you know you might lose
some weight I lost a lot of weight when
I was building my business but I only
ate the highest of quality foods just to
need that much of it because I was broke
and then use the health and strength
that you have the vitality and the power
that you have because of what you've
done to take care of yourself to attack
your business to attack your world good
luck