so if you've been watching my videos
long enough you know that I often invite
you to listen to your heart and to
follow your balls and I'm not the first
person to say that you've probably heard
people say that you should follow your
heart or trust your gut instinct when I
say balls it's very synonymous with the
lower portion of your torso balls gut
kind of go together if you've been
watching long enough you also know that
I use the metaphor that describes three
types of consciousness that is within
the human being in the metaphor that I
use is the head the heart and the balls
but that could also be likened unto the
idios order or the neocortex cortex
medulla Father Son Holy Ghost
there's this triune dignity of man were
united as three parts in our
consciousness another way to say it is
that we've got a rational thinking
calculating mind we've got our
passionate feeling mind and then we've
got our intuitive instinctual mind so
you've got you literally got three Minds
interesting thing that I I that I've
recognised I grew up as a Catholic so
when we pray we do this we'd go in the
name of the Father the Son parting to
the heart to the Holy Ghost
this movement represents our horizontal
consciousness or animal consciousness or
instinct animals horizontal you know
think horizontal forces dogs cats they
have an instinct that allows them to get
through life successfully and we also
have this horizontal thinking so when I
say and listen to your heart
trust your gut or trust your balls it is
literally the the Sun or the passion
part of the human being and the
instinctual part of the human being as
opposed to the rational part of the
human being our triune unity our Trinity
and be a better way to say it so we live
in an environment and we live in a
culture where there's all emphasis is
put towards educating the head brain the
Father right
the neocortex the rational brain what
happens when we go to school is they
teach us how to shut down our body ie
sit and they stimulate they teach us to
stimulate the workings of the rational
mind that's why school is a lot of
memorizing denison the majority of what
you're learning in school and what the
world teaches us as values memorization
you'll understand something about
memorization memorization means that
there is a fact or there's information
that you have to regurgitate nothing
wrong with memorizing or memory in fact
it's the reason why human beings are the
flowers of the earth we have this kapap
capacity to remember in our conscious
mind not just physiologically but also
in our computer we literally have like
computers in that way but all
information is dead all facts are dead
not necessarily bad dead is in you know
they're evil
but that they are based on past events
creativity never comes out of the past
in and of itself true creativity is a
union with the present past fats also
help that's why I often say that I remix
ideas because their past ideas but I
remix them into the moment true
creativity happens only in the moment
that's the beautiful beauty of poetry
and art is that it's spontaneous that's
really the word that I'm looking for
spontaneity creativity is spontaneity
spontaneity only happens in just think
of it physiologically in your heart and
in your your horizontal consciousness so
your heart beats spontaneously
you don't have to think about what your
heart is going to do hey can we talk in
a moment I'm real busy thank you sir
all right cool this is my friend hangs
out here every once in a while so your
heart beats spontaneously you don't have
to do the beating of your heart in the
same way that the instinct that you
would follow or could potentially
recognize respect and move through life
with happen spontaneously you don't know
dog doesn't have to be told how to bark
there's these things that happen
spontaneously
so when I say
listen to and follow your heart and your
balls it literally is really literally
means get in touch with the spontaneity
of your body that's why I spent so much
time talking about the physical health
of the body in relation to navigating
your life so we want to do everything up
here we want to fix our life from up
here life happens spontaneously life
doesn't happen based on facts and
information those are just tools that we
use to that they're like icing on the
cake for our ability to navigate life
but really the power that resides in the
human being is in his heart and in his
holy ghost in his instinct so with that
understanding how do you do it Eliot
what do you what do you mean when you
say listen how could I hear my heart my
balls well what you might be expecting
is voices right you think that you're
going to hear voices like you know
Abraham goes to the top of the mountain
and God says right this is not
necessarily the way it happens those are
stories that help us understand that
there is another intelligence a more
subtle intelligence that's guiding us
that intelligence like I said resides in
your body below your neck if you stay in
your head you're going to be waiting for
voices and if you hear voices then you
might need to get your head checked what
you're looking for is the feeling the
spontaneous feelings in your body
oftentimes they come the when they say
that people make decisions they say that
they make decisions emotionally and then
justify rationally that's because your
first instinct you know someone says
trust your first instinct or the first
word is the real one so if you're having
conversation with someone and they used
it first the first thing that comes out
it's usually the one that's the the most
authentic there it's the true one
because you haven't had time to
rationalize it so one way is to get in
touch with and trust your first instinct
right if you're whether if you're
deciding whether or not you should take
a particular action with school or
career or relationships whatever the
gates may be and you had a
instinct you know the first thing that
came to you is it's not right but then
you know mom and dad said and school
said and the government believes and
everybody else is doing and then you can
you take all that information all that
dead stuff gets into your head and you
start doing this right now you're not
listening to your heart your dollars
into your balls in fact you're building
a case against your heart and balls
based on facts and information which is
dead that other people have given you
based on their experience and most of
their experiences aren't even their
experiences because their listen what
other people told them to do so really
you're following a dead path that first
instinct should be one that you consider
heavily that's your oftentimes your gut
telling you what to do that usually
comes from your gut that usually comes
from your balls you'll feel it very low
in your body if you're lucky I've
navigated my life and made the best
choices in my life based on gut
reactions some of the things that I've
done to get to where I am look like shit
on paper because on paper you've got to
calculate on paper didn't look right for
me to quit my job and start my business
the way it did I did to have four
children and be in debt all those things
it's like pretty stupid if you listen to
the world and you listen to your head
and you put that on paper it's like boy
you're you're going to be doomed but it
was my guts
I followed easier said than done for
some people because we've become so dead
to the spontaneity in our body that we
don't even get that first response what
we start doing what a lot of people
start doing is they start looking around
for what other people will tell them is
the right thing to do you have a
decision to make and instead of
consulting their first response or
consulting the Son and the Holy Ghost
right they want to hear what other
people have to say well you know I'm
gonna run it by this guy oh I love this
one I'm gonna run it by my wife
I want to buy all see what all these
other people say as opposed to following
your own the way you exercise your body
in order to become sensitive to the
language of it is to soften the muscular
system and breathe deeply
you've got to stop for a moment take a
few deep breaths don't you don't have to
make decisions right away but you've got
to become familiar with the instant
spontaneous movement in your body right
be with it be quiet it's a very quiet
subtle fluctuation in the physiology
take your time be quiet and consult with
your body son Holy Ghost right medulla
and cortex it's your it's your feeling
mind and it's your instinctual mind
remember there's a unity of three
there's a there's a triune going on try
unity I'm not saying don't listen to
your head but what I am inviting you to
recognize is that there's an imbalance
in the way that we approach our lives
where the head is taking dominance over
the heart and the book and the gut come
back into touch with your body come back
into the intelligence of your heart and
your balls and then measure it equally
against the information that's been
given to you in your head that's how you
follow your body that's how you trust
your gut and that's how you navigate
life successfully done