we've got a really tough question from
one of our friends here who recently
lost her brother-in-law so her sister
was engaged to get married with a young
man and he was murdered
there was an insurance policy in place
that would have ultimately allowed his
wife to take the money that would allow
her to pay for the house that they were
building together but his mother has
decided that she was gonna step in and
take the money this leaves our friends
sister the young lady who was to be
married to the boy that the man had died
and their child to ultimately face
homelessness so so there's the
possibility that they won't be able to
pay for their home because the money
that would have gone to her is now going
to the young man's mother so during this
time of mourning
there's also it's being tainted by greed
it's being tainted by money issues which
is quite unfortunate because as she
describes they'd like to actually mourn
the loss of their friend but now they're
all worried about losing their her
sister's home and the the old mother is
being very stingy with the money and how
she would describe as greedy and and not
it's very self-serving and not
supporting of the the young lady and her
child what do we do now she's got some
ideas about how to expose this woman but
essentially she's she's making some poor
moral judgments based on what our friend
tells us but she is lawful
she lawfully owns the money according to
the agreement with the insurance company
what if the case maybe the mother does
get the money so there's no real they
can't take her to court or anything like
that so they're looking for ways to
expose her and exact some form of
revenge in order to get back some of the
money all the while feeling very heavy
with grief the loss of their friend so
you know I hate it it hurts my heart
when money comes between love and I
think about me and my brothers and
sisters have had this conversation
before not that my parents have any a
lot of money at all I probably have dead
look like when they die but how would we
handle their estate and of course my
parents are still alive and then you
know we don't know when they might die
but we also we always agree on how we
would deal with it and we look we look
at each other and we smile I can't would
be good we'll be fine and you know
hopefully that will be the case but I
come from a unique place where my family
we actually love each other we're nice
to each other go figure
and so it upsets me and confuses me
actually because of the place that I
come from it confuses me as to how
people allow material objects to get
between what should be the strongest
bonds available to human beings and that
is familial relationship even if they're
not blood-related if they're in-laws
still these are people who have come
into your family have been invited into
your family your tribe you know and not
much means more than that at least to me
so how does she go about it so I'm the
answer that I'm going to give you the
invitation that I'd offer is not going
to be a lot of people are gonna be very
happy with me about this one I'm sure
I'm gonna get a lot of disagreements and
that's fine but this is the way I would
approach it in this way I would invite
you to at least look at it let her have
the money walk away and sever your
emotions from all of sever all of your
hard angry frustrated feelings from the
relationship with her and allow God or
the universe to handle karma which is
really the better way of describing it
karma handle the situation with her
karma is an interesting thing because
the word a lot of people thinks that
like you know karma means if I cut you
somebody's gonna cut me that's not a
show the way it is car
is more of a personal responsibility for
the things that happen in your life and
if this is the way this particular woman
goes about the rest of her life is she
if she's of the particular type of
character that makes choices like this
she's going to be a miserable person and
that misery is going to come back no
matter how much money she's receiving
she's always gonna be a miserable person
because the type of character that she
has who she is it's her doing
that's what karma really translates into
you're doing and this is just a
byproduct of her doing but no to that
because of this type of this type of
doing comes from a ugly place that she's
an ugly person and she's going to get
back ugly you can't so ugly without
getting back ugly because the sower of
ugly is ugly for you too so a particular
thing means you must have it you must be
it so ugly will continue to come back to
her very difficult to deal with
especially when your livelihood is at
stake so now you have your the situation
with our home is being maybe repossessed
and this woman takes the money and she
goes and of course you could say yes let
karma let God deal with her in that in
the way that it should be dealt with and
have trust in that I affirm trust in
that we are our doings our life is our
doings we are personally responsible and
if it looks like if it looks like she's
winning really she's losing she might
even be dying on the inside when she
takes that money you don't know what's
going on there and it really it's none
of your responsibility revenge is not
worth it it's not worth revenge because
now you're tying yourself energetically
to this person it's a marriage when you
go for revenge you're marrying that
person because you you're emotionally
tied in with that individual and you
don't want that especially if they're an
ugly person
leave them alone step away completely
now you have your own situation do not
look at your circumstances
victimhood that's that's really where
you'll fuck it up
if you start looking at your
circumstances as she did this to me and
now I'm fucked because of her now what
you've done is you've taken purse
you've taken the responsibility and
responsibility is a beautiful thing
because when you're responsible it also
means that you're capable
you've taken responsibility and you've
given it to her and now you're it's like
you're being raped there's nothing I can
do it's a it's a very it's a weak place
to put yourself in and it's a weak story
to proceed from take responsibility for
it take responsibility for the fact that
you might be giving the house away and
that you'll be okay don't get caught up
in the same type of idle warship that
your friend the woman is the mother is
tied up in with regard to the material
existence the material things the money
the same way that you feel entitled to
the house that you guys are in and the
same way that you have sentiment towards
some of the things in the house because
this is where your brother-in-law lives
in the same way that your your
emotionally a tie tied to these to these
material objects you're proceeding from
the same place that she's proceeding
from with regard to the money she feels
entitled to the money she's emotionally
attached to the money and she's making
decisions that are hurtful for everyone
associated with the money now the house
it can quickly become your evil could
quickly become your sin you've got to
detach yourself from material existence
material things I am NOT against having
nice things and I this is just a quick
caveat I'm not against having nice
things I'm not against material at all I
like nice things and what nice things
but to be emotionally tied to it
to be personally identified with it is
where we start making these evil choices
that hurt other people hurt ourselves
diminish our personal responsibility for
the circumstances in our life and we
lose empowerment
you're gonna have to cultivate
empowerment in yourself and in your
sister and her family especially after
this this grievous loss and the
circumstances with the with the older
woman so that's it sever ties with her
allow karma to do its work
find a resourceful story of empowerment
that allows you to carry on and detach
from any sentiment that keeps you
shackled to material objects easier said
than done but a worthy philosophy to
carry on carry on in life that will
bring peace to your heart no matter what
circumstances you face done