yo Elliot what's up guys today we got a
question from our buddy Kenny who he and
his friend came up with a grand idea
they were gonna start a business in
Hawaii so he lives in the United States
he and his buddy pack up drive to the
west coast ship themselves over the
Pacific onto the island of hawaii and
there they decide to build their
business and over the course of time
they realize that well maybe this wasn't
such a good idea because it didn't work
out so Kenny's friend decides I'm
packing my shit I'm getting the fuck up
out of here see you next time dude and
Kenny says well I ain't leaving I think
I think it might work i think i could do
something so i ain't leaving so great
Kenny you got a lot of heart there buddy
Kenny's buddy leaves him his van now
Kenny lives in a van Kenny has no money
he has a credit card that he's running
out of credit on and he's kind of uh
he's stuck or he's making himself stuck
because essentially his family has wide
open arms and awaiting for Katie to come
home Kenny just come home you're fucked
up and we're waiting for you it's all
right we still love you Kenny's family
also says Kenny let us send you some
money Kenny we know you're hungry ain't
got no money Kenny let us send you some
money ok he says no fuck that Kenny says
that is honor is too big to do any of
that well you call it Honor I call it
ego stubbornness and trying to be right
you know because somewhere along the
line you believe that it's you you've
been led to believe that you can't make
a mistake you've been led to believe
that you can't fail you're not allowed
to fail because if you fail your honor
will be at stake you've been led to
believe that everything that you go into
you have to achieve the ideal that you
set out for yourself rather than allow
it to be an experience Kenny you have
experience was a great experience was a
great idea I always say follow your
bliss he follows if he followed his
heart he thinks he's in the abyss right
now he says essentially that you know
things it's gonna work out it's gonna
work on us like that crazy-ass gambler
you know that guy who lost it all he's
got let me borrow dolla it's gonna work
out it's gonna work out go home man
that's what you say to that guy that's
what I'm saying to you go home because
being right doesn't serve you the way
that you think it serves you being right
in a situation like this means that if
you fail everyone will say oh but can he
fought to the last end can he fought
till he couldn't fight anymore we all
appreciate and look up to Kenny he's a
martyr you're not a martyr you're a
masochist you don't have to be right you
don't have to succeed and everything
that you do you do have to be fully
present with every experience that you
have so that you get the most out of it
and right now you're suffering so be
fully present with that suffering so
when you do go home you got a good story
to tell at least that's the way I look
at it man done Elliott's it what
[Music]
you