so I have to talk about how the muscular
system is used by the ego to hold back
emotion so over time we've been taught
that it is inappropriate to feel or to
express certain emotions that happen in
the body motions are never wrong they're
actually just happening in the body but
whether or not we express them has been
you know decided by civilization to
either right or wrong the fact is that
they're there and we use the muscular
system to hold those emotions back and
we create what I've termed neurotic
holding patterns this is basically where
the ego uses the muscles to hold back
your emotions and you literally depress
your vital energies this way one of the
areas that hold the most amount of
muscular tension due to holding back or
repressing emotion is the face and in
the same way that we stretch the body so
that we can breathe we stretch the body
to soften the neurotic holding patterns
we we strengthen the body so that we can
become a stronger version of ourselves
we got to consider that the face also
needs to be considered we also have to
stretch mobilize soften massage the
musculature of the face now this week
you guys have noticed I haven't uploaded
very many videos because I am traveling
I'm doing a great deal of driving so I'm
not really able to stretch an exercise
as I typically do so while I've been
driving for hours at a time I have been
using more of the facial bioenergetic
exercises to release trapped emotion to
soften neurotic holding patterns and I'd
like to share some of them with you here
today so the very first thing is you got
to get over this idea of seeming
respectability right our face is how we
meet the world so we're constantly
trying to hold back what is naturally
going on in our face you know what these
fake smiles you know you go around and
you see people with this just on a stone
smile on their face is completely fake
and neurotic and it's bullshit so when
you use these exercises you've got to
get over that those patterns you got to
get over that bullshit idea that you've
got to save face for the world around
you so I'm standing here in downtown
Atlanta and like I just don't
shit you have to just not give a shit to
do stuff like
stretch the jaw muscles right and if you
could hold that if you can hold that for
a good 30 seconds a minute longer you'll
start to really feel the relaxation
throughout your entire skull the jaw
muscles are so tense there so tighten is
so powerful that if you relax them
through
stretching it right you'll feel
tremendously better all over now you
want to like how to contort your face in
many different ways to break up the
muscular tension that's trapped across
the eyes across the mouth things like
holding
sounds help break up the muscular
tension tapping
squeezing like you saw me do here this
particular area holds a shitload
attention as well as the temples
ah
ah so spend some time practicing this
I'm down hearing people like that your
cars are stopping or watching me but I
just don't give a shit you have to just
not give a shit you've got to be willing
to not always say face not always be so
respectable to allow the stronger
version of yourself that has been
imprisoned by the muscular system that
is guarded by the ego which you've been
taught to use against yourself as a
weapon needs to be released do dumb shit
like this but I promise you you will
feel better