so I just put up one of these videos
from my last live event and in it I was
talking about how most of your fears are
bullshit you need to get over yourself
do the thing that your heart is asking
you to do regardless of the external
circumstances basically regardless of
what it looks like you just fucking do
it and the reason why I say that is not
because of what you might get by taking
action in the direction of your dreams
because the goal the prize on the other
end of it is not nearly as powerful it's
who you become when you do the damn
thing right so a lot of people nod their
heads and say yes and ingredients and
would say this sounds like a reasonable
thing but there are a few of you that
are quite fearful and you use stories
and rationalizations as to why this
shouldn't be the case why you should
tiptoe your way around different
circumstances instead of taking bold
action and you've got a good case build
a big case for yourself a good story
around why you shouldn't take action
then there are some of you I've read
some of the comments where you're saying
things like well if you have no fear
then why don't you just go walk through
a neighborhood where there are gangsters
and drug dealers and sing songs so they
can come and attack you now that's just
pure stupidity like what's on the other
end of that like why would anybody want
to do that that means you're an asshole
there's a difference between being a
courageous person and an asshole so what
I want to invite you to do what I want
you to consider is that every single
time you go and do something hard
because that's the other thing a lot of
people their excuses are it's it's
easier said than done it's too hard
right this is really basically what your
your story is that's the story you've
told yourself that it's easier said than
done you know it's kind of hard to do
that well it's supposed to be fucking
hard
look if growing stronger as the metaphor
I use
because we all relate to weight training
because the majority of you here because
you enjoy my strength training and
weight training and bodybuilding rants
if growing stronger and building muscle
we're fucking easy you'd have no reason
to go to the gym you'd have no there
would be no growth if there was no
challenge and that's my invitation to
you is to realize that it's supposed to
be fucking hard it's supposed to be
difficult if it wasn't difficult then
there'd be no growth there would be no
resistance there'd be nothing to force
you to grow stronger with and that's why
I say the most important reason the most
important thing the most important gift
that you receive by taking action in the
direction of your dreams is not
attaining your fucking dream it's you
growing stronger and becoming a stronger
version of yourself
through the challenges through the
resistance and because it's hard
[Music]