okay so this question comes from Nob
smacker he wants to know first of all he
he recognizes Elliot's ability to speak
clearly confidently and with composure
right and he wants to know how to do the
same thing basically what he's
experiencing is a bombardment of thought
coming through his mind and an inability
to organize it and present it in a
consumable way for other people so
basically whenever his conversation goes
beyond the normal chitchat of everyday
bullshit
he he finds himself having to wrestle
with lots of different ideas that are
zooming back and forth through his head
and then when he has so offered to
people it all comes out like vomit right
and he really can't convey his message
so how is it that someone with so many
ideas can find a way to organize them
instantaneously and offer them in an
entertaining and resourceful fashion for
the other person to absorb well the very
first thing I would offer you is some
empathy go back I'll try my best to
empathy or annotate but go back and look
at some of my videos on my strengths
camp channel from like 2008
okay you're gonna see a very different
person you're gonna see a person who is
very ungrounded and has a lot of energy
a lot of excitement and a lot of ideas
that just get vomited at the camera a
little oh I'm crazy I'm hot but my voice
is high-pitched my energy is erratic and
I'm screaming most of the time right
because I just think these ideas across
to you my ideas today aren't very
different than they were back then I
still am the same person at the core
that I was back then but something has
changed in my ability to now organize
and present the ideas that are in my
head and mind you I don't script any of
these videos this is all stuff that's
inside here I do this but really it's
inside here that I bring forth when I
simplify
open up my laptop read the question and
answer to answer it how do I do that how
does that I do that and how can you do
that so the simple answer is breathe
into your balls notice how well my
answer is somehow revolve around
breathing into your balls breathing deep
affords you the ability to ground your
energy grounded energy is slow focused
concentrated and concrete tangible right
where your energy and the old Eliot host
energy was very air high energetic
ungrounded erratic it was a higher
energy your balls are down here your
your head is up here you got to get out
of your head and down into your balls
your balls
and when I say balls I mean the
grounding energy the sexual energy
that's available to all of us in our
pelvic floor that begins in our pelvic
floor and down through our legs I don't
wear shoes when I wear what I do videos
any longer because I need to ground
myself in order to present properly
right so the easy simple answer the one
that has helped me the one thing that
I've used to help me present myself in a
far more social fashion for people to
absorb is by learning how to breathe
deep I can use that as an answer for
both for things on both of my channels
so use the exercises that I've offered
you with regard to leading over the
bioenergetic stool the different
bioenergetic catharsis exercises I've
talked to you and use the bow on a
regular basis these are all going to get
you to ground your energy when you're
grounded right when you've got to feet
firm on the ground you now are in
command of your own energy and because
you're in command of yourself you're in
control of yourself you can easily pick
out what you want to say how you want to
flow and how you're going to present
yourself to the environment you also
have
a stronger energetic whole polarity to
your environment so people will behave
differently with you you have more of a
commanding presence when you're grounded
so all the things that you see me doing
in order to present my ideas are not so
much techniques I do stop pause speak a
lot slower think while I'm talking
because I'm if you notice I'm looking
all over the place a lot of times when
I'm talking I do this I'm not looking at
you because I'm literally going through
a rolodex I'm literally looking for
stuff and then giving it to you as I
find it right I never I didn't learn
these things I didn't go to a course to
learn these things I grounded my energy
followed it followed my heart and balls
right this is this is stuff that most of
my answers are often the same breathe
into your balls follow your heart
it's me trusting my gut a lot more then
my head what you're probably doing is
sifting through the ideas that have been
given to you in as images write your
stuff you've read things you've seen
some people have told to you and in an
ungrounded fashion you're trying to sift
through that stuff me on the other hand
I've got my feet on the ground I'm
breathing deep and now I can in a
grounded fashion choose those things
instead of letting those things choose
me I hope you you're following my poetic
language here it's all very metaphorical
but literal if you can follow me long
enough you see that there's a there's a
mix of science and poetry here more
poetry to be honest but you see how
resourceful it has been for me and I
know how helpful it will be to all of
you and growing stronger so that's why I
love answering these these questions so
starting to ran now see I'm ungrounded
this is the first question that I
answered today but I haven't done any
deep breathing exercises or anything so
invitation to you is begin using my bio
energetic exercises I'm making a whole
video course about it this week should
be ready in a couple
weeks but use the exercises I've taught
you on this channel on the other channel
breathe deep deep slow down focus and
concentrate and be okay with taking your
time when you talk to people you see I
did you notice that long pause just now
I'm not rushing and I don't want you to
rush what I have to say is very
important and if you're willing to stick
around to listen this long because it's
probably about a six minute video right
now that means you've got to patience
the focus to concentration to to deal
with my pauses to appreciate my pauses
people will appreciate your pauses
people will appreciate you taking your
time people will appreciate you thinking
about what you are about to say to them
instead if you just look in sort of
you're just grabbing shit or letting
shit grab you and and taking you down
some crazy neurotic ungrounded path
right people want to know that they're
being listened to
first people want to know that you're
thinking about what you're about to say
to them it's part of the reason why you
guys might be attracted to my style of
communication in my videos is because I
look like I'm thinking right I look like
I'm thinking I look like I'm going deep
in order to bring you out something
profound well the fact is that I am I
don't read these questions and go look
for a book for something to regurgitate
right I'd be all in my head I go inside
and I figure out how how can how can I
best serve this person with a bit of my
experience and knowledge that comes from
the core that comes from my heart
as opposed to what do I know that I
could vomit back up at you so that's it
dude I hope that helps I know it will
help breathe deeper take your time if
what you have to say is important people
will have the patience to listen to you
good luck