hi um my question is kind of a
combination of a lot of the answers that
you have already given but mainly for me
I'm at a point in my life this is my son
got a point in my life I'm more more of
a mom and just don't give anything to
myself I give everything to everybody
else so within me i feel that i don't
have almost don't have a right to do
things for myself or I tour I can't find
the motivation to just get myself up and
doing so why don't we keep get from you
some sense of what what advice would you
give to someone who almost feels like
him I have given up I have everything in
the world that I need help everything
but um physically I don't feel well but
it just almost don't care and I don't
like that I just don't know how to get
our gear
order right
buzzer no service is you feel like you
sacrificed yourself you've given up
everything that you have for them and
that's a role that you become personally
identified right how old is your
youngest
you bend like that bow and essentially
you're moving into a different stage
you've got teenagers and older you're
not making peanut butter and jelly
sandwiches michael watson but you know
what i mean by her not just as if
they're taking on they're taking on
their own characters i disagree with
that to a point my husband has been very
very loving but almost sheltering them
where if you know if i cook a meal and
they don't want it they can have
whatever else they want so they've
always been that's not my personality
that's my husband it's really hard to
work with that so now when you say they
kind of stepping into a role I have a
college sophomore now but she just came
home and she
meet so they don't happen in two ends
that I wish they had or even my son I
don't dead but you can say ha I'm
looking a better deal cemetery no
comment and so I have to do this song so
that's kind of awesome they now you're
ready to move into a new role but
they're not letting you yes okay good
because like I said before with regard
to taking on different roles either
intrinsic resistance or extrinsic the
world around you yeah you've got to
invite them to recognize that you're a
different person now and often times and
this is this general might not be
specific to your situation but this
might be useful often times to get a
different response from the people of
our environment we literally have to
look differently to them we literally
have to put on a different costume if
you're always wearing the costume of
Batman right and everywhere you go and
that nothing Batman Dave and then they
approach you in a particular fashion but
you don't want that anymore you've got
to put on the costume spider-man you
have to put on a different costume my
invitation to you and this is easier
said than done but I know this is what
you want and this will change the way
they behave towards you is to lose
weight start exercising and changing
your diet you need to take some take
control of something for yourself and
not only will this give you a project
that it not theirs has nothing to do
with that that is purely yours because
you've already been apart it's mine now
I'm going to lose 15 pounds but when
they see you 50 pounds lighter there's a
dissonant your daughter goes away for
six months and comes back and she sees a
slender Bob who's cooking vegetables
instead of peanut butter and jelly she
has to figure out how many to deal with
this woman I don't I don't I don't see
Batman anymore so I can't behave like
rod
figure you out changing the physical
appearance is going to be helpful for
two things to change you because of your
habits and your discipline in that
regard diet and exercise but they're
also going to be differently towards it
could be worth trying you know the
deeper issue as to what might be a
challenge and we've talked about it a
challenge to you losing that way could
be a different conversation but my
invitation would be give that attorney
cadet Acharya well I have and I've done
different things and i love the lead in
yes
and i myself just make this number one
make us apart from their guide to find
it it's healthy and strong and smart
code they're all right they'll be okay
that's one thing my dad would always say
too because my mother's might be my
mother well there's the same exact way
my dad would say it'll be alright w-
take care of yourself look the big
strong kids he knows what refrigerator
is he could make some food owning it is
fine let him go do it you did your job
and then you move on do your job
mechanically don't be emotionally
attached to the result right just like
the bow I did it I'm doing my best you
don't want 5 i'll go to the gym and that
is going to require shedding an old
version of yourself and stepping into
and creating a new version of yourself
that's a tremendous journey when your
entire life and change when you change
that way
that's the masochistic character
structure and then want to say your
messages you're a masochist and your
martyr and you will feel bad by doing
that guilt guilt isn't about guilt is
not an emotion Guild's as a concept
whereby what we feel in our body because
you're feeling in your body what you
feel and the brain battle month against
one another I don't know kind of
childhood you had what may have been one
where you should have been a good girl
be a good girl and do what you're told
that's this going up against that and
that creates lots of tension it creates
creates much more than that but it's
very unhealthy physiologically and
physically it causes a lot of the
heaviness in your body the heaviness in
your body is associated with that guilt
okay
bio energetically you have tears coming
up I see it as I'm speaking they want to
come find opportunities where you can
get those tears out get them out the
shower and the tears are there they need
to come out you're very tense yeah
that's why you're so built up here also
you're very tense here and you're
holding back lots of tips I cry it out
get it out until these effects hoping to
get out as anger you have you sadness
frustration but it's coming up as teams
might come show up with him with wanting
to punch and kick coming up with you is
deciding that holding back of the tears
is the same holding back that it's not
letting you do this so you literally
bioenergetic we got to use your body and
your energy to get out that catharsis
you gotta you gotta let it out over I
and then get it all