got the question from our buddy Sam we
losing Belgium says he's got a babyface
he says I just turned 22 yesterday and
people always think I'm a lot younger he
they have no facial hair it's not kind
of like a no childish frame even he says
his body's small but the thing is he
it's not that he lacks confidence so
people look at him and they see like
little boy oh you're a big man and they
kind of mock him for that hasn't really
affected him as far as this confidence
is concerned he says he you know he's
been in martial arts for 10 years which
is great does a lot of solo traveling he
hitchhikes he's self-reliant he's
self-sufficient the guy's a mature
fuckin man probably more mature than
most 22 girls
however covers because of his appearance
again people meet him
they don't take him seriously and then
what ends up happening is that he
overcompensates and acts aggressive I
guess he's gotta like you know prove
himself through his behavior in front of
these people who are disrespecting of
him disrespecting him because of the way
he looks
I keep stuttering because it's freezing
here it's like 40 degrees in Florida a
lot of you guys up there it's like minus
40 degrees and I'm like shivering over
here alright anyway so uh he comes
across as overly confident over the type
intellectual just to make a point that
he's not a kid and people say he's too
aggressive now so they go from saying oh
you're a little baby face but powder boy
to what you're an arrogant prick
so he's like what the fuck do I do how
do i how do I deal with this how do I
fix this dynamic I basically just want
to be seen for who I am not have to play
tough guy all the fucking time in order
to be treated correctly that's it he
just wants to be himself
so what I would invite you to do is to
look up the biography we need the
biography of John F Kennedy I first came
across John F Kennedy store used an
American president
it was assassinated I first came across
the idea this idea about John F Kennedy
because I'd never really studied his his
story up until very recently from
reading mastery I believe either mastery
or 48 laws of power by Robert Greene
either one of those books Robert Greene
is a biographer he basically is a
historian he writes about powerful
individuals in history and in one of
those books he talks a little bit about
John F Kennedy growing up in a very
powerful home you know lots of manly men
in that home you know the Kennedys
they're well known in American history
but he was he was always the smallest he
was always the most frail he came across
very mature very baby face like you know
he's a good-looking guy and his older
age because he retained a lot of proves
useful look and he never felt like he
was garnering any respect from the
powerful individuals in his home and in
his environment I mean he rubbed elbows
with like the men that built America in
many ways
so he took a number of steps in order to
rectify this problem because he he knew
that he was far more powerful than
people were giving him credit for the
first thing I think he did and read the
biography to get it correct a lot of
things I say arnux aren't really like a
exact just give you guys the ideas give
you the shadow so you go and find the
thing but anyway so I think he went into
the Army or the Navy just that you know
to prove himself as a man that's what he
did in order to prove to other people
and to prove to himself and I think he
also had an ass man he was like really
sick and just like had a really hard
time there but he came out a different
man he learned some things about himself
but what he did which was really
significant and one that you might want
to consider is that he wrote a book
associating himself with many of the
most powerful men in the history of the
world I think these were military
leaders and such so he being the author
of a book about powerful men
intrinsically linked him you know people
began to believe he was that type of
powerful man by association
so because he wrote a book about
powerful men people just started
thinking John F Kennedy his powerful
dude did you read that book that he
wrote about powerful men he wrote that
so I don't know how like of course
Elliott Hulse oh you're something given
us advice you know what maybe sometimes
I just point you in different directions
that might open up to advice for you but
I would invite you to look at the
biography of John F Kennedy for
inspiration I think when we read
biographies of people who share traits
in life or experiences in life with us
we get inspiration we feel good we feel
like we're not alone and along with some
ideas about how to deal with the
situations in our life we also feel a
kinship to an individual who has been
through it before
DC and that's why I would invite you to
read this so I don't know if you need to
go to the army or Navy I don't know if
you need to write a book but the spirit
behind that might guide you in the
direction you need to go in order to
garner the respect that you deserve as a
man without coming across as an asshole
or less than you really are
and done