so we got this question about career
path life journey from our buddy Brian
he first of all he loves he's completely
in love enrolled and enthrall passionate
about fitness working out he wants to
become the strongest version of himself
and he loves to inspire others good
stuff man
he he won't he feels great when he's
also supporting his friends with the
ideas that he's learning experiences he
have with regard to fitness and exercise
it makes him feel good he gets good
feelings in his body he there's a
feeling of joy pleasure associated with
fitness and supporting other people in
their fitness becoming stronger right
the other thing is that he's got it
apparently he's got a great opportunity
he's graduating high school soon next
couple months he's got a great
opportunity to begin work in the field
of construction
he likes construction apparently he's
good at construction he sees a clearly
drawn out career path with construction
right very very clear you know this is
what you're gonna do and this how you
gonna get it and that there is a
business associated with moving in that
direction the fitness not so much it's
it's kind of a blur I love it but it's
like a mess construction I can do it and
good at it any nice what seems like a
nice path because really there's no such
thing as a clean path there's no easy
path there is no clearly outlined path
to anything just ask those all those
people who lost everything in 2008 right
the crash of the stock market crash no 8
right the big crash whatever a lot of
people lost a lot of shit and they've
been following that path for many
decades what the fuck happened right
there's no such thing it's a figment of
our imagination safety and security is a
pigment of our imagination we live on a
rock that's spinning at you know
millions of miles per hour around a big
ball of fire there's another way there's
a fucking security right give that out
get that out of your fucking mind
you might play the security game
I just recognize as a game play the game
and maybe it's all a gamble anyway both
look both of these are a gamble
whichever one you decide to do it's a
gamble I can tell you that right now now
one of them might require a little bit
more sensitivity paying attention focus
concentration you might have more
challenges but this one is still a
fucking game too because a lot of what
we think is the traditional easy path
ends up being slavery ends up being oh
shit we didn't see that coming right and
and you're and you're caught off guard
see the thing is with this one you can
relax a little bit right it's very clear
you can relax a little bit that's the
fucking problem you're relaxing so when
the when the the she gets pulled out
from under you boom you're all out of
your ass look when you start down this
path you got to be sensitive doing what
your heart tells you to do you got to be
sensitive you looking around gonna be
creative you gotta be agile no tricks
are gonna throw you off because you here
it's not about what you can't see again
we focus on you know you you can see
what you're gonna get over here you're
gonna get a career you're gonna get but
you know $100,000 a year you're gonna
get a pension pan plan oh you don't know
fuck you're gonna get if you're focused
on what you're gonna get you miss the
most important thing that happens which
is who you become over here
you become somebody who has stuff
because you followed particular path
that perhaps worked out it might not I
hope if you follow that path that you
fall in your ass that way now you have
to toughen up and become what you would
have become if you chose the more
dangerous path that's what it is folks
you see you all you guys like to say Oh
Elliott Hulse is a dreamer or Elliott
hosts like he's not very practical or
pragmatic when he says these things
follow your heart and be adventurous and
then you guys did you offer well you
should do something more responsible
that's because you're focused on what
you're going to get you're focused on
where you possibly could get because
there's no there's no guarantees ever
I'm focused on who you're becoming and
you become far more by following a
challenging path than by following a
well-trodden one it's not about what you
get it's about would you come so you
also know what he should do
follow your heart that's my that's my
most basic offer to you here and lucky
for you there are guys like me and
thousands tens of thousands perhaps
hundreds of thousands of other guys that
have followed their hearts path
especially with regard to fitness and
entrepreneurship and becoming stronger
and sharing that passion with other
people that you can learn from and that
and that fucking cool right none of us
can give you the exact path none of us
could give you the step-by-step
fill-in-the-blanks paint by color
to get what you want but we can offer
you some ideas you're not alone so you
can fucking do it I think that's all I
have to say throw back to this I'm on a
quite a ranting rampage today but I
think that's it it comes back to the
same point don't follow the easy path
don't follow the well-trodden path don't
follow the path that's been laid out
look paint-by-numbers path that we've
been taught to follow because of some
bullshit idea they call safety and
security which does not exist and
oftentimes if you do achieve what they
call safety and security you've done it
at the expense of your soul selling your
soul doesn't look like you know you're
killing people and that you're being uh
you're being some sort of criminal
selling your soul means not you didn't
listen to your soul when it was telling
you to go that way your heart told you
go that way your soul told you go that
way you didn't listen you sold your soul
Oh things look nice things are great
you're a nice guy you go to church still
saw your fucking soul dude okay one last
thing is that when you started your
question with I want to make the right
choice first I want to make the right
choice the first time
yeah that's bullshit nothing is going to
be the right choice the first time you
start on a journey you don't make the
right choice you make a choice and then
you make the choice right do you
understand you move in the directions of
your dreams and that could change you
move in the direction of fitness see I
moved in direction affect my fitness and
my dream when I was 17 years old was to
carry this thing around Cal people's
reps and give him smiley faces when they
lost weight I swear to God that's what I
wanted to do I wanted to carry around a
clipboard I thought it was so fucking
cool when I saw these guys carrying
clipboards and showing people how to
workout go workout keeping their notes
and then like when someone does real
good I gave him a sticker fucking
sticker
he lost ten pounds good job great I love
doing that and it was cool I helped a
lot of fat people lose a lot of weight
helped a lot of athletes get stronger I
had no clue that tens hundreds of
thousands of people we're gonna watch me
through a camp there was no youtube
through the through a bullshit-ass
camera throughout the entire world on
YouTube when I was 17 years old so you
move in a direction and it takes you to
where you should be if you keep
listening to your heart I'm gonna good
place right now when I began it was
Elliott why don't you get a real job
Elliott you have a degree in health care
administration Elliott I can get you a
job that's easy six-figure job Elliott
said no I don't want that my heart
doesn't want that my heart wants to
coughs and give people stickers for
losing weight look at where I am now I
don't say this in an arrogant way I say
this to inspire you to follow your heart
because it always leads to what is
pleasing in the end it may be difficult
in the beginning it may be difficult for
years but you will die on your deathbed
feeling
a strong sense of integrity and loyalty
to your heart you can't buy that