Oh like what the hybrid training you you
think it's best to combine it in that
one workout or or to do like a week of
strength training followed by then by a
week of sarcoplasmic then or by doing
like a whole month of just strength
training and then like a month of
sarcoplasmic training or is it best to
just do it like I said first in one
workout like combine it in that one
session when you a really good book
that's going to support what I want to
say right now me that you read a easy
shrink you can shrink D'Angela model
awesome awesome book I don't like the
way it was written this more of a
conversational style but it's a really
good book and it gives different
quadrants different types of athletes
and you have like athletes that have to
really focus and concentrate on
development of one skilled how other
thing would be like that you're you're
specializing then you have a far in the
destruction you've got athletes that
need to be all things a football player
a linebacker would be that it needs to
be sure to power lifter he's got to be
powerful like a Olympic lifter he's got
to be able to sprint like a sprinter but
he also could have to be able to jump
like a jumper it's going to be
aggressive knock the crap out of people
but he also has to be tenacious and
agile enough to move that's a hybrid
athlete and the way or hybrid athlete
becomes a hybrid athlete right we've all
that shit at once when that ball is
snapped it's either bang or you know I'm
saying he's going to be able to all that
the same time my opinion is if your
first of all depends on what you want
you know if your aid I look that's how
you know if you're trying to build up to
a thousand pound squat
general conditioning I think that's the
best kind of athlete to be I want to be
able to power clean 315 I'm going to be
able to deadlift 600 how's that I won't
be able to jump let's go 50 pound box of
15 inch box you don't say so like Chris
and alcohol to start training together
in a while but the training will look a
lot like they will be hybrid but I'm
trying to give an example I will do copy
sets of stones and then we'll do heavy
deadlifts followed by reverse would jobs
and its body good classic shorter so
it's best insulated that one session so
make accurate because I don't harm train
at a gym a clear so have certain things
that are accessible so good i program
would be almost like I said in the video
Chris up with this morning on the west
side template what site template is
although it's a powerlifting template
Bay different colleges it can be
modified to be very it's very high as
you lift heavy then you can do some
dynamic work and you can use a
bodybuilding right you see I think but I
think the blending the three of those
gigantic work now looking bodybuilding
creates a really solid strong athlete
lift heavy with with high volume and be
explosive that's really its intensity
volume and speed Timbo it was it really
the three parameters at you messing with
intensity is wait volume is pop is by
yielding and speed tempo is jump sprint
throw add those into your program since
you're always still very athletic