it was sup guys we're here at the open
gym on the monday after the strip camp
challenge and i'm here with the winner
of the high jump 62 inch jump and third
place in the shrimp camp challenge
overall my voice is a little lost
because i was yelling and cheering this
guy on we got john f kennedy AKA Frank
our buddy over here and he would like to
share with you his number one habit /
ritual that he uses every day to make
himself such a badass athlete what's up
brother is meditation manages and vision
envision and what you wanting to do each
and every single day I wake up early
like Elliot house at five a.m. in the
morning even before my wife and child
wakes up and I sit down in a vision a
plan of what I want to do that day and
for me yes it is been out famous my
training whatever I want to accomplish
that day long regarded my training I'm
going to meditate on it I'm going to pin
it off in my head I'm going to make sure
our compass shit man it's about waking
up and creating that positive energy for
yourself so that you can encourage the
people around you make that's what it's
about man you know spreading their
positive positive energy to those around
you so that we all can get to where we
want to go in life man so I remember get
up meditate and no develop that positive
energy so you can spread it to the world
that's it Dougie fresh the eros racking
with me on Saturday night out Dougie who
makes 15 second sound bites give us a
quick sound bite on your number one
daily ritual for any success success in
any area of Dougie's life ok without a
shadow of a doubt hands down it's a
success tracker it's above journaling
it's the next level is easier I
basically write down every single night
how my day went what I learned that I
planned the next day and I can reflect
what I've learned the last week day here
and everything like someone valuable
says photos arm's length away Dougie
always adds a little book modem so I
think that's a ritual every time you
hear something like a bell goes off
after
catch him doing this Richard Branson
done you said yeah oh who else is it the
40 billion dollar man for mr. deeds did
it Jim Rohn did it Tony Robbins did it
so a lot of successful people do it i
just like the model that I think that's
the one thing that helps me stand out
mm-hmm young sure I never seen anybody
do that you got something different
whatever it takes thanks brother
absolutely I love hanging out with his
ooh man every time we get together is a
good time so he decided to come down to
shred camp challenge chat it up with a
bunch of fans came to the after party
I'm fucking some dope videos we had an
interview Brian interview in his ass
right now but you'll see the one that we
put up on the channel shortly yeah but I
wanted to get one thing my man Brandon
Carter here today which is your number
one have it your success ritual that you
do every day you could choose it from
any realm of your life viet fitness
finances like your business
relationships whatever what's in the
more it's something I got from brian
tracy like year years ago uh it's in a
book called i first heard of the book on
maximum achieve me and yeah I'm sorry
hour of power right so you get up right
I don't do is a call exact same protocol
but its hour of re first time I meditate
we write down my goals you try to
additional you know visit myself getting
them and basically man visualization
right now my goals meditating that's
really the biggest things this help man
is crazy that's the same thing Frank
said I know right yeah hardest hit again
doing those things you got to make sure
you do every single day are you brushing
your teeth if I don't do it I noticed
yeah I feel like people around me knows
I'm like short I'm not as a react and
instead of rotational me responde
instead of react
and I think I read more reactive when I
don't you know no doubt sharing that
with us man look that's two for two
meditation is a good ritual done