it's got a question from our buddy who's
studying computer science right
apparently this was a major that he
chose because his parents and elders
told him that there's a really good
chance that you've you getting a good
job in computer science and and also he
has an inclination towards you know the
mathematical geekiness of computer
science but he's discovered after a year
or so of studying computer science that
he really hates it and he loves biology
in particular human biology and now he's
he's torn because he's got this
situation where he's invested in
computer science he did like it at one
point but now he likes biology
everyone's telling him to stay here or
his family telling him stay here with
computer science and he wants to go over
here with biology and his friends tell
him since you love it you should go
towards biology now I'm gonna produce a
little bit differently normally it would
be like well you make a decision dude
choose one or choose the other if you
really love this one choose this one if
you really want to be practical and
focused choose that one what I'm gonna
ask you to do is step back for a moment
and look at the big picture of your life
not so much what you're going to do you
see because Elliott house always reminds
you that who you're becoming is always
far more important than what you're
going to do doing is a manifestation of
who you are I recently listened to oh I
always meant always reference this book
mastery by Robert Greene there is a
portion in the book where he talks about
this woman who created robots right she
is like on the leading edge of robot
creation in the world Ryan just creating
all types of she created the first like
robot hand that like actually works and
can think like a fucking hand it's crazy
this woman studied biology she's really
like she her whole life she was into
biology I think that's what it were
began she was into biology and sports
she was just really into mechanics how
things moved and how things work
together but she for some reason was
forced into studying mathematics or or
like computer science similar to what
you're dealing with so there was this
love and appreciation and deep-seated
passion
towards biology and then this the the
embedding of an education surrounding
mathematics and computer science right
that she then now when I watch this then
over time give yourself time dude a lot
of you guys who are in college and
should give yourself time don't be so
worried about what's happening today
because all your experiences later on
they start to move back and in
retrospect you see how they all
contribute to you becoming stronger over
time she began blending her love
no-one's done this right this is why
she's leading she's a leading expert in
this shit she took her love for biology
and her understanding of biology coupled
with her ability to to do computer
science and now she's making fucking
robots now I'm not telling you that
that's going to happen to you I'm not
gonna tell you that you know Hey Dude
take them both and become a robot expert
what I'm trying to have you understand
and all you understand when you watch
these videos is that every experience
that you have every thing that you study
all contributes to a bigger picture of
who you're becoming they all add to you
every year that you feel like you've
wasted studying something that you're
not going to use trust me it adds a
swipe of paint to the portrait of your
life and there's going to come a time
when that's that what you thought was a
waste that swipe of paint is going to
come to the forefront and you're going
to see how beautiful it makes the
portrait of your life so of course you
don't want a poetic answer from Elliott
Hulse you want like what the fuck should
I do
look at this point I say follow the path
of least resistance if your parents are
paying for your school which it sounds
like it is and they want you to study
computer science just fucking study it
dude four years is a drop in the bucket
compared to the big picture in life now
don't let your education don't let your
schooling excuse me same as quote
different wrong
don't let your schooling get in the way
of your education your education is
perpetual it happens every single day in
life until the day you die you're always
being educated
if you happen to be in school for
computer science do the best that you
can to get good grades and pass and make
your parents happy with computer science
but it does not stop you from studying
biology bro go to the biological museum
buy books on biology by listening to
audio programs right now that are about
uh about Darwin right you think I would
remember its name Darwin
hello biology all the biological shit
that he discovered it is fascinating
fantastic shit so you can always study
you can always learn you could always
get better at the things you love
outside of school don't think that
school is your only opportunity don't
think that that four years at university
is your only opportunity to learn
something in fact it's just a drop in
the bucket over time all these
experiences all the things that you've
learned good or seemingly bad in
retrospect will add they will contribute
and they will build upon you becoming a
stronger version of yourself ten years
from now you're gonna look back and say
goddamn that was beautiful
good luck