it's got a really good question from our
buddy Adrian he's 22 years old and he
grew up with a father who was really
hard on him
sounds like he was an alcoholic he was a
weekend dad according to our friend his
mother and father broke up they divorced
when he was very young his dad was a
chronic adulterer and so they broke up
and he would see him on the weekends and
his dad would just berate him to such a
degree that Adrian was even afraid to
ask for things as simple as food and now
that he's an adult the situation is such
that he wants to have a relationship
with his dad
you know I've answered questions like
this before um there's a sense of duty
and love towards him but he hates him
anything and he doesn't know what to do
you know how do i asserted in the world
as a man 20 years old without the
primary male role model as a supporter
in any way shape or form in my life and
this just begs the concern that we do
this is a big part of the reason why i
do what i do we do as young men need
that role model we need a depiction of
the type of man that we want to become
we need a mentor we need someone to
aspire to it's just the way it is the
problem is society is constructed in
such a way that most fathers don't have
the time or the attention span in order
to be that type of role model to their
children your dad in this case was
chronically cheating on your mother and
drinking too much alcohol right where is
the role model and then we end up having
children that look to sports figures and
and pop culture musicians as their role
models and then that leads to a whole
slew of other unfortunate dysfunction
and that's why this question is not
typical it's not easy there are a few
things that I would invite you to do
number one is to look for a mentor look
for a man that you can live up to there
are organizations that provide this you
know I would if you go to church or a
religious mosque or you know what
religion years you are go to a religious
organization and look for men's groups
look for it and in particular look for
men's groups that have men that are
older than you there are other
organizations a friend of mine I think
he gave me a business card for something
that he's been doing lately but it's
basically like a warrior man and they do
like these trips you know and they have
these meetings and stuff there are men's
organizations there not very many of
them a lot of them are faith faith based
so you know whatever your situation with
regard to faith is you know deal with
that but the problem is that that II we
don't know that they exist or were too
afraid to approach them or we've heard
all types of weird stories about you
know the type of relationships that
happen in there but in my estimate it's
always been good I have several friends
most of my friends in fact are a lot
older than me because I've sought them
out as father father figures not that my
father wasn't there my father was there
he was always been a great mentor and
and I aspire to and I'm very much like
him today but a network of men is always
very resourceful that's the first thing
you know even if it comes in the form of
reading books of a particular man or I
know for example the lie you guys see me
as a mentor big brother of sort you
watch my videos yeah and that's why I do
what I do so look for men that you can
aspire to be more like that's the first
thing but it doesn't end there because
that can become a dependency and no real
man is ever dependent on any other man
it's just not the knick it's not the
nature of men to be fully dependent to
lean on to yield towards to help one
another is one thing but a real man
stands on his own two feet and that's
the next thing you're going to need to
do you need and the desire for you to
yield towards a man is there and that's
why and you want from your father but
it's not going to happen and that's why
I invite you to find a mentor but you're
also going to need to stand on your own
two feet and the way that looks is
becoming a success in your own right
whatever it is that you feel in your
heart that you want that you aspire to
whatever
a man you want to be I think it's even
in your email it said something alluded
to the fact that you also are like a big
brother you do like some sort of
mentorship for younger kids that's one
way to make it happen but even more so
to become a success in your own right
either through art creativity commerce
business something where you can say I
built this this is mine I've grown into
this I am a master in my own right
because you are going to need to create
that contrast between you and your
mentor I've said this before and I made
videos and we discussed it at my live
event that every man every growing man
will come to kill his masters the thing
is you have to have a master to grow up
to and then create contrast between
yourself and your master by growing in
your own right this is how men develop
this is how we grow this is how we've
always grown down to when we were living
in tribal type societies there were
always little boys looking up to the men
in their society there were usually
uncles lots of uncles all over the place
uncles and cousins would grow up to
aspire to but eventually they'd have to
go out and many like Native American
cultures they created rituals where the
boy would have to go out and assert
himself as a real man we would have to
in essence cut the apron Springs Springs
apron strings get grounded in his own
sexuality standing on his own two feet
and usually came in the form of hunting
go out and kill a lion some some tribes
had them do
that's African obviously or kill a
buffalo if it was Native American or
perform some particular rite of passage
associated with standing on your own two
feet yes you're a man now because it's
always about growing up to and then
asserting yourself that's how we evolved
so my friends coming full circle to wrap
this up find men that you can aspire to
that you could learn from that you know
you could lean on and yield towards and
then find a place where you can dig in
your own roots and make a place for
yourself in this world good luck