got this question for our buddy who has
a hard time speaking in crowds either
like amongst other friends or obviously
he's giving big presentation sort of
case maybe he feels all nervous and
jittery and sweaty in his body and his
voice changes that he feels like that he
just completely falls apart and don't
know what to do
he's worried about what other people
think of him and then when you're
worried about what other people think
about you you get even more nervous and
the whole thing is there's a cycle of
6ad dysfunction and that's what he's
dealing with so le dose what do you do
I'll give you two ideas that are going
to support you the very first one is
nervousness is happening in your body
and you can't get rid of the nervousness
the jitteriness and the sweatiness from
the head level it strange that in our
society no it's not that strange because
this is the way they they trained us
this is the way they control us through
this thing we try to solve all the
fucking problems at the level that
they're created in our head you can't
think your way out of this you see and
that's what you're gonna do even like
maybe I can read a book or maybe la will
tell me something or maybe something can
happen here that can help me but this is
the fucking problem
you're too much in your fucking head
right can't solve the problem at the
level of which it was created
you got to go to your body and guess
what your body's never wrong your body
might confuse you your body might do
things that you don't want it to do but
it's never wrong and if it's if you
start getting jittery go with the
jitteriness right so before you go
onstage to do a presentation in front of
your class right and how you do this how
you prepare to do this out is going to
be in the second part of this second
part of my invitation to you shake it
out shake your body let it do its thing
if it wants if it wants to shake let it
shake shaking releases you have a lot of
muscular tension and if you're so
fucking good I might just do this for
the rest of the video
and notice what I'm doing to the sounds
of what's happening here is your root
your your softening the inner to your
softening your belly your belly is going
to be really tight when you're nervous
notice your breathing your breathing
stops cuz you're holding your belly in
for a while for me some people that
breathing stops as they hold their jaw
tight or they hold her chest in I hold
my belly in notice your belly notice
your breathing notice your body you
gotta go to your body
you can't think yourself out of this one
dude you got to go to your body
what's your body telling you your body
may also need you to work with it
right if your body is is tense I'm
repeating myself here so that's the
first thing go to your go to your go to
your body see what your body's asking
you to do see how your body needs to be
helped along in the process the other
half of this that's really important one
that I've embraced obviously one that
I've embraced is lack of go for and lack
of respectability I've thought about
this often I probably mentioned it a lot
of times but there's a really good book
a really good video on Tyler RS Dee's
channel he and I keep giving each other
shoutouts I think he's cool and I think
it has something to do with the title of
it is respectability or no it's called
beta shaming it's a fun bit it's a fun
video but basically talks about
different people who just completely
throw out respectability and because
they're not trying to be respectable in
any particular way they're not trying to
get people to look at them with any type
of adoration they just say fuck it I
don't care if you don't like me because
of that everybody likes them right and
they're free that's the other thing too
that's why I never I never really
positioned myself as any kind of fucking
expert I'm just a guy who talks to you
talk to the camera and makes YouTube
videos I'm not an expert don't respect
me I'm not trying to be right I just
like talking a lot right you see you see
how free that position is cuz I'll say a
lot of stuff just like a fool I'll do a
lot of shit just like a fool but I'm gay
through you right so don't respect me
and don't try to be respectable
respectability is a fucking trap being
transparent in that way is going to set
you free
when I say transparent let them know a
nervous right now hey I'm a nervous
fucking wreck just walk up there see
being respectable would be I'm not
nervous nobody noticed that I'm nervous
because being nervous is not respectable
as opposed to walking up there and being
like hey listen guys I'm nervous as fuck
right now oh the crowd will roar they'll
giggle they'll think it's so funny and
then you just go on from there alright
look so bear with me because for the
next 20 minutes I'm my body's probably
gonna shake and sweat look at me oh my
god my shirts all fucked up and then you
go on lack of respectability and an
increase in transparency just be so
honest that people can't help it like
they can't help but like you it's like
well at least you know you're what
you're getting with this guy so that's
it man go check out Tyler's video listen
to your body work with your body I've
got two channels one all about the body
and one all about philosophy life how to
live
that's this channel and there's a big
crossover I make those body videos and
I'm talking a hell of a lot about what's
going on in the mind and I make these
videos and I talk a hell of a lot about
what's going on in the body it's one
thing appreciate respect understand come
to come to yield to the demands of your
body when it's asking you to and be
honest in your in your approach with
people be authentic be transparent and
let go of any idea of respectability
it's a trap done