so there's a good percentage of you guys
that watch my videos that are still
living at home with your parents or are
under the rule if you will of your
parents some might say oppression or
tyranny but they care for you you know
at least most of them do I hope and
there comes a time when you as a man you
have choices that you'd like to make
about the way you want to spend your
time and your energy the things you want
to focus on and it may be in complete
opposition to that which your parents
would want and and it's always
interesting to hear your stories in fact
I just read one word from a young man
who wants to body build he's he's 16
years old he's been working out he's
building some muscle his self-worth his
feelings of self-esteem is growing he
likes the results that he's getting but
yet his father does nothing but harasses
him makes fun of him and tries to
belittle his efforts telling him that
he's wasting his time and that is
behaviors silly and foolish so of course
my heart goes out to you it's such an
unfortunate thing when parents and mind
you I am a parent I'm a parent of four
children so a lot of parents will watch
this and like who's this guy you know
young punk I'm a parent of four children
but I can tell you what I've always even
to this day retained this rebellious
attitude this attitude where I trust
what is happening in me I trust my heart
I trust my body I trust where God wants
to take me more than the promptings or
the conditioning of any man could ever
do I really believe that it's all of our
responsibilities to follow our hearts
and sometimes that means that our life
doesn't look the way even we would have
planned it out much less our parents or
someone else see that's the thing with
parents they want to plan your life for
you because they want you to be happy
but they don't realize that happiness
comes from following your heart by
following the God in you or the universe
moving through you as opposed to the
well-trod path that would perhaps have
you win this socio-economic game there
are ways to win that game also without
selling your soul but anyway so the
point of this video is not to answer
your questions about how to deal with
your parents
but to give you some perspective on how
I deal with my growing children the way
I see parents the role that I see
parents are to play in the roles of
their children's lives and perhaps give
you a few ideas about how you might be
able to put your parents with this with
your dilemmas with your you're wanting
to body build or to what you do any of
the weird things that your parents don't
just don't understand and also so that
when you have children yourself you will
you can move from a far more resourceful
place than that of oppression and then
and terrorizing your children until they
obey do you see any way so if you watch
my videos for some time or this weekend
you've probably realized that I like
poetry I really I enjoy reading it then
sometimes I write it and what I want to
do is share with you a short poem by
Khalil Gibran
the it's from a book called the Prophet
and this one poem is called on children
and it goes your children are not your
children they are the sons and daughters
of life's longing for itself they come
through you but not from you and though
they are with you yet they belong not to
you you may give them your love but not
your thoughts for they have their own
thoughts you may house their bodies but
not their souls for their souls dwell in
the house of tomorrow which you cannot
visit not even in your dreams you may
strive to be like them but seek not to
make them like you for life goes not
backwards note Aries with the yesterday
you are the boughs from which your
children as living arrows are set forth
the archer sees the mark upon the path
of the infinite and he bends you with
all his might that his arrow may go
Swift and far let your bending in the
archers hand be for gladness for even as
he loves the arrow that flies so he
loves also the bow that is stable we can
never understand as parents of course
now it sounds like I'm you know so I'm
speaking of parents I am because I am
one we can never understand that which
the the archer has planned for future
generations and we're evolving very
quickly and it's unfair for us to say
that our children should do act B and
behave in a particular way just because
it's been resourceful for us the rate at
which humankind is moving and the
direction that we're moving is such that
we have to let go just like the archer
and the bow love your children but don't
force them to be like you