it was up guys first thing I want to say
is that I'm walking through one of my
favorite parks those you guys who can
follow me in my heli at hoes Channel I
introduce you to Sawgrass Lake Park
where I'm standing right now as one of
the important spots that I used to visit
there might come up years in about ten
years ago just walking it right out my
goals affirmations I do my breathing
exercises and plot for my life those you
who are not on my Elliott Hulse channel
you're not subscribed to Elliott Hulse
channel well this videos to invite you
to get your ass over there because five
days a week I've been uploading videos
as it relates to experiences
circumstances and wisdom I've gained
over the past few years just with my
experiences as a strength coach gym
owner youtube celebrity and and a lot of
people find that kind of stuff
interesting so I'm not answering
strength questions I'm sharing the other
reason why I'm uploading this video to
the Shrek camp channel especially since
I've been up I haven't been uploading
over there very often over here very
often because this is a sponsored video
why audible those you guys who can watch
my videos long enough you know that I am
a prolific audio book reader and
audible.com has been my preferred source
of audio information and book audio book
learning over the past several years
I've spoken about talking about my daily
walk and the ritual of absorbing
information by listening to books while
I fixer sighs at the same time
that for many years audible has been a
great resource and I want to give a
shout out to them I believe they've got
over 200 thousand titles over there the
other reason why I feel this is a good
fit because study learning reading who
to yourself in a flow of information is
a critical step on your journey becoming
stronger version yourself and one of the
things I've learned in 2015 about life
in general how to succeed in general is
that it's less about the big things that
we do less about the the grand goals and
adventures we go on and it's more about
the little things that you do every
single day it's really about the rituals
that you learn how to instill into your
life and make habits out of right so for
example a lot of times people get in get
excited about exercise so they got these
big goals and these big plans and they
go gone the whole full-bore on the
exercise and diet program but ain't
nothing but three weeks before they quit
what I'm discovering and what I advise
I've been talking about this for years
but 2015 has been a transformational
year for me mainly because I've been
asked to apply a lot of crime talking
about four years is that you gotta find
little steps little bites little things
that you can do on a daily basis and add
up and add up over time and bring it to
where you want to be so it's a whole lot
less about crushing it killing it and a
whole lot more about what are you doing
every single day little by little to get
you closer and closer to your goal
that's really what it's all about that's
what the daily walk the daily audible
video is all about and that's what I
want to talk to you guys about today I
want to talk to you about number one
recapping 2015 how did it work out for
you what did you do this year what did
you accomplish what did you learn how
did you transform in the past 12 months
how did you become a stronger version of
yourself in 2015 look if you wasted the
past 12 months right 11 months going on
12 months
by thinking about it
dreaming about it talking about it
complaining about it and generally being
a UH a Jabberjaw with no action taking
well then look maybe you need to revise
your approach
maybe stop - making such big goals maybe
stop thinking so much maybe put you you
put your feet on the ground get involved
with the activity of actually making
things happen the best way to get
involved the activity of making things
happens with daily and the other reason
why I make this video the other reason
the other thing I want to share with you
are the things that I've learned and the
way I've transformed and little bits of
wisdom I've gathered over the past
twelve months that may be support to you
when I look back in 2015 I see it as
perhaps the most transformational here
of my life those you guys been following
me long enough you see 2015 is the year
that Elliott Hulse stop making YouTube
videos you also see it as a year to the
break
we also see it as a year where Elliott
Hulse depending on how you look at it it
is a different version of himself some
of you guys don't like who I've become
and who I'm becoming and that's all
right because that's evolution and it's
any of you some of you can see the
transformation you realize you know
stronger version of someone else
stronger version of you or someone in
your life doesn't have to look the way
you want it to look it oftentimes won't
look like the way you decided it should
look but to recognize and appreciate it
and roll with it and to honor someone as
they grow takes a lot of detachment
strength skill and love
let's go down this path it's gonna be a
long video we're gonna take a trip down
this goes this path may I doubt we'll
get through the whole thing this takes a
good half an hour or so to get forgiven
this old map this path if you'll see
goes through
the forest goes through the woods here
and and look then it's above water
Sawgrass Lake parks and it's a Sawgrass
lake or river or body of water here in
st. Petersburg take a trip talk to my
friends today about growing stronger and
some of the things I've learned so
habits rituals things that she's doing a
daily basis that add up to becoming a
stronger version yourself the commitment
that's required to choose the most
important things and do it and only it
every single day regardless of if you
like it or not when put to practical use
you got to ask yourself what do I want
what am I willing to do for me 2015 the
ritual the practice of getting up every
single day and listening to audio books
while I work had to take a back seat for
a little while while that develops a new
pattern a new resource of ritual of
writing every day those you guys follow
my videos on the Elliott Hulse channel
if you're just watching this video
because you want a Bible be today go to
the link down below where you'll see my
blog I write a letter every single day
to you guys talking about various
aspects of becoming a stronger version
yourself today I wrote about my four
favorite audiobooks for 2015
for books that have really transformed
audiobooks have transformed my way of
thinking and my attitude towards life
2015 you could read that down below but
the way I'm able to produce that amount
of content you know I produce I produce
an email a letter block slash blog post
video Instagram video I create probably
about six pieces of content every single
day the reason why I'm able to produce
that much content is because I walked it
into my lifestyle I made it a ritual I
get up every single day five o'clock
right it's not a grind anymore for me
it's a habit I want you guys understand
that that's a really important
distinction
are you getting up cuz you're grinding
because you know what happens when you
grind right when you grind something you
sharpen that ass on that grinder you
sharpen it so much that it turns into a
fucking stuff right so those you guys
want a grinding meaning that look to
grind means that there's resistance
right the grind must mean that there is
pain suffering resistance what I'm
sharing with you is just a slightly
different perspective I'm not saying
don't bribe
I think you got a grind in the beginning
and it's probably the most important
thing to do to create momentum but
ultimately you got it creates ritual
you've got to create daily little
activities that come naturally to you
and you never forget to do like rushing
your teeth right now was it a grind to
brush your teeth those you guys were
watching this trip can't channel is it a
crime for you to go to the gym it
shouldn't be if you got a grind every
single time you go to the gym and you're
gonna grind yourself right now to a
fucking stuff the gym should feel you
for it should pull you towards it just
like you wake up in the morning and the
toothbrush calls you it's an action
the weight should call you to action
because it's just the freakin habit is
just something you do every day and the
question whether you feel like it or not
is not even a push in anymore you just
do it
so rituals baby habits baby that's where
I'm at with regards creating content
every single day 2015 asked me to stop
take a break I didn't have any videos
from September 2014 until April 2015 and
then I even took some breaks in between
because I had to figure out how can I
make the make
content make videos and right I like to
write - that's the other thing you guys
enjoy my videos well what you don't
realize is that I'm a writer as well I
love writing I feel like I'm a poet when
I write when I get down in the morning I
start writing you know some of you guys
were still in school or your real
academic types who sit down you might
wear on my resources and make sure it's
grammatically correct I say fuck that I
wake up and I just mental purge that's
what my writing is like and it comes out
sounding poetic it's fun it's engaging
it's entertaining it is informative and
I know that it would be a gift to the
world so I had to make it a ritual other
rituals in 2015 that have supported me
the counting macros not something I've
ever done in the past it's been kind of
an intuitive dieter which you know work
tough work real well - 2015 my body was
like listen dude and you started
tracking these things and that's what I
began doing listening to classical music
I can't while I'm working while I'm
writing while I'm typing
is a ritual meal preparation I've always
been a meal prepare but my wife and I
got on it together so now she and I
prepare meals every single night we're
paying for the next day I even help her
with the dishes these are all brand new
things
Brenda ways of being brand new rituals
into the dark and become a stronger
version of myself
the other thing that I do now and I
invite you to do I think it's a very
powerful tool to get yourself a yearly
calendar wall poster calendar and you
should make a ritual of planning out
your whole year now of course you don't
plan because that's exactly what's gonna
happen right because God the universe
nature takes over
but you plan with intention what do I
intend to create this year we're doing
what I tend to have done complete this
year one of my aspirations as far as
business relationships vocation and
health for 2016 so a new ritual that
I've engaged in and brought into my life
is is looking at and mapping out a 12
month 12 month calendar get yourself a
12-month calendar put it on your wall
use color markers to put in specific
specific dates and gold gold achievement
timelines and deadlines and things like
that so definitely
take your time on a regular basis to
plan out not just your day not just you
not just your month what you hear when
you really become a boss you start
thinking in terms of three years five
years and gets clearer and clearer
especially as you really begin to
realize that time days are like building
blocks and each successful day is like
adding a new cinderblock to the building
that you put you're creating and they
add up to years when you look at it that
way there's a lot less pressure to crush
it to grind and to win right away and a
whole lot more strategy strategic
thinking going on regarding your goal
setting in your achievement so that's
pretty much it today guys I don't know
if you find this video interesting or
insightful or informational
one thing for sure it's fucking
beautiful nothing else he got to hear
Eliot rant a little bit with sunglasses
on while he walks through the woods so
that's it guys looking forward to the
Shred camp challenge this weekend those
you guys were to be there it's fucking
awesome time and have a great time with
the competitors the other YouTube
celebrities and our raucous kid loose
skin sponsored afterparty
the king is the title of my new book
you'll find out about later on this year
so that's it folks I love you I'm gonna
enjoy the rest of this part for us it is
morning