I got a question here from our friend I
can't pronounce his name but he says
Elliot I do not expect you to look at
this but if you read what do you think
about this quote the secret of life is
to die before you die to find out there
is no death brother that has been I
resonate deeply with that my experience
has been over the past several years
I've died to myself and when I speak of
dying I'm talking about an ego death it
I'm still the same Elliot but many of
you could probably recognize that I'm
not the same person it has been a
process of ego deconstruction when the
Phoenix burns down right or when Jesus
says you've got to die to yourself to be
accepted into the kingdom you've got to
let go of your old self in order to
embrace the new one thing he also says
is that you can't put oh you can't put
new wine in an old wine skin so that's I
think that's a perfect example of none
of the benefit in the value of getting
rid of your old container your own way
of containing yourself and interfacing
with the world that really requires a
throwing away
it requires a breaking down or ours of
dissolving it requires a dying to an ego
construct that is no longer resourceful
for who you're to become in the next
phase of your life this is an area where
people get stuck all the time we develop
an ego construct when I say ego concept
on top I'm literally talking about the
interface by which we work with the
world though if you can imagine your
self the outside world which is really a
figment of our imagination but we work
with it we work with our experiences we
work with our circumstances as well as
working with our internal processes and
then the ego being in between it how do
I bring myself to my circumstances when
you're 14 there is a way to be that
allows you to interface with the world
in a resourceful manner it works for you
when you're 14
the problem is when you're 21 and you're
still approaching life with the same ego
construct that you had when you were 14
you lack the you don't evolve you remain
the same old version of yourself even
though you're being called to change
this is where you end up with men in
their late 30s and 40s who have a
midlife crisis and they begin because
that we're lost
because we're still interfacing with the
world with an old version of ourselves
that's no longer resourceful for the
physiological biological change is
happening in our body that you begin
oftentimes they'll begin to make
decisions that they would have made when
they were 21 because there's a there's a
there's a feeling of unease right become
40 and there's a feeling of unease the
things are not the way I think they
should have been or the way there and
then in that anxiety you resource you
you go back to and you begin bringing up
all the old things that are associated
with an ego there's no longer
resourceful for the process of becoming
a stronger version of yourself to to to
be allowed you have to die to those old
desires die to the old fears hopes and
dreams such that there's a complete
obliteration all right old wineskin
right you can't you can't put new if
you're wanting to be new you can't pour
in new goals in the old you you can't
pour inspiration into an old you you
can't pour old wine into an old wineskin
because you'll ruin the wine the wine
won't stay fresh and the wine skin will
disintegrate it can't hold it the
container can't hold it so you're
needing to reconstruct yourself in a new
way so that you can take on the
challenges and approach the the truth
about who you are in the next phase of
your life what this requires is not only
a conscious and deliberate going down
process a conscious and deliberate
catalysis period it
also requires that while you're down
there while you're in the belly of the
beast while you're dying to your old
self so that you could be reborn again
you begin to look with those things that
are actually true you begin to look at
the things that you've ignored you begin
to look at the things that are truly
resourceful for you and what your legacy
will be in your life right so there's a
process of death and dying to those
things that are no longer resourceful
and a bringing forward of those things
that you've either forgotten about that
we're in the shadow that need to be
resolved that need to be brought forward
because they're gifts right shedding
light on those things that have been in
the shadow allows you to process them so
that's that I have more to say about it
but I need a break
I'll leave you with this last analogy by
the way you know I refer to biblical
stories and whatnot because most a lot
of people know them I don't refer to it
because I'm Bible helping or hoping that
you'll become a Christian I am NOT a
Christian myself but I am a lover of
wisdom I am a lover of wisdom literature
I'm a lover of religion because it is my
experience in my belief that the
manifestations of God being Abraham
Moses Jesus Buddha Muhammad Krishna
Zoroaster Omaha LA all come to earth at
a particular time they're all imbued
with the Spirit of God to teach us
things that we need to know so I truly
believe that the the pure essence of
these teachers teachings are loaded with
value and can bring value into anyone's
life so I advise you to open yourself up
to reading the parables in the Bible and
reading other wisdom literature that
being said Jonah in the whale is a
wonderful story about what happens when
it's time to die to yourself and be born
again Jonah was a blessed dude Jonah was
doing well he was well off his wealthy
he was well-liked
in his City and he was winning God your
intuition the universe however you'd
like to relate to the omnipotent the
unknown to the ever-present to the
Creator will tap you on your shoulder it
happens not by a deep voice coming from
the cloud that's a figment of our
imagination those are vain Imaging's and
idle fancies as baha'u'llah would called
it but it comes in the form of a sense
within for me it comes from a sense
within when I quit youtube videos
because God had been kind of asking me
to do this thing and you can watch my
videos leading up to my choosing the
quick where I'm like something's not
right
I don't know what's going on really I
was resisting
but essentially God was saying heyy I
need you to give up the things of the
world for a moment because I have
another job for you Jonah was doing well
God tapped on the shoulder and said
Jonah I need you to help me out with
something I have another mission for you
but you're gonna need to detach yourself
from the things of this world I know
you're a successful guy I know that
you're doing well right Elliot I know
that you're doing well you've got a
million subscribers on YouTube but I
have greater things for you I mean need
for you Jonah right all of us like
myself resist ah I can't do that I can't
give up all of this fame I can't give up
all of this fortune I can't give up
everyone loving me and so what happens
is when you get that tap on the shoulder
if you ignore it you end up like Jonah
Jonah went out on a boat with his boys
not too long thereafter a storm came
right and he ended up getting tipped off
over the boat into the deep dark watery
unconscious and not only did he die deep
into the waters right into the darkness
into the shadows because that's where
the work happens the work always happens
down deep below in those watery
unconscious areas but he was swallowed
by a fucking whale in the belly of a
whale now what happens in the belly of a
whale down deep below in the unconscious
digestion happens and what is digestion
Jonah was being worked on in that belly
what is digestion digestion breaks
things down and when it breaks it down
it pulls out those things that are more
most resourceful it pulls out those
things that are needed it pulls out
those things that are nourishing and it
gets rid of the shit there are times
when you will be digested in order to
get rid of the shit so that you're
nourishing self can rise to the top done
I think I'm going to finish there
[Music]