okay so we got a question from our buddy
Johann who his father is in the hospital
right now with a brain tumor and is
gonna die pretty soon and Johann cannot
bring himself to go to the hospital see
his father because it hurts him so much
he gets really choked up he becomes
angry frustrated and he feels as if
going to visit his father just makes
things worse for him and he won't go and
visit him he goes and sees his father
and you know his father can't speak so
he's just kind of like laying there
looking at him and it just makes you
want uncomfortable but he feels guilty
you know he's like I want to and it
truly it seems as if he loves his father
but the pain is just too great what does
he do things days and weeks are going by
and he's not seeing his father you know
Johan my concern more is more for you
than actually it is for your father
because he is going to pass like I said
he's going to die but you're going to
live with the guilt of not sharing this
time with him for the rest of your life
if you don't and even though it's
uncomfortable for you to show up there
and be with him just for a few moments
you need to get over it okay that's the
first thing and it's easier said than
done so I'm going to afford you just an
alternative idea i would say the first
thing is just dude go and cry ball you
know all the uncomfortable feelings that
you're getting are merely a form of
dissonance it's the resistance against
you actually letting out that which is
bubbling up in your body so a real man
and when I say a real man I mean someone
who's grounded in their actions would go
and see his father and just if he looks
at you with that I'm gonna die and miss
you son look cry just ball just hug him
and cry and ball and leave it all right
there on the hospital bed it's going to
be so cathartic in so many levels and it
will free you from the guilt of having
to live with never expressing this with
him he's going to pass he will be okay
you are going to be in pain for a very
long time if you don't do this if you
can't bring yourself to doing this the
other option would be to write to write
to him every night before you go to bed
pull out pad and pen and you write out
everything and this may even be more
impactful because you can when you write
you actually take the time to embody
your feelings with words words or
symbols that represent abstract ideas
and feelings so by writing it out you
can actually come to greater grips with
what's going on and then also he will
feel peaceful knowing that his son is
with him even though he isn't with him
share those letters with him you know if
you go there and it's just too tough to
take or and you just hand him the letter
and you walk out maybe someone else
could read it to him or if you just give
it to someone and say here place to take
us to my father apologize for to him for
me not being there but he will get the
opportunity to read it and you will be
free from the burden of carrying all of
the emotion associated with a painful
loss of your father or losing thereof so
that's it either way it's more a form of
catharsis for you it's more of a way of
for you to get out what's happening in
you because that suppression that moral
judgment or that restriction of your own
emotion hurts you physiologically
physically mentally and it will hurt you
for a long time because of the guilt
associated with doing that you got to
get it out good luck buddy