so our friend the Medi wizard is a
genius apparently he's in the top 5% of
his class
he's studying computing computer
engineering 20 years old and apparently
he's gifted he says that his parents and
teachers everyone recognizes like what
is pretty freakin brilliant computer
engineering is not easy shipped to be in
the 5 percent of your class it's awesome
problem is he fucking hates it he wants
to be a Navy SEAL right so Computer
Engineering geek to Navy SEAL and
apparently this is something that he's
felt in his heart from home for a long
time since ever since I was a kid I've
always wanted to be a Navy SEAL and I've
done everything that everyone's asked me
to do up until this point I'm in college
now I'm at an age where the choices I
make is going to determine the rest of
my life to a great degree you can always
change your mind but to a great degree
what's going to happen for the next
several years is wrapped up in the
choices that you make here today the
world supports you parents teachers the
accolades associated with all the all
the greatness of your talent being
expressed through computer engineering
and school versus I want to be a Navy
SEAL boy I will be a cowboy that's what
it was really what it is it's that
calling in every boy's heart to be a
fucking cowboy we all work we've all
been there we put on our cape and we've
been Superman we take our sword we're a
man we've carried around semi-automatic
plastic guns and look man I've been out
there because there was there was a time
in which I did I was going into the
Marines after college and I did all that
I forget what it was called officer
school anyway
I did all their tests and stuff I mean
because a part part of me a part of us a
part of men part of our DNA is wrapped
up in warrior nests and it's not good or
bad it just happens to be the
conditioning that we receive it's our
karma from generations of warlike
behavior I mean the history the recorded
history of the world is based on warrior
matter if it's the East the West Africa
South America men we have always one of
the things we do we build and we kill
and that sentiment still lingers with it
us and right now it's raring its ugly
head
or perhaps beautiful head right because
what I'm about to share with you is
going to make you really think a little
deeper right it's completely different
from where you're going right now so I'm
going to preface what I will offer you
with one of the most profound statements
I've ever heard
successful people don't make the right
decisions they make their decisions
right so what that means is if you
choose a which is your computer
engineering degree or you choose be your
Navy SEAL this coming cowboy I will tell
you that this is the wrong decision the
wrong one absolute wrong decision you
will fuck up the rest of your life
by making this decision and this
decision is the absolute wrong decision
it is the worst decision you could
possibly make you will totally fuck up
your life if you make this decision
right damned if you do damned if you
don't
that's another profound one damned if
you do damned if you don't so the point
is that it does not matter which one you
choose it will I'll offer you a little
bit of insight it will matter but really
what matters is who are you when you are
in this situation are you going to make
the situation which is you go in so you
can do the whole Navy SEAL thing and the
minute you get into buds you and there
you got somebody screaming in your
fucking face and you're like sucking
water and drinking all this saltwater
because you can't swim and you're like
Eeyore tired and you're dying and you're
starving and you feel like you're on the
brink of death you know what you're
gonna say boy it'd be nice to be an
air-conditioned classroom studying
computer engineering shit everybody was
right I'm talented I'm gifted why the
fuck am I doing this right I got I
guarantee you I promise you you'll have
that situation if you choose maybe
feels and if you choose the the other
one right the traditional path one that
everybody wants you to do that you
happen to be cursed with the ability to
do you're going to 38 times more so than
none we're gonna be like sit in class
daydreaming about crawling through
barbed wire with guns in your hands and
jumping out of their airplanes right
both of them you're going to be screwed
both of them are going to offer you
conversations that do not support the
choice that you've made neither of them
are the right choice what you do based
on which you choose is what matters more
than anything who you become in the
process of whatever you choose so your
damage if you do you're damned if you
don't I'm not going to tell you which
one to do that's up to you but I can
offer you this one little piece of
mighty advice when you're on your
deathbed when this game is all said and
done because really that's all it says
we take it so fucking seriously it's a
game folks
really in so many regards but that's
that's that's for another rant you are
going to be more proud of the choices
that you've made for yourself for
godless of the outward circumstances so
in other words you'll be more grateful
for the mistakes that you made because
you followed your heart then for the
success that you gained by following
other people's verdicts for you no one
goes to their dying bed saying you know
what I'm so glad that I did what
everyone else told me to do what's
coming up in your heart it's not right
it's not wrong our parents our teachers
the world bound will tell us what we
should do there is no should there's
what's going to happen and you're the
only one that can make that choice but
if you follow everyone else as opposed
to following yourself you will be
resentful at least if you choose Navy
SEAL and it's a fucked up experience the
worst experience ever
you made it it's yours self-reliance
mine I'm responsible see the problem is
nobody wants responsibility because with
responsibility comes hey you made your
bed now sleep in it right people with
their cake and eat it too I'm full of
all these love Psalms today right I
don't know proverbs what'd you make they
want their cake and they want to eat it
too
so choose the Navy SEAL thing he'll be
the worst thing never fucking do but
it's yours sleep in that fucking bed
you're gonna hate it and then resent it
but it's yours
choose the computer engineering hey same
thing if you hate it fucking resent it
but someone else made you do it
good luck