we got this really good question for our
buddy James here and pull it up and he's
asking about his energy and social
interactions he says that uh you know he
can talk with others and provide good
energy for about an hour to when he's in
group settings but after that time he
becomes almost disengaged from a lack of
energy lackluster and quiet since he
just ends up sitting there the lack of
focus like a sink full of water being
drained rapidly and uh he finds this to
be a problem he says do we have any
suggestions how I can mint to maintain
my interest in these conversations with
other people or um or so they just
changed my the people I hang out with
dude I can totally relate to you a lot
and as energetic as I am and as much as
I can talk in these videos and so my
videos like 20 minutes I can go on and
on and on and on there's a big
difference between interacting and a
social group of people where there is an
exchange of energy those who have higher
energy and those who have lower energy
and just like water energy it like you
mentioned goes from higher to lower and
people can drain you I talked to a
fucking camera this camera didn't do
anything to me it's just a lens and I
can go on and on and on and on but in
social interactions I find like yourself
that I start out with a bag I'm
generally very good socially in the
beginning but quickly I allow and when I
use that word allow I want to come back
to that and have you understand how
you're doing this as well I allow other
people to drain my energy when you show
up with a lot of vitality and vibrance
like you probably do in the first hour
to hear your interaction with other
people the the the table is set for
who's going to dish out and who is going
to receive and if you end up being one
of those people who are a dish or outer
of your energy then you very quickly end
up with an empty dish and everybody else
is full you know and there are those
people who are just they call them
vampires they're just endless pits
bottomless pits that will drain you of
everything you have all of your
nourishment if we continue to that use
that metaphor of the table they will
just eat
eat and eating you give and give and
give and you can very quickly not only
just lose your energy but become very
resentful to people in your group or
their group as a whole and I personally
and I would invite you to also consider
that you have to protect yourself before
you get to this point where you're
completely drained and now you feel
guilty for not being able to interact
socially recognize that in your just
your personality and I relate to you in
this particular way you're a giver you
just you just give it all out there
so in that way you're also Victor you're
not just a victim but you're also the
creator of this this imbalance between
energy that ultimately leaves you
drained I've recognized this about
myself and I've battled with this since
I was very young I mean I remember being
in elementary school and I'm I was just
a firecracker ball of energy right they
I had so much energy they gave me pills
to shut me down a little bit because I
just had too much of it and because I
was you know ten years old I had so much
of it that I just I just spiked them
like a machine gun
everywhere I go home take a nap and I be
good again you know that didn't work
when you know as you get older and and
and the drainers the vampires become
more pathological and in you you start
recognizing the the pathologies the
sicknesses and how they're using you to
feed them to feed their to feed their
illness in this way so without going
down that route and you quickly start
putting up fences you puts up put up
walls and you start being very cautious
about who you relate with and how you
dish out your energy and as an adult now
I've come to this place where I I'm
still the giver that I typically in I do
so much better on the with the camera
because the camera doesn't take anything
from me right but um but I'm still a
dish or outer of my energy this is what
I love to do I feel as if it's you know
it's a part of all of our legacy to give
in this particular way in some
particular way we have to give
you my friend are an energy giver in
these social interactions but be mindful
of the tendency to be drained and when
you're amongst people feel no guilt for
checking out own it when you when you
feel as if you need to recoup your your
energy and you need to step out just
just say hey guys it was great I'm gonna
take a step over here I'm gonna go over
here now or I'm gonna go take a walk
just go take a walk if you're at a party
I get it do you wanna go sit in the
corner and stare it and start meditating
right start doing Qi Gong right go to
the go into the corner go or just start
doing some bioenergetics right I mean
well maybe you do I don't know yeah
maybe you will that starts some
conversation around you but anyway you
got to go you know you have to go
somewhere you got to cultivate some
energy go for a walk do just check out
just leave for a little while
don't apologize just say hey guys it was
nice I'm gonna go take a little walk Oh
is everything all right now I'm cool I
just want take a walk go and be with
yourself again recharge yourself again
ground yourself once again because it's
one of the things that you're going to
experience is that when you not only
have drained yourself but now you're
you've got this this cognitive
dissonance where there is a moral
judgment placed on what's happening
physiologically what happened
physiologically is your fucking drained
what's the moral judgement is oh I'm a
bad person because I can't interact with
everybody and they all look like they're
having fun and now I am I'm a douchebag
because I can't hang out with them and I
think and people are gonna think poorly
of me so that's the moral judgement
being placed on the physiology
physiological response within you and
that is a trap also so it makes you even
more tired instead of allowing that to
happen and allowing allowing the social
interaction to beat you up own it and
check out feel ok be okay with being
quiet also when they're when you're in
social interactions what's going on over
here and and there's an opportunity to
be quiet like you really have nothing to
say don't feel as if you have to talk
that's another one of these things where
we it's one of these social weirdnesses
where we feel as if because there are
people around and there's conversation
that it must go on and then there's this
awkward silence if you don't say
anything when that awkward silence shows
up you know what's a really cool thing
to do that will ground you it'll focus
you ground you and it will it will
change the energy completely once you
get past the awkwardness is to look at
the other people look be the one to look
in the eyes and breathe deeply if you
look in someone's eyes right
and now awkward silence and you find
that your breathing has been interrupted
now you're increasing the level of
anxiety making the awkwardness that much
more awkward but if you just stop and
you just be with the moment be it
another dude or a woman and you just
look at each other and breathe there is
a level of intimacy that occurs that
goes far deeper than the superficial
words that you're spitting at each other
because you feel you have to in fact you
might find the greatest communion
between yourself and others in the group
in that moment of silence breathe
through the awkwardness and you'll find
that there is a deeper level of
relationship that you can develop so
that's it man don't feel bad about it
look people always want to talk to me
and sure don't feel bad about it own the
moment step away and gather yourself if
you need to and seek to develop deeper
bonds with people instead of superficial
bullshit language about sports and the
weather done