so sometimes people ask me Elliot why do
you like Ron Paul so much very first
things you got recognizes that it's not
ron paul that i love as much as it is
the idea of freedom and liberty freedom
and liberty is what i am attached to and
in love with ron paul just happens to be
the bird that's currently singing that
song at the forefront whatever bird
sings that song it's a beautiful song
and I'll be attached to it I think most
Americans if you ask them do you love
Liberty do you love freedom they're
going to say yes right well I'm not so
sure that's always true and i think that
the definition of liberty and freedom
has been sort of miscommunicated and
confused so I made this short video for
you just to ask questions in three basic
areas like broad areas that you can ask
yourself to find out if you love freedom
and liberty or not and it is just that
black and white there's no half pregnant
on this you either love the idea of
civil rights for everyone in every
capacity or you don't there's no I like
these rights but not those rights it's
one or the other so there are three
areas that we're going to discuss and
you ask yourself yes or no on these
topics it's not about being right or
wrong okay if you choose not to love
Liberty that's fine that's your personal
philosophy that's okay i'm not here to
tell you that you're a bad person the
point is you can't go around saying that
you love Liberty if you want to take it
away from someone else the three general
areas are civil rights monetary policy
and foreign policy as far as civil
rights is concerned if I want to keep my
guns I should not infringe upon the
right of someone else to marry who they
want to marry I should be able to do
what I like to do with my life and not
infringe upon the rights of someone else
so if you want to marry a man marrying a
man or a man marrying a goat I really
don't care as long as you're just not
interfering with me or anyone else
you're not causing harm to anyone that's
a whole point and on the flip side
anyone on on one end of the spectrum
shouldn't interfere with my or someone
else's ability and freedom to do what
they want when you value civil liberties
it essentially means
you leave everyone else alone to do what
they want to do right so you're the love
freedom where you don't in that regard
then its monetary policy so everyone's
been worried about the economy and we've
got these inflation's and these
deflation we're basically experiencing
inflation that's causing all the gas
prices to go up I mean a gallon of milk
is going up everything is going up in
price and it's mainly because the
government's intervention in our
monetary policy or a monetary policy
that's just not sound in my opinion
which is one of intervention essentially
the printing of more money like you when
you were a kid and you had baseball
cards if there were just a handful of a
particular player the value of that
player was high right but if there were
tens of thousands or hundreds of
thousands printed of that card the value
goes down the same thing is happening
with our money that's why things are
costing so much I went to the store the
other day and an orange cost me a dollar
and I live in Florida it doesn't make
any sense so you either believe the
government should get involved with how
money is created and how its distributed
which is another very important point
should the government be she taking
money away from one person to give it to
another taking money from one person and
giving it to the others the same it's
just like stealing doesn't matter who
has it or if you like that person or if
they're in a part of the socio-economic
ladder that is that you don't like
there's you can't take something from
someone that they rightfully earned and
I'm not talking about the one percent
you know the people who are creating
these policies of these unfair policies
I'm talking about your general
entrepreneur and job creator right you
can't take something from him and give
it to someone else and believe in
freedom now you may think that's okay
and that's fine you should think that
there's wealth distribution with regard
to monetary policy and at the government
should keep printing money that's if
that's your deal then that's fine just
don't go around saying that you love
liberty or you love freedom because
that's not freedom that's not Liberty
okay it's not right or wrong and then
foreign policy is the same idea do we
now be very clear that there's a
difference between defense defending
yourself and
sending yourself towards others and they
may call it pre-emptive Wars you can
give it whatever name you'd like it's a
crusade of sorts to spread democracy in
the same way that the Crusades spread
Christianity whether you think it's
right or wrong to spread this idea of
democracy by infringing upon the
livelihood of other people getting
involved in wars that that really don't
have any impact on our safety at home
and let it be clear we are very safe at
home our defense is good but do you feel
as if that yes the America should go and
extend itself into the affairs of other
nations namely what's going on with with
Iran and Israel that's a big one why are
we there do you believe we really belong
there then that's fine that's what your
deal is just don't say you love freedom
and liberty because it's not the same
thing freedom and liberty means
non-intervention essentially means no
one's going to tell you what to do and
you don't go button your nose in other
people's business and telling them what
to do so this video was just to make
things clear not to tell you you're
right or wrong but let's get very
focused and clear about what Liberty is
because if we lose sight of what that
actually means we'll continue down the
slippery slope of losing all of our
freedom and liberties and that is the
foundation upon which this nation was
built Elliot's it what