got this question from Matt he's uh he's
working as a mechanic and his manager
the guy that he works directly with is a
total bully like just beets on and
basically takes things out of his hands
puts him down makes him feel terrible
and our buddy man who used to be an
outgoing type A personality guy that's
basically what he says um is feeling
depressed it's been a year now he
doesn't know what to do this guy is his
boss but treats him like a bitch you
know in different terms and Matt is fed
up he doesn't know how to stand up to
this guy but he's it's really ruining
his life
he says that he can't work out anymore
he doesn't want to eat it's really
messing with him Matt I've said this in
other videos but um one of the things
that happens to us when we're children
is that out of the kindness of their
hearts because they want to see good
things for us our parents tell us no
stop you can't aggress yourself you
can't move forward there are certain
things that you need to hold back on and
defiance against the parent is one of
them they're know is stronger than yours
in other words you can't tell them no
but they're constantly telling you know
you know and I think the majority of us
can relate to this you know that your
parents were bad or my parents were bad
it's that this is how order was held in
the home so the most powerful tool that
we have is a human being
which is to say no which is to deny to
turn something down that doesn't feel
good is slowly taken away from us so
that we become very passive and kind of
even in many ways passive aggressive
where no one wants to really step up and
say no they kind of take the shit and
then you know do something on the side
to make themselves feel better what
we've got to do is we've got to
strengthen our know once again we've got
to become we've got to stand up for
ourselves and no this is like the point
of your question what do i do how do i
stand up for myself practice saying no
in more comfortable situations because
you might notice that this is a pattern
in your life being indecisive and not
having the ability to
turn things down when you would really
rather you know you become what's called
a yes-man
and you know someone wants to go
somewhere you really don't want to and
you just say okay well let's go say no
practice no not only practicing no don't
only just practice no with other people
will practice it with yourself look in
the mirror and charge up your body I'm
always talking about deep breathing make
sure you're breathing deep look in the
mirror and say no no no I won't I won't
no no get very animated with yourself
and bring that no out bring that know
from the depths of your soul breathe out
because it's a tool that needs to be
undone up and used again then when you
feel comfortable in yourself saying no
and this shouldn't take very long
practice it for a week go up to this man
before you do this before you go up to
him right because you don't want to be
you don't want to be too high in your
energy when you do this one be grounded
make sure you're breathing deep make
sure you can feel your feet and walk up
to him and kindly explain to him that
you do not like the way you're being
treated here look him in his eyes
because you own the know you own that
moment he can't beat you up right and if
he does then just sue him and then you
have the whole business to yourself Lou
come in his eyes breathe deep you might
be scared at first and that's fine
that's normal but explain to him
don't bah use a sandwich technique where
you say something nice in the beginning
and nice the end you tell him I will no
longer accept the type of behavior that
you're portraying towards me I do not
appreciate being treated the way you
treat me don't be angry see there's a
difference between being assertive and
making your point be known and
frustration see because when you're a
kid and you said no at first it was just
a note you know no I don't I don't want
to eat right but then you know your
parents say you have to eat more all
right so then our know becomes angry no
bring your no into a place of
grounding and stay to him without being
angry just being assertive letting him
know you're you're informing him I do
not like the way you're treating me
that's it you don't have to offer him an
ultimatum you have to offer him anything
you'd have to give him a decision to
make
he just let him know look him in his
eyes and be silent he's gonna freak the
fuck out because he doesn't know what to
do he will have no clue what to do
because you are not following the
pattern the established pattern you've
created a pattern with him and and he's
gonna freak out he might be angry he
might be shocked he might be scared who
knows but just stay in there and watch
him and ask him once he's gone through
his convulsions just stand there and ask
him say is that understood just make
sure he understands as simple as that
you have to do this this is not a
question of like it would be a nice idea
this is something you have to do because
if you don't start strengthening your no
now and it seems like you're a young guy
people are gonna walk all over you for
the rest of your life bro it's going to
happen in very subtle ways because
you're going to keep averting or and
diverting this necessity to exercise
they see the same way you exercise in
the gym you want your arms to be
stronger so you do some curls and
presses you've got to exercise your
defiance it's the most powerful tool
that a human being has in a world that's
constantly pressing itself upon him know
what you want what you don't want and
assert the fact good luck Eliot sick
what