so I have a question here from a 19 year
old girl and I almost cried I want to
cry for you reading your question
she begins with Elliot I am ugly my
family thinks I'm ugly and I've been
told so I have no friends and I hear
people say that I'm ugly they point and
they call me names I live in a small
town where everyone knows me as the ugly
girl
I once had a boyfriend and he broke up
with me because his mom told him that he
shouldn't be dating an ugly girl now the
very first thing is I want to commend
you for your ability to maintain some
form of grounding to be able to look at
the circumstance objectively which is
basically what you've done for you to
write the way you've written to me under
the type of pressure that you're
experiencing where everyone seems to be
your fucking enemy means that there's
something greater there's something more
powerful within you that's seeking
expression so for that I feel good for
you one of the things that we need to
understand especially those of us who
who feel as if we don't belong as if
there are so many people that don't
understand us as if we don't fit in as
if we're not good enough as if we're too
ugly is that we're living in a world
where there are multiple levels of souls
evolution and the way the soul of each
individual person expresses itself is
based on the evolution of that soul and
there are those who are still fucking
animals they live and look like human
beings because of a flesh that they walk
in but their souls expression is still
so base and primal that they can't see
beyond the flesh that is presenting
itself in other people because true
beauty is not found in the face
it's found in the character it's found
in the spirit its found in God's ability
to express itself through you
that's where beauty is found but we live
in a culture that praises the surface
that praises superficiality that praises
the facade and we have so many people
that have not dug any deeper than the
surface level in their own evolution
that for them to be able to see beyond
the mirages of other individuals makes
it very difficult for those who don't
fit in who don't stand up especially
visually so it's this is your souls
plight is to perhaps discover a place of
compassion for those who are still pigs
in their souls evolution I sound very
judgmental here and I am I'm I'm a
little upset but compassion is the place
to be when there are those that just
don't understand the reality of self
life beyond the flesh and what they see
and for you to be as well grounded and
pragmatic as you are to approach me the
way that you have means that your soul
is probably very mature and the
experience that you're having is perhaps
a way for your soul to continue learning
new things as you evolve as their soul
evolves as God works through you you see
the place where you might want to
perceive from now is to remove your
attention from that what you're
receiving turn it inwards and discover
the gift that's within you and focus on
developing and expressing and offering
it our greatest beauty is found in our
souls expression through service to
others in any way shape or form that our
heart feels fit and it's very important
because it doesn't look like Oprah it
may not look like Oprah see when I say
look like you may not express the same
way Oprah did Oprah was an ugly girl
she always tells the story I watched her
biography ugly girl told you she was
ugly who sexually abused felt ugly but
she found it in her that her ability to
do what she does do the Oprah thing
because it's unique in its own way and
I'm not an advocate for Oprah I'm just
using her as an example to serve other
people made her a beautiful person but
you may be you're really good at taking
care of plants what greater present gift
that you could bring to the world than
to develop horticultural life develop
the vegetative life in the world now
that's just an example maybe you love
music maybe you are an extraordinary
violinist or piano player or maybe not
maybe you just know how to appreciate
good music lean into and allow the
depths of that to happen through you
maybe you're going to be an incredible
mother because you know what
the world needs a lot more of those we
don't need any more successful people we
need more really good moms and again we
live in a culture where that is looked
down upon in fact so many women that
they feel as if it's an assault on their
rights as a human being to be a mom to
stay home and to care for their children
to bring forth life nurture care for
develop and love their children what
greater gift to the world that you could
give than to be a great mother you don't
have to be a fucking CEO and do the dick
contest thing with every single man in
the corporate world my point here is to
invite you to consider that your beauty
may not be the world's superficial
beauty but it's in there because each
one of us have it and it's your job to
go within discover cultivate and offer
it however it looks we
out comparing yourself even your gift to
other people's you just do the best that
you can with what you have and find
pleasure and joy and allowing God to
express itself the universe Allah the
DAO to happen through you unobstructed
good luck