have a straight question for our buddy
Alec who says he's a tough guy he likes
working out and talking to women he's
not gay he says but I like to cry what
does gay have to do with cryin anyway
but hey this is what he says says for
example he'll go to a movie and the
movie sad he'll cry and his friends will
giggle at him you know someone dies in
the movie gets all sets of mental and
cries another example is when I just sit
down and think about what the world is
coming to all the corruption loss of
life the evilness and so forth I don't
know why but I just start I get upset I
start crying I cry so easily any
suggestions or anything to help me not
be so sensitive Alec you clearly are new
to my channel because I teach people how
to cry I don't know if you've seen this
I actually use exercises that I teach
you exercises through these videos that
help people cry I've made videos where I
say you need to cry bro don't stop
crying my friend in fact it's one of the
greatest gifts that you've been given
don't harden yourself to the sensitivity
that allows you to experience life and
all that it has to offer many people
don't realize that the inability to cry
is synonymous with the inability to
laugh and orgasm they come from the same
place feel in your body where your cry
comes from your crying comes from here
just take notice next time you're about
to cry Alec here you start getting hot
and then the movement goes up into your
throat into your jaw yeah and then you
spit it out it's the release valve for
this for the emotion in your body that
most people have chosen to bite down on
you literally have to bite down on your
tears because you've got to stop the
movement of energy up into your throat
in your jaw tighten your upper lip
tighten up that lip right my daughter
she's really sensitive my youngest
daughter she cries at everything and she
realizes it makes everybody upset but I
tell her you could cry just cry but I
know when she's trying not to cry cuz
she was like this
this area the fee that people have
become so tense taught and and crowded
stifled stagnant with energy in it's
also the place where laughter comes from
that laughter reaches a little bit
deeper down into your pelvic floor
laughter is a little bit more like
orgasm in this way laughter comes from
the belly up through the chest and what
do you do get get get get get ha ha
looks very much like ah it's happening
in your body the same level don't don't
we defy that area that's associated with
releasing sorrowful feelings and sobbing
because you'll also tighten yourself
against the experience of laughter and
joy feel what happens in your body when
you orgasm because this is that this one
runs the deepest tears laughter orgasm
if you tighten your jaw you can't orgasm
orgasm looks like this there's a feeling
that happens deep within your pelvic
floor right you're you're about to jizz
and notice what happens to your face oh
you got to be soft here Oh
orgasm looks like oh right ha ha tighten
that shit up you are in orgasming
nobody orgasms put a tight fucking face
in fact if you want it here's one here's
a technique for follow these guys who
bust nuts too quickly
tighten your jaw right so if you're if
you want those guys three stroke punks -
Chuck - Punk chumps and you want to last
a little bit longer one of the things is
you can tighten your jaw go like this
and put the tongue on the roof your
mouth and then breathe five seconds in
pause five seconds out
what does that also look like someone
who's trying not to cry
someone who's trying not to laugh try
not to orgasm don't stifle that shit
brother it is one of the most beautiful
currents moving through your body be
grateful for it I have to rehab people
who can't do it you've got it as a gift
go cry like a little bitch enjoy every
bit of it because it allow you to enjoy
life done