yo Elliott hey whats up guys today we
got a question from our strength camp
online member Richard who goes on to
describe how he and his wife have found
interest in watching my training vlog
videos of my son camp channel and most
recently I've introduced my wife into
those videos i've been recording my
workouts I did this for many years and I
started training her earlier this year
and I decided well babe I'm will work
out you gonna be in the videos and she
resisted a little bit but glad to have
her there because you know a lot of
women get to see how strong woman works
out my woman is strong man and he goes
on to say how he and his wife kind of
have noticed the deep and profound love
that we obviously share with each other
and he goes on to say Elliot how do you
love someone into the strongest version
of themselves right assuming that that's
what I did right in love and Colleen I
love her deeply love her so much I could
eat her I do in fact she's delicious how
do you do it right well you know I'm not
gonna stand here and act like I have an
answer for a question that that
multi-dimensional but what I can do is
offer you a very interesting story I
once heard it's a weird story in fact
it's called a 10 cow bride it's all
about loving someone up to their
potential you know so it goes beyond
just our relationship with our women but
loving anyone in your life so there are
these three dudes three guys they got
that shit got cats eyes then they're on
their little row boat in the middle of
nowhere right starving sweating lips are
all chapped and shit cuz the sun's been
beating down on him for days
and they thirsty and I see they see a
little island somewhere they said oh
land land they get over to the to the
land they get on the island and him and
a king comes out and he says welcome to
our island you look like you need some
water you look like you need some fruit
so meet and a good time maybe some wine
so he brings them he brings these three
guys into the island and all the people
there or they're having a great time
they're probably half naked and stuff
because that's what people on Islands do
right and they're playing music and it's
always good music on those Islands I
don't play bullshit-ass music good music
wine eatin havin a good time they're
healthy again these people nurse them
back into health they all respect each
other love each other and it's a it's a
grand old grand ole time they have but
as time goes on and I guess they were
smoke signal in or some shit and somehow
the people back home discovered where
they were and they were coming to save
him we're getting off this island and
although the guys had a great time they
want to go home so the first guy he says
well thank you king thank you so much
for taking such care of us and being so
hospitable thank you people of the
island and he says goodbye and he walks
off second guy comes over shakes his
hand also thank you gratitude you people
are great we will be back say hello or
something I don't know and then they bat
hey guy bounces but the third guy comes
up to the king and he says King I
appreciate everything you've done for me
but I don't want to leave just yet in
fact I want to marry your daughter the
King says oh that is so wonderful that
is great we are also excited we'll throw
a huge feast and he goes over to his
daughter and he brings her over and
she's batting her eyes and shit and the
he presents her to the man it says thank
you so much for wanting to marry my
daughter she's a good woman and you know
we do bet dower ease and stuff here so
he says all you'll have to do
is give me five cows for this woman for
my wife you know that's I did traded
back man you know so he goes I sorry
King that ain't the one king of what
that I'm crazy because I got multiple
daughters and she's definitely the best
one and she knows she's the best one bat
in her eyes and shit and he goes no no
no no that's not the one so the King
goes over is like oh you must mean this
one Cynthia right what's a good island
named Cynthia ain't no damn Island named
Juanita pairs quanita any brains Queenie
took we need to look at all for love
shoes and sexy she's batting her eyes
and shit tuning key the guy goes no I'm
sorry King that's not the one I want
that 18 points to a little overweight
perhaps mrs. some teeth hair looks a
little not so great daughter and the
King goes whoa man hold on you don't
want her do you and she goes you don't
want me do you and he goes yes I do so
the King says listen man I get it
whatever it is maybe you'll freak or
something but hey you can have my
daughter for two cows right because they
do diaries two cows I'll take no more
and she goes yeah I'm only worth two
cows and the guy goes no I will hear
none of it i will pay you ten cows for
this woman and everybody who King goes
no the girl goes man you don't know what
you're getting yourself into it don't
work that way ain't no tank how bright
the man says sure I'll hear no more of
it i will pay you ten cows tomorrow and
i'll marry you're not so strongest
version of herself wife daughter now my
wife
alright whatever and they throw a big
party and everything goes great he gets
her 10 cow gives 10 cows to the king and
uh they get married they have children
life goes on storybook closes reopens
ten years later the old buddies who was
there with him the first time came back
to celebrate and say hey man we know
that you didn't come home with us but we
wanted to catch up with you came back on
the island there like that things are
looking pretty good around here King
what's up bro hey dawg who's that fine
woman you wit and he goes hey that's my
10 cab ride they say no no no no no you
didn't pay 10 cows for that ugly girl
last time we was here did you they say
yes then what happened how was she so
damn gorgeous right now moral of the
long-ass story is that he saw the beauty
in this woman even though she couldn't
see the beauty in herself and no one
else recognized the jewel that she was
and he paid the dowry for it meaning he
gave all that he believed that she was
worth in the form of love you know these
are all metaphors and shit it's not
really cows is how much you offer your
love to someone you love someone up to
the strongest version of themselves and
they reach that they become that wife
children co-workers if you can offer
your love and your appreciation your
gratitude and can see the gym that they
are even if they don't know it even if
the world doesn't know it they will grow
into that they will rise up to that it's
an expectation that goes beyond this is
what I expect you to do it's an
expectation that comes from the service
that you offer that person letting that
person know how beautiful that you think
they are let that person know how
amazing you think they are every single
day every day I come home with
cows for Colleen I reminder that I think
she's the most beautiful woman on the
face of the earth I let her know how
desirable I think she is she still makes
my mouth water I remind her of that
so it's not so much about giving someone
a plan for becoming a stronger version
of themselves i never asked colleen to
work out never once i asked her to work
out she was busy having babies for the
past 10 years she's just decided I want
to exercise never once asked her to do
anything that I thought she should do to
become a stronger version herself I just
loved her up to the capacity that she
was worth loving her up to her capacity
means we only gonna buy good food in
this house well then health always has
something to do with it you know you can
never really tell someone what a
stronger version of themselves look like
because it's very subjective but there
are some basic rules to this shit you
should probably be healthy but never
once did I force it on her I loved her
enough to give it to her you know every
time we went out of our way to buy
organic food when we really couldn't
afford it I was showing out another 10
cows because I thought she was worth it
that first time I bought her a nice car
man I remember she drove around us some
jalopies for a long time we had kids in
it man and I splurged because she was
worth it she was that was my 10 cow
dowry for her that day so i guess i
guess i guess the long story short here
is going on 10 minutes is that you love
someone up to the capacity that you know
they are and you remind them all the
time you show them all the time
[Music]
don't Elliot's it what