yo Elliot so we got this question from
our strength camp online member Nick st.
Nick like Santa Claus haha well our
friend Nick st. Nick is growing up and
his family that he's sort of leaving
behind don't really they're not evolving
the way that he's evolving he's getting
involved in his health and his personal
growth he's becoming a stronger version
of himself but they're still smoking and
drinking and partying and just just
straight-up naughty right Santa you know
their home being naughty and you're
doing nice things you got gifts right
and he's starting to feel guilty because
he's not spending time with them they're
starting to feel resentful towards him
because you know now he's better than
them because he's exercising and eating
well and growing stronger and they're
still eating cheese doodle cheez-its and
the twees Twizzlers and drinking RC Cola
and pabst blue ribbon beer all right
what else smoking Marlboro Reds haha so
you know they're naughty and you're nice
now you got gifts and the thing is that
uh that you're not sharing your gifts
with them right and you know what they
don't deserve it so you give them cold
and I guess it in your way of being
Santa Claus and giving them coal is your
sort of turning your shoulder 20 you
know away from them and not giving them
the love and attention that they once
received from you and so you know the
coldness begins and family separate and
then you know the typical path then
becomes you you move across the country
and you don't see each other for years
and resentment grows between the two of
you and you know holidays coming you
call and you kind of say well hello and
there
hello but there's kind of a fuck you
behind it but inside everybody's hurting
because really I just want to hug you
and I miss you and I love you and it's
all uncomfortable weird and an
unfortunate so you know it's funny Saint
Nick then I'm gonna have to teach you
how to be a little bit more like Santa
Claus right what if Santa Claus do man
Santa Claus doesn't hang around all the
time he ain't there all year long and
when he does come what did he do he
drops a gift that tickles you and he
sneaks away you don't need to
necessarily separate yourself from the
people who are your family you don't
need to separate yourself from from
really anyone it's a matter of how you
bless these people how you bless the
people in your life while maintaining
your own maintaining your own space to
grow and develop and early on in your
life it's going to be more you need more
of that right because in order to stand
on your own two feet you got to kind of
step out you got a you got to create
separation and I totally understand that
but um at the same time you don't have
to hang out with them and drink PVR's
and smoke Marlboro Reds you can make a
phone call and say hey Dad how you doing
I really missed you and you know what
drop him a gift send him a card right
it's really simple you don't have to be
there you don't have to engage and
you're damn sure can't change them right
that's like if if your dad well or if a
kid this kids let's stick with our
Christmas metaphor once say ah he wants
an iphone for Christmas and you get them
up you get them a hobbyhorse right I
know y'all know what the fuck that is
right getting one of horses that they
rock on all right a little wooden horse
right it's like hey I gave you a gift
that's kind of that that's like and done
to doing what you think is right for
someone because you think it's right you
know hey Dad you should stop drinking
that's like fuck you I won't more beer
right it's not up to you to give him a
hobby horse when he wants an iphone it's
not up to you to tell him hey daddy
here's some organic eggs
and vegetables you should eat this and
he's like I just wanted a pizza
but it doesn't take much to send a card
if he likes beer send him a beer man
done Elliott's it what