- programming and while I have a
question a lot of people ask me what is
the one book you would recommend and for
nutrition or health and it's always your
book that's the same one I recommend I
was just about to ask you so coming from
you what is the book that you recommend
uh I recommend that book because yeah
the best books I could recommend in all
the relevant fields and cultivated my
knowledge and experience in those key
areas and wove it into a system that
helps the person identify which key bits
of knowledge are going to make the most
rapid change in them right yeah so if
you score high in the stress chapter the
stress column you go to read the stress
chapter which is like a little book on
stress all the things you got to know
where you're never going to get better
mm-hmm so you know my book is is a
synthesis of many good books and you
know an entire lifetime and clinical
experience of knowing what is important
to worry about and what isn't important
to worry about you at any given stage of
your own evolution or journey right
because I feel like that book can heal
anybody well it a I tell people of time
before you spend five hundred bucks an
hour to come see me get it read it and
back to sit for four to six months and
then if you still a problem it's worth
coming to see me but if you come without
doing that you're going to pay me five
hundred bucks an hour to read that book
to you in a nice room with okay well I
love reading for five bucks now but you
know it's not really the best use of my
time nor their time or energy or money
right certainly there's cases where
people need me to clarify things but I
don't know of any single book that ties
the key essentials together in a package
that's fully customizable to any
individual there is none right you know
that's one so if I had to say what is
another great book that I think
everybody should read out see nutrition
and physical degeneration yeah because
that book comes from a time period where
science scientists weren't prostituting
themselves that you know scientists are
now the biggest prostitutes there is
yeah
and Weston Price was highly regarded as
a scientist was extremely intelligent
made many advances in multiple fields
and is the kind of guy that has the
credibility to listen to write and his
research was in the field authentic
observational not theoretical making
stuff up sliding scales based on some
illusory factor right and he shows you
with vivid vivid 'ti through photographs
what for example happens when a native
population eats processed sugar
processed flour or white men's foods for
one year and how their offspring now
show signs of genetic dysfunction and
inability to reproduce themselves
authentically so you have things like
flat feet craniofacial distortions
occlusal distortions airway distortions
balance and coordination distortions and
all the things you see in the pond'rous
cats the pond'rous yes right so because
food and water are what we recreate
ourselves out of they're really sort of
the the the paints and the artists
palette right and Elliott wants to make
himself bigger and stronger or faster if
he chooses the wrong foods from the
artist palette the wrong liquids it
actually goes against his training and
the training becomes even more of a
threat to the body as opposed to an aid
to accomplishing an objective so Weston
Price did a very good job of showing
that the first criteria for putting
anything on the palate of food the menu
is it it be legitimately good food the
second most important thing is that it's
the right good foods for you mm-hmm
right for example you can take
pineapples to the Eskimos and feed them
pineapple and they'll probably think
it's lovely and sweet but six months
later they all be swollen up bloated
they'll be gaining body weight like
crazy because they don't
the biochemistry to metabolize something
with that concentrated sugar in it
because nothing like that grows in an
ice field right so point being is you
can take blubber and feed it to the
Hawaiians and make them fatten sing to
write and throw their in biochemistry
off but the point I'm driving home here
is that both of them were eating
high-quality unadulterated organic raw
good food just the wrong ones yeah so
Weston Price made it very clear being
out nature and good food alone won't do
it for example he sure there were no
healthy vegetarian tribes so if there
was a healthy vegetarian tribe there was
a close one close by eating meat that
showed improvements in health overall
mm-hmm so he showed clearly that you if
it was a choice between eating meat not
eating meat that eating the meat
produced better overall general health
based on many reliable biomarkers such
as bone structure dentition energy
levels bowel movements things that are
normal to look at those those
realizations are really kind of like the
bedrock of what health is right it
doesn't matter what your your 24-hour
cortisol DHEA rhythm is or your
melatonin levels or your testosterone
levels or any of these other things
people are so vividly excited to measure
today and spend tons of money mmm right
if your diets wrong and you're not
getting enough sleep and doing the
things you got to do all the
testosterone patches and hormone patches
and supplements in the world are really
just a waste of time energy and money
and they actually are worse because they
give you a license to think that you're
okay yeah forth so you drive yourself
deeper deeper and deeper into the
illusion that you're behaving
effectively with regard to what it takes
to be a healthy human being you see my
brother