hey what's up so we got this question
from our buddy uh anonymous here today
he says that amongst his friends he's
been longtime friends with he's taken on
a particular role where he says he's the
cool confident guy who happens to be
sitting on the couch and having
conversation with other fellow weirdos
and unchallenging forms and ideologies
at the party so he's kind of the
magician nerd type amongst his friends
he says he's cool he's confident he's
witty but you know what there's more to
me than this and what he's doing is
starting to grow resentful towards his
friends for always approaching him from
that particular perspective you know
when you when you deal with a bunch of
friends especially boys we're like a
pack of wolves and everybody takes their
role right King warrior magician lover
and you happen to have taking a
particular role at a particular time and
they've snap shot at you and put you
into a pickle particular box and this is
normal natural human beings do this to
each other because we feet find comfort
and stability and one of the things we
want to feel comfortable and stable
about is our the people in our
environment so we put them into boxes so
that we can deal with them comfortably
on a daily basis now if you become too
erratic and start changing your mind and
changing who you are and behaving in
certain ways they're going to number one
become resentful towards you you like
what the fuck is going on here dude who
do you think you are that's one of
that's a great one who do you think you
are as if they know who you are or
they're gonna say things like why are
you trying to be different or why are
you trying to be more like that guy or
why are you changing on us they grow
very resentful and they become very
uncomfortable because they now have to
adapt to new circumstances and human
beings are lazy especially in our
dealings with other people we want to be
able to approach you the same way every
single day but human beings like
yourself are expansive multi-dimensional
dynamic you should be growing evolving
every single day there should be
something brand new about you your
patterns should change now many of us
get caught into our patterns based on
our character structure and the the
psychology of our are basically our
psychological makeup but you should be
evolving beyond that also and that's
what I always invite you to do in
becoming a stronger version of yourself
it's not so much what you do amongst
your friends but it's who your being and
you should be evolving your
now the real issue which happens to be a
deep issue with all human beings is that
they come to we come to idolize each
other one another meaning we take a
snapshot of a particular person and see
them for that which we have told
ourselves stories and believe that
that's what they are and that's all that
they are and that and that now they can
feel comfortable in relating to you that
way it's an ideology meaning that's
where the word Idol comes from many of
you say to me I read your comments and I
read your messages Elliott you were my
idol the problem with that is that the
idol is created the idol is never the
person the map is not the territory the
menu is not the meal idolizing someone
or putting someone in a box based on
your perspective of them the
circumstances you had in a snapshot that
you feel comfortable about them being in
it's like eating a menu thinking that
you're going to get the nourishment of
the food that's on it the idol is not
the person that's why I Daltrey is such
a bad idea because it's not fair number
one to the thing or the person that
you're idolizing and it's not fair to
you to because if you choose to imprison
somebody in that particular way that
means you are in the current of
imprisoning and others will imprison you
as well never allow yourself to idolize
someone not meaning worship but see them
for a piece of what you've chosen to see
them for you see them for the part of
them that you like you see those who say
well Eliot you're my idol and I idolize
you well that's very flattering but also
very scary to me because now I become a
slave to your idea of me and I guarantee
you I'll make this promise you meet me
especially to spend a few days with me I
will destroy how shatter all of your
idols like Muhammad in the temple I'll
destroy all your idols like Moses coming
down and seeing all them fucking idols
and getting mad because I'd altar he's a
sickening of the mind don't idolize me
because I will make you mad I will break
your heart I promise you I'll break you
heart cuz there's some nastiness there
are some parts of me that you go boo hmm
I could never imagine I'd break your
heart and then you grow resentful I know
some people who do this they've done
this to me I know some of you've done
this to me but you don't have as big a
horn as some of the people to make
YouTube channels that have adult Erised
me they idolized me and I broke their
heart and then what happens resent hmm
disgust your fucking fault it's their
fault if they begin idolizing you and if
you decide to change on them they need
to upgrade their idolatry or stop the
whole fucking game all together because
it's silly you understand be free in
yourself and allow the evolution to
happen through you if today you are the
sit down conversation and challenging
idea man at the party and tomorrow you
stand up and do backflips and you dance
wildly with women that's who you're
allowed to become you're allowed to even
explore different versions of yourself
right you come to know yourself and the
world has come to know yourself know you
through a particular way but you know
what I'm feeling groovy today I'm gonna
just change up today don't feel guilty
they're gonna make you feel guilty
people won't make you feel guilty about
evolving changing being something else
fuck them fuck them fuck you if you
don't like me today and you loved me
yesterday fuck you that's your problem
that's their fault what are the
strangest things is Elliot I used to
hate you but now I love you and then it
goes again but I hated you again I love
you again again look it has no bearing
on the actual person what they feel
about you has really no bearing on you
it's their adultery it's their ideology
about who you are and that is a prison
for you as well so mourn then just like
I'm warning you all of you now who see
me as an idol
I'm going to disappoint you because I'm
going to change there are some things
about me that you're not going to like
don't say it your idea about me is your
idea and it's your fault
if things happen to get uncomfortable
between us that's your problem my friend
my anonymous friend deal with your
friends the same way adultery is a
sickening of the mind it's a diamond and
when I say this word I use this term it
sounds strange because like it doesn't
mean that they worship you it means they
have come to deal with you in a
particular way and you represent
something to them
don't let them shackle you up into that
representative ideology of who you
should be don't do that shit to me
either
done