so we got a question from our friend
John he goes on to talk about how he's
having a hard time fitting in with
people because he's just a bit too loud
and opinionated and and he turns people
off he goes on to say how people tend to
enjoy his company for a little while but
almost like a child who has lost the
interest in a toy that once entertained
them they seemed to drift off and and
John's having a hard time because nobody
wants to hang out with him for a long
time because of his vitality because
he's just so boisterous John asks me
what I think simply because he has a
feeling that perhaps I've dealt with
something very similar because I'm a
pretty high-energy boisterous vital
person right loud aggressive and and
he's right the tendency for me is to be
that particular way and John you're
absolutely right when I was a kid up
until I mean not too long ago ten years
maybe go I've had difficulty in making
and and maintaining friendships and
relationships just like yourself and I
also like you refused to shut down my
reality shut down the vitality that I
hold and is being expressed through me
in order to help other people feel
comfortable you know they actually even
gave me ritalin when I was a kid because
I had too much energy this kid was just
too much so they had to give me pills to
shut me down just a little bit it's
lonely I was lonely there's no other way
around it if this is who you are and you
were hell-bent on being yourself because
like Ralph Waldo Emerson says that one
of the different ones difficult thing
probably the most difficult thing for a
man to do in a world is constantly
trying to change him is to be himself
and it seems like you've got the
strength of will that regardless of what
other people think or say you're going
to be yourself Ralph Waldo Emerson also
goes on to say that to be great is to be
misunderstood and I've come to realize
through my courage and experiences in LA
that even though there are going to be
people that don't like me if I continue
to be relentless in my individuality
that I'll be able to express the
greatness that's within me a lot of
people gonna be turned off you
experience this you've got too much
energy and just like a child that's very
hyperactive has a lot of energy runs
around a lot you make adult so you make
people who are much more clenched held
in tight neurotic you make them very
uncomfortable for a number of reasons
number one because they're energetic
processes are shut down to a degree that
bright lights and you're a fucking
bright light bright lights shot them
right most adults experience this too
much loudness too much excitement they
shut down because they're energetic
processes who they are has they built up
a wall right and you also remind people
of the type of vitality that they may
have experienced and expressed as a
child that through socialization they've
had to shut down so I don't wanna make
this video too long
listen my friend continue to be yourself
it's going to be difficult people are
going to like you plain and simple
that's it people aren't going to like
you you're probably not going to have
very many friends but if you're
relentless in being being yourself and I
don't mean this in an arrogant way I
don't mean you go around
flaunting and being arrogant about who
you are but just being genuine being
true to who you are because even as I
come across as a harsh person everything
that I do comes from the depths of my
heart and the people who meet me in
person know that I'm genuine in my love
and appreciation in sharing my ideas
even though they may be diametrically
opposed to others they they appreciate
because I'm doing it from my heart not
from a place of anger frustration and
arrogance so continue to share from what
from a place of your heart and those who
really need to be attracted to you the
ones that you've been set here to to
liberate through your own personal
freedom will be attracted to you Elliott
sit what
[Music]