it's funny how like oh yeah you know I
remember that I remember you come to me
I play the saxophone it's just funny how
like life takes whatever course is
supposed to take I played the saxophone
with a bunch of kids I'm thinking of one
kid in particular David Dominique I
don't be watching my videos but he was
in high school with me were pretty good
friends I keep it through elementary
school and we were both basically the
same at our instrument I was good at
saxophone he's good the he played the
trumpet I believe and today he composes
his own music I believe I just see him
on Facebook and stuff he tours he's like
all over Europe and stuff I think and
he's really a badass or when it comes to
to playing his instrument and like
making a living doing it he's 35 years
old like me and he's ah he's really
taking something that he loves and he's
always loved as we were like in
elementary school play instruments and
he's he's making a life not even earning
a living that's fucking bullshit or any
living he's creating a life around his
love for music I think that's the
coolest fucking thing ever but I on the
other hand I actually dropped out
because there was uh either you play
football or you play in the marching
band you don't do it'll do both and I
was a little bit better at smashing
people's faces in then twiddling my
fingers so I was like well played
football it's turned out for the best I
suppose
right now my call me captain tosen baby
there's a we have a great sport academy
okay and then we got like a music
program it's all right I'm like that kid
that's in both of them and that's a girl
yeah it's funny how they make the kind
of a chirp chirp a casino yeah the music
to talking with the gym like a douche
bag for instance yeah and I'm like don't
talk with the geeks in this department
which is for ya you gotta bring it
together I think I don't wanna I get
that feeling you know well I'll just
look at the uniforms I think that's what
got me was like imma put on a football
helmet pads or we're gonna put on like I
don't know like there was like a big
chapter where like golden pants and
white sleeves when I was like yeah I'll
take the football helmet hahaha but uh
my brother took it and he yearns a life
he built a life around music he did some
really cool stuff with his students he
teaches elementary school good choice
what do you see yourselves doing
retarded question no but maybe you've
thought of it ten years from now he's
got that's a long time from that oh man
well everything I love doing changes
within months right that's it you know
three months of playing my guitar
non-stop and after that into sprinting
sprinting all the time and it's like I
wanna go I wanna be like the Olympics or
something after Dino like offering a
guitarist it just changed stock reports
right like right now I'm kind of like I
lost reckon conditioning I like that
connection like watching Paul check in
you it's a I love connecting the two
things velocity and strength
cool like I love that stuff right I like
how long I know what happened you know
that's all bull ring base its hold the
arena Paul introduced me to the I to the
remix of holistic health philosophy
religion and fitness I mean to take the
things and those are all things i love
but people will tell you well either
you're going to be a scientist or you're
going to be a coach or you're going to
be a musician say wow i'm going to some
crazy fucking blending of this shit and
i'm going to turn it yourself brand new
if the world's gonna love it that's true
creativity in my mind because not to say
that everything has been done and
figured abuses definitely that work
that's definitely true at all but what's
available in the way of creativity now
because there's so much that has been
done is that much greater because you
can remix just like Puff Daddy began
remix in music from 70s with hip-hop
it's like no you just take take I've
been reading a lot of uh yo call yo the
psychology through reading a lot of
gauteng who's a soft philosopher and
I've taken a lot of work of Wilhelm
Reich and then Joseph Campbell all which
have nothing to do with weight training
and blended it with power lifting body
building snowmen yeah and somehow
creating something that I don't think is
really that prevalent brand new so if
you love multiple different things that
the gift now to the world's into
yourself will be how do I boom this shit
together and create something brand new
they kind of give into it right I gotta
make a living I got to make money yeah
do something right and if you're in my
spot you know it's okay I could go into
University and go into this science or
whatever and dumped gives me a better
chance of getting an awesome job
difficult to music I'm like you know a
lot of search for gigs and stuff frankly
that's a tough life right but you know
you talk to guys that are searching for
gigs and they're like yeah you know what
I don't have too much I've been living
on the road with my band but it's a good
time you know and and when you do have a
little bit and they go and they have a
few drinks and they enjoy themselves
feel like life is good then there are
guys who have a really good job can't
stand going home to their wife hate
their fucking boss their customers get
on their nerves and they got to take
pills so they could sleep at night they
drink their weekends away and they're
depressed reason John Gooden what's that
which is a misconception right yeah Seth
Godin you should feel the icarus
deception by Seth Godin he talks about
this very thing yeah we've been lied to
about what we're supposed to do because
a real gift to ourselves into the world
is to do what our heart wants us to do
and I got to tell you this in my own
experience it works out if it's pure
from your heart my father was a really
wise guy and I spent some time at our
house yesterday and he's just adamant
we've just been adamant since I was a
kid and I guess that's where I get it
from that as long as you follow your
heart you have nothing to worry about
you will never have anything you'll
never be hungry you'll never be sick sad
or depressed as long as your heart is at
peace you could have no food you could
have no legs and you could you can't
speak any longer but if your heart is
that piece and you feel good in your
heart you're a happy person how many
people have everything but their heart
hurts you talk about that you tell about
like three branches you know like
have your herd animals right and
everyone suck in their heads right it's
just kind of like how and everything
works right your kind of born into the
world and it's like you got to put stuff
in your head right and it's just that's
just how it is right and we kind of lose
what we really want we kind of think of
the same thing but they're really not
right you know they're not what you've
been told and then manipulated to do
based on the most insidious form of
slavery which is fear fear and then
guilt which is an offshoot of fear but
it's a very closely tied one so you do
what you're supposed to do because
you're afraid of the boogey man the
world has told you about you're not
going to have health insurance because
guess what i just got health insurance I
poor kids we're fucking fine if you live
fearfully bad shits gonna happen to you
you're not going to come true what about
your pension plan are you gonna pay for
your kids college how are you fear fear
fear fear fear fear fear fear or honor
to those who have served you guilt well
my parents did this for me they did that
for me like dad wants me to so guilt
those are all manifestations of the ego
because there's no fear or guilt in the
heart the heart is love it's pure
pureness it's a sad thing when we've
what we've created a magnificent society
I suppose it's all relative but it's a
horrible thing when the individual units
of that society are poisoned by the
fears that keep them shackled to a
system as if they're slaves and it's
like if we could break out of that
fucking fear life will be beautiful even
if you just have a little bit you don't
need much you want to blend these things
together it's funny right like if we
thunderheart right we can totally tie
that into our physical being everyone's
hunched over right arm hardest hit me
right it's it might be coincidence but
at the same time it's still there right
we can see it I mean if you study the
ancient forms of meditation and exercise
which were blended meditation and
exercise work when your study martial
arts Qi Gong yoga tai chi its movements
it's meditation through movement because
the body is the fucking mind I said this
so many times and you literally have
four parts of your body that have
emotional content tied to it emotions
happen through the body that's why it's
called e-motion its motion it's
happening here and if you have pain
emotionally it shows up physically in
your body if you need concrete evidence
or if you have the slightest bit of
imagination to put two and two together
and get fucking for just look at the
brain it's literally literally looks
like a flower tied to its stem the
spinal cord that roots itself in the
soil of the body just look at the
nervous human nervous system the soil
through which the flowering of the mind
is created is in our body so if the body
is if you've got poor soil what kind of
fruit you're going to have and vice
versa so the body has to be well cared
for and that means stretching that means
exercising their music breathing deeply
all right talk about breathing into your
balls you understand that right it means
having a soft enough muscular system
that you literally massage your organs
way down into your pelvic floor each
breath that you take difficult to walk
around that way but you can practice
through the exercises IT
through yoga breathing through chi-gong
breathing this is where we have to go
back with regard to exercise not lifting
I love lifting but but we don't need any
more meatheads we need more people with
sensitive strong bodies that are able to
carry them through life in a creative
grounded fashion that what's really
missing