hey what's up guys Elliott Hulse here
just getting the ball rolling again
after two weeks of a lot of activity a
lot of stuff a lot of things taking my
time and energy all of which were
extremely pleasurable so the last time I
spoke to you guys I was in Amsterdam and
I was able to upload a video that Sunday
but the following weekend I was offering
a and facilitating a grounding camp in
Amsterdam was attended by over a hundred
brilliant Souls courageous Souls men and
women willing to get uncomfortable and
have a good time and we absolutely did
that and then the next day Sunday when I
would typically upload a video we were
on the road so I was flying Sunday and
didn't get a chance to speak with you
guys but as soon as I returned it was
nose to the grinder right away we had
the strength camp world summit where on
the first day we had over a hundred
awesome people at the gym at Trent camp
and we went through a clinic followed by
a business seminar followed by the grow
stronger experienced on the third day
and then the strength camp challenge on
the fourth day so you could imagine I've
been pretty busy and a little little
worn out also because I have sustained
blessed to receive another injury right
so many of you know about my ankle
injury I'm going to talk more about it
later it's it's good that I put it into
perspective right because one of the
first things that happens when you get
an injury is people go oh that's so
horrible oh I wish think I wish things
will be the same or will you go back to
where you were and that perspective of
sorrow or feeling bad for me in
particular don't ever feel bad for me
and wanting things to be back the way
they were prior to a tragedy this is the
way people look at circumstances in
their life is not resourceful in any way
shape or form but it's the reaction is
the way people typically think of the
events in their lives me on the other
hand I
a completely different approach and I
look at all circumstances as
opportunities and so I want to be able
to provide you guys with that type of
context for my ankle injury you know
I'll do that in a video coming up here
pretty soon but I have loaded a video
just a couple weeks ago called every
wound wound is a wound right every
injury is an opportunity to grow
stronger and I don't just say that good
to console myself or because it sounds
cool I say it because it's a living
philosophy for me and you know the more
challenges I have the you know the more
opportunities I have to grow stronger
it's a way of life right a lot of people
like to watch Elliott Hulse videos to
get inspired but you know when it comes
time to apply it I think it's far more
resourceful to watch me do it right I'm
right there with you guys making my way
through life so watch me put my words to
action and that's what this is all about
but anyway I upload this video here for
you guys
today in order to introduce you to some
of the work that I had done while I was
in Amsterdam I was fortunate enough to
be interviewed by several really awesome
people four of which you're going to get
to meet pretty shortly proceeded after
this message that I'm sharing with you
there will be a trailer for a video
that's on another YouTube channel
it belongs to four gentleman who
interviewed myself and Colleen while we
were in Amsterdam so this video is an
introduction to that trailer so that you
guys can go over there and watch that
and also just to let you know that I
have more content on the way I did other
interviews I recorded some of my
presentations and I want to share some
of my experiences and perspectives with
you as it relates to the powerful two
weeks that I just came out of it's
almost like one of my teachers put it
this way with regard to the rapid
evolution that many of us experienced
over the past several months as being in
the Starship Enterprise
you know when things you go into
hyperdrive and it goes real slow at
first and then claps and then shoots off
well that's how my life has felt for the
past two weeks it seems like things were
moving and then clapped into hyperdrive
and and so I'm trying to process it and
then at the same time draw perspective
and use it as a way to share and speak
with you guys so I look forward to that
and look forward to watching this
interview I'll see you guys next time
done
well do all
that's it just like we finished I'm well