what's up guys today we got a question
from our buddy Diego who says at one
point he was a couchsurfing lazy fat bum
who didn't want to do anything but watch
TV
then one day miraculously an idea struck
him thing and he was mobilized with
energy and aspiration to move towards a
particular goal that he set for himself
and it had been great for two years he
worked with passion and courage towards
achieving this particular goal but it
was some point the passion and courage
drained out of him and he could no
longer mobilize his vital resources to
do the work that was needed in order to
achieve his particular goal in fact he
says he started to even beget get
getting dumber like I'm getting as I
make more videos today he started
getting dumber
he couldn't even put two words together
he couldn't be able to wasn't able to do
the things that he needed to do to
achieve his goal all right and he
wonders how is it that I went from a
couch potato had great success and now
it seems like I'm coming full circle
it's frustrating what do I do about this
well I'll keep this lesson short one
thing that you need to know is that
nothing in a life is linear now that
goes against everything that education
has taught us and everything that is
logically linear but you can understand
that the undercurrent or what make light
makes life don't do what it does is non
linear news it's it's not prickly it's
goo it moves circularly life is circles
life goes like this it might be going
somewhere it might not be the whole
thing might just be doing this we got
hours and days and weeks and months and
years and centuries and epochs and it
just keeps doing this if you study many
different forms of wisdom tradition
including the Hindu tradition they
believe that we've been doing this shit
for forever this is just what we're
doing we're just wiggling around this
whole time but we have a tendency to
think that we're going somewhere we're
shooting somewhere and it's all going to
be one straight line it's bullshit this
tree I'm looking at right now
it would be nice to believe that what I
on the outside with regard to it doing
and becoming treat it's completely
linear but that tree is a byproduct of
the seasons because the tree grows in
particular ways in particular seasons is
guess what the seasons do their annual
they rotate so it's summertime right now
the trees doing something totally
different right now and even looks
different than in January when I was
looking at the same damn tree nonlinear
all of life works this way it's in
seasons the problem arises when we
become attached to one season not
realizing that you have to let go of it
in order to allow the next season to
come through if you're so attached to
summertime in all of its heat and
ferocity and as it starts cooling down
and moving towards winter which is
basically what you're moving into right
now you're moving into contraction but
you're holding on to expansion in the
summertime then you make yourself sick
is it's completely of mind fuck it's the
ego doing this thing ego gets attached
to things that it's built stories about
itself around and you built a really
good story about two years of being a
success and now that it's time to let
that shit go your huh and you're making
yourself even more tired and more sick
and more were demented that's why that's
why when you say you can't think it's
because you're not allowing yourself to
relax into the winter of being whoever
you're going to be in the winter and I
promise you one thing there's a
brilliance of the winter version of you
or the contracted version of you and
it's just as brilliant although very
different from the expanded version of
you
you see you have to learn to be in the
moment with it so if you're feeling lazy
it might mean you need to chill the fuck
out it might mean that you need to just
relax it might mean that you don't push
yourself especially energetically and
psychologically to be what you were in
the winter time in fact if we keep using
the same analogy of the seasons every
year is different than the last year
summer of 2000
seven is not the same seven seven 2009
and 2012 2015 will not be the same type
of summer it will always be different so
you're going to come back as a new
mobilise expanded version of yourself
and you're going to be new and different
but better I say because you allowed
yourself to rest and you're moving with
the flow of life life flows like doesn't
aim
none of this aims and shoots and gets
there it all does this and we're just
doing this thing we're not going
anywhere we're not doing anything we're
just being and that's what being does
you can't predict being you can't pin
down being you just be being and that's
it see I use language see languages so
it's such a shame it's beautiful that we
use language because it helps us
describe our psychology it helps us
describe the things that our inner
realities but the minute we reduce them
to words or symbols we lose so much
especially when we have a rudimentary
language like ours where where it's
almost like you can't have one without
the other right so I'm saying this
because I often use the term becoming
the strongest version of yourself well
that's a term that sounds very linear
you're becoming a stronger version
yourself really it's being a stronger
version yourself because in every moment
you have to be the strongest version of
yourself to be becoming the strongest
version of yourself don't get caught up
with where you're going and the way it
should look like based on what happened
last time or yesterday it's like I'm
reiterating myself from a video last
week be in the moment and find the
brilliance in the moment then winter
time contraction is a beautiful thing
for you this is a DejaVu I made this
video last week but I'm going to
reiterate it again here watch my videos
from winter literal wintertime literal
Wichita I pick a video from January
right where I'm talking slow
and I pause a lot
I'm a very contracted version of myself
and I got up every day and I made videos
anyway and I didn't judge them
I didn't say boy I'm not as expensive as
I was in the summer time last year I
can't compare myself to old versions of
myself because that's a useless
proposition it's a useless conversation
stop comparing versions of yourself with
past versions of yourself and be present
with the version of yourself that you
are right now and know too that you're
not always in control of the version
that's being produced you play your part
by being in the moment but also God or
the universe Allah science whatever you
worship is going to dictate what happens
next
also nature says it's going to be hot
you're going to be an expansive person
for the next two years like you did
previously now nature says you need to
contract and if it didn't work this way
we'd explode try this inhalation and
exhalation is the greatest example of
how the human being gets himself into
the flow of life that's why all
meditation focuses on breathing because
it is the essence of being in the river
of life breathing that's why I say
breathe into your balls folks get out of
it when you breathe into the wall into
your balls means you're getting out of
the way of your ability to breathe
breathe but now get attached to
inhalation because inhalation is good
inhalation is expansion inhalation is
nourishing there's a lot of good stuff
coming in with insulation so let's just
love inhalation
you'll explode it won't work you gotta
you gotta exhale you gotta let down you
gotta let go you gotta chill out
you gotta allow you see inhalation
expansion is a doing you were doing a
lot during those two years the ego loves
doing because doing gives you something
to do and doing is pleasing to yourself
and everybody else around you you just
need to do something get up and do
something do something with yourself the
world loves doing exhalation is allowing
exhalation is contentment order your
content so that's a nasty word in our
culture what are you just gonna all that
things happen yes because it is in
allowing it isn't contentment that you
gain all of the nourishment needed for
your next expansion it would be like if
you're if you're having sex with your
girlfriend and boy hey the stroking is
great I've expanded right my penis is
big and expanded man and I'm loving this
this is doing this is like during your
days of working good well at some point
what do you need to do boom explode
letdown orgasm is let down you see you
got to give yourself room to be
aggressive and tender tender aggression
term I often use my coin should
copyright that I don't give a shit if
you guys steal my stuff as long as the
spread and wisdom you gotta be tender
aggressive man so your aggressive time
is over be a little bit more tender
let your life be in ejaculation none but