kind of question for my 18 year old
friend who says that he has no drive to
do anything he says that last year he
was thinking about going to the military
but he kind of got started and then quit
he says there are lots of places that he
can go and get work and you know the
invitation is open to him but he just
doesn't go and do it and basically you
know this repetitive behavior of
starting things and stopping and then
wondering why is it that I don't have a
drive to get all this shit done so
without going into the implications of
the situation I want to give you one
very practical tip that has been very
supportive to me in getting shit done
especially when you don't feel like
getting shit done because I've been
there I'm there quite often or I just
I'm not even making these videos
sometimes I pull up to my gym and I'm
sitting my car and I'm like I'm just not
in the mood to make videos today and you
might even be able to tell some of my
videos my Energy's a little bit lower
than others and it's just those are the
days where I just fucking do it anyway
choose something now he this is very
important
choose something anything it doesn't
matter what you choose what you choose
is not nearly as important as what
you're going to do next don't even use
the word commit don't even think about
the word discipline just do the thing
every single day whether you feel like
it or not your only commitment is to the
activity not to the grand scheme not to
the big picture not to the implications
of what it is that you're doing it's to
do the thing so for example me I walk
every morning now the grand implication
is that if I wake up every single
morning and I go walking a number of
things are going to happen I'm
enlightening myself because I listen to
audiobooks I'm getting healthier because
I'm taking in lots of oxygen walking by
the water and I'm burning fat because
I'm exercising my body on an empty
stomach right so those are all the
higher implications oftentimes the
higher implications aren't as powerful
as your commitment to just fucking doing
it now I use the word commitment cuz I
can
of anything else but when I am laying in
bed and it's cold outside and I'm
snuggling next to my wife I don't think
about getting up I just fucking get up
and you just do it you make it a habit
you want to get to the point where you
don't have to exercise will to get up
and do something it becomes like
brushing your teeth now hopefully you
don't have to like exercise your will to
brush your teeth you just get up every
day and you brush your fucking teeth
because it has become a part of your
routine habits become your life really
ends up being a composite of all the
habits that you've developed over the
course of time so whatever it is and you
know what it really again it doesn't
matter what it is it could be as simple
as I'm going to shower every day like it
could be as simple as that if you're so
if you're so carried by the wind and
ungrounded that you don't even bathe
yourself every day because trust me I
understand I get it there are certain
things that are just fundamental to
human beings existence on earth that we
some of us just can't motivate ourselves
to do start small start with I'm going
to bait everyday and what that's going
to do is not only make you smell better
but it's also going to help develop the
self confidence that's needed to take
that habit-forming behavior that
characteristic that's associated with
performing habits and apply it to bigger
things so let's say now I'm going to
work out every day now you don't think
about it anymore but you know you can
you know that you have the capacity to
form a habit form a habit so you don't
think about it you just say okay I'm
gonna exercise every day and then you
just exercise every single day there
gonna be days you don't want exercise
but you do it anyway don't mean you have
to have a good workout not all my videos
are good I know that but when it's time
to my videos I just make videos I just
make videos I might hate my videos
sometimes I watch my videos and I hate
the video i watch the video I'm like oh
god that was terrible that was bad now
as long as it was sincere I upload it a
lot of times it's like
you know the the main criteria for my
uploading a video is was I sincere
wasn't what it's not was it a good
performance or you know whatever the
case may be what other criteria that you
know the populace might gauge my success
upon it's just a matter of doing the
thing so you might go to the gym you
might not have a great workout but it
doesn't matter
you did it anyway and that's the point I
want to share with you pick something my
friend if you're having a hard time
getting a job or joining the military or
doing something grand something that has
grand implications for your life back up
for a moment don't do that just yet
begin with I'm going to drink eight
glasses of water everyday something
stupid simple and make sure you do it
I guarantee over the course of several
weeks you're gonna do that thing is
going to happen without you thinking
about it and then you're going to be
confident in yourself and your ability
to create habits and then you take that
new tool and you apply it to something
just a little bit bigger move it from
drinking water to I'm going to drink and
eat vegetables with every night with my
dinner we have a salad every night with
my dinner and no matter what you have a
salad with your dinner every single
night right so it starts to grow in in
implication then you take it to I'm
going to look for a job every single day
no matter what I'm going to do you see
and that's it my friend habits are the
building blocks of our lives not the
goals or the grand schemes or the vision
or the big idea it's what you fucking do
every single day that matters more than
anything develop good habits that will
carry you through to having a very
successful life done