my puddin's about the autonomic nervous
system and it's one of your standing in
front of the Union and that is I know
that you can manipulate physiologically
you know through like intermittent
fasting you know what's going on there
how about momentum you find one of the
states as more are conducive towards
maybe creative learning intellectual
learning spiritual
letting go letting go is passive you get
but that's where that's where you gain a
lot of wisdom let go for example this is
just what been my experiencing and as
you're watching me do what I do it's a
better the station of my becoming more
creative when you watch my old videos
I'm very aggressive very male very
in-your-face
area ungrounded right when you watch me
now you can tell that my aggression is
society and I'm becoming more feminine
or soft and more yielding every time my
eyes to this the eye that you would be
attacking me or with our eyes you know
if you want very aggressive with someone
you're here with them look you're very
concentrated with your view way neither
this is all mental when you're looking
away very passive correct might retreat
to the passive part of my mind when I
start thinking and I really have to get
I have to gather useful information that
not on the tip of my tongue stuff that
is rooted in my body that's found in
there that I've absorbed through
experience and I know is available to me
but it's not here it's not aggressive do
you see a lot of times you want to know
like how is it that I can
speak the way that I speak and I always
seem to find right worth because I go to
my feminine barman when I go to a very
unaggressive a very yielding place that
what is there like a fucking psycho
when I say this now but it's almost like
instead I'm dad I'm gonna say it anyway
you guys know a thing it's almost like
divine revelation when I come up with
the things that I say and it doesn't
mean that God is doesn't mean oh Jesus
it means that I'm going to a place of
divinity I'm going to a place of
softness that it's not so crap that's so
progressive in order to a lot of time
talking and it's not Eliot talking watch
my videos in life today what'd I just
say
and I always ask how can I repeat that
performance how I did that because I
literally go somewhere else
to the darkness darkness is also
synonymous with yielding that's the
black what about like on a daily basis
we'll say you're faster by your flight
is that better for a state like reading
you know trying to study both if he
created like all something or after
you've told me wow you're slowing down
is that better kind of try to digest
information it's a balance of tennis
at all times there too one way we are
technic see it and men in our culture in
general they were tendency to be more
angry with us more aggressive and we
lose a lot because there's there's no
there's no passive and then you can also
this funny if you go back to the east
look at the two pictures look at Jesus
with your Buddha Jesus is doing shit I
mean he's got a big fucking mouth these
flip the tables and they're killing his
ass
what is Buddha doing it's it's very
symbolic of the two types of different
cultures and if you take it to extreme
on either way what ends up happening
kill yourself you send the fucking tree
gets back see so it's a matter of where
are you in that dance between aggression
and tenderness there may be times where
you don't forget basically the winner is
the one who doesn't get knocked over but
the key is to heal so you don't get
knocked over so I have to go
okay you see how you deal in there it
was in your yielding that you were able
to defend my strength it was in your
being feminine absorbing that you were
able to say
Bridget Bridget smile haikus
oh good you see some becomes a very
that's the balance the balance is
aggression bartender no be too
aggressive because live too aggressive
I'll fall over and even in my yielding
if I stiffen too much in my yielding too
aggressive you about Hill so it's a
ballad assume you have to do there right
we had to be progressing I'm going but
I'm also soft I'm also a gilding it
would be nice that I can say yes no
black white right but you know what it
is black-white yes-no that's why that's
the magic that damn simple is that the
whole thing that's why my answer sucks I
know you got it with regard to the
autonomic nervous system parasympathetic
sympathetic anabolic catabolic what
we've been anabolic what are we also
path kind of all its let it go and allow
them to dance happen and be sensitive
enough to know the right activity for
the right time that sucks because
there's no manual on that there's no
right answer on that does that help yeah
Chris Chris and I work together all day
long all day long
we have to talk about is it you might
want to crush it what happens where you
season's happen it's like it's like
winter spring fall and stuff it's like
will you be mad like it's kiss it's a
good one it's summertime but you wear
your new boots right these are brand new
it is so cool it was summertime doesn't
you guys just do it
summer times they call the students baby
soon but it's winter time doesn't matter
it's funny some take that shit off
brought some coke it's just being
sensitive to the environment
intrinsically and extrinsically and
navigating
it requires sensitivity and the key bait
that nobody wants responsibility the
term responsibility in England
response-ability
your ability to respond appropriately