so one of the most damaging forms of
neurotic holding patterns that you've
heard me talk about is that which
restricts our respiratory pathways by
causing muscular tension in the extra
respiratory musculature so the muscles
of the mouth neck chest belly a deep
abdominal wall or pelvic floor so I've
shown you different forms of
bioenergetic exercises and I've often
made reference to this idea of deep
resonating sounds and the reason why he
presents ounds is so powerful is because
it literally massages the extra
respiratory muscles and opens them up
relaxes them in the same way that
shaking and vibrating relaxes your the
entire muscular system deep resonating
sounds open up your respiratory pathway
and it is an ancient form of meditation
because it causes you not only to
breathe deep but also relaxes the mind
into the vibration of the sounds so I'm
going to share three different chance
with you that mankind has been using for
very long I'll start with one of the
oldest which is the own which is uh
comes from the east I think it's a Hindu
idea and the sound is as simple as going
like this Oh
[Music]
Oh
you
so you might notice me opening my mouth
which relaxes the muscles in my mouth in
my throat also opens up the respiratory
tube the pathways down into my belly and
I even feel my belly vibrating if you're
more Christian inclined and it makes you
uncomfortable to say ohm because maybe
you know there's superstition about
different sounds what whatever the case
may be
you may be familiar with this chant ah
[Music]
hallelujah
and finally the third of the three that
I'd like to share with you and invite
you to practice in order to open up your
respiratory pathway with these deep
resonating sounds is more of a Muslim or
Islamic chant that sounds like this ha
lalalalala
ah ha lalalalala
[Music]
lalalalala Lala
so as you can see these exercises which
are blended with spiritual ideas
religious ideas are resourceful not only
mentally emotionally spiritually but
very resourceful physically and I invite
you to use it to help become a stronger
version of yourself by making your body
stronger by deepening your breath which
enhances your physiology and also calms
the mind