okay so today I'd like to answer a
question from one of our friends but
before I begin I mentioned a few weeks
ago on my strength camp channel that I
might start answering these types of
questions over there but after coming
back after several weeks and reading
some of the messages in the inbox in the
youtube inbox on this channel which is
where you should send me your questions
I realized that a lot of them are just
inappropriate for for the crowd over at
strength camp at my shot cap channel so
I'm back send me your questions that I'm
here to support you with any ideas to
help you grow stronger and grow through
the challenges in your life okay nothing
that I say is right or true or you
should take as gospel they're just
different ideas that may be resourceful
to you and that's why I do this okay we
got a question from our 15 year old
friend Fred Fred's dealing with a very
difficult situation at home where his
mother is becoming suicidal
she's she's had multiple boyfriends I'm
not exactly sure where Fred's dad is but
she can't seem to maintain a stable
relationship and she has mentioned and
has attempted to take her own life on
many different occasions fred is
convinced that she won't do it but the
fact that she's proceeding in this
fashion by by acting as if she would
brings great concern to his young heart
Fred I told you understand dude here's a
perspective that's been resourceful for
me when dealing with the pain and
anguish that I watch people that I love
very close people that I love go through
pain that I wish I could take away you
got to understand Fred that the best
thing the absolute best thing that you
could do for your mom is to become the
strongest version of yourself now that
doesn't mean that you ignore your mom
completely but energetically you've got
to back off just a moment because your
mom is moving in a different direction
than where you want to go in life and
the fact that she created you right
you're her offspring means that you can
carry her honor in a different direction
a lot of times if we energetically
involve emotionally involves
one who is moving down an anchor
especially someone who's who's stronger
than you you're it's your mom she's a
bit stronger than you energetically
simply because you came from her and
you're still very immature and I don't
use that term to mean that you're not a
bright kid but you're young and you're
still very vulnerable right she can take
you down a path that that will have you
spiraling into dysfunction for the rest
of your life you don't want that to
happen not just for you you don't want
that to happen because of her because
she is going to die someday as we all do
but you can carry on her vision night
vision but you can carry on her her
honor it's a better word for it you
could carry on the honor of your mother
through developing the strengths in you
so that you can inspire others in her
name you got to understand that the best
thing that we can do for anyone in our
lives
is to become a stronger version of
ourselves and even through that you
might inspire her to be a stronger
version of herself I just watched a
video on on Maddie fou sorrows YouTube
channel and you can go on my Facebook
and you'll see it and it's a video where
he trains his dad who was fat and
diabetic this is an incredible example
you should probably go look at this but
his dad had a really bad life he will
Aust his wife he lost his parents at a
very young age and he was raising his
sons by himself he became obese he
became diabetic he became very sick on
the brink of heart attack and Maddie
this is a perfect example I'm surprised
I didn't think of it earlier but I just
saw the video a few hours ago go watch
this maddie decided he was gonna become
a bodybuilder even though maddie was a
fat kid also because he you know he's
dealing with his dad situation he
decided I'm gonna be a bodybuilder and
I'm gonna build myself up out of this
I'm gonna build up my body I'm gonna
build up my health and I'm gonna become
a stronger version of himself and you
know what he did he went back and
trained his dad you should see the
transformation video he trained his dad
to go from about 300 pounds to like a
hundred
he's something but ripped he's a ripped
old man now because Maddy decided to
become a strongest version of himself
first and he was energetically strong
enough to bring his dad up with him that
might happen that might happen for you
but you got to focus on yourself first
but if it doesn't happen like I said
before Maddy's example understand that
you can take that strength that you
cultivate and use it to move forward in
your mom's name and you can share
stories that were resourceful and
peaceful and helpful and feel good to
you with your children and your
children's children but that the anchor
of dysfunction that she's carrying with
her shouldn't either weigh you down nor
shall you drag it forward into your
future or future generations it stops
with you grow stronger inspire her but
more importantly inspire forward Eliot's
in what
you