both fairytales and they're both true
and they're both saying the same fucking
thing with different language right I
mean Joseph Campbell
I mean it's they're just mix even our
science it's just a myth it's a way to
use abstract things to describe that
which cannot be described right be it
stories about animals you know animals
and floods or quarks and bosons it's
just they're telling the same story but
ones using well here it is
and these people are saying y'all here
it is - we're I think religion screws up
and loses their credibility in the way
we think our consciousness is in the
world today is that they want to prove
that they're the stories are literal
that's like Wow not only that retarded
but you're losing the power because the
power is in the myth do you see like the
analogy what it's the greater picture
the greater thing that it's pointing to
not the literal translation of this
thing but you're not you're not a
believer if you say that you know yeah
that Jesus didn't walk on water
or rise from the dead well it's like
really it doesn't matter if you did or
didn't the message of the story is
resurrection resurrection being born
again being completely deconstructed
even in the body and coming back again
it's a nature it's a law of nature to
continuously evolve to die and be born
again I do it all the time
you know I spoke about it when I tore my
bicep I killed that character I was born
again that's a powerful message as a
powerful principle of life is death and
rebirth death and rebirth death and
rebirth definitely what does Jesus do
dies and is reborn now it's not the
story that's powerful did okay all right
fine his body came up and they used a
zombie right okay he came back to life
but that's not the point of the story
the point of the story is the principle
of resurrection of this cyclical nature
of
universe duel we say dualism because
duelist in order to understand unity you
have to understand to understand one you
have to understand too so we are in
order to understand what yeah we have
not sent two so we use duel duality as a
metaphor as a as a myth as a as a
leaning on to understand unity so it's
all one thing and if everybody's telling
themselves stories to try to understand
the one thing but yet they get mad at
each other for telling different stories
they're missing the whole point of the
thing which is unity so let's stop this
shit and unify I mean unified theory of
the world I mean the scientists say it
and the religion saying there's only one
God I have one god I'm undivided you
know I am everything I'm the world I
created the world and I created me you
know and saying that's myth of religion
it's no different than the unified
theory of the universe in quantum
physics yeah some people say quantum
physics is it's a joke you know why
quantum physics is joke cuz you can't
figure it out with these symbols you
can't you have to tell stories about it
that's why that's why the stories are
actually more powerful because they
don't tell you yes this is true the
stories lead you on a journey to
experience the truth instead of writing
it down on a board and saying equals MC
square that's about as far as it goes
why is that so popular as far as it goes
you don't need to know that
language right that guy that the
constructionist yeah Orson language he
thinks that light weights the thing that
divides things up you say light and dark
already said is negative or positive one
word moving to another word and then
that most words I like so Dex worth
update right there just saying sumos
where is this symbol there's only one
symbol for love but love is such a
dynamic thing you think it's so much for
I and love that different people have a
different interval love is when you
throw the word love up there you you you
I'm using my friendship in my imagery
right how's history and then there and
you should imagine with each other match
it and then you can never match one my
love is right a lobbyist such a dynamic
emotion every single time we feel it's
different there's only one word and that
word is dead right yeah so then it's a
lot of philosophy like because then just
GZ things like philosophy it's all
motion almost as long as you're speaking
it it's all bullshit right because yeah
it's the moment you speak it you're not
going anywhere you can't solve the
problems possibly because yeah it as
long as you do it in language she can
use lobby he's a very good mathematician
and uses logic to show me exactly what
doesn't work with language and you're
all those treaties like just a couple of
words and he breaks them up yeah that's
it and then he's one of my favorite
quote is on what cannot be speak of must
be thou thou who says I'm trying to find
it exactly what he says that which can
be described but he's not the dad the
dad for the down that can be described
as not the truth and because that's it
what cannot be speak up must be pass
over in silence
he's just just just just leave it yeah
and use other things
during the art or music they're all
inferring that infirmities and language
this Kannada wasn't confusing which is
the worst I want it's the worst one ya
cuz ya make arts arts and stuff like or
even movements and things like no
emotions and when you try to lock it
down with words you can never get it's
like a matrix it's a good veil that
right it's a construct so play the same
thing you need that constructs so a
second it's like a double sided ZZZ word
it's like a window that you can look out
through in a cave but think that's the
only window there is so you can all you
can see the cave yeah I'm the cave we
decided that the broke the window on the
KB's is purple was broken which everyone
is a slightly different window and every
species that's the only thing you can go
with this standard a window and then you
try to describe it yeah with that with
itself the mission I think it's true
yeah that's we know I'm seeing that yeah
and then different people then it's like
you better tell me you have nothing to
use by itself so you're using that
window to try to break break that window
the part in which you know you don't
want to think it's powerful about what
we're doing and what we do when we speak
about what we see through our window is
that we give people permission to accept
what they already see through their
window yeah there's a lot of things that
people are seeing but because I got a
big mouth and you have a big mouth and I
just talk about it they look out their
window saying I knew that was always
there I knew that was always there
thank and all I'm doing is basically
saying hey you're allowed to see that
shit and then when they see it they're
so grateful to me because it's like wow
open my eyes through the main thing I'm
opening through his eyes so it's not
like I can give you anything I can't
show you anything that you don't already
know I'm just giving you permission I'm
clearing clearing it out for you a
little bit you see that yeah oh yeah I
start talking about it describing it and
they're like yeah yeah yeah
there it is it's like it's always been
there I didn't give it to you I just
told you you're allowed to look at it
your life to be excited about that did
you follow me that what that and that's
what you know they would call you don't
get language it's the fuck
hook up the whole experience that's what
they call it guru a guru is someone who
brings light with them that's what they
do they're a shedder of light if you if
you break down the word goob Andrew and
I don't know the roots but someone told
me this that it means like bearer of
light just someone and what does might
do just does light because the lights
are on the light create this delight
create that the light create you guys
know like just illuminated brought it to
your consciousness nobody could give you
anything that you don't have already so
here's how we evolved consciously and
this is how this game keeps going that's
why I keep saying become the strongest
version yourself and inspire others if
we bring it if I bring enough light to
other people like them and they can
spread that light to other people
it's an it's a conscious virus shedding
shedding light upon the world it's all
by the biblical stuff to shed light
bring light to the world
candle light is a metaphor for
consciousness open it open it
in yourself and open it in other people
and that's why you know like they say
the forces of good and evil I don't know
if I truly believe that that's it needs
to be described that way as forces of
good and evil but there are two opposing
forces that play this game and you some
of it you might call darkness and some
of you might call lightness but even
that is an unfair distinction because it
you know we suggest that light is good
and dark is bad but it's not we still
want to judge those so I happen to be a
bearer of light and this is the thing
that I'm doing the things that I'm
talking about is a is one side of a
devil
coin and the other side is whatever the
other side is and it's justice it's just
fine
call it evil if you like because they
I'm sure they would call me evil but you
don't have to fight it
we're not fighting we're dancing and you
know what the dance sometimes it's it's
a bloody dance and it has to be felt
everywhere you could call that evil
right bloodshed children all over the
world
you could be against it you could be
angry about it it could happen to you my
brother was there and he died my uncle
was there my father
it took my leg this thing is what we
would call ugly thing war but a true
understanding of God the universe the
DAO realizes that it's it's just the
opposing force and it has to happen and
I can judge rightly or wrongly good or
bad but it doesn't matter it's going to
happen and we have to experience it so
you know of course the soul is now crazy
and you know I'm projecting World War 3
between the you know the West and the
East but really that's it's what we're
doing it's the West Indies yin yang you
you see and the big thing is coming
together and it's supposed to come
together they're supposed to oppose each
other whatever happens is just what's
happening on earth it's just and as eggs
are broken as the construction happens
what did I tell you earlier about Jesus
death rebirth death rebirth death Reaper
so who experience a lot of death and
destruction it's only necessary for a
rebirth you have to have this World War
III has to happen we can judge it one
way or another but rebirth doesn't
happen until is death first
so where does that leave us what do we
do as individuals without judgment
do your work whatever it is that feels
you feel coming up in you especially if
it's if you can feel it in your body the
head the head is this should be your
slave your body should be your master if
you feel it in your body that I need to
do this then it's your responsibility to
do it and the biggest sin is not
trusting that which is happening in you
you're not trusting God because guess
what
God is doing this thing it's doing it
through you and you can either resist or
you can go with it
so we could place judgment on what that
action might look like they're gonna be
people who are gonna judge it may not
look it like it but you still have to do
it and it doesn't matter we've got to we
have to sever ourselves from attachment
people love me and they wouldn't want to
see me do this it could be anything it
could be all types of things you know
it's a you know I can stand here and it
sound like you know kill people or
something it's not really what it is
sometimes it's the most subtle action in
the direction of your dreams that's
holding you back you know for example if
you are you know you're very artistic
you play the piano if your dad wants you
to be a lawyer I'm a lawyer your
grandfather's lawyer you know stop this
piano shit you know this is you've got
to carry our name that I hear a
tradition a revolutionary action like
transformative action for that man he's
basically saying no dad playing piano so
what it wasn't Elliot says do whatever
your heart says I'm gonna go shooting
fuck people go right no no no it's never
that extreme that's that's you making up
stories about why you're too scared to
take action where you really
you wanna take action and it usually is
something of the heart so if we all jump
up yeah it's a cop-out if we all simply
follow our hearts we contribute to a
less neurotic world and it's it's the
neurotic world that's keeping you from
not following your heart and the only
way and this is gonna sound dualistic we
win is if we just follow our hearts
easier said than done but it should be
an effort it should be an effort you
should put your effort into it it's a
worthwhile effort because otherwise you
stay in the you stay as a roadblock to
evolution God it's happening and you can
resist or you can go