it's got a question for my buddy Edgar
who has a girlfriend they're both 25
years old here's a girlfriend who lives
at home with her mom and dad he lives at
home with his mom and dad and they have
a baby together they're turning one and
the baby lives with his girlfriend in
their house and he's eager to move out
of his parents house damn right and your
dad and you're 25 fucking years old it's
eager to move out of his parents house
and he wants to remove his girlfriend
from her mom's house with his child the
baby and move in together and he's
willing to do whatever it takes to make
that work the problem is that the girl's
parents don't trust him justifiably so I
mean you got their daughter pregnant and
for a year she's been living with them
and you still live with your mom and dad
and now you want to remove her from the
roots from she came and you impregnated
her impregnated her during this time so
she's got a baby I mean you can only you
have to put yourself in the shoes of the
parents here you know you got their
daughter pregnant and you and for a year
you weren't man enough to take care of
your situation I mean to get her
pregnant and then the parents now are
wanting for you to marry her before you
move out then take her with you and just
and start your life and do whatever it
is that you think you need to do in
order to fulfill your obligation as a
dad or just get the hell out of your
parents house I really know what your
true intention is but here's a year the
prior years a problem your concern is
how do I get them how do we convince
them to allow her to move out of their
house with my child and in with me right
no words or even actions for that matter
because I know you said you're going to
get two jobs to be able to take care of
them are going to fulfill the desire
that they have which is to rest in the
assurance that you are a purposeful man
meaning that you have a clear vision of
the life that you want to build for
yourself and that you are purposefully
taking a sh
on a daily basis in order to fulfill
that and have her be a part of it this
is what every parent of every daughter
wants for their son-in-law and what
every woman wants for herself she wants
a Purpose Driven man with a vision for
what their family and life will look
like you live at home with your parents
and get women pregnant who you're not
married to or at least for a full year
have no intention of being with i have
only displayed an inability to get clear
on who you are what you want and take
purposeful action towards it so they
don't trust you what you're going to
have to do is number one get in touch
with this is going to take a lot of
self-exploration it's going to take a
lot of time effort energy you're really
going to have to transform become a
different version of yourself a stronger
version of yourself what it's all going
to require is that you search the depths
of your heart and develop a vision for
what your life will look like with this
young lady and then enroll them in this
vision and they're going to have to see
you taking purposeful decisive selfless
action towards making that happen right
because your actions of getting to job
it's almost like you're scrambling now
right the way they see your behavior and
the reason why they're asking for the
type of commitment they're asking for is
because you seem like a scrambler no you
know you should happen look busted nuts
get girls pregnant now you're gonna go
good job so you can patch it all up but
like a year later you know you haven't
earned their trust and it's gonna take a
lot and I don't blame them for wanting
to like pin you down lock you up ball
and chain your ass so that they know at
least legally you're bound to take care
of their daughter and their grandchild
you gotta man up for yourself you've
gotta man up for your woman and you've
gotta man up for your child and then
they might respect you as a man
do you understand so that's it my friend
I don't blame them I wouldn't let my
daughter move out with you you know you
got a pregnant to begin with I'd be very
upset about that okay put yourself in
their shoes and then a full year goes by
and also now you want to scramble and
get two jobs fuck that you got to become
a man you got to show them that you're a
man otherwise move on buddy peace