hey whats up guys yesterday I introduce
you to the park where I was a city lunch
and meditate visualize and set up my
goals and plans for for the day week
year and life and Lahti guys found that
fascinating today to see behind me
actually that one right there that's the
very first house I purchased one in four
you could call it a house but release it
it's a freaking condo that I bought when
I moved down to Florida I have to talk
about being 90 thousand dollars in debt
and that's only partially true a part of
the part of what I was wrestling through
when I first moved down to Florida was
was trying to get out of a upside-down
mortgage those you guys want to stay on
that means basically I brought my house
you know this is the level of ignorance
that I that I had at a time and I
started my business at the height of the
economic crisis 2008 I bought that I
bought this townhouse that I was showing
you guys there for a second for about a
hundred and fifty thousand dollars right
that's like when the bubble was was big
right and you know I'm 23 24 25 years
old I don't know any better all i know
is i'm moving down to Florida the houses
are cheaper than they are in Long Island
four hundred fifty dollars 150 thousand
dollars you can't even get a decent
closet in New York so I thought I was
getting a deal well the fact is that i
sold it there it is right down there
I had to I had a short sell it those you
guys are familiar with was dealing with
banks I had a short sell it for less
than forty thousand dollars all right
I'm walking through the backyard right
now nobody kicks me out what up figure
today I'll show you guys that but you
went a little bit in a little bit on my
story and show you the backyard that I
used to train in train my daughter in I
used to film some videos in its really
the place where I plotted and schemed my
way to strength camp I'm hanging out in
this backyard building my equipment all
right filling up sandbags and dragging
tires when I was I was training for
strong man and when I was training my
clients sometimes we come back here you
can see this big long field I would drag
tires up and down that field I do i do
sprints up and down this field with my
children it was actually uh getting
realistic about it because we have a
pool now but I have a big yard where I
could drag drag sled and it's two
sprints but anyway we're just we're just
moving along back here see I don't want
to intrude on anybody but there's
there's my backyard that was my backyard
right there and uh and upstairs in that
room right there Colleen gave birth to
two of our four children she's on a home
birth to three of our four children and
two of them were born right up there or
is it right up there
I spent a lots of days in this room
right here typing away plotting away
thinking scheming meditating and all the
things that I had to do to get where i'm
at right now so I've got some nostalgic
feeling good feelings about this place
behind me here you can see there's a
there's a there's a lake or a river that
runs through more like a swamp sometimes
we see alligators out here I don't think
we're gonna see anybody any right now
but that alligator song that's to pick
up your dog shit time there's an
alligator sign around here somewhere but
I even the park yesterday that I was in
that's a funny thing about Florida is
that out we got alligators and all kinds
of strange birds you'll hear them in the
background but it's beautiful so anyway
uh getting outside today to make this
video and getting outside yesterday make
the video that I spoke to you guys about
reminding me of a current in balance
that I'm harboring which is I don't get
enough sunshine you know since I moved
to my new office and and since we we
move into a different house I don't get
outside as much as I used to eat I used
to hang out out here all the time he's
hanging out at that park that spoke to
you guys but all the times go to the
beach all the time to the house was so
small we had we had myself and Colleen
and three daughters living in that it
was a tiny tiny place um we didn't have
Benjamin so we move to another house and
uh
that really messed up my credit I still
rent I still write today because our
credit was so destroyed because of
dealing with the banks and that
upside-down mortgage in the ninety
thousand dollars in debt so you know
talk about come up but I'm still on my
way up I don't think we haven't stopped
coming up only time we we stopped going
up just when we start climbing down
right that's the natural rhythm of
things so up and down baby so getting
outside and getting some sunshine also
remind me of the fact that sunshine
carries a tremendous amount of vital
resource energy the Sun the Sun is what
gives us the life we live right without
the zombie we wouldn't exist all this
greenery I'm wearing green today all
this greenery is a byproduct of the Sun
making its love its daily dose of love
giving its daily dose of love to the
earth and the earth provides its fruit
and we are a fruit of the earth we grow
just like these plants grow without
sunshine we don't grow nearly as healthy
as these plants would you know like
these plants they wouldn't grow if
they've been getting sunshine sunshine
brings us the plan to eat animals we eat
life comes from the Sun so when I was
younger you know you guys understand
that uh my parents aren't American my
parents are from Belize when I was
younger my parents would use a lot of
the traditional medicines and
traditional law bush medicines my mother
would call Bush medicines and and
healing techniques and and and rituals
even of the Belizean people you know
heavily heavily steeped in a Native
American culture African culture and
European culture were quite mixed and
one of the things that my parents
brought home from Belize for us was the
supplementation of fish oil interesting
thing I remember being 34 years old
climbing up on the counter and popping
fish oil pills I thought nothing of it I
in fact I just enjoyed it because I was
a kid they were chewy and I don't know I
kind of like taste it I oil in my mouth
but um I never questioned it never asked
my parents why why was I taking these
taking the cod liver oil that's what's
cod liver why am I taking the cod liver
oil and until I was much older until I
actually you know I took it I took it
throughout you know elementary school
when I was young especially during those
times when the brain is growing you know
when you're a little kid your brain is
growing your nervous system growing and
that's when I took took it for the most
part when I got a little bit older and
uh I started to inquire about fitness
and a nutrition I asked my parents ask
my mother said why don't we take these
fish oils why do we take this uh this
oil supplement everything why did you
give it to us when we were children
and she explained to me that well number
one it was tradition in Belize to give
your children cod liver oil every day
and sanity once a year now you might be
wondering what's entity is but any of
you guys who've taken like laxative
tease this is a tea that makes you go to
the bathroom so those were the two
things that my parents carried with us
carry with them from Belize to to
America the Senate seat we never took my
ma didn't like it so she can give it to
us with the fish oil was something that
we always took and later on when I
started doing some research I discovered
that fish oil is very important for
brain and nervous system development and
not only that when I looked deeper and
started studying the work of Weston a
price he showed how in traditional
societies throughout the world foods
that were high in vitamin A and vitamin
D we're talking about the Sun or highly
praised these were these were things and
highly sought after in fact there were
certain traditional cultures who would
send they would go out an expedition to
the sea when a woman was pregnant or she
was nursing or had small children in
order to get magical seafood just
imagine right these magical seafoods
were high in vitamin C vitamin A water
dr. Weston a price and his fascinating
book titled nutrition and physical
degeneration also talks about
x factor that's found only in these fat
soluble vitamins and and that our
ancestors were wise enough to make sure
that the women the nursing women the
children you know basically those were
growing you know woman's growing a baby
inside are the brain and the nervous
system the baby's growing and children
should be taking fish oil cod liver oil
supplements my kids do i do on a daily
basis in fact i use living fuel
essential omegas right now when i was a
kid my parents is to give us a weird
little one that was uh had a picture of
a boat on it out remember the name of it
and then as I got older I used Carlson's
cod liver oil and now I used living fuel
living essentials you can click a link
down below to learn more about it I use
that now for a number of reasons from
what I understand the fish that's being
used and some of the fish oil
supplements today can grow toxic because
our water our water waves are very toxic
and also casey krejci the creator of
living essentials puts a ton of other
things in there that's uh that supports
our health our vitality our brain our
blood and our skin so you can of course
you can check all that out if you'd like
to and and that's it man you know today
I figured I have to take a swing down
south south st. Petersburg is where I am
right now I hadn't had to meet someone
earlier and I drop off my kids at school
down here don't want to make this video
to just bond with you guys a little bit
more shares on my experience on my
insights support you
come in a stronger version of yourself
that's our mission folks to continue to
grow stronger and empower one another no
better way to live a life done