trying to find the answer to one of our
life's dilemmas you know big decision
that you have to make is a lot like
trying to find an object in a dark room
right so obviously there's some things
there there's an answer there but you're
steeped in darkness and you're in this
room and you can't find a thing well
there are generally two ways that you
can go about that one would be to pull
out a flashlight right you've got this
flashlight in the flashlight has a a
certain circumference of illumination
that it provides and you go around you
search you're searching all over the
place you're trying to find the thing
and with effort because there's a
concentrated light eventually you might
find some clues and then back up there
it is you got the thing right with that
cut that little concentrated light a
little circumference of illumination
you're able to pinpoint the answer you
find it finally a lot of effort is
exerted with that a lot of concentration
a lot of what we've been conditioned the
type of continent consciousness we've
been conditioned to use through
education through school that focus we
can use to find the right answer but
there's another form of intelligence or
consciousness that we can use that with
that that's accessible to us which is
very much like flipping on a light
switch now in that same room if you flip
on the light switch you don't have a
concentrated effort you don't have a
concentrated illumination that you're
actively pursuing that answer with
because when you flip on the light
there's a passive illumination that
allows you to simply go well there it is
and walk right over to it it's a lot
less effort per se there's a lot less
concentration there's a lot less trying
to piece together the puzzle and and
then search for the answer it's more of
a allowing illumination and easily
finding the object right big difference
between putting on a flashlight and
flipping on a switch you can understand
this
so the question then arises Elia what
the fuck are you talking about right
because of course I use analogies and
metaphors and weird language try to
describe these big ideas the majority of
the time we're trying to find the
answers to our dilemmas our big
questions are what to do in life with a
fucking flashlight in a dark room and
you know this is true because now this
is based on another assumption
Eliot House's assumption or my belief
which I mean science it's irrefutable
but you know we've been told a lot of
stories against it the body is the mind
and you know what's happening
psychologically simply by looking at or
manipulating the muscular system a
person who's deep in thought looks like
they're concentrating you do a lot of
this and the eyes do a lot of this if
you like pay attention to someone who's
searching for an answer
what their fucking eyes are doing is
searching they're looking around they're
searching someone who's confused they're
doing a lot of blink blinking and
there's a lot of concentration right
here the eyes and the forehead this is
where the ego resides all becomes very
crunched up you know you're thinking
that somebody who's thinking what do
they do hmm thinking about it and that's
where you typically revert because
that's what you've been designed you've
been taught you've been conditioned to
revert to this in order to find your
answer that's like using the flashlight
concentrated and trying to find the
answer very difficult very difficult and
and your chances of making a mistake are
that much greater when you revert to
that flashlight because there are all
types of there are all types of
manipulative tactics that the world has
used to grab your hand and kind of focus
it in certain areas right you can't you
can very easily fool someone or control
someone with just a fucking flashlight
right you just grab their hand and you
like you can you can move around or you
can kind of whistle in particular
directions and fool them wait what what
right these are all the tricks and
symbols of the world getting us to do
this and we're all fucking confused
because I hear a whistle over here whoo
and then there's like Oh somebody's
saying something over here and then you
I read a book that said look over here
and then so you're really concentrating
with your video you're
Radek you're all fuckin ungrounded you
flip on a light switch nobody can
fucking fool you right flip on a switch
it's like ah you're not gonna fool me
bitches right here
a person who flipped on the light switch
a person who is steeped in illumination
a person who's trying to proceed or
letting go because there's a lot less
trying with this particular strategy
that I'm going to share with you a
person who lets go into the illumination
that's already within them a person who
cannot be fooled so easily a person who
the light switches on and can very
easily navigate without being tricked
looks not like this looks like this
and his energy isn't centered around his
face his head his eyebrows his forehead
his concentration or his energy drops
down into his body he's relaxed he's
breathing his belly his chest his pelvic
floor are all soft just like the big
soft light that's turned on when you're
trying to find something in a room it's
a lot more passive that's a very
difficult thing for many of us to do
especially men right we'll be aggressive
all the time this is why I often talk
about tender aggression you've got to be
a lot more tender in order to utilize
that form of intelligence you gotta let
go into that intelligence you've got to
let go into that illumination once that
light switch is on you don't have to
walk you don't have to earn you just go
hmm when trying to decide upon the
course of action that is going to to be
greatly impactful big impact in your
life you know it'd be a big decision
you've got to make right and it's all
subjective I know sometimes like
breaking up with your girlfriend's a big
decision my you're 17 years old you know
adults like to do this you all right
17 years old Oh big deal yeah yeah yeah
we will find love later no motherfucker
it's a big decision right now I'm 17
years old and my experience is potent
right now right adults like to do that
they like to negate the experiences of
children because they're young you are
you're just a teenager are you you got a
whole life ahead of you let the bitch go
that's why I talk to you guys I know a
lot of you guys are 14 15 16 years old I
know a lot of you guys are 56 65 years
old
I talk to you with respect because I
understand subjectively that these
things are important to you right you
might only be 14 years old but that
a big fucking problem you've got because
physiologically you're experiencing it
as stress in the body my invitation to
you stop working so hard to make the
decision and when I say that I mean stop
going to your head so much stuff going
to the face and thinking and detaching
from the subtle intelligence the big the
big flood light of intelligence that you
have within you relax your body breathe
into your balls and the decision will be
made for you