got this question here from our friend
Alvaro who essentially wants to know how
does he deal with his fake friends he
says that he's been he's grown up with
this pack of wolves and I'll tell you
what I mean in a moment by that that
that at this point they're 18 years old
they are constantly talking behind each
other's backs putting each other down
and our friend Alvaro in fact the the
point at which they like to pick on him
is the fact that he has a girlfriend
that he's been with for about two years
and they want to know like why are you
such a faggot because you got a
girlfriend for two years and you haven't
had sex with any other girls don't you
feel tied down so on and so forth so
they use that as a means to to get at
him but they're you know they're a bunch
of fucking hyenas and they do this back
and forth with one another and Alvaro is
like how do I deal with this well I'm
gonna try to give you perhaps one of the
most simplistic answers to these videos
that I've ever made and that is they are
simply not your friends I mean it's as
simple as that and I'll tell you why
when I say pack of wolves before I
basically meant that they are exhibiting
the behavior that many young boys
probably between the ages of I want to
say 12 13 to about 18 I mean they're
getting kind of old for this shit
but the truth is you know you'll
probably you'll see people doing this
forever
yeah it's just the maturity level of our
culture where when in group states they
sort of want to create pecking orders so
they the some will posture themselves as
more aggressive or as leaders amongst
the others and oftentimes in order to do
that they create contrast so in order
for me to position myself as the alpha
male I have to create contrast the best
way to create contrast is to put you
down
it's a fastest way to create contrast
but it's a fake contrast because in
order for me to feel is it I'm the alpha
in the pack or I'm the aggressor in the
pack in order for me to receive that
feeling if I have to put you down it
really means that it's not an authentic
feeling of groundedness and true alpha
ness when using you know I use that term
alpha to describe the
psychology you my friend have actually
already checked out of this and you know
this just basically I mean I know this
based on the question that you sent me
and the fact that this is very important
the parameters by which they judge
themselves in order to see who is above
who in the pecking order
don't even fucking apply to you this is
where we've got to be very vigilant
about how we get intertwined with
certain cliques and groups and groups of
friends because what happens is because
the human need to belong is so strong we
will do whatever their group finds the
group thinkers right the collective
consciousness unconscious of that group
you'll start measuring yourself by the
parameters that are strongest amongst
the group even if they really do not
resonate with your heart he says that
these guys are you know a part of the
how they get at him is with his
girlfriend thing and they think it's
cool to like to be with lots of women
but also like the derogatory towards
them well that's not a parameter by
which you gauge your self value that's
like that's a totally different that's a
totally different ballpark so you're not
even playing their game now part of the
thing is that you've you've grown up
with these kids so you come to know
yourself through the mirror of their
communion with you
to that community know this and have
this plant this seed in your heart they
are not your friends and you were very
different from them in fact you stand as
a low the true alpha is that needs no
one to prove himself you don't need them
to prove yourself you stand as the alpha
outside their bullshit pecking order
based on parameters that make no sense
to you see yourself as above their shit
okay now that's just a story also maybe
they're good guys I don't know I don't
give a shit talking to you you're above
them you're better than them
you're better than that and that's okay
be with it but you don't necessarily
have to become priggish about it you
don't necessarily have to become
stuck-up about it you don't have to rub
it in their face in fact don't say
anything because the true
self-sufficient man self-reliant man
needs not say it for other people to
know he's not prove it to anyone he
knows and that is a very balanced strong
alpha place to come from if you will be
with that and build yourself up in that
way and they will naturally fall to the
wayside because as you grow in your
personal development as you become a
stronger version of yourself the
stickiness or the attractiveness the mag
magnetic power of energy that's beneath
you or you've graduated from merely
drops off it merely goes away and when
they hurl insults at you it will be like
your four-year-old little brothers
curling insults at you it's like you
know you're four so nothing you say
really carries any weight do you see
from a personal evolution standpoint
they are four years old you're 18 years
old who gives a shit what they say
they're beneath you in that way there's
an
so that's it I'm done