today I'm excited to be speaking with
Elliott Hulse professional strongman
strength coach and author you can know
exactly how to lose weight but still be
obese what I invite people to do is to
realize that no matter what you know and
what you even do because that's just no
one step closer to to the roots of
what's transformational it's who you are
that's important my uncle was a gymnast
a martial artist he ran marathons he was
a bodybuilder and I was four years old
and here's this guy he was essentially
Superman because we can do standing back
flips and why break bricks in half with
his hands so you could just imagine that
my consciousness the way I think it
rises out of an environment where at a
very young age it was like well you know
you can actually do things that Superman
dude I was like walk on your hands and
do backflips and chop bricks and you
don't put anything in your body that
doesn't support vitality these had
talked about how even at your you know
lowest point financially you still
focused on eating healthy foods and
investing in your body because that kind
of seeds into everything else who the
jury literally becomes the cells of your
body I mean you want to think better
consider what your brain cells are being
made up and how to strength ty internet
was the vehicle through which you you
approach this world you know it was your
body you're physically weak I don't see
how you could be mentally strong
emotionally strong what happens in our
mind happens in our body what's
happening in our body is linked to our
mind so there's really no separating
them if you want to become more
intelligent to have better relationships
you want to make more money it begins
with the mind and the mind literally
drops down into the body via the
peripheral nervous system so that's a
great plan never thought about it that
way you know we think of our mind kind
of a separate thing but it literally
connects into your physical body yeah
okay there's no separation between the
neocortex the cortex and medulla and the
brainstem and what does the brainstem do
that do it branches out into the organs
and the muscle so it's like your youth
returning your bicep but really you're
you're trimming your brain you're
training your mind yeah it's all
interconnected what are the biggest
frustrations or
your clients there well it's not the one
that they think it is they've got this
thing that they think is their problem
but really when you take a good look at
it you realize that that is just the
manifestation of a deeper problem that
you didn't see so growing stronger
physically a lot of people say well yeah
you know what I'd like to deadlift more
weight I'd like to squat more weight I'd
like to press more weight but as I
mentioned earlier who you are determines
what you do so focusing on who you are
is more important so you can come to me
and say well you Elliott and I want six
pack abs but then I have to take a look
at well that's fine we can help you burn
fat and can help you train that muscle
but the nervous system the connection to
those muscles is completely shut off
because you're on medication or you're
eating foods that potentially shut down
the the nervous systems connect you know
your ability to turn all those muscles
we can take it one step further and say
well why are you not digesting your food
properly why is it causing inflammation
in your gut and that could take us to
the fact that oh you've got money
problems you're seventy thousand dollars
in debt and your wife is upset about
this and she's thinking about leaving
you and you just found out your
daughter's pregnant so it's like wait a
second you came here one a six pack abs
but we just took a look at your
digestive system and we realize that
your digestive system is screwed up
because of your stress in your life it's
like okay that's nice want that why is
that a problem you get their biggest
challenge to think yeah exactly you said
I want to lift more on it I'll be
stronger I want to squat more but in
reality I mean it's so much deeper than
that dig deeper and find out really why
you're doing it you know what's what's
behind the motivation what's going
your mind it's easy to Trey I'm all
sweaty because i just finished training
i mean it out elma dark exactly but
nutrition is 24 hours a day right an
hour a day is about four percent of your
entire week right yeah okay so this is
doesn't require that much we've got to
do it what are like three suggestions
you would give to anybody that's
starting out that's trying to you know
chant transform their body physically I
always take it a few steps back and go
to the root of well what is the context
of your question for me it's always
where are you coming from what is the
root of this I'm just more fascinated in
big picture of things I'm more
interested in who are you are you asking
me that yeah then ok you can do these
three three three tips but you know that
people want tips so you know one of the
things i would invite someone to do and
it's all basic stuff it's not sexy at
all is are you sleeping at night it's
like dude you totally lost you missed
your anabolic window and you're doing it
every single night and you think that
this is like I heard someone say this
the other day I think they commented on
one of my videos that I'm genetically
inclined towards being a night owl oh my
god that's the biggest crop at SH that I
never heard a night in life electricity
in the home just came out bout like a
hundred years ago what do we do up until
that point when the Sun Goes Down you
settle down you know that's where your
DNA is that that's how you're busy allow
your physiology responds to the
celestial bodies we think we're
different you think we're separate from
even the earth and the Sun and the moon
significant you realize that your
hormones are dictated based on where the
where the planet is and you think that
you're you're genetically disposed to
doing shit outside of your roots your
planet shocked at how many people just
don't drink water I don't want to talk
to you about building muscle if you
don't drink water you see that's like
going to a dentist and be a thing I'd
like to have to be early shiny white
teeth and he's like okay well you know
how kind of toothbrush to use a brush
your teeth Oh brushing teeth yeah i just
don't like doing that got a result it
was just not genetically inside to brush
my teeth yeah it's just not in me people
are fighting for the closest parking
spot they can find
at a gym where they then go inside in an
air-conditioned room and they walk on a
treadmill so good you want to walk from
your car to the to the gym they get in
the gym and you walk up a freaking
treadmill you people void movement if
you keep doing the same thing so your
whole life you know on this linear path
that you're saying you probably won't
stay on it it's just gonna get boring
but if you keep changing it up and
you're trending in the direction that
you want to go then even if it's not in
your path you know you still get to
where you want to be yeah and then your
life is full of experiences yeah and I'm
way to board not to have lots of
experiences I don't know how people
really live it's like have you ever gone
back to high school and seemed like the
kids that are doing and look exactly the
same is where you left them and it's
like boy it's like a saying here's a
pass by but for you one year is passed
by and dies Elliot thank you so much for
sharing this valuable information with
us today check out whole strength com do
you want any products that will help you
build muscle get strength and become an
alpha male ah thank you so much Elliot
you got it I'll see you guys ask
yourself today what are you gonna do to
create your legacy all right take care
thank you hey guys DJ here I hope you
enjoyed the interview with Elliot such
an inspiration I like how he just brings
it back to the basics you know sleep
hydration movement that's really what
matters if you want to see more of his
videos check them out on youtube his
channel is called strengthcamp also
click the link below to see the full
interview where he talks about his full
journey and when the key characteristics
of becoming an alpha male you'll also
receive access to interviews with other
fitness experts such as Vince that money
Scott Herman tellurian access to the
exact training and nutrition program
that I used to put on 12 pounds of
muscle in just under 90 days so check it
out below take care