one of our friends wants to know about
multi-level marketing apparently people
are approaching him with the you know
bottles of juice that cost sixty dollars
and subscription programs where they
send you dishwashing liquid for a you
know twenty dollars a month shit like
this of course I'm making light of a
business model which is called network
marketing or or multi-level marketing
and this is basically where you know you
go out you sell to your friends that's
the point of multi-level marketing it is
kind of grassroots so you're going out
there and you're like you're sort of
like a door-to-door salesman and the
doors that you knock on are usually your
friends and your family and your
neighbors as opposed to using the
district distribution of television and
you know things of that nature right
it's really it's really a grassroots
form of marketing a particular product
and you're gonna have people who come up
to your like dude you can become a
millionaire really easy really fast if
you just sell this juice right and and I
know because being an entrepreneur and
of a entrepreneurial mindset I've
explored these options I've I've
actually been a part of a multi-level
marketing program and it was about
selling freaking juice I like grape
juice that they had you believe would
you know cure cancer but um but anyway
that was neither here nor there that was
an experience and what I learned from
that was that if you do participate in a
program like this you can win you can do
really well but a couple of things have
to happen first it's not going to be
easy you got to be a hustler just as if
you were going to start any other
business you gotta you can really got a
hustle your face off and if you've ever
met somebody who is in multi-level
marketing their bug in everybody I meet
guys at barbecues and like they find out
that I'm a trainer and they like they
won't leave me alone about their protein
shake and like they really think that
this protein shake is special and I look
at the label in amicus i could buy this
shit at GNC bro it's like why do I have
to sign up but it doesn't matter they're
convinced you've literally got a
brainwash yourself or just be you know a
convinced person about your ability to
sell this thing being a hustler and
you've got to be completely passionate
you got to be really passionate about
that product you see I I'm a hustler and
I work hard and I've been able to build
my business and you know different
levels but I couldn't get passionate
about the fucking juice you know like I
would tell people like you know this is
really cool business opportunity because
it was and the juice tastes good but I
just could not justify I could not look
people in the eye and be like okay yeah
so it's forty dollars a bottle of those
fucking juice and and you gotta sign up
and buy like a box of it every month you
know otherwise you know it's not gonna
work for you I felt like a douche bag
again it has nothing to do with the
model of multi-level marketing or
network marketing it in and of itself
may wear it does work there's no
question but it was the content you know
the juice I I wasn't convinced but if
you're look hey if you're convinced
about the thing then you'll do well
because brian tracy has once said I used
to study a lot of brian tracy when i was
in sales at the gym us making a sale as
a transfer of passion if you got passion
for something it's very easy for you to
make a sale in my business what I do I
sell my ideas with regard to fitness and
personal development I don't really have
to sell anything cuz hey I'm already
passionate about the shit I'm just
saying hey I'm fucking excited about
this I think it's cool it's helped me it
can help you yeah right but um but I
couldn't get that way for the juice and
realize that you're gonna break your ass
it's not easy anybody who comes to come
to you with the the quick and easy spiel
just ignore them they're lying to you
they're full of shit you're not the
weight work your ass off and gonna have
to really enjoy the juice good luck