so got a question from one of our
friends who is really fun and outgoing
he says he's got the gift of gab and
women really appreciate him and are
attracted to him he does real well in
the early stages of relationships but
the minute they get together he gets
really uncomfortable wanting to assert
himself on the decisions being made in
the relationship so basically says he
wants to be a good guy but he doesn't
want to over impact you just want to
overpower the decision-making process or
just because basically be a controlling
jerk as what he says in the relationship
and you know that there's so much bias
against this idea of the controlling
machismo man who's always telling women
what to do okay so he wants to avoid
that but he doesn't want to suppress his
natural inclination towards
decision-making and being and having the
upper hand what does he do how does a
guy behave in this culture when the
natural inclination is towards moving
forward taking an aggressive assertive
action and deep fully truly there are
women most women appreciate that and a
world that tells us to you know soften
up take your time be a little bit more
you know feminine in your approach with
women and then you got like a
relationship with two vaginas and that's
never good so what do you do man this is
the way I look at it you know I've I've
been with my wife for very very very
long time we have a great relationship
and there are two types of decisions
that need to be made in our family now
because now like I've got four children
and I've got a home I've got like the
decisions being made now are much bigger
than you know we're going to the movie
tonight we're gonna go see Batman well I
want to see spider-man well I said
Batman you're coming with me woman like
shit like that we don't we'll even go to
movies and shit we're making some deep
ass decisions you know in our lives like
you know where our children going to to
go to school or you know where are we
going to live shit like that so the way
I look at it the way I've experienced it
is that there are two types of decisions
that need to be made and you've got to
know your domain there are spiritual or
contextual
decisions right and then there are
worldly and or content contextual
rightness a context and content content
you'll write the name in fucking word
decisions context content spiritual big
picture and grounded more day-to-day
reality decisions though they're on the
complete ends of the spectrum of
decision making one of them looks like
what is the mission for my family or
what kind of career am I going to move
towards what kind of business am I going
to build what kind of person am i
becoming right what kind of version of
me am i becoming this is this all very
big picture it's very abstract it's very
in the future it's very it's very
direction oriented right big picture
direction oriented decisions and then
there are more grounded day-to-day
practical what needs to get done
decisions which are like you know where
are we going to live or you know like
what kind of house are we going to live
in what kind of furniture are we going
to get now these are expensive choices
what kind of car are we going to drive
even what kind of food are we going to
eat or we're gonna go eat at Z grill or
grazie do you see like you see what I'm
saying I tend to make and I think that
most men will be better off taking the
position of big picture spiritual
contextual decision-makers and then
leaving the rest and I say leaving and I
don't wanna make it sound as if you know
it's just the rest it's the leftovers
but giving responsibility to the woman
to make a lot of the grounded day-to-day
decisions right so if your girlfriend is
asked it wants to go out to a movie and
she wants to see spider-man and you and
see Batman go see fucking spider-man
dude who cares you know why because
you're an emission spider-man or Batman
really doesn't fucking matter to a man
on a mission get in touch with your
mission your mission in life your vision
where we're all where we're going with
this this is a very spiritual this is
very contextual this is a very big
picture when you're focused on the big
picture stuff which
in tip-tippy generally you know it's in
our DNA to be more big-picture oriented
than the little shit like look my wife
wants brown furniture and I really like
black furniture oh and I love this guy's
who like I always wanted a leather couch
but my wife wants one with the flowers
dude let I get the one the fucking
flowers who cares you're focused on your
vision you're going somewhere you got
bigger not more important I don't want
to like say one's better than the other
but you got big things that you're
thinking about that quite frankly I
don't care what you what color you paint
the house I do you wanna call it a bit
cover the house pink I do not care
you know what in fact leave that to the
woman I said once before depends on the
contact sometimes I get confused people
get confused with the shit that I say
but a woman's home is like her vagina
and you don't want to tell a woman how
to take care of her vagina you let her
take care of the home and that and that
is a metaphor for the grounded day to
day content of life let her decide and I
guarantee I'll tell you right now as far
as quantity is concerned it's about 90
percent that stuff and 10 percent the
stuff that you're focused on you see and
when they're really big content driven
questions she's going to come to you
because she trusts you because you shown
her your your ability to be trusted by
moving yourself her and your
relationship and family in the right
direction all along while she's taking
care of the day-to-day while she's
taking care of the grounded practical
what's going to happen four minutes
minute out hour to day to day stuff do
you see so brilliant it it's not a
matter of being see the guys that look
that our idiots are the ones that like
they want to control everything so he
tell her women how to decorate the house
they tell their women what kind of car
they're gonna drive they tell the woman
what we're gonna eat for dinner really
but they truly grounded superior man
knows where he's going and all that
stuff he happily lets his woman he
embraces her ability to do those things
he in fact he supports her
making those decisions I want my wife to
make those decisions
so that's it good luck do don't get too
wrapped up in this think big and let
your woman choose the day-to-day stuff