where
everything I'm learning in my life is
starting to question what I've learned
my whole life I like to follow that and
go matter George Karl and keep George
Carlin the guy vs
I modulus big and when
and is there a middle ground or somebody
s paid and suffering
so is there any sort
I've been using this metaphor with dance
right
the dance is the physical expression of
rhythm rhythm is music
there's no linear music it's always
up down down up down left right left
right left right you see so there's a
duality the entire universe all of this
shit is due out that's why I said Adam
e011 right we'll do this power symbol
what is it zero one zero one of them in
a nice day winter so autonomic there is
system parasympathetic sympathetic
what's this duel shit going on if you
look around everywhere like down to that
atoms protons neutrons like how is it
that there is this plus and minus going
on everywhere right it makes you wonder
if there's only one way well if there is
just one no that one looks like
science culture science fortune they we
come to a place or the very long time
where where there's heaven in hell we're
preparing against there's this and then
there's that there's no is that what I'm
inviting you to explore is religion yes
logic guests dance they both support
each other if you're keen enough to see
if you watch a lot of it is interesting
because it's remastered eyes din to a
great degree if you go to the roots of a
lot of bed it's some amazing powerful
shit explore it and then explore science
and you end up in the same fucking place
they're just speaking different
languages black white Adam Eve but
really Adam Eaton at me are you
following me yes but today I'm quiet a
beautiful
I don't see that because because they're
so diametrically opposed penis vagina
they don't look anything alike what
happens when it come together baby power
shit there's different and you believe
it because someone's saying penis only
kill the vagina someone saying date I
only kill the night how absurd is that
someone saying poetry only Killa science
science only kill the poetry my poetry
killing his poetry dizzy there's this
advice of this and we're spreading apart
we're saying that it's it's one and not
another when really that's the biggest
lie we've been told it's so funny
because I love this porch of this whole
of Genesis familiar with Genesis there
was paradise Adam II paradise they
didn't know that they were separate from
God which basically means it was an Adam
Eve right it's everything was what it
was peaceful shit was perfect the minute
that they rarely night it might mind you
they eat from the tree of wisdom why is
it that it's called the tree with
why is it a snake always if you notice
like Egyptian art it's always a sign of
wisdom so there's a snake there's a
creature of wisdom in mythology the
snake ohs represents wisdom they're
eating from a tree of wisdom and the
very first thing that happens when they
bite that Apple penis vagina they
recognize their separation we've lost
paradise because we gain the wisdom and
this is why it's wisdom because the
digital age is powered by penis vagina
01 you see so this is this recognition
of Adam and Eve instead of a believe or
their separation from God that causes
all the shit like Cain killed Abel and
now we're all screwed i mean we're
killing each other left and right y de
que el is brilliant fucking brothers
Cain had a different attitude Abel had a
different attitude one was more of a
cultivator of the land the other one was
a what they call it no man it's this
separation Cain killed Abel the jews
killed or Muslims killed Richards
Christians to the Muslims to see
cannulated the same fucking shit they're
both offspring of Adam Eve there who are
both from paradise but they woke up and
that waking up is powerful but also our
downfall
how man has fallen they say the fall of
man is because it's done you get that
yeah
but if you revive it again awesome
right so by definition you're saying to
another
increase and also has if you are
my definition and all these are stories
to describe the undescribable to
represent that which could never truly
be known so mythology or religion is
mythology whether in the term ethology
don't get it twisted it doesn't mean
that it's a lie it's olive eight mints
don't mean oh we come to believe that
when you say bit I shut the fucking bed
Oh careful because myth mythology are
the powerful stories that we've used as
a race of human beings since the dawn of
creation or I use that operation but the
Boeing up of people here somehow we've
used it since the beginning to describe
that which cannot be seen but we feel
the way the mythology plays out is
merely happenstance it's mere the Native
American merely happened to live amongst
Buffalo so they've got a buffalo guy
there's no fucking Buffalo in Jerusalem
do you see so what people end up
tangling with is my stories better than
your story when they all look if you go
to the root of all every single one of
them it comes to the same thing Italy
you got to be very detached very
objective about this to accept what I'm
saying because what happens is we become
personally invested in our myth and any
attack on something that personally
invested in is an attack on me right
science is a religion because it's just
a story to describe the undescribable
because if you look at the quantum
physics really I mean listen to some of
the things that I sign says it comes
down to you okay there's just funny
energy and we can't predict it at all
studying rifle physics or people say
they want to put physics is 0 for quacks
you know why because when you get to the
roots of quantum physics they can't
explain it any more it's just a fucking
story to touch it to explain the
unexplainable religion have these huge
animals science happens to you really
big words do you see is that helpful
yeah
question can i find myself by myself II
how I believe it is
what are you believing that's the thing
you good after seven why do you have to
believe why can't you just experience
because I I shoot it was given to me
nobody chooses their vision that's why I
brought you can you can change you grow
up religion is the religion sorry Carly
okay is that so we should press well
let's just wish the cards who I love
this conversation by the way I don't
know if you guys can tell I can talk
about this shit all day long what's up
Elliott's it what
you