good morning y'all I guess you could
imagine where I'm headed that's right
strengthcamp and you probably also
notice that I haven't been uploading on
this Elliott Hulse channel very often
this week in fact I've uploaded three
videos to the strength camp channel this
week and none on my la health channel so
and what you guys think I'm neglecting
you in fact it is my assumption that if
you're serious about being the strong
was versioning yourself you're committed
you're an action taker and you like what
I have to say in my videos then you
should be a subscriber to everything
Elliott Hulse or shrimp camp related so
YouTube channels Facebook instagrams so
felt neglected that's because you're not
connected bro to get on that anyway I'm
heading over there right now because I'm
going to film another video for shrimp
camp because I've been doing a lot of
things at the gym lately namely to help
my wife out but also I went there the
other day to interview dr. far on our
resident neuroscientist so so I figured
since all those things took place at
strength camp and all those things are
fitness fish related even though even
though everything is related you know
the body is the mind those were fitness
related type things so I put it on the
front can't channel and that's basically
how I'm gonna roll drinking my high ph
ionized water with sea salt I can't tell
you if the ionized water makes a
difference but I know it's filtered and
I add the sea salt like I've been doing
for years in order to well maintained a
certain mineral equilibrium within the
body most of you probably know you
learned in school that human the fluid
in the human body blood had the same or
very similar well I understand identical
sodium and mineral content as VC
interestingly enough there are those
that say we crawled up out of the sea so
anyway maintaining connectedness
to our roots to our biological roots
make sense to me so I try to find any
opportunity to do that so that's it
anyway I'm going to cut this video short
because I'm rambling and I'm trying to
get through traffic while talking at the
same time Jane a good idea to make for
good videos and don't make for good
driving so i'll see you guys on the
other channel because i'll be uploading
them at the same time done