hey so today's question comes from our
buddy Felix he goes on to say Elliot I
think I have a problem
it's a problem I've been dealing with
since boyhood every time I find an
attractive woman I can't get her out of
my mind I think about her unceasingly
all day long she's running through my
mind she asked if her legs are tired ha
ha ha all right anyway so here's the
problem
says I've been in a relationship for 3
years things were great love my
girlfriend just the other day I go to
the gym and I just decided to help this
girl out I can't get her out of my mind
now I'm concerned about this because I
love my girlfriend but yet this woman's
legs are tired from running around in my
mind all day he goes on to question
whether or not he might have some
pathology he's suffering from an illness
he even gives it a label he says this
might be some sort of beta
characteristic not exactly sure what you
mean there buddy
so the very first thing I'd like to do
is approach this by saying that I think
one of the most damaging things that
happens to human beings is guilt and
it's done to us and then we do it to
ourselves and it always almost always
centers around a moral judgment being
placed on a spontaneous natural primal
thing happening in the body of a
physiological response physiological
happening that you really have no
control over a lot of it begins at potty
training a quite a significant of it
begins at potty training because two
things around that age around that age
you're you need to go to school and
mommy needs to go back to work and the
world needs to continue going on and
you're shitting yourself you should be
ashamed of yourself
but yet you're not physically
physiologically mature enough not to
shit yourself so you begin feeling
guilty about your body that's what
that's really where it first begins
so the world is and your parents are a
the home is a microcosm for the world
because your parents are the agents of
tyranny in the home this is you know our
parents have been conditioned I have
been conditioned because I'm a parent
also and then we bring the conditioning
into the home with the children and we
damage them that way
and this is one that could be avoided in
many circumstances but you know what
Mommy has to go back to work right
because they got to pay for their for
the Lexus all right they got to keep
cable TV on you know sad so you need to
stop shooting yourself and the guilt
begins then because your body is
spontaneous in its way it does what it's
supposed to do at the right time your
body's not stupid when you get an
erection because there's a hot chick
around you your body's not stupid no
matter what you've committed to in your
life you could be married for 40 years
but you're going to get an erection when
there's a hot chick around you you're
going to be drawn the guilt is
associated with not accepting not
appreciating not realizing really it's
ignorance that this is a natural
physiological response and it's OK in
fact it means you're healthy other
strange thing that parents do to
children around that age and I do my
best to avoid doing this my children we
do pretty good job we're pretty liberal
in this way is the dinner table you'd
better eat don't get up until you eat
this is this is a really tough one here
the child that has wants to get up to
move around whose body is far more
intelligent than your old mucked up sick
sad depressed and conditioned body by
society once they get up and move around
its body's not hungry but you're gonna
make it sit there sit there no get up
till you eat so the bit divide the child
starts feeling guilty like why don't I
want to eat this is there something
going on wrong here this is the roots of
our guilt and then it begins and then
after that it begins like now you have
an erection and that's not don't touch
your dick and that's not okay and so
these are all spontaneous things that
happen in our body
shitting eating and erections we live
our life forever and ever having
problems associated with it people got
eating disorders they got sexual
disorders and their guts are all fucked
up alright the digestive system
digestive system and
I mean that's what we are we eat and we
fuck we feel bad about it ah fucked up
world we live in so that's the first
thing dude anybody any man who says that
he's not attracted for other woman
because he's so pious
you know he's with his girlfriend for
three years and I'm not attracted other
woman is either sick he's so sexually
repressed that everything recognize his
own erection or he's full of shit he's
bullshitting himself and trying to
bullshit other people so the very first
thing dude you're fine you're cool this
is great now here's where it becomes a
problem especially if you've made
choices in your life associated with not
fucking other women right and you know
having to run around in your mind all
day is kind of like a continuous fucking
it's a low-grade foreplay for yourself
what are you go do jerk off right you're
thinking about her but you can't do
nothing weather man I mean the
circumstances have have left the
building and yet because you became
addicted to and greedy for possession of
the thing that gave you the joyful
experience that you had because the
attraction was a joyful experience it's
a beautiful thing man a beautiful girl
you approach and you help her out you
feel the good feelings in your body
allow the good feelings in your body to
happen appreciate the good feelings in
your body watch it without judgment I'm
fucking turned on right now
she's really hot breathe take a deep
breath smile be in the moment and then
move on you see now this is where you'd
have to be disciplined but moving on is
very difficult if you begin the
adventure the whole physiological
adventure with guilt stepping in the way
because you never allow it to fully
embed itself you're never allowed to
fully happen in your physiology and one
thing your body doesn't like is
incomplete shit right it's just a part
of it it's a part of what makes us human
being we don't like incomplete
I think even if they if you take a pen
and you draw a circle and you just leave
a space even a monkey will pick up the
pen and finish the space because it's
like they're primates like shit needs to
be finished finished doesn't always
necessarily mean you're going to fuck
her finish means you're not interrupting
the process with guilt you're not
interrupting the physiological response
with guilt allowed to happen you smile
say boy say to yourself and I'll say it
to her because then she's maybe she's
gonna she might get open then now you
gotta be a problem because both of you
are drooling say to yourself boy that's
pretty nice smile give her a smile of
appreciation don't let her know what
you're thinking she probably already
feels it but let her know I appreciate
appreciate you I appreciate what's going
on here I'm experiencing it and then say
it's nice have a nice day and then move
on require some discipline but I
guarantee you that you'll be grounded
enough in yourself if you don't let the
the cognitive dissonance which is the
moral judgment place it on your
physiological response to happen guilt
is an ugly fucking thing and like I said
it's as ugly as not letting people shit
when they're supposed to shit forcing
people that eat and feeling bad because
you've got your dick is hard it's weird
it's weird so a perspective that might
be helpful for you comes from a quote
from Osho I love OSHA reading Osho since
I was in high school oh she was
incredible and he goes on to say
something to the effect of when you see
a flower don't and you love it you see
this flower you see this beautiful form
that you're moved by don't pick it
because in picking it you destroy the
entire circumstance imagine I love this
flower so I'm going to kill it and
that's what happens when we want to
possess possession is one of those
things that really screw us up in many
different ways it's art it's our
neediness I want to own it I want to
have it right and you see her and
instead of appreciating her like you
should appreciate the flower you want to
have
now you fuck it all up because now
you're carrying it around in your head
and you destroyed the beauty of the
circumstance to see the flower and
relish in the moment is a good thing but
now you pick it you destroy and that's
you know a lot of relationships end
because of the immaturity of both
partners and not realizing that once you
own someone the attraction goes away
that's why people you know they're in
and out of relation but they fall out of
love no fucking fall out of love you
were just greedy for that bitch you got
her and now your your nature you fucked
it all up
I don't own my wife my wife doesn't own
me we appreciate each other man I
appreciate that woman I appreciate that
woman so much that I would die for her
but I don't own her she wants to get up
and go somewhere I might be disappointed
but I'll say you have to go if your
heart is calling you to go go we don't
own each other you don't own anyone
because if I did own her if I did have
the capacity to pull her strings force
her I now have picked the flower because
it's mine now and what I do I removed it
from its source of vitality you pick
that flower you remove it from source of
vitality a human being source of
vitality is in there the self possession
there's in who they are
you can't own them so let it go
and that's it man you're allowed to have
sexual joyful pleasurable feelings in
every regard in any circumstance but you
lose yourself when you decide that you
want to own earth suck possess and trap
that thing appreciate but don't try to
possess done