you kind of remind me of wrong Paula um
ah of course I love row politician and
the fact that I disagree some of his
policies but he's just a straight up
honest did and he just speaks the truth
which is so rare in politics so we're
everywhere so rare everywhere yeah
exactly so I see Robin I'm all about
getting out of the social conditioning I
see romp on politics I see you in
fitness and I just gravitate towards you
guys and like I sense genuineness
necessary for it to me thanks do you
think you're like at your deepest nature
that you're an infinite being like if
even if you die can you go to some other
consciousness and that you've been alive
for forever let's go back to that block
of ice yeah oh where that water come
with that I scupper from water with the
water come from well the atmosphere well
it has the atmosphere is there less
atmosphere or more atmosphere since the
beginning of atmospheres well I once
heard that all the water the tears same
water that's always been here in just
its honor and it goes into the clouds
and then it goes back to earth and it
goes in class and this is what the water
has been doing since the earth has been
is evolved so it's like that piece of
ice to be like well you know I'm just
this piece of ice I'm completely finite
is retarded because you know what that
piece of ice is going to end up in my
glass of water or in someone's soda and
they're going to drink it and I'm gonna
piss it out and it's going to evaporate
go back into the fucking clouds that's
gonna come back down again so where else
nice yeah that's the nature of human
being we're we're a physical
manifestation of a cloud reality a
spiritual reality yeah um you imagine in
the future fake like make clones and
instead of your consciousness just only
controlling le holes maybe you could
control like 100 le holes is all at the
same time without he's boring again I
don't want to do this form again I
already did this for I first of all my
ass is way too big yo I can't deal with
this one anymore like I wouldn't want to
be clones first of all the conscious
there's no way that
no one's really my experiences but at
this if this consciousness could kind of
like go into another body yeah I'd like
to try that out I like to try out what
it's like to be like you know in India
Mike just sit and do your goggle domain
is dentist I saw they had these street
dentists and yoga one of mixing words
here in India one day he's good guys are
like people can't afford dentist so
these guys sit on the street like I'm a
box and I dig people's teeth out like
the people in the town love them that
seems pretty cool or or maybe I don't
know there's so many cool things that I
might want to try I don't want to be
cloned I don't want to do elliott hulse
again this is worn out all right there
yeah yeah yeah maybe I'll see what it's
like to to be an African or European or
Asian ah you know I might be cool yeah
and maybe I've always thought be called
me the eagle it's like fly around in
Eagle imagine let me you be robbed of
that pic of an experience of an eagle I
mean it flies miles above the earth it
can spot tiny little things and it zooms
in and catches it and it's okay no I
don't want to be reincarnated as Elliott
else again own homes don't be a fucking
ego I Yeah right that's got to be cool
not the awesome what are your thoughts
on uh there's lots of guys to go through
stages on like one-night stands casual
sex monogamy is soul mates um I believe
you've been with your wife since you're
really young yeah 40 yeah 40 know uh
like do you think you were you're like
soul mates do you think what just
happened this way this is the way this
is the wave of dads happened for me you
know the dance and that's why I call it
is as part of its when we're doing it
sometimes it's neurotic but then there's
like this is where the spirits taking it
and I have no hang-ups about
relationships and dating or premarital
sex at all
I just happened to have married that the
high school girl that I started having
sex with when I was 14 hello no it's
just like you know we dated we would
apart for me each other we dated would
apologize finally we just kept happening
it was like well Harriet I mean yeah
let's try this one out we got married so
I have I have no preconceptions about
rights or wrongs on how people choose to
live their sexual lives or you know
marriage or anything like that yeah I
feel that my experience with my wife has
been a positive one and it's added it's
contributed immensely to the man that I
am today I know I wouldn't be because
I'm so she's so grounding for me that
she's been like a rock throughout all
the difficult times and even you know
times that are just confusing that uh
you wouldn't experience me as you're
experiencing me now in this way if it
weren't for her so it's been nothing but
a positive it's all positive but I you
know I can point to a lot of things that
on paper look good about my decision so
I'm cool with it awesome so a big thing
about your philosophy is just having
zero expectations and just going where
if the dance takes you knowing that
where the dance takes you is the most
magical thing and what that's meant to
be that's exciting thing in the world
see halloween is coming up right where
do you live Santa Barbara California All
Right see what the US Halloween's coming
up right yeah and the stick when we do
the strange thing at Halloween they
create haunted houses now you know if
you go into a haunted house you're gonna
get fucking scared right I'm you go in
with the intent that something's it a
job out by let's scare you and you're
gonna shit your pants you're just gonna
freak out you're walking to a potential
into the haunted house not knowing that
she said it happened but yet nervous
people all over the country line up the
going haunted houses on Halloween why
because there's so much pleasure the
experience of being shared and being
taken by surprise yeah if you do it to
ourselves we watch horror movies
suspense movies because there's so much
excitement and bodily pleasure in
in that excitement in a net anticipation
not not knowing so why do we have to
recreate it why do we have these
recreation when we could just live our
lives that way yeah it makes perfect
sense that's a great metaphor I don't
want it though I want I want just this
mystery to happen yeah one big thing
like I've learned in just relationships
in general is not to be media so what is
not to be needy weather with the friends
or dating and then then that I'd I was
thinking I should apply the same
principle to like God or the spirit or
whatever you want to call it and not be
needy with God which is like okay just
do whatever you want like maybe I'll
designers but take me wherever you want
and that's when you'll be taken to the
most magical amazing things oh oh and
super for fuck respond and it's magical
yeah yeah absolutely yeah you always end
up in the coolest places I'm where I am
see I had a particular idea about what I
wanted yeah and I took certain actions
towards it remember that's only fifty
percent of the game God it took me the
other fifty percent again and they're
some of the coolest shit that I couldn't
predict it it's like wow I could never
imagine but these stupid YouTube videos
that are making just so I can get work
in second direction it's going to be how
I reached would you say 85 million
people in your online and sin I like
that that totally is is a monster
jumping out of the closet going boo yeah
so when you say 85 million I'm like good
whoa that's crazy and it's not
pleasurable it mystery yeah that's a
slow with it man it's so much cooler
than you could have played yeah exactly
it now I think after you buy willing to
take risks and jumpy on every
opportunity you have you're telling that
God's Spirit give me more opportunities
like you're saying if I take a risk you
better have my back up there and it's
like whatever force it is always has
your back if you take the risk see
having it out of your back it's just
tricky thing because having my back
means you're going to take care
in a way that I want you to take care of
it right so if you go into a fight you
say uh yeah what you got my back right
that means you're calm down motherfucker
you're gonna do to poach this dude right
yeah but what God has your back you have
to be detached from how he's gonna have
your back it might be you know what yeah
I got your back but you need to fucking
get your cut your legs broke off in his
car accident wheelchair right now yeah I
got your back there in a wheelchair and
you're depressed and you're hungry and
you're in the street you know I thought
you had my back that still has your back
nothing is you're not looking for the
new experience that he's offering you he
isn't having your back means hey I think
you should have a new experience goodbye
legs wheelchair what are you gonna do
buddy cuz i know you'll grow stronger
through this experience I know there are
beautiful things on the horizon through
this experiences there always are so but
now you're upset because you thought i
was going to uh to steer that car out of
the way so you can get in car accident
yeah that's your fault you were that you
were attached to some outcome that you
expected yeah see now some people might
say that's just a delusional mindset
that's pure positivity and that the
world is really chaos for me I've just
had so many coincidences in my life and
ups and downs and I'm all my downs like
if I get into a car crash or something
like just for example the downs it's
always like there's some hidden lessons
in there so it's because what you're
doing is you might pull it it down but
what you're doing is you're being
sensitive because you can label
something good or bad but you can also
make something that's labeled bad good
yeah so people would be like oh yeah
you're a positive thinker not
necessarily I just know that I could
choose how I'm going to respond to every
circumstance you see have you ever read
uh Victor Frankel's a man's search for
me no leave the Holocaust do you use the
Jew in Nazi Germany and he found
enlightenment happiness joy he
experienced while in a concentration
camp and he talks with such poetic
potency about that experience that you
would be that you could read it and do
it Wow
wish I was in the concentration camp
with you so beautiful it's his choice to
have felt that way about it you like to
called it bad but he turned it good
that's crazy do you have any fears in
life right now anything I don't know I
mean I I don't think so Barrick see
there are things that are Eric to me put
it this way the other day that I have
certain preferences but I have no
attachments and it goes you know good or
bad so fear would be like an attachment
to do not experience in certain things
and I wouldn't want to experience my
family dying do you see so that's an
attachment so I have a preference I
preferences i prefer to watch my
children grow up and have grandchildren
you see what I'm saying but I'm not
attached to it such that I'm fearful
that it'll be taken away from me because
if a part of this dance means well you
know one of your children is gonna get
sick cancer died well there's a part of
the dance and I'm not afraid of thats
going to happen again i have a
preference I'd rather that not happen
but about beautiful if it does yeah
gotcha well put um I really liked how
you uh I remember like a month ago you
uploaded a video about girlfriends dad
is an ass or something and then you took
which is a great yeah but then you took
the video down re uploaded a new
a day later saying that the place where
you were coming from was you weren't
quite coming from the best place in the
first video and I was wondering I'm just
starting to make these vlog videos what
advice do you have about making these
vlog videos do like I do my best work
when I'm not in my head and I know I'm
not in my head because I'm feeling and
using my body when I talk animated I've
been body my words that means they're
more true if I'm coming from if I'm
thinking too much it's the different
types of thinking too because a lot of
times I'll pause in my videos and I'll
look do this and that means I'm trying
to get out the way and I'm trying to
channel what needs to be said as opposed
to trying to memorize something that I
should be saying or pandering to a
particular ideal that the audience might
have see if you if you're if you're
truly going to be controversial which is
always entertaining you've got to truly
be yourself and if you're answering
questions with the intent to pacify a
particular ideal the audience has then
it's wrong then you have done it right
even though everyone gives you a round
of applause it's not it wasn't a true
answer it didn't come from you it came
from information or it came from
prejudice came from a biases and ideas
so when i reuploaded the video I you
know I realized like you know past
couple weeks I've been making videos
from my head and I need to go back to my
body and I you know I did some
meditation and you know just start
breathing deeply I was like okay cool
get back to my body and then I
represented the video is a more in a
more real way that this is the way I'm
talking right now this is real doesn't
mean it's right doesn't mean it's wrong
doesn't mean you'll like it better yeah
it's just it's coming from me now yeah
and that always feels better awesome huh
yeah I feel like there's so many people
are giving advice on that
like just blogs google search you could
google search anything you can find
answers to anything but there's so many
internet marketers marketers out there
there's so many people on the forum so
you probably people ask for advice and
people give them advice but as what
you're getting and so what I like trying
to find when I'm getting advice is to
find someone new who who's genuine he
was speaking from their heart does
that's the best way to figure out it's a
good advice in my opinion if it's
genuine I got on the whole weight with
you just happens also i was recording a
video just now now sigh just write about
that stop going to your head put all the
answers and go to your heart and go to
your gut go to your body for the answers
and a lot of times the heart and the gut
isn't pretty it doesn't give you that
one that everyone is going to applaud at
it's not going to give you the one that
everyone's that are not it says say yes
you're right but it's going to give you
the one that's authentic because it
actually comes from you so it also means
that you're along with your authenticity
is going to come some confusion from
others and an anger frustration even
crucifixion by others because they just
don't get it you know I think that's one
of Jesus's last word forgive them father
cuz they just don't fuckin get ya
basically that's what he's dead he's
like look they just don't get they're
crucifying me right now and that's
really what's gonna happen you're going
to get crucified because they just don't
fucking get it yeah which is part of the
fun it's fun to have people hating on
you it's even more fun when you find
that you know those needles in a
haystack that do get you know yeah it
was yeah it's like when I find someone
who also like was really in the wrong
pollen like look like a yak Chiek
understand there's like a real Gaia out
there that make changes that it's not
just felt like inverse Democrat there's
actually some real people
there there's a there's a couple of
different types of people you're going
to find in your audience and one of them
they use a term fanboy you know got
bangle Elliot's fanboys I resent that
not just for the people that watch my
videos I resent the term completely
because I hope that when I speak it's
not not to tell you anything it's simply
to awaken you to something that's
already in you and I don't want you to
agree with me because you want to be my
fanboy I don't want you to say yes
everything Elliot says it's right and
true I want you to agree with me because
you feel it inside you that oh my god
like when when he said something well it
says something it touched me like I feel
it that's when you know something is
true you feel it you don't eat it you
didn't read it somewhere in a matched up
that's usually what the people who argue
with me the most are like well that
didn't match up with the book that I
read or didn't match up with my parents
said it didn't match up with my religion
doesn't match up with the school yeah
but when you feel something in you it's
now yours you just embodied it right so
le ho said something you didn't agree
with me you felt that and that means all
i'm doing is inviting you to awaken to
your own genius yeah I feel like lots of
successful people and people just kind
of put them on a pedestal and
successfully about a bunch of yes men
that just surround them that but it
makes me retarded they'll be like oh
great advice like like maybe it was
something you could do is just make a
video we give you the most worst advice
you possibly can yeah just make it
really obvious and just like do
experiment to see it like they're going
to be some people that are just like yes
that's the best thing you've ever said
let me read configuration yeah like
really yeah it's like guys just doing
this prove a point that like don't
blindly listen to me don't blame listen
to anyone know what do you feel and our
feelings are never wrong because
sometimes I might say something that
perhaps is is authentic genuine comes
from me it's true and I truly believe
that this idea of truth is purely
subjective you know we have science tell
us a lot of things that we have taught
science to like repeat science but
truth is always subjective if you think
Jesus Christ rose from the dead and
walked on water that's your truth dude I
mean you don't need Sciences to tell you
yes or no if you believe it all right no
it's not my business to to dabble with
that you know but if i say something
think that awakens of feeling in you
often times there's cognitive dissonance
associate with it because it takes a
stab at your your deeply held belief so
if i say something about your religion
yeah let's say I challenged that lets
people go back with it people are you
immediately you're you're gonna go to
your body the very first response is
going to be visceral you just touched my
body the asshole usually tightens up
these are the typical physical responses
to stress your become a tight ass anus
tightened up belly's it tightens up
breathing stops reaching down here into
your pelvic floor shoulders hiked up
heart rate goes up so if you notice
those things happening physiologically
within you i just touched you and
because you got a visceral response to
something that I that challenges your
rules deeply held beliefs means you had
better explore that one dude yeah look
into that one because if now here's the
thing if I didn't touch your body if I
say something and you you're so
conditioned in a way you don't feel
anything and you just nod your head
you're like though that guy's an idiot
click off then it's like well then
you're a lost cause someone who won't
even argue with you someone who just
says no you're an idiot and they go away
who it's because they haven't they had
an embodied what you said they're in a
lack of better terms or a lost cause
they're not your person but someone who
you touch a visceral level and they're
like no no they're like no you're wrong
you're wrong and I'm angry and I want to
tell you why and I'm gonna spit it all
out over the keyboard that is probably
one of your best fans in the making
because if they are courageous enough to
explore that feeling besides you you
know it's not about you that violate
host if they explore that feeling on
their own and they come to a new
realization because they were curious
enough about that gut reaction they'll
come back later and they're like you
know I hated you at first I couldn't
stand you I thought you were full of
ships and I thought you were meathead
this the all types of stuff people say
to me this is my most common testimonial
response my first met you I hated you
ever first watch your video I couldn't
stand you then the longer I watched and
the more I thought and the more I kind
of mulled over the things you said the
more I came to realize there is
something being said here this guy's
making sense and now I love you and it's
only because of your courage to have
explored that feeling that I gave you
you feel really bad when I'm saying this
right now you want to rip my face off
good you're feeling something and go
explore it come back later that's that's
a sensitive person that's a person who's
like hey looking good for you but
someone who's like dick head moves on
like that yeah great planet you've
probably gotten like some pretty crazy
in boxes huh yeah yeah some of the stuff
people well I'm I'm gonna use the word
blessed but I know it's a fucking dance
not like God just threw this shit my lap
um but I'm blessed to have ninety eight
percent of the correspondence that
people have with me is positive you know
there are a handful of people that are
just like freaked out weirded out they
say things that are just like boy you're
superstitious and you've got
superstitious scientific people you got
superstitious religious people there the
two words into the spectrum yeah what
ninety-eight percent of it is is
positive it's if it's not needy it's a
positive safe nice hey dude I actually
have another call the guys trying to get
through right now not tonight promise to
do a call at one thirty this was fun yo
send me uh let me know when the
recording is up not jealous onion email
no I like this this was a good
conversation right away yeah thank you
for dinner huh I
very good take care yes you're the other
dream characters over here the whole
dream world and while you're in the
dream it feels so real like that you're
the character and then suddenly you wake
up and you realize you're actually the
whole dream world and to it though
that's such a fun thought it's also mmm