we've got a question from our buddy here
who's been living with his girlfriend
for four years but recently they've been
having some rough times and they're on a
break he says since I've made some
mistakes in the past that's caused some
damage some hurt
essentially he wanted her to work out he
loves working out loves training and he
invited her a few times probably not in
the nicest way that she should train get
your fat ass in the gym bitch something
like that and women don't like that I
don't think anybody likes that but
anyway he sees the wrong that he's done
he's like look I just love working out
and I invited her to go and work out and
stuff she took offense to it and it's
they've been together for four years so
apparently this was very hurtful for her
because she wanted to take a break the
thing is to also and he recognizes this
that uh that women one of the most
important things for women probably the
most important thing for them because
I've got daughters and I see it in them
and they're young yeah not even my
oldest is nine years old they want to be
desired
it's just an innate quality of the
feminine because the feminine is the
receiver is the receiving end of this
sexual dichotomy they want to feel worth
being brought they want to feel as if
they're they're approachable they want
to feel as if somebody wants to go into
them right that's that's why it's very
important for them their appearance is
very important to them in many instances
then what they need to feel as if
they're feminine enough to draw in
masculine energy and when you say things
to women like you know why don't you go
to the gym and start working out they
they start to feel as if they're not
desirable women want to feel desirable
no matter what make your woman feel as
if you desire her because a part of you
does you might be caught up Ito wise and
what she should look like and and he
leads to this but really he does desire
her he does love her make every effort
man I'm giving you guys this advice and
carry it with you to the days of your
death make a woman feel desired
it's the most it's really powerful
anyway so he wants to prove his love to
her that's what he says he loves her
wants her back should I find a way to
prove my love should I let her go see
what happens down the road a little bit
of both actually do you think she may
give me another chance in the future
cool okay so when I say a little bit of
both what I'm going to invite you to do
and share a resource with you and some
ideas and you're going to do your best
to prove your love really love is one of
these things you can't really prove you
can behave in a loving way towards an
individual and open yourself
energetically to them by saying I love
you looking them in their eyes and
sharing your your body with them and I
don't mean just sex when I say sharing
your body I mean standing with an open
posture giving her your heart literally
and figuratively and you're gonna have
to let her go and I'll tell you what I
mean in a moment so the first part of
the equation is this is a really good
book I enjoyed reading this book several
years ago it's called the five love
languages how to express heartfelt
commitment to your mate right and that's
really what it is it's not how to prove
your love but it's how to express
heartfelt commitment to your name now
I'm gonna go very quickly over the five
love languages because you might find
that through trial and error I mean
you've been with the one for four years
but there's a particular language that
she wants to receive love through and
you it would be it would be advantageous
to you in your relationship to begin
approaching her from that place the five
love languages I'll just tell you what
they are really quickly from the index
of the book anybody I'd write anybody
who's who's in a relationship that they
would like to keep together to get the
book now it's not all-encompassing it's
not the end-all be-all but it gives you
a perspective through which you can
share your experience of love with
another individual so ah you probably
can't see this here but the very first
one is words of affirmation the second
one is quality time third receive
gifts forth acts of service and five
physical touch those are the five
affirmations quality time receiving
gifts acts of service and physical touch
and the one that we like to receive the
most is usually the one that we tend to
give out the most see so Abbey's five
you can imagine which one I am
words of affirmation I love people
through my words this is why I make
these videos this is how I share my love
with you see I'm loving you guys also in
the way that I like to receive love and
my wife understands that I might the
people in my world understand that like
Elliot likes to be offered words of
affirmation he likes to be told you're
doing a good job Elliot keep up the good
work it's just for whatever reason based
on my experiences as a child and my
genetic makeup I enjoy receiving words
of affirmation if somebody affirms me
verbally I feel as if they're loving me
it's just you know the way it is I don't
want gifts quality time is important but
not so important acts of service you
know I can usually do what I need to do
physical touch well of course but that's
kind of a given for most guys so I speak
this way to the people that I love and
and and a lot of them receive it you
know my friends part of the reason why
I'm sure they hang out with me because I
talk the way I talk I speak with them in
affirming ways or enlightening ways and
I do the same to my wife but it's not
her love language
she needs to be felt she needs to feel
as if she's desirable and the way she
really ends up feeling desirable is when
I perform acts of service now I'm not
talking about Connie Lingus right is
that the scientific word I guess for
oral sex acts of service it's not that
kind of act of service it's like if I do
the fucking dishes dude if I do the
dishes my wife is like putty in my hands
or knees get all weak and she's like oh
she good like she's she gets excited let
me put it that way if I wash the fucking
dishes so I know that if I want to get
the best response for my wife I want her
to feed
love to feel desired I wash the dishes
or i clean something or I don't know I'm
not the greatest handyman around the
house but like I'll change the lightbulb
or something and she feels feels look
very simple I don't get it because to me
I just want you to tell me you love me
you know I want to talk about it so
you've been with this woman for three
years I think three or four years you
know what she likes
does she like gifts some people like
gifts because she like to be touched
quality time I think is a big one for
women I think that's a really big one
receiving gifts acts of service quality
time I think those three are are the
more feminine ones quality time gifts
and acts of service but anyway I'd
invite you to read the book dude and the
other end of the spectrum here the other
half of my piece of advice here is not
to be caught up in the results I may
have said this in a video earlier this
week or coming up but you do have to
sort of let go because if you go about
the acts of service let's say you know
you clean the house she still lives with
you you clean the house and you're
sitting there like oh man I clean the
house she's gonna be so happy he's gonna
come and give me a hug we're gonna be be
happy again everything's gonna be good
you set yourself up for a fucking
letdown dude okay you can you can't
invest in the outcome you can't invest
in the result especially if it involves
another person's response to your
behavior you do it because you love her
you see now you're showing her that you
love her unconditionally most people
have a condition based on their love
right well I did the dishes where's my a
blowjob right no you can't do it that
way you do the dishes because you love
her and that's how you strengthen or
repair the relationship you do the
things out of the pure sentiment of love
not to control not to manipulate not to
really not to receive back in any way
shape or form we don't do kind things to
people because we want something back we
do it because we love doing it for them
find out her
language of love perform it for her
unconditionally and often and don't be
attached to the result you will be an
aggressive man in your activity but
you'll be tender and you're allowing her
to open back up to you
done