how to release sexual energy without
masturbation or sex so our friend Mike
is 24 years old recently discovered the
no FAP Theory movement that basically
says no porn and no masturbation gives
you superpowers and fixes some of your
issues says he tried this for three
weeks and it seems to have worked I'm
very confident feel better and flirt
with girls more social grounded and
aggressive cool man but I have no
girlfriend so what can I do to release
this sexual energy stored inside my body
in mind I feel like it's not so healthy
to hold on to this right but at the same
time I noticed that if I do masturbate I
immediately feel less confident and
social for a couple days you know give
me some support here so the very first
thing is I'm not an expert in this
particular area although I have dabbled
with a few different ideas and I want to
share a resource with you called Qigong
meditation but specifically embryonic
breathing fascinating fascinating book
and I read this in conjunction with a
lot of the works of Alice and alone when
I was studying this very feverishly
about a year and a half ago and this
whole concept of bioenergy Chi they
would call it in this particular
language Chinese medicine but um
Alexander Lowen called it bioenergy and
and basically it's how the energies in
your body you know sexual energy you say
how the sexual energies move throughout
your body is really it's the root of the
energies it's our most primal base
energy how they move throughout the body
and how they are obstructed in many ways
how their flow could be increased and
and how it's all linked to our ability
to breathe so the muscular system I talk
a lot about this how the muscular system
breathing and the energies of the body
are all linked together right and you're
experiencing this right because it's my
it could sound all very new age and
foo-foo and bullshitty but you're
experiencing it right you don't jerk off
and all of a sudden you're a different
person right what is that right can you
can you pinpoint that down to a specific
molecule or something and and even then
you know it's still it's very mystical
right this is this idea of human energy
bioenergy Qi whatever you want to call
it
very mystical can't be pinned down but
can be experienced and that's what's
important
grab this book and and what you're going
to learn in this book and it's very like
you're going to need like a notebook in
and a highlighter with you and you're
gonna have to like because there's so
many this is written in in like ancient
Chinese context and and they use so many
different metaphors and poetic words to
describe things the part of the reason
why I like reading lowens work is
because it's kind of the same stuff but
it uses like Western scientific type
language as opposed to like you know so
some of the words and some of the things
they use to describe these ideas or like
mystical heavens water paths they just
look water paths false dawn Tien and
things of that nature but anyway I'm
sorry anyway this is a description of
what or this is a diagram that kind of
depicts what I experienced and I'll give
you a brief overview of what you're
going to learn with this embryonic
breathing what you're going to
experience with the sexual energy in
your body when I began deep breathing
down into my lower Dante and
specifically or your alot of the good
feelings come from pulsation a lot of
your sexual feeling and sexual energy is
stimulated by the pulsation of your
prostate okay and that's kind of like up
in your asshole
it's like it's not really your dick it's
a little bit deeper than your balls it's
underneath like where your perineum is
straight up from there that's why when
you go get like your colon check
doctor sticks his finger in your ass and
there's no wonder so many of us have you
know dysfunctional colons as we get
older because a lot of these ideas are
you know too silly for people to study
but anyway I began practicing this
embryonic breathing along with my
bioenergetics and what I discovered was
that you can not necessarily release
that actual sexual energy in the same
way that you know you ejaculate but what
you do what you can do is you can move
it through the body in that circular
fashion that I showed you that picture
that I showed you up the back and down
the front of the body and it's almost
like a sick Euler
orgasm that doesn't require physical
release it's incredible I the only way I
could really have you truly understand
it to experiencing so study the things
I'm sharing with you if it's that it
fascinating to you what it looked like
specifically was I remember laying on a
bed my my feet together my legs spread
almost like a butterfly stretch but I'm
laying both hands not on my balls but
down like in front of them right fingers
spread mouth wide and breathing deep
into my balls right fuck breathing into
my balls but in such a way that the
stimulation the energy that stimulates
that particular area created an erection
in me but it wasn't like a stiff I need
to ejaculate erection it was more of a
there's energy moving in your body type
erection and I had no desire for sex or
or jerking off it just felt like a good
feeling in my body and I was able to
through the concentration through the
meditation that you learned in this book
and you know if you continue to follow
some of the resources I share with you
cause the sexual energy to move up so I
felt like an orgasm or like chilling in
my body through my face I mean not
feeling in your face when you're orgasm
like pins and needles as I breathe and
I'm kind of getting it right now because
I'm talking about it almost like chills
in your body and it was like this
circling cycling of the sexual energy
throughout my body and I got up but I
felt like a million bucks I got up I
felt like incredible I did this just a
handful of times and I stopped doing it
I don't know why I guess I just didn't
have the time you know but I'd still
participate in many different other
exercises should do this Morgan but um
but I have sex a lot but anyway at that
time I wasn't cuz I was experimenting
with something because then the book it
tells you you know experiment with not
ejaculated and how do you not ejaculate
by orgasm and it's through the methods
that I'm sharing with you right now
another good book by um Chia I think is
the guy's last name but anyway uh it's
called the multi-orgasmic
and I believe that's another good book
it's this Chinese Qigong Chi energy type
type type stuff I know some of you guys
are gonna completely tune out when I
talk about this shit but hey let go
experience that try it yourself if
you're of the no fad mindset and you see
the power in it also understand that
it's not new it's an ancient ancient
practice that the people of the east
turned into a science and they call it
Qi Gong or Qi work um you know and then
things of that nature so that's a dude
fascinating stuff again I'm no expert
I've just you know I dabble with a lot
of different things that I find
fascinating I experienced it and and
pass it on to you so go look into that
buddy
good luck