so today we have a question from our 20
year old friend Brandon who's in medical
school he's getting ready for exams
right now and he's studying hard but
it's also his girlfriend's prom she's in
high school and he's decided to set that
down for a moment simply so that he can
make some space for the woman that he
loves no big deal
but there are a few months there when
there were you know on rocky ground when
his girlfriend decided to find a fuck
buddy I guess you know Brandon is in
college he's still in high school some
dude wanted to bang her and she was like
cool so they you know they were fuck
buddies that's what he calls him and uh
and that had passed but now that Brandon
needs to go to her his girlfriend's prom
the fuck buddy who by the way had been
sort of disrespectful to Brandon at one
point by making moves on his girlfriend
when they had gotten back together again
so Brandon has all types of really bad
feelings towards this fuck buddy and now
he's going to have to face him in prom
at the prom in high school not only that
this is where he really this just burns
him up his girlfriend still friends with
the fuck-buddy and they want to take
group pictures together
Brandon's freaking the fuck out because
he knows that he's going to stand with
his girlfriend in a picture where the
fuck buddies is somewhere behind him or
next to him and he ain't having it he
don't feel too good about that and he
wonders how do I go about this I want to
love my girlfriend I want to be with her
I want to go to the prom and support her
in this particular way but I cannot
stand to be in the same room much less
the same picture with this man who had
disrespected me and also was fucking my
girlfriend I get it he doesn't want to
be a tyrant he says that you know I
don't own my girlfriend she makes her
own decisions she's a grown woman but
it's hurting my heart to proceed in this
fashion
I get it man and here is where I'm going
to begin our conversation what you're
looking for on the outside is respect
and when I use that respect if there are
so many associations with it because
it's a loaded term it's one that you
know you find in the Bible and it's like
women respect your men and it sounds
almost as if you should bow down to them
so this idea of respect is son
sort of like an external bowing down
someone else shall bow down to me right
me and my wife actually talked about
this quite often and I say to her baby I
respect the shit out of you she's like I
know it's funny because I respect you so
much and we have in mutual admiration
for one another we have personal dignity
and mutual admiration respect for one
another
but because the word is so loaded and
when you know if Colleen goes and hangs
out with her friends and says hey I
respect Elliott it almost sounds like
what is he beating you so we when we
have conversations with people who just
don't understand the dynamics of
sexuality we she's chosen to use the
word honor and I just wanted to lay that
out there so that when you hear me say
respect because this is going to be the
the focal point of our conversation I
want you to every once in a while
replace it with the term honor because
that's really what it is you're honoring
yourself and others it's just another
way it's a deep and profound respect but
it's another way to describe it but
doesn't have the associations with
domination because it's not about
domination now you want your girlfriend
to respect or honor your what's
happening in you with regard to the
circumstance you would like for her to
not take pictures with this guy I know
you'd like for that not to happen you'd
like for her to respect your feelings
and choices in this circumstance but you
don't want to be a tyrant and you will
be a tyrant if you give her an ultimatum
so I mean it's a very difficult
situation you're in and I'm just
I'm painting the picture for how
challenging this is if you say to her
well you know what I'm not going to come
to the prom if we take pictures with
this guy your ex fucks book fuck buddy
because I don't like this you can go
angry and resentful to the whole
situation and in fact if you do go and
take the pictures with him and her
you're going to be angry and resentful
for a long time because you didn't
respect yourself and she didn't respect
you and the guy who disrespected you is
there also when you got these fucking
pictures and she's let's say you guys
have children one day you say you get
married whatever the case may be these
pictures will surface and the animosity
will grow will be it'll be a disgusting
stain on your relationship so what do
you do if you decide to pout and do it
anyway you're screwed if you decide to
be a tyrant and say no you're screwed
because now you're you know you're not
you're not being a nice guy you're stuck
and that is why our conversation is
going to revolve around a special kind
of respect the kind of respect that
demands no not demands it's wrong word
commands respect I hope you see the
difference because a demanding of
respect means you shout a commanding of
respect means I have so we will call
this self respect you command respect
when you have respect do you see that's
how you command things you can't be in
not in possession of something and
command it you can demand something
you're not in possession of but that's
an empty place to come from and the only
way to command something is to own it to
embody it and that is where we'll begin
my friend self-respect now I know many
of you watching these videos and I knew
yourself my friend Brandon you might be
waiting for Elliot's tip trick tactic
what words to say how to go about it but
that won't happen in this video because
as I've often said everything that you
do is a reflection of who you are
meaning to people could say the same
thing make the same choice and one wins
and the other loses I can tell you well
you know what you need to do you need to
tell her no we're not taking those
pictures now that could go two ways that
can go she's gonna say yes Brandon I
honor your choice I respect you and I
will move with you in this way and be
nice wouldn't it or it could go fuck you
Brandon you think you owe me you think
you're in charge you think you could
tell me what to do you can't get over
this petty bullshit that happened years
ago grow up that be fucked up but both
people said the same thing what you get
from other people are in a respect or
anger frustration mmm
dishonorable reflection what you get
from people is a mirror reflection of
who you are the world is your mirror it
doesn't matter what you present to the
mirror what matters is who's presenting
to the mirror I hope you understand this
it's not about what you do it's not
about what you say it's about who you
are and if you want honorable behavior
reflected back to you
you want respectable behavior reflected
back to you you've got to own your own
dignity and self-respect
it's not the answer I think most of you
were expecting or if you've been
watching my videos long enough you get
what I'm saying so I won't reiterate I
think you understand or you should
reflect on it if you will how do you
possess own and then command the respect
you're looking for there are two very
important parts to this two extremely
potent parts and if you can learn to
embody this these ideas and infuse them
into your character and into your
lifestyle I'm not saying that every I'm
not saying that everything is going to
work out the way you want it to work out
and I'm not saying this circumstance is
going to wait work out the way you want
it to work out but you will be in
possession of one of the most powerful
mastery tools at your disposal so listen
closely number one to develop your own
self respect you've got to look at
yourself and respect yourself not just
through conversation in other words
saying to yourself I respect myself I
respect myself I respect myself
you've got to embody that's what the
word means in body self respect meaning
you've got to get your body your
emotions involved in the brain washing
in the academics a brainwashing because
we think it's up here but it's down here
to the nervous system to the autonomic
nervous system washing
so when you look in the mirror and you
look deeply into your eyes and connect
with the eyes of the reflection you see
in the mirror begin to breathe big
because that's how you want to feel
about yourself you want to feel big
about yourself you don't want to feel
small about yourself you want to feel
big make yourself feel big by moving
this particular way like a bird in his
wings expanding his energy I feel my
energy expanding right now Bri this way
maybe 10 times with each time each time
you open up your chest and each time you
let your hands open up and you spread
out this way imagine a ball of potent
love and strong positive vibration
emanating growing and emanating from who
you are I am big
I'm expansive I hold my dignity and
command the self respect whoa I wish you
saw my body when I was doing this shit I
gotta get like a camera that it shows
because this is it this is it guys it's
in your body when you get your body
enrolled in a self respect you eat this
is what I did I'll do it again after
several breaths
I'm gathering the energy I expand my
energy watch what I'm doing and I
possess dignity and I command respect
even as I display this for you
I just embodied that and those of you
who are sensitive probably recognize by
shifting character just now I'm not the
same person my energy is different than
it was right before embodying what I
want this is the magic it's the magical
key to affirmation you know those of you
who've watched that movie the secret and
you say well that's silly you can't just
think good thoughts and the good shit
happens to you you're right the missing
link is action and it isn't just action
meaning now I'm going to go out and do
stuff
I tell myself positive things and I want
to go do stuff mm-hmm
action meaning emotion you've got to
infuse emotion with what you want to
have happen in your life so that you
become the thing that you want you need
to become respectable to command respect
but you can't just say it you do it and
the most beautiful thing is you just
need to do it in front of the mirror
long enough that you feel it in your
body see I get goosebumps when I do this
shit because my body is vibrating with
that shit
learn these techniques that's number one
and number two because the world is your
mirror you only get back what you give
and although you may be in self
possession of respect if you don't give
it away I know this is crazy it's like
la you're telling me to possess this
would also give it away yes both that's
that's life that's the yin-yang dudes
it's it's blackness at is light and
darkness it's all of this I create all
these things when I say that second time
I said it this week I think I'm quoting
Ezekiel in the Old Testament
since speaking from God he says that I
created good I create evil like a great
light I create darkness I create all
these things in other words it's all God
giving away self possessing and giving
away are one thing they may seem
opposite but I guarantee you you'll
experience a growing of your own
self-respect when you respect others
bang I just gave you guys a secret to
success
embody your own self-respect grow that
energy in you and every action that you
take will be infused with it and that's
what the world will give you at the same
time you need to give away your respect
and in giving it away your dignity and
self-respect will grow
and then make your choice
about your girlfriend inner fuck buddy
or any other choice you make in life and
whatever happens happens whether you
like the result or not but a magnificent
thing will happen regardless of the
outcome you will have possessed yourself
the entire way through you will not have
lost yourself like most people do most
people lose themselves in the world the
world grabs them and tosses them in any
direction it feels necessary you make
choices from a grounded self possession
deal with the results and it will always
be good done