hey we got this fun and interesting
question from our buddy 19 years old
just started working out
he's eating right starting to feel his
body is the way he describes it and and
he's excited about the progress he's
making but one thing that he's noticed
is that because he's getting up earlier
and he's exercising and you know
exerting himself in that way he finds
that about halfway through the day he
gets tired and of course it's kind of
normal you're doing more so your body's
going to require more cultivation and
that's fine Thermal National the thing
is he says that he discovered something
really interesting or we had an
experience and he's wondering is this
real he says I got done with my workout
one day earlier this week I got to him
with my workout and I figured I'd go
home and be tired like I typically and
after a long day of becoming the
strongest version to myself and uh on my
way out I noticed a really hot chick I
said to myself you know what I'm feeling
pretty damn confident I'm gonna go and
introduce myself to her he goes and
introduce himself to his hot girl on his
way out of the gym and he says it was a
complete mess completely fell apart you
know he tried his best but like really
she wasn't interested but it didn't
matter because he discovered something
even more important he said I was more
energized for the rest of that day than
I can remember ever being energized
normally I be tired but after subjecting
myself to this dangerous experience by
being courageous with this young girl I
was animated for the rest of the day I
had more energy than ever before Elian
he asked so let me give you a specific
question towards the end of his email
says do you believe that doing things
you're afraid to do makes you feel more
alive and gives you energy well my
friend you've stumbled upon a central
principle of all these videos that I
create and a lot of people think I'm
completely irresponsible and out of my
mind and nuts when I tell young men to
go and do dangerous shit to trust and
the most dangerous thing is to trust
your heart and your heart drew you
towards this girl and what was the
experience a complete fucking
right guess what most of the time when
you're courageous enough to follow your
heart in the beginning and perhaps for
quite some time it's gonna be a complete
fucking mess I know this that's why I
often say you don't take the call to
adventure you don't follow your heart
you don't do the thing that your body is
telling you to do because of what you're
going again you do it because of who
you're gonna become right my friend and
how did you become after experiencing
that dangerous moment by subjecting
yourself to that experience that was
dangerous because mind you stresses
stress regardless there's going to be a
physiological response in your body to
stress regardless if it's you're jumping
out of a helicopter or you're talking to
a hot girl what kind of person will you
afterwards
animated you're more vibrant vital alive
energetic ready to go you're becoming a
stronger version of yourself because of
that and what happens is that the stress
is a unique type of stress and I've
heard it described this way of course
there's stress and there's a
physiological response to the stress but
there's a different color to distress
and you stress now I don't know if you
stress eu stress is an actual word but
the person who shared it with me was
trying to combine the term you for
euphoric right it's euphoric with stress
you stress distress is a kind of nagging
chronic stress where you're constantly
anxious because you can't pay your bills
or you'll never get the career that you
want or you'll never live up to your
daddy's expectations and you go about
life with this nagging distress that
ultimately leads to your demise that
just stresses you out and grows you
older and more degenerated over time
that's where that's the stress that most
people deal with you stress is a
completely different phenomenon there's
a physiological response to it in your
body which is sympathetic that's why
you've got so energetic but it's colored
with euphoria because of what you're
becoming
you just exercise what I believe to be
the iron quality in becoming the
strongest version yourself and
courage and the experience was a
complete mess but you're growing you see
this distress makes you sick and dying
you stress creates growth and that's why
I often say go do dangerous shit right
now because Elliott Hulse is a douchebag
and he's trying to give bad advice to
young men but because I know that when
you jump off that cliff and your only
intention is to fly before you hit the
fucking bottom you're gonna animate all
your vital resources to learn how to fly
on the way down and that's why you have
to jump you know there's a different
type of response to that clip than a lot
of people most people experience and
that is they stare down that cliff their
entire lives until they're like 40 45 50
and the guy they call this midlife
crisis this is when you've committed to
all of the trappings notice that word
trappings trappings trash of the world
now you got a family you've got a
business you got a career you've got a
boss you got tasses they can't jump dude
because you're too trapped by the
trappings of the world now my book I say
you still joke but anyway the point is
but if you stand there you just keep
looking down that cat into that chasm
and it begins you know you reach the
edge of that cliff when you're 25 years
old guess what you're gonna live with
for the next 25 years distress that
kills you because you didn't jump
there's that part of you that's always
tapping you hey dude
motherfucker I told you to jump 20 years
ago you still didn't jump did you how do
you feel about yourself well I've got
$100,000 in my bank account man who
gives a shit
my wife's hot who gives a shit I got
children to take care who gives a shit
you should have jumped when I told you
to jump and now you got to live with it
right that's distress you stressed what
it looked like this is fucking crazy
this doesn't make any sense my heart is
telling me to do it
ooh and you let go into the river of
life and let it carry you where it's
going to carry you and you be okay with
the challenges be okay with the failures
but you will revel in and you will you
will be so overjoyed by the successes so
much more than the successes of the guy
who stood on the cliff and waited all
his successes are traps more money more
problems first of all so don't let the
world ever tell you you need to do
things that make more money that's a lie
right more money you make the more taxes
you pay the more you have to hide it
this is the new one I figured out
because I just I just started making a
little bit of money I grew up poor and
was poor up until maybe two years ago
nobody can tell me you gotta find ways
to hide your money what the fuck am i
what I gotta hide money for it I make
any sense I make it so that I can live
right you gotta hide it that's a fuckin
problem more money more problems oh you
think you need a girlfriend right or you
need a family or you need a career you
need you can't get away from problems
you cannot get away from problems it's
what kind of problems you want to choose
and you can choose the problems or allow
the world to give you their problems
with their trappings or you could jump
off that fucking cliff and create your
own problem and you know what the thing
is with those problems you'll love them
a little bit more because they're yours
you take a little bit more pride in
dealing with them because it's yours and
when you overcome them you not only
receive what would seem as the the gift
on the end of it which over here is we
call that trappings what we're here it's
really a gift it's it's really the
universe or God saying congratulations
brother you exercised your ability to
grow courage to grow commitment to grow
discipline and now you get the gems and
gifts associated with virtue right
sometimes it comes in the form of a nice
car and a nice neighborhood sometimes it
comes and it usually comes from feeling
pee
of mind with yourself you feel good
about yourself
you can sleep well at night knowing that
I listen to my body I listen to my heart
I am doing the right thing for me
regardless of what all the trapped
people told me so that's it my friend
this is kind of a video to assert your
assertion to agree with your assertion
yes do dangerous ships even though the
bitch might have slapped you in your
face do it again and do it again and do
it again
fall in love again and again and again
even if you get your heart broken every
single fucking time learn something from
each experience that's how your wings
actually grow so you can fly but keep
doing it keep doing dangerous shit till
the day you die how do you guys watch my
videos and you know that I've been going
through a bit of a transition here it
was the dangerous fucking thing that I
did I quit my yo Elliot
series on my other channel why because
I'm committed to my growth and growth
only happens through dangerous action if
I stick around doing what the world is
pleased by me doing and is the easy road
even though my heart is telling me
otherwise if I stay on that well-trodden
path that well cut out path and I even
created for myself you see there will be
a lot of distress in my body and I'll
have to face it at some point you know
they say there's a Judgment Day I
believe we faced multiple judgement days
while we're walking on earth I don't
think Judgment Day day comes when we're
dead now you're gonna go to heaven or
you're gonna go to hell judgment right
Jesus is sitting on a big throw no the
judgment today is today Judgment Day is
now and the judgment is going to allow
you to live a life of hell now or to
choose your own Kingdom to live heaven
on earth now I understand and it comes
in the form of personal growth
I'm done