we got a question from one of our
buddies who's uh he's being rejected by
his friends right so apparently he every
time he hangs I asked his buddies to
hang out they're like uh no nevermind
you know maybe some other time and then
he he catches them all hanging out
together ha and he's that guy that they
just keep leaving out it's been
happening for two years he says boy
you've got patients and what somehow you
know what do I do I'm it's summertime
home all by myself and my friends don't
want to hang out with me I can't figure
it out he says every once in a while he
like sneaked into where he knows they're
hanging out and they'll be like they
look at each other like uh he's here
right it's awkward but I tell you what
the fact that you recognize that it's
happening is great because you don't
want to be the guy that doesn't know
that he doesn't know and he shows up
he's like hey what's up guys but they
all hate him and he doesn't realize it
you realize it so you know awareness is
transformative in and of itself that's
cool now the reason why I took your
questions because you're looking at a
guy who got rejected a lot of times I
had friends who were friends that I grew
up with that over time like for some
reason yeah I could I could give you my
ideas about the reason they just didn't
want to hang with me anymore right then
it was like bro we've been friends
forever and it was just like peace you
know they hung out with each other and
they left poor Elliot house by himself
right and and this happened on multiple
occasions because I went I literally you
know in the search for who I was because
I was a big part of my journey growing
up as a kid and and even today that's
why you know my more wrapped up in this
idea of becoming the strongest version
yourself so about discovering yourself
and maximizing your capacity but you
know it's a neurotic because of the
experiences that I've had as a kid
anyway so I went from one end of the
spectrum if I showed you like my friends
from when I was you know I don't want to
say the ages because some of them watch
my videos and a book Eliot you know
they're going to send me like an apology
email probably not but from one stage of
my life to another stage of my like they
were on the other ends of the spectrum I
hung out with everybody and everybody
rejected me I got
checked it on both ends of the spectrum
right I just did not fit in so I took
your question because I can empathize
what do you do well I can only tell you
what I did I got busy working on
becoming a stronger version of myself I
realized one of the things that I
quickly realized early on I was athletic
I was more athletically inclined
stronger and physically superior than
all the kids that I grew up with and you
know most throughout high school my
entire life and I quickly realize like
oh fuck you all up like you know no one
likes me but I kick all your asses so I
started working out and playing football
and I put all of my focus and energy on
developing my skills as an athlete
getting stronger getting bigger getting
faster and getting better at the sport
of football and you know inherent in
playing a sport there comes a you know
comes a new group of friends because you
know you're all the cool thing about
sports is that although you're very
different you know if you've ever been a
part of a sports team it's like you know
they're all the different cliques in
high school are there you know you've
got every walk of life but you all come
together with a common goal because it's
like you know we put our differences
aside we're going to win and you're
focused on something so that allowed
that allowed me to hone my group of
friends bring in a group of friends to
lead a group of people and to use the
gifts that I've been given that I
naturally have to gain influence in
school and socially so that's my
experience it was through sports and
football but I guarantee you bro that
there's something about you that's
magnificent
you know and you're going to have to
work on that and find a group of kids
that appreciate that you know there were
like the drama club kids and then there
were like the artsy kids there were the
kids who smoke pot every day you know
not that I'm telling you to go hang out
the kids a smoke pot every day but there
were definitely groups of kids where you
had a natural inclination towards
because you were naturally gifted in
something that they valued that you can
go and gain influence with you know I
would invite you to play sports because
that's you know it's what I do
but if that's not your inclination find
a group find other cliques of
individuals that you can gain influence
with that you could earn friendships
through because you have a common goal
or a common value clearly the values of
your old friends don't match up with
your values and that's why they're
rejecting you either that or you just
weird
peace