so that was question from our buddy Kyle
who says he receives absolutely no
gratification there's no sense of
gratification associated with sex
anymore as if there ever was beyond the
physical release associated with orgasm
and I do this because most of our
orgasms are not full they're more of a
simple ejaculation that feels sort of
good as it's on its way out as opposed
to a full body experience with another
individual but anyway the point here is
that psychologically energetically
there's there's it's not gratifying at
all so almost like jerking off with
someone else's body he says what's up
with this how do I go about enjoying sex
I mean it seems as if it should be
something that's that there's there's a
lot of emotion and pleasure joy in
experiencing this activity with another
human being
where am i messing up it got me thinking
today actually it's funny I was thinking
about I've been thinking about this for
the past couple weeks some experience
with my wife the other day about a week
ago we were having sex and we finished
in both at the same time right
afterwards we said thank you to each
other now we've never discussed this
we've never philosophize we never
considered it but at that moment when we
both looked at each other and we both
said thank you
at the same time smiled and said thank
you I realize we've been doing this for
like our entire relationship we've been
dating since we were 14 years old and I
don't know where we began doing this but
the end of sex we would say thank you
recently I've been listening again to
the power of myth by Joseph Campbell and
he talks about when primal man you know
our ancestors before civilization as we
know it would kill an animal and eat it
we would offer up gratitude and thanks
for the meat that that animal provided
by giving itself up for our continuing
our own lives for our not only our
pleasure in the eating of the animal but
also in keeping us alive and supporting
us in our activities you know it's
nourishment that comes from this piece
of meat that gives us the energy to go
about our lives and we then create in
with the respect we do it out of this
desire to honor the animal our
activities this is back when things were
sacred right when every act every
everything that we did had a air of
magic mystery and spin-spin sacredness
to it and then we got to situation where
meat came easy and even even the
agrarian cultures-- you know there was
this idea of a prayer praise for the
earth for providing the plants that we
ate we no longer do that to any great
degree and even if we do pray you know
I've got some friends who are Christian
and they to do this before every meal
they're praying to a higher power they
bring to some some form of external
reality an external God out there
somewhere thanking it for the meat or
the grains or the vegetable vegetation
that they're eating with little regard
to the actual meat the animal that it
came from the the earth that provided it
somewhere out there
we're totally detached from engaging in
the raising and the killing of the
animal or the farming of the fruits that
we would eat we're so detached in such a
way that we just stuff our bodies with
this thing right we chew on the meat in
the same way that this lack of grata
for the animal that gave its life for us
it's being present is the same way that
sex has become just a beating of the
meat as opposed to eating of the meat
it's now this individual is not so much
an individual not so much a sow but in
it and it's a body it looks nice boy I'd
like to put my dick in it and you you
fuck you ejaculate and then it's like a
well that's done I think it's the sense
of gratitude but of course you know I
put myself out there too
to be criticized but also perhaps offer
some ideas the sense of gratitude that I
experienced with my wife when we have
sex not even having sex for 20 years
right yeah we just turned 30 for 20
years it's that sense of gratitude that
keeps it gratifying
do you see gratitude and gratification
are synonymous in the same way that most
people who overeat are never fulfilled
because there's no sense of gratitude
associated with the meat that we eat I
think if we begin cultivating a sense of
gratitude for even the small things are
in our life you know they're obviously
there's the eating of food that sustains
us and there's a having of sex that
sustains the race of human beings but
even for the small things like breathing
seeing hearing smelling that will be
much more gratified in the expression of
these things in the partaking of these
things I think there's a comedian I
can't remember his name but he talks
about how we live in the best time where
everything's fucking awesome he says but
nobody's happy and it's not because
things aren't fucking awesome or that
they could be better or they're looking
somewhere else they need to be looking
somewhere else right because it with you
in the sex situation you're probably
like well you know there's fuck this
bitch I got to find one that's going to
gratify my needs gratify this deep
desire this longing for gratification
for feeling embodied for pleasure deep
spiritual pleasure you're going to look
you're going to keep looking I'm just
going to keep fucking all these women
and never really get that gratification
because you're never
extending gratitude towards the
individual that you're partaking in the
act with if you want gratification in
your life you've got to extend gratitude
do you want gratification in your sex
look at the woman I'm not saying that
you need to love her for the rest of
your life
but look her in her eyes and extend a
sense of gratitude for offering a piece
of herself
to you because that's really what it is
in the same way that the animal offers
up its body the woman is offering up her
body to you you might not respect her
but that's a choice she may not be
behaving in a respectable way and you
just want to fuck her because she's hot
but if you want to have any sense of
gratification in your life do it for
yourself and say thank you after having
sex with her body