and finally Elliot what's with your
fucking hair why don't you get a haircut
so your hair tells you a lot about
history the hair the hair of an
individual tells you a lot about their
heritage and I'm coming to this place in
my life where being more authentic with
myself and with my the world that I
influence is growing in potency in my
heart you know I I just had this need to
be as authentic as possible with myself
stop lying you know I think as we as we
age we grow in wisdom the lies that
we've held on to if you're an aware
person growing in wisdom the lies that
you've held on to and the the mass that
you've worn slowly loses its strength
and the real you comes out right and
this is you know you get to watch me do
this because I've been making youtube
videos from you know Lord knows how many
years I've always shaved my head and
from high school on I mean watch a lot
of my old videos bald head bald head
bald head bald head because there was
ashamed of my hair because it's not it's
it's not nappy it's not straight some of
it goes this way some of it goes that
way it flips it squirrels it's all it's
all over the fucking place like I am but
I cut it off because it said that about
me and I was ashamed of it and then I
began maybe two years ago I began
styling it I started putting products in
it then I'd style it and make it look at
a particular ways you know almost
European like so what a lot of times
that's what brown people do you know I'm
a African native European mixed man
brown in this world that's what I call
it you know a lot of times brown and a
lot of black people not all but there's
this tendency to want to measure up in a
European driven world you know it's it's
it's a Commerce driven world based on
European values right and whether we you
want to argue with me or not it is
that's what it is
the system we live in and you know we
find ways to rebel but we also find ways
to fit in so we style ourselves our
behavior our character our clothing our
hair to meet some of those pressures and
in my longing for authenticity and
shrewdness and rawness I've decided that
I'm no longer going to shave off in
shame the crown that makes reference to
the African in my blood and to the
nativeness in my blood into my brownness
I'm not going to style it any longer
either in order to look a particular way
that might be pleasing to some but I'm
going to let it grow wild and free nappy
and ugly and let it move in every
direction that it feels it wants to move
without manipulating it because it comes
from my roots it's Who I am so know this
when you see my new crown it is to make
no statement beyond this that I aim to
be as authentic transparent and real
with myself and I will offer you nothing
less or more than that and this is the
signpost for that sentiment I hope this
video was helpful done