hey another witness the bad person very
soon when it's time but I'm gonna
preface it by my favorite quotes you
probably heard me say it before that
every action is measured by the
sentiment of which it proceeds the most
important thing is your conviction about
what you're going to go do you got to
become the strongest version of you
before you go out there and start or at
least the Omnitrix you know it's never
ending of dynamic but at least have a
firm grip on your journey of becoming
strongest version you before you can
expect to inspire anyone else and when
you're in business I said this before
also it's a transfer of passion really
doesn't we could sail sales it's right I
listen to an audio program by brian
tracy several years ago he says the best
salesman cuz that's what you're going to
become your sale first your sales
because even if you're a great trainer
get all the information everything in
the world and nobody hires you you're
not a trainer you're salesmen tourists
and I think people need understand for
sales to work you've got a transfer
passion
good from me right and and the way it
looks in business is convention your
passion will look like a strong
conviction about what you're offering
now the very thing that you're most
hesitant about which is why would
anybody want to train with me right all
right you ask important questions but
that's the one that I I wanted to work
with first that very er that very
question in you will and that very
hesitation in you that ambiguity within
you is going to color everything you do
every piece of marketing material you
make every conversation you have with a
potential client it's going to be
colored with I'm not too sure about
myself and so I'm giving you shitty
answer if I answer is very similar it is
is I train people in the backyard and if
you don't trade in the backyard and
you're a retard right you got to be
doesn't meet at your Aryan back but it
means your firm Hey look back your
training is where it's at in fact it's
the way with the future and its
historical past you're still training in
air-conditioned gyms with treadmills of
such and such then there's something
wrong with you and then you start
creating good guys and bad guys see
these guys they drink in the backyard
this is what they get is they train with
me this is what's going on and this is
the best shit ever if you want to hang
out those guys
fine but get out it's conviction all
right I see and you can only cultivate
that in yourself that's something that
you're going to have to practice then
you're in it then you can never convince
yourself see what's right aboard it is
we think that like some people have
things you have this distrait gets
character really Oh hurry it was really
good on these Alan boxes listening to
today really everything is just a story
you're telling yourself all right right
you're able to approach the world with a
particular virtue but that virtue is
only a manifestation of a story that
you're telling yourself and we're all
telling ourselves stories all the
clothes you wear if you hang out with
everything about how you want Maggie
life is a story you've told yourself
someone has told you but bottom line
you've accepted so what I'm basically
things you can have to brainwash
yourself and your brain wash yourself
just way everybody else is brainwashing
you with repetition and passion look in
the mirror that sounds crazy I know but
look in the mirror and you look at
yourself and you say to yourself that
back your training is only training that
matters is the training everyone should
do and I'm a maximum backyard training
and a person to become cognitive
dissonance
I'm talking on my cell phone is fucking
weird so there's the old type of
resistance with that resistance is the
same resistance that she experienced
when you open her about you're going to
feel it gently with a visceral level
what happens when that resistance is
broken a brand-new emergence get over
this is cut the discomfort of the
resistance and a brand-new you emergency
you'll breathe deeper was there a step
for you between in all the parts and
stuff to wear your another department
when you're honest you is very easy to
cultivate courage so I'm going to give
you the step right I'm gonna need you
myself and it'll be cool be cool to hear
whether the fact is that you're going to
experience something different what I'm
going to give you the key that a lot of
stuff happen and it's courage i went
from training out of my bag this I mean
this principle applies across the board
to everything it's conviction and
courage I trained to people I work with
my dad and and I realize I was getting
sick and tired of literally driving
across town with a thousand pounds of
sandbags tired barbells like I had a gym
on wheels on in this 1988 fan that my
dad gave me because I didn't have
anything else to drive and it didn't
have windows I want to refrain bringing
on me and I'm just like I'm a warrior
our stomach because the rain will do it
so doing this thing but after a while I
realized okay this is going to go
anywhere I need to jump right to your
you got a point I feel you know I feel
like there is a point where you have to
say okay you know i'm just going to do
this you know it stopped being is
confident about it earlier saying now
really you know I'm gonna do it it
happen zero you got that point I came
out time realized that it's come on yeah
trying to so good get practice you see
so i invite you to recognize with that
point homes and you you like shit when
getting your boots that's when your job
don't wait don't hesitate jump it's
going to look like there's it on paper
it's like you're an asshole why are you
doing it it's not making sense a number
of things are going to happen you're
gonna choke you're going in your boots
the kawaii means it's time to do
something something big is about
happening right something bigs about to
happen that's that cognitive dissonance
quaking in your boots right the missing
that scared that's when you vibrate
something's about to explode you feel
that waiting you gotta go whatever it
takes just doing about how bad
hey a number of things going to happen
number one you're going to be you're
gonna practice courage you know I can do
it and once you practice courage you can
do it again do it again do it again do
it again takes private case it's
exercise you're exercising your courage
number two it might fail that would be
great if it fails because it's just
discard one way it doesn't work be
prepared to fail I was very prepared of
that I even had a failure plan which is
like a little weird because it's like
you know the whole idea failures you
don't know what to have plans with a
friend level plane or failures and my
plan was oh yeah I'm not going back to a
job i live in florida they're migrant
workers that they pay to take origins I
can do that because I was not going back
to make respect of the job picking
oranges right so if you're developing an
app to the courage you've just learned
how to don't work and that's essentially
it is practicing your courage and being
okay with failure because if you keep
knocking on doors eventually what will
open I only have a blueprint I don't
have a definitive answer I have
encouraged me for you when you feel
scared go do that thing whatever happens
good for you when you were standing
around the man when I was scared what i
did was i decided to open budget so when
you hit story about the open budget
because it sounds just like
I'm encouraging you to do I had a
mortgage which function the hand since
2007 you know the banks will get any way
they shouldn't give me a bunch before
it's not important I had my wife and my
first order that i started my business I
mean everything was like on shaky ground
and I was like okay and I don't even
have any money on the clients privates
welcome back across town and it was time
to do something else that like all that
shit is quaking so uh boy is funny like
credit it's an interesting thing the way
we played this one he gave the country
but anyway credit grows it was still
sending me these blank checks who gives
me a blade like really actually got my
check I got a blank bucking chain and
probably buddy check out and it paid for
my first three months at my gym and it
was just a minute which was a garage it
was in a nice garage you know we had
feral cats everywhere crackheads coming
and
really nice ladies that if you paid them
right now Mike a blowjob I'm saying they
were it wasn't nice but it was like he's
mine you see and I used to credit cards
first a month if a business analyst came
and looked at what should have been my
books he would have been like okay kid
you're retired like making sense you're
so the bad idea and long story short
tada Karia you see that would have
happened if I if I just didn't say
fucking now i had to pay back ninety
thousand dollars in credit card debt I
had to get out of the mortgage there was
like a lot of tough tough times but I'm
willing to go through
we have money saved up you don't have
any money pretend like you have money
ask somebody for money show up and be
like it makes something up I make it to
the Make It Right see you laughing does
that accessories got great figure it out
it's funny because when you're under
pressure your your many like your idea
is magical my my best ideas came from
days was like okay Colin have any money
for rent well you better go figure it
out cool and my old magnificent ideas to
them and it was like bang I did it so I
kind of almost thrive on like I feel
good you put yourself in that pressure
situation get comfortable all the life
Camping's actually it's interesting and
fun it's an adventure if you keep
looking for dangerous shit to do you
know because the many stuff getting
comfortable it's like maybe I'm just
arrived it's like it's just take some
comfort let's go play some games and it
usually is a gamble but like that's
where that's what magic lies in the game
like this like literally this is a
gamble I'm standing up here and i am a
little fuck i'm gonna say you guys paden
come here than 50 you here that's like
understand little all over the place I
don't know what I Miss Emma what's good
you know what's gonna happen looks like
that's why I drive so i invite you start
playing that game you know do what
you're doing and then just throw
yourself off to click see you can fly
you figure it out you let the ground
it's not over again on the next life you
see is that helpful through what
or courage tactics strategies blueprints
useless courage you can make anything
happen you do it your way you come back
to me three years from now bug guess
what this now I did wow that's that's me
how'd you do it courage cat it did you
practice certified crazy fear looking
for
that is a pedal