you've heard of the Yamamoto water
experiment yeah familiar would like the
crystals I see staying fucking to the
crystal if I love you to the crystals
infinitely right obviously as a
experiment is a it's been criticized by
the scientific community live but um
would you agree there is some power in
certain in certain words and certain
thoughts because I feel like for me for
example and I've suffered when I don't
mind telling you this I trust you in a
weird way don't like that hey the church
was wrong but wasn't it yes mr. was um
hey I'm sale oh yeah yeah I have this
thing where I'll feel on top of freaking
world on one minute and all it takes is
somebody to somebody it could be anybody
to say a comment that's
counterproductive in my I guess
self-esteem will go from here all the
way down the fuck here and you would
side with me so he'll know it won't do
something cool crazy in the gym will
break like a personal record I'll feel
really good and then I'm facebook i'm
telling i'm doing i feel like shit
somebody cuz somebody's to be played
into somebody deflated me or I saw this
or you know just it could be anything
didn't you tell me earlier that were
like me you struggle dolphin especially
as a kid will what are you I yea sorry
identity and when you don't know what
you are you rely on other people that
tell us you are you know and we all get
we are from the world we like to grow up
in New York or to kind of segregation
yet Irish gated the Jewish
in Porto Rican stations and you knew
what you were because they told you your
ancient watch nice to talk to each other
that wish i can speak like that lations
kids worry kid but when you don't fit it
and you're looking around for what I am
if you start to grasp you start to hold
on to what am I and if somebody says you
in a big head you will quickly have an
energetic effect on you you'll quickly
feel as if I have a dick to this day if
I am not mindful as I make youtube
videos so I've subject myself to the
world or criticism to this day if I
really comment sometimes that's like
Elliot you're a pseudoscience is quack
retard not a lot book anyway mrs. to you
i will feel bad about myself and
probably like so fourteen-year-old kid
agree just become couch watching see
much Bob before all that place type of
all jet really you don't say Here I am
that'd be like you know second-guessing
myself your best bet number one it is
possible is to stay away from criticism
just stay with someone who you know is
going to put you down I hope I just
don't recon I don't do it if there's
somebody that you know does this to you
just don't go near them stay away from
them also get very aware with the
specific criticisms that Bobby because
there are some criticisms is just like
but then there's this beautiful
this that gets me be very aware of what
that is so that when you see it coming
you can you can prepare oh I see this
one coming so I hope that's helpful for
you the thing is it like we all wrestle
it's nice to say and it's nice million
all says ignore everybody just don't pay
attention anybody do your own thing but
it's still about and it's still a matter
of being aware of where you're going to
receive that which is going to dethrone
you but all your air out and how to deal
with it actually comes if you find that
your you sink once you've gotten that
bad feedback and know that it's your
fault that has nothing that person or
what they say you're choosing now to
give power to that person's birth you
gave them that they want they deflated
you that blows Mickey angry enough to go
back to build yourself back up it's like
that person verbally rape too seriously
they just took Lee just took life would
it help to I guess build myself up if I
found out where I was acquired in the
answers like I told you I had a Spanish
father or Venezuela mother I was don't
worry about it altered it's like all
these different things you know the
English are pulling me in Spanish no it
doesn't that none of that matters all
those are all other forms and thickness
of our vaccination you've got same arm
same set of balls brain in your head as
the blackest black guy and as the
whitest white guy we're all the same
that regard those are just labels that
we use in order to 95 equal to places
that we know how to address them oh
you're this so I deal with you you're
that know what you are can't figure me
out I stop trying to be myself out and I
love dance with people try to figure me
out oh you think that's what I am good
about fully right now show you them
and it goes beyond we look like it going
it's also associated how you carry
yourself the things that you say the
things that you do the things that you
think that we serve the world oh you
think even religion philosophy oh I'm
pro pro life no ping yung that's a pro
choice doesn't it doesn't matter your
day habit for all day now don't let
anybody box you in that's what gear
takes people today each I possibly in
aren't you
you take out they got smart writing
think I'm smart intelligent well-spoken
I'm gonna fucking speak like a nigga
right now right oh you didn't like that
maybe really look at a couple right I'm
come back and we'll just be like ice
time make it more coffee that's me desk
all talk down Elias