today so I got this question here from
our buddy Chris Murphy he says that uh
his job is destroying his body so he
works for ups and this sounds crazy he
basically he gets these truckloads that
come in with boxes that look way up to
120 pounds maximum but anyway the whole
thing is he says he's roughly picking up
roughly a thousand an hour or one
package every three seconds that's a
shitload of packages and he has to take
it off the truck and put it on this
conveyer belt
so just imagine a thousand times an hour
he's going from here to here boom and I
mean the weight like he says can go up
to 120 pounds each now he's back his
fingers his neck her so he's hunched
over it's all messed up his wondering is
there something that I can do to
strengthen my my body so that I can
handle this brutality this what I'm
going to call pattern overload of just
doing this a thousand times an hour all
right I'm gonna take a wing right every
few seconds all day long I mean your
your fucking machine I get it this is
your work this is your chosen profession
your line of service to the world so
that you can receive back the money you
need to feed yourself I get it sometimes
that's just the way it is right you
gotta work everybody's got to work I
mentioned in one of my videos the other
day a beautiful quote by Khalil Gibran
something to the effect of my stuff that
I dreamt that life was joy
I woke and saw that life was Duty I
acted and behold Duty was joy that means
whatever work you decide to engage in
that is your joy choose it and if you
didn't if you if you do it joyfully
you'll have a joyful life Duty is joy
beautiful beautiful thing but your
body's getting all fucked up right what
are you doing so here's what I would
offer you because mind you he also
mentions that I've been an athlete my
whole life I do CrossFit and I you know
I
city power lifted for a while you know
the guy's no slouch he's a good shape
what you need is a systematic method of
unwinding right because what's going to
happen the reason why I'm answering
questions like this on this channel
because this is where I'll be answering
them all time is not only is your body
going to become deformed due to the
pattern overload that creates all the
stress on your joints but you're also
it's always going to also going to
change your character because by
repetitive use of certain muscles that
change our posture they literally put us
into a the form of how we're going to
then function right and you're gonna be
like beat down tired and miserable your
entire life is gonna fall apart if you
can't figure this shit out right I hate
to say it it just won't be that your
back hurts and your shoulders hurting
your fingers hurt you're gonna have all
types of other problems if you don't
deal with this here is your only option
my friend there are many different ways
you can go about it but this must be
done
you must systematically unwind your body
that means undo all the damage done
during the day while you're moving boxes
once every three seconds and it's going
to come in the form of see everything
you're doing is flexion let's let sweat
sweat sweat right it's going to be
extension looks a lot like the boat in
it but when I use that word systemic
that means it's going to have to be with
the type of frequency that will undo the
damage of your pattern overload yoga my
friend that will be my answer for today
find a yoga class and do it every single
day you might even be better off in fact
if you find a really good yoga school
where they work on corrective or there
was a tighten term for it restorative
yoga restorative yoga that's exactly
what you want it's more like physical
therapy yoga
opposed to you know a lot of like the
movements and poses and shit this is
like you're all stretching and unwinding
restorative yoga there's a class in my
in my city that I go to often that's
restore - yoga that's the one that I go
to or find a restorative yoga DVD or
videos on YouTube I bet you got you but
you can find some and follow it every
single day even if purchased ten minutes
dude I would probably dedicate now or a
day to it
forget honestly you know what sometimes
you gotta make priority you gotta set
priorities
forget powerlifting in CrossFit for a
moment maybe put that aside for a little
bit of course you need cardiovascular
strength and you can get that from
walking you know just go for a walk nice
brisk walk in the morning like I always
tell you to I should be a part of your
medicine for the rest of your life just
brisk walking but yoga's going to have
to take presidents or restorative
organic stretching if you don't wanna
use the word yoga some of you guys get
like all superstitious and shit about
the term yoga I love a sudden you know
the gods are gonna the clouds can open
up and like Jesus is gonna strike you
with lightning if you do yoga
restorative Organic stretching if you
will every single day that needs to be
your training and that's it man long
story short you're its pattern overload
due to repetitive movement which you're
doing over and over and over and over
again that's going to ultimately destroy
your life
sorry to say that when I say destroy
your life means you're not going to be
the strongest version yourself because
your body's distorted and painful unwind
it through organic stretching or yoga
you have to do this sorry done