good eye so Elliot is going to come up
here and easy on the fuck you destroy it
for you guys you're going to bring the
fucking house down so please prepare
yourself for that so let's give him a
team capital slow clap right now and
bring you that
[Applause]
laughs
ah
you're all good little boy yes you are
hmm
sitting there doing as you're told
mm-hmm because that's what you've been
taught from the time you were babies we
had a child in here yesterday and
immediately the energy was shut that
baby up because we have no room for
spontaneity we have no room for noise we
have no room for life baby grows a
little bit older boys touch things you
want to jump on things you want to run
you might want to break something
because it's fun to break shit and what
does he get
sit down shut don't touch don't move
little by little you begin to not trust
yourself I want to move I want to touch
I want to feel something I want to laugh
I want to cry but it's inappropriate
so those feelings come up whether they
be true meaning coming from your
authentic self because sometimes you're
supposed to cry sometimes you're
supposed to be fucking pissed off you
have the goddamn right to be your
god-given right to be pissed off you're
right to laugh you're right to cry it's
your right to feel it's right to explore
the world through your body
and then we get education we value
education all these books what's the
first step in education when you go to
school how do we operate you sit in rows
you shut your mouth and you raise your
hand so little by little you become numb
to the feelings in your body little by
little you begin to distrust the feeling
in your body little by little your
authentic self deteriorates and in its
place is a head full of dictates a head
full of ideas a head full of knowledge
and a dead dormant body now where is
life experienced this is your being
where is life experiences that
experience in the realm of ideas or is
it experience in the realm of sensation
you see I got a lot of questions over
the past few days from some of you to
give one gentleman in particular
that I can't answer for you because I
would be enabling and perpetuating the
exact same pathology that the world has
given you and that you've become
addicted to there is nothing I can tell
you there's nothing I can teach you I
have no information I have liberation
liberation is an experience not an idea
when you fill your head with more ideas
and then it comes time to act action is
done through the body but instead
because your bodies are all very dormant
they're all very dead they're all very
good boy oriented you go back to your
head I thought it was interesting
earlier this weekend someone asked when
and how do I touch a woman
you can't calculate sex you can't sink
your way into bed and you're not fucking
anybody with your knowledge it is in
your body you've got to get out of your
head what is the symbol for a crazy
person
what are we taught to do bring in
information spit it back out I got the
idea how can I regurgitate it never in
our education are we taught how to
integrate mind with body intelligence
now intelligence is a holistic aspect of
intellect instinct and intuition we have
to integrate the three your head your
heart and your balls we are living in a
culture and we are operating from a
space of worshipping the head and
ignoring the heart but yet science has
told us that the heart has the largest
electromagnetic field in the body in
fact I've heard it said Yoga woowoo
stuff but still that the heart is more
powerful than a thousand suns but yet we
go to the intellect and ignore our
intuition we there is no intuition
because the minute intuition arises you
negate it with a fact you're not fucking
with facts so today I'm going to shut up
and I'm going to invite you into a
practice of liberation it's going to be
very uncomfortable we talk a lot about
getting out of our comfort zone well
we're not going to talk about this we're
going to fucking do it
I'm going to introduce you to Osho
dynamic meditation this is a practice by
which we get back into our body through
deep cathartic breathing because your
body is fueled by breaths and
spontaneous movement grounding and
presence we're going to get back into
our bodies and it's going to be a
challenging journey because your bodies
are stifled it's not your fault
like Jay would have said earlier you've
been taught this so we're going to
unteach it we're going to undo it and we
are going to express ourselves from our
authentic selves
so here are the first three things I
need you guys to do the first is I'll
offer you a warning and an invitation an
open-hearted invitation is an authentic
invitation from me if you're unable or
unwilling to get uncomfortable
physically uncomfortable emotionally
uncomfortable you are going to feel
things part of the problem with feeling
things is that you got to process it
what I'm going to do with you what we're
going to do here today is going to bring
up feelings it's going to bring up
sadness perhaps for some of you it's
going to bring up repress joy for some
of you it's going to bring up anger for
some of you if you're fully engaged so
if you're unable to be fully engaged
with the process that we're going
through no judgment on you then the next
few minutes you'll have an opportunity
to silently sneak out the room because
we will not have anybody in here who's
not fully engaged if you remain in this
room it's because you are committed to
being fully engaged because those of us
who are going hard don't need spectators
and judges amongst us or about this
again no judgement I get it this is
tough so you will silently sneak out the
room and here's your opportunity to
sneak out the room as whorl about to get
up and move some things around how much
how much time have I been speaking so
far how much time do we have left
too long you're wasting my time let's
stand up grab your things grab the chair
that was under your ass and if there was
an empty chair next to you grab it too
if we could have the the JC geniuses
move this white thing so you guys can
take your chairs and get them out of the
way if there are chairs over there you
could perhaps move them over to the
slide we need room