got this question here from our Twitter
friend his name's skip skip the quitter
says hi I'm the worst quitter ever
excuses after excuses I always find a
way to let people down great believers
in my success every time I finally get
close to being able to be stable in my
life or having more success I just quit
long story short he he made the
basketball team starting starting
position on the basketball team they
lost the first game and he quit few
months later he quits school he drops
out of school he just wants to go home
and play call of duty that's what he
says I just can't seem to get myself
going the worst about this all is that I
probably know exactly what I need to do
so on and so forth he thinks maybe he
should break his xbox basically long
story short he wants to know why he's
such a big fucking quitter you know when
your soul chooses the body that it's
going to go on this journey of life with
it knows that there are certain
challenges that are going to help its
progression right bear with me I'm being
a little bit poetic here and if you
don't believe in Souls or or whatever
just kind of pretend I'm it's a fairy
tale but it's a cool one your soul
chooses your body and chooses your
parents it chooses the experiences that
are going to be inherent in the
circumstances of your life and it knows
that there are certain challenges that
you're going to face based on how the
stars lined up based on your genetic
makeup based on the the time and the
place that you're born they're going to
be certain challenges it knows this
there's an innate part of you that knows
this and it shows you because it knows
that for its own fulfillment for you to
become the strongest version of yourself
if you will that you've got to get
through these fucking challenges they're
put there specifically for you right
they're not arbitrary see we have these
experiences in our life that are that
are not fun that are difficult you lose
a loved loved one you lose a limb you
get really sick see these are easy ones
your doesn't fucking and just quit
basketball because he lost a game but
you're gonna experience shit in life you
can experience some tongue tough fucking
shit I mean you can lose you can lose
your parents you can lose your children
you like I said you can lose your limbs
you could be flat broke and hungry there
are so many different experiences that
that you're probably going to experience
in life you know getting in an accident
and there's so much and each one of
those each one of those aren't arbitrary
think about how bad it could possibly
become that is not arbitrary it is
purposeful it is set there for your
growth right that's what life is about
life is engaging in all of those really
difficult situations for your growth
because always on the other end of that
pain is a stronger version of yourself
that's why that pain is there like we
wait train in the weight room you know
it's very painful to the body we subject
our body to the pain of let's waiting
lifting weights in order to experience
the growth that's on the other end of
the pain catabolism audible and
anabolism life is that balance between
catabolic and anabolic catabolic is when
you're being broke the fuck down
anabolic is the bounce-back associated
with going through the circumstance so
here you are your I assume your failure
young dude and you're faced with these
little bullshit circumstances like maybe
you know you didn't get good grades in
school so you fucking quit you didn't
win the basketball game so you fucking
quit you're still like taking babe like
for example I'm looking for big problems
like I want big problems to come my way
now this sounds crazy and I've said it
in many videos in many different ways
for many years but I basically like like
sometimes I ask God like what's the next
challenge for me right what do you what
do you want to have happen to me
so that I'm forced to grow you lose a
fucking basketball game dude you're
still like you're still in nursery
school where this is all concerned
you mentioned breaking your xbox yeah
maybe you should just fucking break your
xbox and then move out of your parents
house go live go live in a tenement
dwellers goal if like intensity without
with the homeless people or something go
do something
it forces you to look the ugliness in
the face so that you can deal with it so
that you can grow past it so that you
become a stronger version of yourself
every time you back away from any of
these challenges these circumstances
these failures there's no such thing as
a failure okay you didn't lose that
basketball game because you're a failure
you didn't drop out of school or you
didn't have the experience that caused
you to drop out of school because you're
a failure handle circumstances posed to
you in order for you to grow stronger
even if you fail and fail and fail you
get knocked in your fucking face ten
times you're not a failure until you
quit motherfucker you're a failure
because you're not choosing to play life
now if you don't choose to play life
while you're here and you don't go
through the challenges that are inherent
in your soul development you'll probably
have to fucking come back again I'm
being poetic you don't have to believe
in reincarnation I happen to think that
the soul doesn't like energy does is
never is never destroyed I mean we go
and we come we go where we come and your
soul being a form of energy it's not
going to be destroyed doesn't fucking
just disappear like it's not here
anymore
just like when water melts it goes into
the air it's not is that that the water
is not here anymore it's just in a
different form then it comes back into
water turns into ice boom boom boom same
thing with us we were ice were hard or
tangible or material we turn into ether
of air right when we die boom boom
anyway that's neither here nor there the
fact is that this metaphor of the soul
called the mind
called the great unconscious whatever
not gonna be satisfied with your
bullshit performance here on earth if
you don't take some fucking chances grow
some balls put yourself in desperate
situations just so you can grow that's
when you produce your greatest work
that's when you become the strongest
version yourself if you have an easy
road towards becoming Trucks version
yourself trust me you haven't gotten
started remember hearing a story about
Van Gogh great artists during his during
his days of creating his works of art no
one would buy his shit he was a fucking
failure I mean he died he died not being
able to sell his his art I mean today
his artists is worth millions in many
cases starry night you've seen these and
even in that situation where he's faced
with such challenges that he really
couldn't sell his art for very much at
all when he felt that he was becoming
comfortable or content you know maybe he
had enough to put food in his mouth
apparently he lived with his brother I
think and uh and we sell some art and
got comfortable because he could feed
himself he could buy some some art
equipment and kind of like live his life
on coasts easily he noticed that his art
started to suffer his soul wasn't
progressing he wasn't becoming a better
artist a stronger version of himself and
he would purposefully give away all his
material and go live in the street until
he felt the muse come back till he felt
that passion deep within him that causes
him to grow stronger in his particular
craft to come back he threw himself into
the frying pan you you get a little warm
and you run away you can be a pussy if
you want to that's a choice you're gonna
die a pussy you have to do it all over
again
might as well man up now face to heat
and grow stronger