so our buddy Rob has met the perfect
woman right so about a year ago he met a
woman who was beautiful in every way and
more importantly she was into fitness
and she supported him in losing weight
so she was a very attractive woman you
know and you know they had on-and-off
relationships for the past year
essentially now where the relationship
has sort of solidified a bit you know
that their date they feel good about
each other they're dating they're having
sex it's not official but as he moved
closer to this woman he realized that
what she's got some some serious
problems
you know she's got relationship baggage
she she likes to drink and party a lot
and this is definitely a detriment to
our buddy Rob and his goals in life so
here he is finally with the woman who
was very attractive to him you know in
the beginning they weren't very close
you know but he really was lusting for
this chick
and she was she was yielding a little
bit she gave him she tickled him a
little bit and now they're in the
situation were finally throw together
but he gets a deeper look and realizes
that boy this bitch's problems she's
nothing but beef and you don't want any
don't wanna deal with it he's like I'm
conflicted now because I was attracted
and all the good things that she had she
still has but there are spiders and
cobwebs and a whole lot of nastiness in
that closet so you got to recognize that
there is a primal nature to the man and
woman and it is embodied in the nature
of the penis and vagina so if you if you
just recognize the form of the vagina
soft and yielding
it is often and always actually a
representation of the character of the
female the woman advertises and brings
in softens and yields so basically
they've got to become attractive right
marketing do what you have to do in
order to bring in fine create a
environment where a man would want to
come in right like the vagina right they
attract and absorb the nature of the
penis is to hunt down
and a grass assert itself the energy
builds up in the man and he has to go
out and assert he has to go and find a
place to rest so you've got all these
penises and vaginas out there no matter
how complex we think we are as human
beings and and uh sophisticated we think
we become the nature of the penis in the
vagina does not change attract and
absorb hunt and assert it's the way we
behave in life it's the way we the way
our bodies look okay so you've got to be
very careful right because if you have
an ungrounded searching and a asserting
behave at a-- tude
that means you tend to turn your brain
off especially when it comes time to sex
you hunt you hunt you hunt and you look
for somewhere to rest somewhere to
assert yourself and if the marketing is
good and the yielding is right pussy is
good right you tend to lose your head
you completely you lost yourself dude
you got tricked and it happens all the
time both ways right the marketing is so
good and once you finally get the
product you're like ah I'm really the
products always the same vaginas vagina
penises penis it's all about the
marketing the presentation of it so
anyway what will happen often is you you
get past the marketing you receive the
product and you're like boy this is
garbage
this is trash this is not what I want as
you're experiencing right now and you've
got to be as you are thank you my friend
for being this way very aware of what's
going on because you could be still
fooled by the marketing I have plenty of
friends and I've known plenty of people
who they're still attached to the
marketing that brought them into the
vagina it was very good marketing and
she still markets that same way but once
you get inside and you realize that this
is nothing but what a mess this is just
a problem that you really wouldn't want
to deal with it's only going to make
your life more difficult to deal with
they're still attached to that beautiful
marketing oh man look out she's so hot
dude yeah great what the product is
terrible marketing is great products
terrible you're going to be detached
enough to see this and
you've got to be able to act
appropriately in my my suggestion
lamentation is to cut and run dude the
marketing is always a trick the
attraction is always a trick right she
got you to allow the absorption to
apogee loud she brought you in you saw
what was there now get out and go
because what's inside there it's far
more important than what you see on the
outside right if this type of if it was
this type of woman that you get inside
and you realize boy you know she's got
all the same values as me she's moving
in the same direction as me I could see
that she would be a valid and valuable
partner in the type of life that I want
to construct for myself regardless of
the marketing that's the one that's the
one you want to stick with that's the
one that you want to take a little bit
further that's the one that you want to
build a life with not the one with the
really good marketing right so that's it
dude it happens both ways you know the
majority the people that watch my videos
your it's dudes it's guys but it happens
both ways there's really good marketing
right men that are really almost
feminine in their marketing they're just
so soft in their presentation the sexual
stuff has gotten a little weird in our
culture but anyway and then you find out
boy this guy is just useless right so
women beware as well always look at the
core values of the individual how they
live their life the things that they
hold dear to their hearts what they
actually do when no one else is looking
that's how you know whether or not this
is more than just a penis vagina ploy
and something that is long-lasting good
luck