hey what's up guys today we got a
question from our buddy hunter who's
concerned about leaving old friends
behind especially since he says they're
good people so hunter is 21 years old
he's going about his life in a very
successful way and when I say that he's
actively moving towards becoming the
strongest version of himself in
different choices he's making about his
future he's got friends though that have
been friends obviously for a very long
time who although he loves them and they
share a tremendous history together
don't have their shit together he says
in fact one of them he says is somewhat
of an alcoholic and that's you know it's
making his life miserable but also
Hunter's suffering because he's kind of
dragging along this alcoholic friend he
also has another friend who he says is
very indecisive it's a character flaw
that's wreaking havoc on a lot of the
choices that he would ultimately make in
his life to move forward but simply
can't and you know it could be things
like you know old girlfriends that just
keep popping up and make his life
miserable or career choices or school
choices or choices with his parents but
even what either way this guy just can't
make good decisions and he goes on and
basically he wants to what hunter wants
to know is how do i sever myself from
these toxic relationships although I
have a deep and profound love for these
men that I've grown up with great
question
so the very first place I'd like to
start is with something I once heard and
that is that the people in your life
represents one of three things you've
got people in your life who are crystal
balls and when you look into them as a
crystal ball you will see your future
when you see that person you have to ask
yourself do I want to experience and
characterize what this person represents
in my future it could be good it could
be bad
it could be completely neutral then
you've got people who are mirrors the
interesting thing about a mirror is that
it
gives you back exactly what you give it
so you can have someone in your life who
is mirroring back good things about you
and not so resourceful things about you
meaning you could find someone in your
life who you're instantly attracted to
and build deep bonds with because you
have the same virtues in certain ways
you have the same goals and ambitions
you're the same character that allows
you to join forces and at least enjoy
each other's company but also be mindful
of the fact that there are going to be
people who you are instantly repelled by
disgusted by you look at them in you you
can't figure it out sometimes or maybe
you can point it out exactly what it is
that makes them that causes you to be
disgusted by them the thing with these
people and you've got to be very
objective about this is that they too
might be mirrors reflecting back to
parts of you that need to be considered
if you look in that mirror and you see
an ugly spot it's up to you to rectify
that not the other person that person is
a mirror in your life even though you
don't like what you see and then you
have angels angels are interesting in
that sometimes they're very overt and
obvious about how they're bringing
blessings into your life an angel could
be very obvious in that you might have
needed a piece of information to help
you move your career forward and they
just showed up maybe you're having lunch
one day and a an older executive walks
by and he sees you're having a sandwich
that he likes and he says you mind if I
sit down and have a conversation with
you or share a table you say yeah sure
no problem
and through that short conversation he
imparts of bits of a bit of information
on you that that allows you to make some
choices in your career that allows you
to escalate your success dramatically in
a short period of time and then you may
or may not see that guy ever again that
dude is an angel I've had some of those
in fact I've had all three of these I'm
going to talk about different stories
that might support you in being able to
relate how this works in your life but
also with the angel sometimes you're not
ready for the blessing sometimes you're
just not mature enough to see what that
person is trying to give you oftentimes
that person doesn't even know that
they're an angel in your life I mean
none of these people know all I'm
offering you is a perspective on how to
decide what this person is in your life
so that you can choose how you go about
the relationship sometimes you have to
cut off relationships just like that
just boom always whether or not you
maintain a relationship or you cut it
off that person is or was one of those
three things or a combination so you've
got your friends here who are making
poor just poor decisions poor choices
they're moving in a direction that you
are it's something that the way they're
just choosing to live their life is
contrary to where you want to go in your
life it's very obvious so let's begin
with the crystal ball and let me use
myself and some experiences I've had
with friends as an example for you I
move down to Florida I don't I don't
have any friends in Florida when I moved
down here about 10 years ago all my
friends all my family everything that I
knew about myself growing up I left in
New York I needed a clean start for many
different reasons
so with that clean slate I knew that
anybody that was coming into my life
need to be needed to be assessed you see
now your circumstance might you might be
different because these people came into
your life when you were a child but
still you can create a clean slate just
by washing your conscious slate clean
just taking a step back and looking at
everything objectively meditation helps
you do this so I'm going to use one
friend an example there was a and he
still is a friend who made his way into
my life during a time when I needed some
support moral support and building my
business
and although he and I were completely
opposites I mean completely night and
day you look at us and you're like you
had there's no way that you guys can be
friends just by our dress by the way we
look the way we carried ourselves the
way we spoke but he offered consoling he
offered support
he offered confidence he offered a lot
of the things that I needed in my life
at that particular time to make
courageous choices about my business and
I kept him around although he seemed to
be an anchor because leaning on him for
that support was easy because this guy
is just a friendly guy and sometimes you
just need friendly people to to lean on
to to lend an ear
in other words but at the same time he
made really bad choices he drank a lot
and went to fights all the time was
arrested here and there dressed really
weird completely inappropriately and
offensive to a lot of people that I was
trying to also create space for in my
life and they were like what is this guy
doing here young punk so at some point I
realized that I need to cut off this
relationship with this guy but what I
didn't understand at that particular
point it was that I just needed to put
him in his place he showed up as a
supporter right a an angel in a way and
then I began to look at him as a crystal
ball I began to say fuck if I hang out
with this guy I'm going to end up a
degenerate also in some way shape or
form because the people that you hang
out with support your character they
tell you something about yourself and
they also take from you and you receive
from them you're sharing your life with
someone you can't share your life with
someone and not be influenced by them
and I recognize that this guy was I'm
sharing a part of my life with him and I
was scared of the fact that perhaps he
was a crystal ball and that my future
would be as dysfunctional as his present
like I gotta separate myself the same
way you're feeling about separating
yourself from your friends and I did
that for a short period of time about
six months
in that span of time in that space that
you create between your circumstances
your friends and yourself you are
allowed to reflect sometimes you just
need space see right now you're saying
that you need to cut off your friends
completely well I'm saying create some
space because they're there for a reason
they supported you in some particular
way and when I say support it could be
as simple as moral support an ear that
was there for you too
they lend it in ear for you they were
just friendly like my friend although it
seems as if they're degenerate they did
help you otherwise they wouldn't be in
your life at this particular point so
there are angels to you right now or in
the past
so back to the story with this friend of
mine I decided to take him from the put
from the place of Angel and look at him
as a mirror and say to myself well you
know he came into my life as an angel I
looked at him as a crystal ball I didn't
like what I saw on the crystal ball
let me put him in front of my face and
try to see what I'm missing about myself
through him and I look at him and I
think of myself and I realized that at
that time in my life I was a hard-ass I
was just a warrior with a snarl on my
face I had a sword one hand a sneer on
the other face literally a shield in the
other hand because it was just like boom
I just was deflecting anything in anyone
that would get me off of my track I was
rigid and focused focus is good
rigidness is no way to live your life
because like I mentioned before to grow
into becoming a king without the
flexibility of the lover you become a
tyrant and I was becoming a tyrant and
there standing in front of me was my
friend who for a lack of a better
description is like a teddy bear
he smiles I mean he's always sweat he's
always friendly his major purpose in
life is just making sure everybody gets
along hey I might be a douchebag cuz he
knows he's a douchebag
I made the douche bag was like I I drop
shit on the carpet no clean it up and
like I'm just nasty sometimes and like I
make bad choices but I love everybody
and friendly with everybody I'm a good
guy that's what he was and when I looked
at him it was the exact opposite of what
I was giving and I was ashamed because I
knew that if I'm going to become the
strongest version of myself the
character of the lover the peacemaker
the one who knows how to enjoy life and
appreciate the good things and smile and
laugh things off was not present in my
character but is needed for full
actualization personal development and I
looked at him as my mirror and saw my
weakness and over time
it's been many years I've had to you
know I always talked about becoming the
strongest version of ourselves and I am
on the same journey folks I'm not
stronger than anyone I just gained
perspectives and use language to share
my journey with you guys as I have
certain experiences and I use different
metaphors to describe the elements of
becoming the strongest version yourself
metaphors like the king warrior magician
and lover now I'm using this idea of the
crystal ball the mirror and the angel
we've got to follow my language you've
got to follow how I'm trying to share
this with you anyway so over the course
of the years where my warrior the
warrior in me was beginning to gain some
traction I'm developing my kingly
qualities I'm realizing what I've built
and I now need to manage myself that's
what a king does a king is a manager I
need to manage myself and I need to
manage the kingdom that I've developed
and developing your kingdom is your
sphere of influence your world your
family your friends your business
everything that makes that surrounds you
you're not isolated you're surrounded
you're the focal point of your life King
but everything that happens and all the
people surround you every man is a king
in his own life
and as I started softening the shield
putting down the shield realizing my
sword is getting dull and it needs to be
sharpened I back away from the
circumstances of my life and begin to
look at it like a manager a king that
needs to balance himself I realized that
this friend who was once an angel then a
crystal ball that showed me something I
didn't want to have in my future but
then placed in front of me as a mirror
to show me how I'm lacking once again
became an angel and to this day in my
life in my court in my kingdom he acts
as a lover not love her like I'm
homosexual with him but as the
embodiment of pleasure joy friendship
love in life he teaches me how to do
this I look to him for ideas about how
to be more friendly how to be more
appealing how to enjoy certain things
that I didn't even know existed you see
you know part of the the sinful
pleasures that I engage in in my life or
smoking cigars he introduced me to this
idea and he loves and he shows me all
the different types clothing the
clothing that I wear when I was a
warrior I wore camo everything because
I'm ready to fuck shit up
you can't go everywhere in camo and
expect people to like you
also even my body looked like it was
armored because of all the muscle and
fat that I had covering me look at my
old videos
this friend introduced me to the idea of
physical appearance I consult with him
when I don't know what to do with my
hair
when I don't know what kind of clothes
to wear based on the occasion he
introduced me to all kinds of different
music I never heard of so when you talk
about your friends being degenerates and
losers and not supporting you and
becoming the strongest version of
yourself and anchors or toxic people I
invite you to step back and ask yourself
always go back to yourself always go
back to yourself and say how are these
people showing me or teaching me
something about myself you're never a
victim of the people in your life and I
venture to say that very rarely do you
need to actually cut people out of your
life you need to put them in their place
not meaning telling them their place but
gaining a perspective for how they fit
into your model of life even the most
degenerate people in your life may be
there to teach you a lesson to show you
your future to offer you a blessing done