hey one of the things that people often
ask me is Elliott how is it that you are
seemingly successful in so many
different areas of your life how is it
that you're balancing family business
training and multiple other things that
they engage in and enjoy doing and make
it look easy well it's it's taken some
practice but there's one tool that I've
been using since 2004 and I actually
heard it while listening to the luck
factor CD program by Brian Tracy and it
is the keeping of lists so this is going
to be a messy demonstration because it's
a work in progress I'm always using
lists and when I say work in progress
it's actually using this list so what
you're going to see here and hopefully I
don't have anything embarrassing on here
but what you can see here is two sides
of the page and often what I'll do is
this is my big working list this is kind
of like things that need to get done but
they're not on my day to day over here's
my day to day what you can see is days
of the week so you've got Friday and
then Monday and you'll see that from
this list I drag and drop things over
onto the days of the week that I want to
get them done and what I do is simply
cross them off when I do them this list
evolves and this one changes from day to
day so what I do is I open this up rip
off the page repeat on the following
page by writing down the things that I
haven't done on my big list these are
like medium-term goals right these are
things that need to get done within the
next three months minute maximum it
shouldn't take much longer than three
months to get these things done it's my
working list my big list like my yearly
and life goal list goes in a completely
different notebook but I'll make a video
about that another time this is the one
that you're gonna want to start doing
take a clean sheet of paper cut in our
line it up in half you don't have to put
a line but you have it broken down into
two sides one side is your medium term
goal list and what I also do with that
list is I brain dump anything that comes
into my mind with
to anything that I want to achieve I
just dumped it on there sometimes I dump
things on that side and it just gets
crossed off because I realize later on I
really don't want that but I wrote it
down so it gives it life you know
ultimately that it may make its way onto
my working list on the other side of the
page and that's going to be outlined by
the days of the week if today's Monday
you write down Monday what are the
things going to do on Monday and then
Tuesday Thursday Tuesday Wednesday
Thursday Friday so that's it it's really
you know I've used many different
methods I've used planner pads I've used
all types of software little gadgets
years ago they have these like a pump
eyelets they call it and stuff look
what's worked better than anything has
been this archaic system of writing down
lists checking them off
ripping off the page and starting over
again it just seems to keep things
moving forward try that I promise you
you'll notice far more success than by
just flying by the seat of your pants
good luck