good Sunday morning guys Elliott Hulse
here back at the gym some of you guys
noticed last week that I uploaded a
video and took it down promptly I made
that video at my office and quite
frankly I just wasn't feeling the vibe
man I mean the the environment just
didn't evoke inspiration in me right so
if I'm going to make these videos they
had ought to come from my deepest
heartfelt sentiment of truth and you
know when the environment isn't
conducive to my really expressing myself
like I have in the gym my whole life I
think this is just my temple maybe
that's why we're doing this on Sunday
mornings because the gym is Church to me
so I can do my preaching that much
better here so I've decided to you know
what I don't want any videos to be
uploaded or remain uploaded that I don't
feel really portray or give the gift
that I hope to give through these videos
so I'd rather not have it out there and
that's why this week we're starting over
again and I'm here and I've got a great
question from one of our friends then
I'm gonna go ahead and read it's a
little lengthy but I think you'll
appreciate getting all the details our
friend has to share because I have a
good feeling that many of you will
resonate with where he is coming from so
he goes on and he says yo Elliott he
actually says hello Elliott thank you
hello I'm writing to you in hopes of
benefiting from you because you embody
much of what I'd like to be you're a man
and I am NOT I'm 24 and I've been
putting off my life my real life for a
counterfeit dream since I've stopped
I've since stopped but I have been using
drugs and alcohol to numb myself to the
fact that I was deeply unhappy I find
myself at the end of this road and I've
slowly been climbing out of the hole
that I've been in my entire life I've
been eating better and I no longer do
drugs of any sort and I've started going
to the gym
great that being said I'm the opposite
of virtue years of neglecting my life
have made me weak and cowardly I thought
I knew what I wanted to do with my life
I thought that I would be just this
whimsical sort of folk singer character
I thought that getting a job was
bullshit but I didn't build any sort of
foundation though I truly do think that
I have the potential to play to move
hearts
I haven't refined myself at all I was
lying to myself with substances and I
have this pain in my heart that won't go
away I can't seem to get interested in
anything beyond a surface level people
either outright
dislike me or really don't care for me
and I can't blame them I've made my bed
I want to make my own authentic
signature in this world that was the
dream but now I'm scared that I'm just
going to end up nothing that I'll end up
terribly unhappy in some job which I
think I would rather commit suicide than
do please help D so uh David there are
thousands of David so I can say that and
nobody will know you're still anonymous
I've got to go right back to the
fundamentals I would like to begin here
today by inviting you to take a good
look at the type of language you're
using against yourself when I hear you
say things like Elliott you're a man and
I am NOT the very first thing I thought
because I took it very literally was
that oh this is a woman but as I went on
I came to realize that it was an
evaluation about your worthiness as a
man and to use that type of language
with yourself is violence against self
right and you really do go on I want you
to read what you sent me you really go
on and you begin to or you continue to
stab yourself in the leg you begin
shooting yourself in the foot you begin
cutting off your nose to spite your face
this whole time what I'm saying is that
your your language verbal lead to
yourself is very I perceive as very
violent let me see where else you go
years of neglecting myself have made me
weak and cowardly right you also go on
to say that you thought you knew what
you wanted in your life and and then you
evaluated what I believe just based on
what you wrote here was your hearts
calling which is to be a folk singer and
then you evaluated it poorly it's almost
like you know a seed was planted in your
heart or your heart opens up right this
is when our heart speaks to us our heart
is tender all of our hearts are tender
and when our heart opens up and says
this is something that I'm yearning for
and we especially if we if we tend to it
and then later on when it doesn't work
out the way we thought it would work out
namely because we aren't an alignment
right we'll talk about that in a moment
we then placed judgment on it right I
just want to be some whimsical folk
singer right this is what my heart is
what your heart clearly told you because
you went on to begin explaining how I
still have some hope for that but you
call it whimsical right and you and you
when you downplay it dude when your
heart is speaking to you that is your
intuition
the thing about intuition is when you
ignore it
it begins to dim right because it's like
your heart is like a woman man right
women are of the heart manner of the
head your heart is very feminine your
varnak heart can be hurt very easily
your heart needs room and space to open
and it just like with a woman right you
you treat her bad she's not going to be
open to you right you treated poorly
she's not gonna get wet and and and want
to be open and and have an exchange of
sexual energy with you the same thing is
with your heart your hearts going to
close down man every time we judge
what's coming up in it
right so let me back up for a moment and
begin with the language you're using as
far as you know personal violence is
concerned and then I'd like to talk to
you a little bit about and share
perhaps some perspectives on what it
means when your heart is calling you to
be a folk singer right that's not wrong
it's never wrong nothing that your heart
ever speaks to you is wrong your heart
is always correct because it's true
right anything that's coming from you is
true everything that we all the words
that we used to evaluate it now are
secondary right there's a primary
movement in your body your emotions are
always primary anything that happens
spontaneous is true is it resourceful
and can I just go about it go about
trying to experience it in a spontaneous
way as a different story right I want to
be a folk singer well doesn't mean that
you drop everything and go do it it
might be but the fact is that it is a
yearning and it is right and it's true
and it should be looked at with our
heart with regard to our hearts rights
because this is where I'm going right
now with this with regard to our hearts
everything that comes out of our
emotional body is there to be observed
the minute we place judgment on our
anger we play judgment on our sadness we
place judgment on our hearts yearnings
we begin to distance ourselves from
ourselves
the minute we look into them right even
if they're not resourceful right let's
say that your emotion at the moment of
anger is completely unfounded it's
completely unresolved
it still needs to have the light of day
shed upon it so that you can process it
so that you can look at it so that you
can be with it so that you can resolve
it nothing especially a yearning is
anything to be judged
and it is everything to be embraced and
it knowledged right and please take
notice that's a very big difference
between acknowledging the spontaneity of
your heart acknowledging the spontaneity
of your intuition right because that's
what that's the seat of your intuition
your heart is the seat of your intuition
your head is the seat of your intellect
and your balls are the seat of your
instinct baby of the three the one
that's the most ungrounded is the one
that's furthest from the ground anything
that we begin doing do to judge our core
our Center our heart quarter-sawn core
right our heart anything that are
ungrounded perspective places upon the
heart or upon our balls upon our
instinct is secondary right the brain
comes next
it's just the way we've evolved even
right even if you look at biology and
the way the brain evolved we've got the
brainstem the reptilian brain the
mammalian brain of the neomammalian
brain right we're moved from our roots
and it is our flower that allows what's
happening in the root to blossom right
especially if we train the flower right
so let's begin moving in that direction
right we're talking about the root
system and your heart your instinct your
intuition but your head the head can be
a beautiful servant or it could be a
horrific master if you allow your head
to how can I put this
if you allow your judgments if you allow
your conditioning if we allow our
stories we allow how the world has
trained us to think about ourselves and
others to suppress and dominate our
heart and our instinct then we are not
fully grounded we're not fully human
we're not grounded in our truth in our
reality and every time I hear someone
say I'm not a man or I am you know all
all the negative derogatory things that
I've said that I heard you say none of
which and here's how we can use the
intellect in order to affirm what I'm
saying right now none of it is founded
in truth not a single thing you said I'm
called big game right from the beginning
bro and I share all this with love I
share all this with compassion
I get excited so bear with me you know
you're a man I am NOT that is the
judgment bro that it is an evaluation
that is not true do you have a set of
balls do you have a dick you are
biologically a man right I don't care
what anybody says you can put on a
makeup and a dress you're a man so what
you're saying is not true it's an
evaluation right you go on also to call
your hearts saw a calling of being a
folk singer character whimsical
is your instinct is your intuition
whimsical whimsical means completely
ungrounded it sounds like the wind
because it means are getting blown in
the wind do you make schizoid decisions
maybe maybe because the head is get
being flown blown in the wind but for
you to acknowledge what's coming up from
below is very grounded I think your
judgement was me I think your judgment
that it's whimsical is quim's achill
people either outright don't like me or
don't care for me and I can't blame them
so we've got to make a distinction
between our judgments right because you
say people don't care for me right they
don't like me and our observations all
right I know I'm kind of going off in
many different directions here but I I
think this is important I want to
clarify this you say that people don't
like you well in what way what what
happened to you that tells you that
someone doesn't like you right well uh I
asked her to bring me jell-o pudding and
she brought me jello jiggly jello
instead she must not like me Wow I mean
I got it I need the observation you give
me no observation if that's the
observation that means you know like you
should to pick up the wrong fucking
thing right because it could really be
that simple often times when people
share stories like this with or shared
judgments like this with me people don't
like me and I say oh well please tell me
what did you observe that gave you this
that allows you to make this observation
and then when they what they come up
with doesn't indicate that someone
doesn't like you it just means they did
something you didn't like
right that's another thing too you know
when another person shows up in a way
that you don't like it's more about you
not liking you than them not liking you
right maybe her face or his face is just
some people
people got oh my wife called it the
other day she mentioned someone having a
resting bitchface ha ha ha I had to
crack up I don't know where she got that
from Colleen cracks me up sometimes
she's kind of like she's straight she's
I'm Wiggles and she's prickles and I
every once in a while she'll come out
with something swaggy and she said that
night I really died I was like resting
bitchface I like what the hell is that
mean well it literally means that like
I'm judging this person as a bitch based
on the way she looks right so this
person does she's a bitch
and she don't like anybody but that's
just her resting face you can judge
someone not liking you just based on who
they are right I got a mean face
sometimes I get it from my dad like we
just walk around sometimes like a mean
face and really a lot of times it's
because we're thinking all right a lot
of times my dad just has a mean face
because he's working right like when I'm
working I think that's where I get it
from with regard to the amount of
intensity and aggression I put into my
workouts like I just that's just the way
I look around don't shit well you show
up one day and I'm doing that I got this
face on you might think well Elliot
doesn't like me there must be something
wrong with me dude once again an
evaluation a judgement we got to get
very clear with this and finally dude I
invite you and invite everybody here
because I've made lots of videos about
this to be very mindful about the words
and the language you're using with
yourself the word becomes the flesh in
the beginning there was the word this is
all truth biblical truth right the word
becomes flesh what you speak and Buddha
says it too right you know something to
the effect of your thoughts become your
words your words become your actions
your deeds your deeds become your habits
and at this point it's probably a hip
habit you're 24 years old you probably
have bicha Lee talk poorly to yourself
now I don't know where it came from
it could come from you know parents
talking poorly to you I think society
sets us up now
to win senses us not to like ourselves
sets us up to have a tremendous amount
of guilt and shame right so you know
being a product of civilization right
that might might show up right cut we're
constantly having being shown why we're
not good enough wherever it came from
what I'd like you to do now is to begin
to notice it when you hear the voice
within right and this is look some
people call it Satan the devil right
what's the devil the devil is anti truth
the devil is ego truthfully you know we
use metaphor to help us understand
certain things especially as we you know
pre-modern people's right we the depth
the devil's of metaphor right there is
no dude with the horns right you know
why I know cuz when you seen him right
observation versus superstition but it
is very easy to see the devil within
it's very easy to see the demons within
and it's very easy to in an objective
way we recognize that's not my voice
that's not the voice of truth all right
that's the voice of ego as always of
conditioning that's the voice of untruth
the truth is you're perfect just right
where you are we all are perfect right
where we are whatever your circumstances
are right now it is 100% perfect because
there's exactly where you are there's
nothing more than what is right your
judgment on what is is something that
the intellect had been fed right them
look dude when you're ruled by this you
can be you're literally ruled by this
this is the easiest way for the world to
control you that's why they put us in
schools right in order to manipulate our
brain brainwash us because you can rule
a person's body through their brain and
I always say that the body is the brain
right so you understand how there's this
one thing going on but you've got to
take control you've got to I don't even
say take control first observe
the garden right I'm gonna use a
metaphor for you right now alright so
you see how beautiful metaphors are
first observe your plot of land observe
the garden right just look at it right
now you might look at the garden you'll
recognize that there are weeds in there
all right what do we do we'd strangle
the beautiful budding roses and the
beautiful flowers lilies and whatnot
right so just just notice when those
weeds come up john Ashtaroth calls them
automatic negative thoughts recognize
immediately recognize when that
automatic negative thoughts comes up
it's a weed and pull it out right one
thing that you could do to pull out that
weed is to replace it with a positive
present intact at the present tense
affirmation I'm so stupid
you can refrain that immediately it
comes up hey look it comes up for me
I got all kinds of judgments going on
inside me I recognize them I distance
myself from them and I transmutate them
by saying something positive about
myself right I am so happy and grateful
now that I am creative I am
out-of-the-box
I am a thinker I am awake that is one of
my favorite affirmations when something
comes up and I'm judging myself because
everybody's going this way and I'm going
that way and I'm like I must be wrong I
say I'm awake I am awake I am awake
right it's just an affirmation to
replace or a flower to replace the weed
right back to the garden Brian Tracy
says that you have to consciously and
deliberately plant flowers in the garden
of your consciousness otherwise we'll
fill up with weeds by default that means
we have to be very active about what I
am saying to you right now right many
times we want the thing before doing the
thing well I wish I want to think
positive I'm going to start trying to
think positive that is like working out
you say you're starting to eat better
you're starting to work out well
thinking positive that's probably where
to begin that's definitely where to
begin
that's 100% where to begin I want
anything to happen the FIR
thing I got to do is I've got to train
my brain I've got a brainwash myself
into it being real do you see all this
my man to simply invite you to be more
compassionate with yourself
and when I say compassion I don't mean
boohoo empathy compassion I mean really
knowing your power you're placing your
responsibility in this world you as a
folk singer it's not about you folks
singing it is about you singing for the
world it is about God singing through
you is it about you being a hollow Reed
in order to bring forth the beauty that
is meant to move through you it is not
just your right it is not just a nice
idea it is your responsibility to sing
that folk song done