so lately I've been getting a lot of
questions pertaining to pornography lust
and masturbation it's taken me a while
to sort of digest my own ideas and do
some research to to come full circle and
offer you some sort of insight ideas
that I'm playing with associated with
love lust masturbation and pornography
definitely a very important topic to
consider because they bubble up in our
biology lust is a conceptual emotion
like I'll talk to you in a moment
love is the mutual exchange of feelings
between ourselves other people and
everything our environment
masturbation is the gratification of a
biological process coming up and and
these are all things that we have to
consider and talk about so before I get
started the disclaimer is that you
either have to get over your own hangups
in order to listen to this conversation
or just become a bit more mature man up
you're giggling while you're watching
this then that's cool if you want but
just consider how important this idea is
I'm going to play out a situation for
you that we can you can follow along
with you and your woman would be that
your wife or your girlfriend for a long
time but someone that you have mutual
exchange of physical relationship with
and emotional exchange with relationship
with are walking through a mall as
you're walking holding hands feeling
good about each other a beautiful woman
passes by now Beauty obviously is in the
either beholder but for some reason
there is an energetic exchange between
you and this other woman she you find
her attractive she clearly finds you
attractive and we know that on a
subconscious level on a deep primordial
body level you are actually making love
to that woman there is a vibratory
exchange you know feelings come up and a
vibrant person is a person who can bring
up feelings in their body and exchange
it with their environment you're doing
that with this woman as you hold your
lady's head also there are things like
pheromones that are that have been
suppressed because we've become very
afraid of the body and we
very controlling of one another so we
use things like deodorants and perfumes
to really shut down the body's ability
to recognize pheromones but they're
still there and we still recognize them
there are smells being exchanged between
you and this other woman now for good
reason to a degree there we've shut
these biological senses or perceptions
down because it'd be a little weird if
you're standing with your woman and this
lady walks by and you start smelling
like like there's some luster or there's
some love going on between you and this
other woman she would get very upset
and if it was the other way around
you're walking with your lady and a guy
walks by and you start and you smell her
getting horny right for him it's going
to be weird right so uh it all comes
down to you know our need for control
and that's a totally different topic but
you know she's not gonna be very happy
if you get out of control and and it's
completely subconscious you're not doing
it purposefully it's biological
processes going coming up in your body
and and this is normal and natural so we
got to put on deodorants cover it up and
we really lost touch with our ability to
recognize through smell so it's
happening what is happening at a deep
level and you recognize it between you
and this woman like I said there's
actually love going on between the two
of you like Christ says in the Bible if
you two think of having sex or making
love to a woman it's like you've already
done it now in a deep primordial
biological balls level 100% true you
know the assault happens so this is
where we'll move into to the idea of
lust right so lust is a conceptual
emotion and I say that because you don't
really actually feel lust you feel the
biological processes in your body you
might get an erection you feel good
they're good feelings lust is a concept
just like envy in that there are
feelings coming up in your body that
cannot be gratified right away right so
there is an assault on your biology
because you feel this emotion that you
cannot get out
so you're charged up and there's a block
between the reality of the situation and
the current feeling in your body one
it's not about right or wrong it's about
what's happening right so your body is
charged you're holding a woman she walks
by and that's it you're left with
nothing more than an image of this woman
right you don't know her you don't know
anything about her
but you were charged your body is
charged now your heart rate goes up your
eyes dilate all types of weird sexy
things happen you might have a sort of a
hard-on on and but you're still holding
a woman and you're left with nothing
more than just the picture of this woman
now masturbation becomes a consideration
because you've got an image and a charge
within your body that needs to be
discharged your body's asking you to
discharge this your lefting nothing with
nothing more than an image of this woman
Oh while you've still got your
girlfriend or your wife and then she has
nothing to do with she's not partaking
in this at all it's not right or wrong
but it is an exchange that you've
already had with another woman and
you're going to decide to help your body
discharge later on that evening you're
still holding the image just the image
not that actual woman whoever she is
you're holding that image in your mind
your body is still charged by that image
and you decide to masturbate now first
on the morality of masturbation your
body gives you recognize certain
charging feelings in your body where
they need to be gratified when you feel
hungry
you have to eat it's telling is your
body's charging you up letting you know
do we better put some food in our body
when you get an erection and especially
if it's associated with something that's
going on in your mind so you've got the
mind and you got the balls involved your
body's asking you please let
discharge via the image that you're
holding in your head and you help it
come to fruition we help your body
discharge so I really don't see it as
any different I'm sure some people would
argue with me but at this point I don't
see it is any different than fulfilling
the gratification to eat you should be
grateful and that's one of the things
that I think this entire conversation
needs to be centered around grateful for
your body's ability to charge you're
grateful for your body's ability to be
vibrant enough that someone else
receives your vibratory level or
exchange strong enough to get an
erection and aware enough for you to be
able to help it discharged and able
enough to help your body discharge all
grateful and be grateful for the ex for
the other woman for providing you with
an image that you can partake of the
mastaba Tory act with right the problem
becomes this is where it all because
everything I just described I think is
normal and natural that's going to
happen the problem becomes when that
image is not just an image any longer
and that happens when we become very
attached to it right so the assault now
grows the sin grows now when you have
this image of a person in your head and
you've subjected the real person to what
this image is now it's very difficult we
cannot see each other subjectively right
everything that in the world is an
object to us everything is an object
your parents your wife your children you
see them objectively because you don't
feel their feelings you don't know them
you're not inside them you're not
experiencing the biological processes
that are going on inside them in
multiple different ways the only one
that you can be objective or subjective
about is yourself so we've got this
object this woman that we see
objectively and as we normally do we
paint pictures around pink stories
around the objects of other people the
assault on her is if you hold tight to
that objective view that image of her in
your mind because now you've subjected
her to the slavery of your own
imagination the assault on yourself is
the continuous lust that you're going to
feel and like I said lust is an
agitation in the body it's a biological
process in the body but just like envy
like you see a car that you really like
you want that car but you can't have it
this sin happens when you become so
attached to it that you're uncomfortable
you're in a constant state of charge
right and you've got to do something
about it now
recognize that the original circumstance
was a biological process right there's
an image you help use the admission help
discharge yourself but if you attach
constantly consciously to that image
you're now subjecting that person to
slavery and you're being unfair to
yourself because in reality whatever
reality you have but in reality there's
probably a chance that you cannot go
ahead and be that be with that woman I
mean you saw her once that was it you
know who she is but the image is there
so it's unfair to you and it's an
assault on your woman on your partner
because now you are measuring reality
against your imagination you've got this
fabricated woman in your mind that
you're jerking off to and you're
attached to and you're going to
superimpose that image and those
expectations on a real human being now
mind you the image that you're holding
in your head that you're that you've
received and painted for yourself about
this woman is probably very very wrong
like I said you can't see her
subjectively you're not her so
everything that you've made up about her
is unfair to her but now you're taking
an imagined imaginary woman and you're
superimposing it on the expectations for
your wife or your woman
so it's an assault on her right unfair
to everyone in the party
I think my point here is that feeling
and partaking of the love exchange that
she had with that woman
though momentarily you should be
appreciative appreciative of thank you
you should also be appreciative of your
body or your body's ability to charge up
as well as your body's ability to
discharge but you've got to cut the
image out at a certain point and this is
where pornography gets kind of weird
because pornography is purely images and
you're constantly playing them over and
over again in front of your eye so
they're embedding themselves in your
consciousness and then you are going to
superimpose the image associated with
the pornography on yourself which quite
frankly could be humiliating or
self-deprecating right because I mean
how many of us have a 12-inch dick
I don't maybe some of you guys do that's
great but I think about 90% of us don't
have 12-inch dicks and can fuck for you
know two hours straight whatever the
case may be it's imaginary and you know
that it's choreographed and the way the
woman is having sex in that movie the
way she looks is all choreographed as
well and then we tend to superimpose
that on our woman so to come full circle
again the great grateful and happy for
the biological processes but be detached
from the image of that which you have
used to masturbate and even with the
pornography if you're watching
pornography if you're using it for the
charge in the discharge watching it and
can charge up the discharge and then you
turn it off and you turn it off in your
mind as well I don't see that it's an
assault I don't see it is very sinful
when I say sinful I don't mean it in the
Christian Way I mean it in the way that
it's actually meant to be used is to
miss it's an archery term than to miss
you missed the point
mr. point dude you're watching
pornography and you're not going to
little porno life right you missed the
point dude that's just an image and now
you're superimposing it on your wife so
be detached from the image of
chu ality that you've created and enjoy
the reality of the sexual relationship
that you have with another person okay
so I hope that was helpful it was
interesting still messing with this in
my mind but hopefully these are things
that can support you becoming stronger
talk to you later
Eliot sit