I got this question from our 18 year old
friend lives in Norway it's had a
girlfriend for for a few years he lost
his father and his grandfather cancer
recently and had a trusting problem for
many years but his girlfriend has always
been there for him until recently she
moved away now she's acting weird found
out he found out that she's cheating on
him
and now they're going this whole back
and forth thing where she I love you but
I hate you oh come and let me punch you
in the face oh come let me give you a
blowjob
this this whole dichotomy this whole
back and forth bullshit that is you know
kind of like what young love is about
oftentimes because you you're leaning on
each other you're needing each other but
you're wanting to stand on your own two
feet and this just this struggle between
the two of you that's what he's
experiencing and his life is a mess he's
broke he's lost weight he drinks too
much and smokes weed I told her don't
contact me but then I say at home want
it and this I mean this guy goes on and
on I mean just look at that email I mean
it's just long ass history is it long
story and I sat down and I read the
whole thing you know I feel for you in
many ways and uh and I have some ideas
for you I might support you right you're
18 years old this is young love and and
I don't say that in a mocking way see a
lot of times people will say or adults
will say to young people
oh it's young love it's your first love
you'll get over there's there's other
fish in the sea as if the circumstances
you're going through is not potent at
all see people often forget what their
experiences were like especially adults
adults often forget what their
experiences life like when they were
developing your developing man and you
have young love and I say that with the
utmost respect for you and your current
situation okay it's just the way it's
supposed to be one of the things that
you're going to have to learn very early
on is that a man has to have his mission
first your mission your heart's calling
the world asking you when I say the
world I mean the earth
our femininity and everything that she's
produced ie humankind putting your dick
energy into that that's what men do we
reach out we aggress towards and we
build skyscrapers giant penises
extending to God monuments so we build
Taj Mahal's monuments to beauty and to
sexuality to earth right you build
cities we build businesses enterprises
empires rage Wars this is what male
energy does and it is right I believe I
don't know if it's fucking right I know
it's right I'm putting my foot down on
this one it's right that a significant
portion of every man's energy go towards
giving himself to something greater than
himself and I don't mean his woman what
I mean is go and build an empire
when I say Empire I do this go and throw
yourself fully into something that you
really want to have happen build a
business start producing artwork write a
book write a great novel or a shitty one
but write something build a skyscraper
the Taj Mahal like I said I'm
Michelangelo right David Wright David
created Michelangelo throw yourself
wholeheartedly into an activity that
allows you to transmutate your sexual
energy into service to the world the
more a man makes love to the world to
his environment to nature to earth the
more he's attractive more attractive he
is to the opposite sex
that's why I've often said that men
women are interested in men who wear
uniforms because it looks like he's
doing something that's where a
significant portion of your male energy
needs to go it shouldn't go into her
vagina you give her what you have left
and
she should be grateful that you're she's
there with you as you were building your
skyscraper as you're building your
castles that's not to say that she
should be a tag-along and that women
aren't worthy of the same endeavors
but you need to each put your put each
other in your rightful places again it's
not patriarchal that's not what I'm
saying I'm saying male domination over
the female but knowing where she is in
your life I have a woman oh and I have
to have this conversation with her all
the time she's probably gonna watch this
right now she's gonna she's gonna slap
me pick me away arm for saying this I'll
smile she knows what's going on I make
these videos I create my little Empire I
put my sexual energy my male energy into
producing for the world and I'm happy to
have her and my family to come along
with me all right sounds like a very
egocentric place to come from but I tell
you what it gains not only self-respect
it gains respect from your woman and it
gains respect from the world that's what
men do
that's what male energy does fucking
phone
we reach out we aggress we build right
the penis extends itself and it lets out
seeds we drop seeds what our C's do
Johnny fuckin Appleseed goes out there
and drops itself exerts itself into the
soil and produces fruit go and do that
fully engage in that if she decides to
come along with this is the conversation
you need to have with her it's the
conversation every man needs to have
with a woman before they embark then I'm
saying real some real hard and fast shit
today I might contradict myself tomorrow
don't don't don't engage with a woman if
you can't tell her my work is important
to me the first thing that's important
the first and most important thing to me
is my mission and doing my work
you see I don't answer this fucking
phone because this is my work I'm the
most important thing for me is doing my
work is building my thing now doesn't
mean that you you could maintain that
warrior mentality and you you cut off
and don't experience anything else in
your life that's this completely
imbalanced way of doing but you know
where your priority lies don't give up
your manhood for some vagina
done