got a question from our buddy
bolt-action he wants to know if he
should bother with women at all he seems
to be a very purposeful dude he's got
all sorts of goals and aspirations in
its life and he feels that women are
merely a distraction and in his mind he
sees them merely as things to have sex
with and even still he's got to deal
with all the bullshit just to get in
their pants and in his mind he believes
it might just be better off you know
just forget it all together I will be
far more successful in all of my
endeavors which include bodybuilding and
career and a few different other things
if I just forget them all together any
any questions me as well it was no
Elliot what do you feel about your
ability to achieve had you not married
your wife and had so many children would
you be a more successful man there are
number ways that I want to approach this
but number one is you've got to ask
yourself what is it that you are
approaching women for most of us tend to
be very shallow in regards who are how
and why we approach women and it's
usually sexually based which is which is
the law of attraction I mean you've got
to be attracted they've got to be
attractive to you you've got to be
attracted to them and that's how things
move forward but if you are a bit more
pragmatic about your approach towards
how you are going to take this
relationship you're going to ask
yourself is this someone who can support
me in reaching my goals you see right
now you're just seeing women on that
first level right somewhere to bust a
nut okay that's one level and it's the
most superficial level an important one
nonetheless but a superficial level but
when you see this individual when you
see a person of the opposite sex as a
potential teammate that's going to
support you in becoming the strongest
version of yourself and helping you
create a beautiful vision for what is
the future you could be proud of then
you're going to look at these people
these women in a totally different light
so you ask me how I feel about my
situation at
I am so grateful for the teammate that I
have in my life my life my wife more
than anything is my teammate that's how
I see her we have a vision for the type
of life that we want to create for
ourselves individually she doesn't hold
me back at all in fact she's my greatest
supporter in every single golden
endeavor that I set for myself you know
she's recently become even a business
partner she does so much of the work for
me so that I can continue doing what I
do for you guys she's also a great
mother to my four children she also
takes great care of my home without her
the vision that I have for myself in my
life and in my business would not be
fulfilled and a big part of that also is
that we can't do these things by
ourselves you life is expressed through
the relationships that we have with
other people life is enhanced by the
relationships that we have with other
people on you know sexual but also
different levels friends family and in
my opinion in my experience everything
that I achieve is far more enhanced by
my ability to share it with those who I
love and those who have chosen to love
than if it was just me by myself so it
is not right or wrong whatever you
choose to do it's not a matter of you
know I'm right you're wrong or this is
the right choices - the wrong choice
it's a matter of perspective and right
now from your perspective from your
level of being able to see women in a
particular light all you are receiving
all you are gleaning is a warm vagina
there's so much more to it especially if
you look at the character of the
individuals look at the amount what
virtues and values you hold dear to
yourself and how they in conjunction
with that other person you seem like a
very business oriented man like no
bullshit kind of man find yourself a
no-bullshit kind of woman and together
you guys can create a super strong no
bullshit life and get things done good
luck