got this question from our buddies nut
dog and I and I'm smiling because I had
the same situation that he's dealing
with when I was a bit younger he's got a
friend that is a ladies man and wherever
they go girls always love his friend and
kind of ignores him right and it's
gotten so bad that even like our friend
our the dude that's asking the question
the girls that he comes to like
eventually just kind of say how do i
hook up with your friend all right so
the whole thing is that he can't seem to
hold tracked women and his friend is
just like a magnet porn and and now
what's happening is he's jealous he's
growing jealous of his friend and it
this is not resourceful for their
relationship as friends I guess right so
here's what here's what you got to do
this is this is my most practical advice
he has a gift right you cannot compare
yourself to someone who has a gift a guy
like that is clearly gifted in the the
process of bringing women close to him
right some guys has had that right and
as you say you're not a bad-looking guy
there's nothing wrong with you it's not
like you're kind of a weirdo there's
something you know obscure about the
your looks or your character or your
behavior it's just that your buddy is
fucking gifted that's like comparing
yourself to you know if I play football
preparing my comparing myself to like a
pro level NFL football player right
and I'm like 19 years old whatever the
case may be you're comparing yourself to
someone who's clearly got a gift that
you don't have and it's not fair to you
it's not fair to anyone it's not fair to
him it's not wearing it fair to anyone
especially yourself to compare yourself
to your gifted buddy now once you get
that get that through your head that
there's nothing wrong with you you just
have a friend that's really good at this
shit you got to go and figure out what
the hell am I good at because you are
good at something we all have gifts the
thing is that we live in a world where
there are certain gifts that are more
appreciated more highlighted than others
right
this is slowly changing because the
Internet has given his democratized
talent right basically you can now earn
a living and be well praised and have a
good life by being really good at
something that 10 20 years ago was like
no one's gonna pay you for that dude and
it's not I'm not even talking about just
getting paid what I'm saying is that you
should be able to express yourself and
feel good in expressing that gift that
you have and whenever you express
yourself and give you receive so it's
kind of you know like your buddy
it gives his gift of talking real well
or whatever kick you know how whatever
energy he gives out least often women
and he receives chicks you're going to
find your gift you have to you have to
it's it's our life's mission each one of
us till the day that we die to uncover
and develop the gifts that we have you
may have multiple you might only have
one or two but dabble with different
things try out different things
experiment experience and find out what
draws your heart because when your
friend sees you doing that thing he's
gonna grow jealous of your ability to do
that right what maybe you don't have
that like fix cars right you're just
really good at like taking apart engines
with your eyes closed and could put it
back together he's gonna be like fuck
man like I really wish I could do that
that's so fucking awesome that's great
there's gonna be a little bit of
jealousy there whatever the case may be
maybe you learn how to how to play the
mandolin and like you just you play so
so beautifully but you attract people to
you it's like man every time you play
that mandolin every crowds gather around
you I really wish I could do that hey
don't compare it you know how to get
chicks I can play this mandolin the
point is get over the comparison to
other people you've got to stop this
it's the most insidious form of slavery
that we do to ourselves we've been
taught it mind you but we do it to
ourselves we continue it by doing it to
ourselves and what I'm inviting you to
do is to stop that and then look for the
magnificence that's available in you and
growth
I hope that helps too