so we have yet another question from a
friend that doesn't know what to do with
himself hang out write his name hi so
apparently Kyle graduated high school
went to college to study art right of
all things art got to college first year
in sided I don't like this quit so then
he decides to go back a year or so later
to study drama of all things drama and
time goes on and he's ready to quit
what's to quit but his mom won't let him
because guess what now he loves
something else
he loves training weight training it's
all he can think about his training so
he doesn't know what to do now
that he's got to finish up this thing
that he doesn't like that he chose which
is drama and he wants to go and train
Kyle here's what I'm going to offer you
dude
there are a couple of red flags the fact
that you chose art and then you chose
drama and now you're into training all
are fairly creative type activities art
obviously I mean that's the
quintessential you just call it all art
drama is a branch of art training is a
form of art also because it is the
creation of your own body you're using
your body as a piece of art if you study
like I'm not Arthur Saxton but uh
Sando Eugene sendou he often talks about
the art of bodybuilding it really is an
art so you're moving in a direction that
your heart is carrying you you're doing
the right thing by moving into these
subject areas there's there's there's a
tint throughout there's there they're
related to each other so you're in touch
with what's going on in your body this
is good the problem is you're not being
grounded about your approach and you
might not know some of the rules about
taking a particular approach in a
direction right it might not be that
you're not a grounded person but you
don't know these things the secret that
I'm about to share with you so your
heart is going to lead you in a
particular direction and you seem to be
in touch with that because you keep
knocking at a very similar door but
that's where it ends
passion doesn't make shit happen passion
gets the ball rolling but commitment and
discipline gets the thing happening so
for example passion will get like two
people in bed right damn you a good damn
you look good I'm in love bang and
they're fucking right I mean this
happens all the time but 60% of people
get divorced because they don't realize
that what drew us together is just the
beginning
what jules together is actually it's
kind of a facade it's a little bit of a
trick nature played a trick Don trick on
you like with that chick and you like
you guys had sex and now you were
passionate about each other but now it's
gone that was a trick that was like
Cupid you know it's like made you stupid
you become pretty stupid when you become
passionate about something and it
doesn't mean that you don't want what
you're going after but all reasoning
gets thrown out the window right it's
like that I use love as an example
because love and sex is is very obvious
we all experience this at a visceral
level but when you have a passion about
something right a particular line of
study or an activity or vocation that
you want to move in the same thing
happens you become very passionate about
that thing I love training right I
guarantee you that if you quit drama and
you enter the training the same shit
would happen you'd fall out of love with
training just like everybody falls out
of love with the person they first fell
in
and you fell out of love with art then
you fill out in love with drama you're
going to fall out of love with training
because you don't realize that in order
for a true manifestation of the love
that you're sensing and feeling towards
a particular thing or a person to come
to fruition you've got to build the
character traits the virtues of
discipline and commitment marriage works
and building a business works and
becoming a tremendous artist in any
realm of the arts or or to any technical
skill if you want to be a musician you
want to build businesses you want to be
an entrepreneur
you want to be a architect whatever it
is it's developed in the period of pain
it's developed when you have experienced
the love and passion but then you put
the discipline and commitment to making
the thing happen to work okay now what
you got to do is you've got to remember
how good it felt in the beginning
especially when shit gets hard because
it's going to come full circle and I've
experienced this right I've explained to
you before that I've married my high
school girlfriend 14 years old when
you're 14 years old you're raging with
passionate hormones and that's all it
was when we were 14 years old who's like
God drew drew us together but for some
some reason I mean the stars line weird
things happen what the case may be we
stuck with each other through very
difficult times year after year after
year decade after decade even gave her a
long-ass time nobody does this but I
learned a secret by doing it we've had
some rough times I mean I just tell you
we have some tough times but for the
past Emerson is my second oldest three
year for five years but that's five
years it's been like five years of
fucking honeymoon because we've gotten
past all of the pain associated with
growing straight
in your ability to create to manifest
and it's like we're 14 again I'm with
each other like we're 14 again right
you're going to experience that again
with art if you stick with it you're
going to speed us out again with drama
if you stick with it you'll experience
that again with training if you stick
with it it comes full circle the problem
is everybody likes to start when nobody
likes to go the full fuckin circle it's
about that circle and you'll be happy
when you go through all the pain
associated with building the virtues see
you end up on the end of those end of
the spectrum or stronger version of
yourself because it's like damn I had to
be really committed to make this shit
happen right to be to be the best at
drama right whatever it is you choose I
had to be really disciplined there were
times I didn't want to do this thing
there gonna be times cuz now you're all
excited about training there any times
we don't want to do the fucking thing
right people who are married or in
relationship but you guys are young guys
and relationships you love you
girlfriend or 19 we're so in love with
each other trust me that shit dies that
fire dies bro that shit is gonna die
right but if you develop the commitment
and discipline associated with getting
through the tough times that have to be
set in front of you in order for you to
become a stronger version of yourself
not only will you re experience the love
associated with your young love and your
look young love for your vocation but
you'll be a stronger version yourself so
I'm ranting I think you get the point
right choose a thing because you love it
and then eventually you're going to hate
it but stick with it anyway because
you'll come full circle love it again
and you'll be a stronger version of
yourself because of it end of story
Elliot's it