what's up guys Elliott Hulse here in
another Sunday morning with Elliott said
what today we got a question about what
it's like to ride high and to crash down
low we've got a great question from one
of our friends who I think a lot of you
guys will resonate with his name's
Brendan he's 19 years old he goes to the
University of Binghamton where he's a
sophomore and his first year when he was
a freshman he really found himself he
started studying more philosophy and
motivational reading books by like Les
Brown and of course Osho and Alan Watson
so he's mixing a lot of these Western
and Eastern ideas about expanding the
mind and focusing the mind and he was
able to use that to his advantage during
his freshman year and really grow into
him into the stronger a stronger version
of himself achieving many goals and
doing really well really excited about
himself but then he goes on to describe
what happens next and that is summertime
so those you guys were familiar with
this man-made cycle man-made season of
especially for those of us who are in
school of beginning our activities in
the fall right and getting all motivated
with school and doing and doing and
doing it right and reaching a climax and
then coming back down where summertime
now we're now we can chill now we could
rest now we could do whatever we want
right we spent eight months nine months
doing what someone else wants us to do
right and we do the best that we can we
even use motivational tactics to get
ourselves to do that frigging thing
right get good grades be awesome be
fantastic be a leader I'm all about it I
believe in it I think that's great that
you want to be your best at whatever it
is that you're doing
but then all of a sudden right
especially if you're if you're doing
this thing like a gangster like yourself
Brandon you get to this point where man
I'm riding high but then it all comes to
an end because there's the end of the
semester right and what
happens next is critical to the rhythm
of your life and I've discovered this
personally not while I was in school I
was probably a bit too unconscious to
realize these shifts when I was in
school plus I played football so during
the summer it was pretty much you know
nose to the grinder during the summer
also but I noted I started to notice it
as an adult when my children started
going to school and and then coming out
of school during the summer and I hit me
the hardest Brendon the summer of 2013
and just for perspective many of you can
see that prior to the summer slump that
I had in 2013 that hit me like a ton of
bricks brother I share this with you
because I know where you're coming from
you can see that there was one version
of Elliot where I was what you all you
got to do is look at my face I was
leaner right I just I just look at my
face you know a lot about what's going
on with Elliott Hulse
right you'll have to see my whole body
you don't have to look into my mind but
my face was leaner and then I came back
in 2000
you know August the end of August
September 2013 and that's what I look
like and it was the first summer that I
rely got I even made a video at that
time talking about the depression I was
going through I really hit rock bottom
and it was difficult for me but I
learned a lot of things about myself a
lot of things about rhythms and a lot of
things about rituals that I want to
share with you here today
today Brendon so that you won't go
through this type of traumatic shift in
your physiology and you're energetic
strength and of course your life mastery
right all this works together so the
very first thing I want to share with
you is is my story how about I start
there that summer my kids got out of
school and and it was the first summer
actually that I had a little bit of
money right prior to that I mean we were
struggling to have money for vacations
and stuff like that and but that summer
of 2013 business started picking up a
little bit of people-watching more of my
videos and
was the first time I was able to take my
family on vacation right and I had been
working busting my ass for several years
up until this point part of the reason
probably why hit me so hard is because I
had been like in school you know that
grind mode since 2003 for when I first
moved out for like ten years like ten
years I was in school I was in the heat
that summer time didn't make a
difference to me but that summer 2013 my
kids were getting a little older they
got out of school I had a little money
and I decided we're going on vacation
I'm letting loose right yeah I know a
lot of you guys can relate to this and
it wasn't but the two weeks that I took
where I let my all of my patterns all of
my wit um's
all of my rituals go I figured hey I'm
gonna have a great time so I'm not going
to force discipline upon myself right
because discipline is one of these
things that you do cuz you got to do
right I mean you discipline yourself to
study you discipline yourself to clean
your room you discipline yourself to
brush your teeth depending on who you
are hey when it's vacation time right
when school lets out or when you go on a
you're your first let go vacation like I
did hey throw all that shit away right
cuz now we get to go wild a lot of
people this is how they operate on their
weekends right now and I'm discovering
what I'm going to share with you doesn't
relate just to these summer slumps
people hate mondays because Monday is a
slump too because of what I'm going to
share with you in a moment here related
to letting go too abruptly so anyway you
probably get the point that two weeks I
my sleeping patterns were off I was like
you know I wake up at 5 in the morning
during that those two weeks I said fuck
it I'm sleeping even if I don't need to
sleep I want to sleep right plus I was
sleeping a lot because well be
completely honest I was drinking a lot
all right prior to that I there were
many years where I didn't drink at all
right and you know at that point I just
just something I decided I'm gonna do
right
I'm gonna let it all out because I
wanted to feel that what it felt like to
- partying - just relax the way
Americans relax right the way people
relax the way we're conditioned to relax
which is with alcohol and slothfulness
so I did it I gave myself a chance to do
that so uh I also we took this trip I'll
let you know where our trip was we took
our car we drove because I couldn't find
before plane tickets we drove up the
east coast to Savannah Georgia and if
anybody knows anything about Savannah
Georgia the food is amazing man this is
where Paula Dean's restaurant was this
was actually the year that Paula Deen
got in trouble for being somewhat racist
but I didn't care I wanted some of her
southern good cooking some of us
southern fried racist cooking I didn't
care man that that food was incredible
right and funny thing is I saw a lot of
black people there a lot of black people
working there a lot of black people
eating there it seemed almost like you
know that was a media bullshit stunt to
throw that lady under the bus anyway I
took a picture with a cardboard version
of her and I ate all her fried chicken
and potatoes and shit but it didn't stop
there there are several great
restaurants in Savannah Georgia in
Atlanta Georgia because that's where we
went next and then we took a trip to
Tennessee right so you could imagine I'm
drinking Tennessee whiskey and eat drink
eating fried chicken all right what are
they they also like kool-aid down there
right tea sweet tea I was drinking sweet
tea
well anyway between letting my diet go
letting my sleeping rhythms go you know
any type of exercise was thrown out the
window I stopped exercising for those
two weeks I didn't meditate which was
you know it's very challenging to find
quiet time for yourself when you've got
four children in a hotel room right so
you know a part of it was logistics you
know item I couldn't exercise I couldn't
meditate so I really just wash my hands
and say yeah I'm just gonna let go and
man I came back from that summer
depressed you say here that you can't
you you seem to be caught in you're in
your thoughts this year as a sophomore
right and that just can't seem to get
the same rhythm going for yourself you
can't seem to get a foot the way you
want once were and your dinner and
you're not able to take action that's
really what you're you're worried about
you say you know you spend a lot of time
and thought but you're not able to take
action like you did you're wondering
what happened to you for the beginning
this sophomore year and a few things I
want to just share with you to offer you
the chance to have a bit more compassion
with yourself number one is that these
with um's are set up in a very arbitrary
way where you know you're you're taught
to you for 19 years dude you've been
taught to grind for a particular time
and then let go for a particular time
now you as a sophomore in college
college being that you came out of high
school last year and into your freshman
year dude you were filled with all kinds
of excited juices you are all jazzed up
your adrenals were riding high your
focus I mean think of it this way you're
in a brand new environment brand new
people brand new opportunity you could
reinvent yourself
freshman year college is an incredible
time because you really get to stand in
who you are so your motivation was high
that's one thing to just consider for
yourself to be objective about realize
that your level of motivation going into
your sophomore year just isn't going to
be as high and that's okay because
you're settling in really what you're
experiencing Ovie's for is heat four
years is you're settling into and
allowing yourself to become a different
version of yourself that first year dude
that's it the momentum good for you a
lot of people go into that freshman year
then they shit the bed they can't do it
you set yourself up with high momentum
and I believe that your freshman year is
indicative of what the overall
experience for your college is going to
be because
that's in you that's when you explode it
that's when you shine it's there the
other thing that I want to share that is
going to lend you to a bit more
compassion for self is that you're going
to be a different version of yourself
through each cycle alright it's it's
natural to ride high and come down right
sometimes it's definitely natural to do
this sometimes the way it happens is
based on unnatural clocks but what
happens is when you I've done this so
many times with my fingers in these
videos when you go up right I'm up I'm
riding high and then you come down
you're not going to start again at the
same circle right you're not good life
doesn't look like this life is not this
right so you're not the same version
yourself you can't expect yourself to be
who you were during the last cycle
it won't happen you have new experiences
you're older your physiology changes all
kinds of shit happens but the ego like
you refer to wants to attach to what was
you had a great year last year but let
it go because it's no longer you're not
that person anymore
you've got to allow yourself to go
through whatever you're going through
right now to reemerge on the right
timetable as a stronger version of
yourself just because summer ended
doesn't mean that you're supposed to
come back up on that next circle you
might still be going down and I invite
you to have some compassion for with
yourself while you're still down because
if we try to force ourselves back up we
are we're stunting the process we will
destroy the process because now we're
trying to make the thing happen it's
almost like the story with the butterfly
right if you let the butterfly while
it's still in its cocoon slowly emerge
and little pieces stick out and then all
of a sudden it built it it turns into
the beautiful butterfly great it takes
some time but if you get in there you
out of ego compassion Rika's consumption
sometimes you
it's purely our ego that's trying to
help you see that butterfly trying to
get out you see its little wing stick
gal you say oh I'm going to help that
butterfly come out of there you start
fucking with the cocoon peeling it open
the butterfly ain't gonna come out right
his body's gonna be swollen and fatness
its wings are going to be short and you
just destroyed its life it's perverted
it's screwed up you messed with it when
you're coming out of these down spots
these dark spots these slumps you've got
to allow the process to happen watch it
unfold you read a lot of books on
meditation you say well this would be a
great time to just watch be the watcher
right this is as far as your brain is
concerned now with that perspective here
are a few things that are the most
important to maintain throughout your
life in order to avoid a very difficult
sting with these these drops with these
dark times it's all about maintaining
ritual you've got to choose now I'll
share with you mine I'll share mine with
you but you've got to maintain whatever
you find to be the most resourceful
rituals for you to continue with a
positive rhythm in your life right now
based on the story I told you about me
and going to Georgia I realized after
that summer number one I can't fuck with
my sleep patterns if I begin distorting
my sleep patterns which means for sure
get to bed before midnight right I mean
that's a that's a hard and fast rule
that I denied this point I never defy
that right I don't care who I last year
during the Shred camp summit when we had
all I had a bunch of guests man me and
my wife were out there and we were we
were partying and we were dancing it was
a great time midnight came and I said
babe let's go we got and I started
hugging and shaking hands
there you go it's midnight you've got to
have particular principles for yourself
you your own you hold fast to your own
law right and one law for me there's no
go to bed past midnight your respect I
can avoid it I can walk out of here but
for sure I get to bed before 10:00
usually by 9:30 every single night today
Sunday you know what time I went to bed
Saturday night 9:30 not because I don't
have friends and better shit to do well
it's not better there's nothing better
there's nothing better than can
maintaining my rhythm other shit to do
right that other people want to do it's
because I know I'm gonna wake up and I'm
gonna maintain this stride imagine I'm
running this sprint man I'm gonna
maintain my stride I've got to maintain
my rhythm so your sleep-wake patterns
have everything to do with your
physiology bro
absolutely your hormones are dictated by
the positions of the Sun and your your
adhering to that rhythm right you're
wide awake staring at screens at 3:00 in
the morning dew' in the morning
you're fucking with the biological
rhythms right your pineal gland the
master gland is associated with sleep
weight cycles right the third eye I call
you third fucking eye your third eye has
everything to do with light sensitivity
right and if you're blaring light on
your master gland your pineal gland then
you're going to have a cascading effect
they call it the master gland because
it's the one that precedes all of the
others you want to fuck up your adrenals
fuck with your sleep-wake cycles fuck
with your third eye you want to fuck up
your digestive system which is a
byproduct of the adrenals I mean it goes
from here right down there and so you're
releasing catabolic hormones when you
should be releasing anabolic hormones
and you're releasing an about well you
probably aren't releasing anabolic
hormones at all because that requires
rest and digest that requires darkness
sleep yielding sleeping right so if you
got that all screwed up right away your
your over catabolic you're over
stimulated over over sympathetic right
you're beating the fuck out of yourself
and you're burning the candle at both
ends
let me put it that way so sleep-wake
rhythms essential you finished school
and you look at when you were going to
bed when you were in school and when you
go home for summertime you go to bed at
the same time now because you could
sleep late you stay up late you maintain
that rhythm this isn't a commandment
from hosts this is it's a pretty good
fucking idea cuz it's true right it's
biologically aligned right the next one
my man is maintain your your diet
maintain your diet schedule maintain how
you're eating through as much as you can
throughout the year right that two weeks
that two weeks man is all took for me
while I was in Georgia eatin puddin and
sweet tea threw me the fuck off cuz once
again my physiology was off right my
digestive system Hat is having to go to
work I'm releasing more insulin than I
probably had in many years right I
gained like 20 pounds I swelled up
retained to hold out of water and got
sick in the head I really guy couldn't
figure out what was going on with me I
was depressed if I remember I'll link
the video down here but um you know
search my science channel those of you
guys who know fact-finder's go find that
video where Elliott Hulse is sitting in
his car after seeing dr. Glazer was my
psycho analyst and talking about being
depressed well in retrospect right when
I made that video I was just being
transparent cuz that's what I do but in
retrospect months later I was like
another water I was fuckin depressed and
then exercise right your rhythms your
diet your exercise bro there shouldn't
be a day that goes by that your heart
rate doesn't become elevated to some
degree for some amount of time you might
not be pumping iron you might not be you
know in your club sport at school
but definitely get out there and jog get
out there and walk get out there and do
sprint intervals get into some body
weight calisthenics you know wake up
every morning and do some do a circuit
that also has a tremendous effect on
your hormonal rhythms right because when
you when you exercise when the Sun comes
up right here's how it works when the
Sun comes up you're to become more
anabolic your body releases and I'm
sorry catabolic this is your adrenaline
which I'll have a lot of this morning
your adrenaline your cortisol these are
these are energizing hormones
now when that Sun comes up and those
energizing hormones rise in your body
you got to take full advantage of it
we're designed to rise with the Sun and
blaze all day not blaze but blaze be
excited shine and put it that way you
blaze around 4:20 that's when the Sun
starts going down right so you allow
yourself to really be fully expressive
during the daytime so that right when
the Sun starts setting your body can
settle down when I'm exercising when I'm
in a good exercise routine by the time
you know
seven o'clock 7:30 runs around comes
around I'm scratching my eyes I'm like
oh boy it was a hard day so I'm hitting
the ground I'm hitting the bed I'm going
down here I'm going to sleep I'm coming
in a ballot because guess what five
o'clock the next morning Bing I'm up I
get up a little bit earlier than the Sun
rises which is yeah it's not abiding
completely so it's really rise with the
Sun but Sun doesn't rise with 7:30
around here right now and uh man that
hour two hours I can get a hell of a lot
done so uh and I love getting up early
man I love nothing more than getting up
early having my cup of coffee saying
some prayers reading some books just
being by myself and I have a window
right by my dopin by my chair and I can
just watch the Sun come up
right either that or I go for a walk all
right just to energize the body like I'm
telling you right now I walk by the bay
and I watch the Sun come up I'm the Sun
is rising in me life is rising in me as
life is rising right you see how
exercise becomes a lifestyle exercises
who we are we have these arms and legs
so that we can move right locomotion
that's the whole reason why we have
bodies to get out there and do stuff so
our physiology is designed to be most up
to run most optimally when we actually
do that bro and that's it don't wanna
overwhelm you all right it's got a lot
of school work to do you're already
overwhelmed so number one have some
compassion for yourself and realize that
you're never going to be who you were
last year let that guy die I know how
hard that is
I remember how popular and pleasing
Elliott Hulse was yo Elliott was so many
of you it's not easy to let go of very
pleasing part of you you had all these
friends right you are RN you were leader
of the pack you were doing all kinds of
cool shit and everybody the greatest the
hardest thing to do is to change in the
face of those who appreciate you hey
Brendan where is the old Brandon where's
the worst that's not the Brandon I know
where is that motivated Brendan well
fuck you he's dead it's a year later
you're allowed to be different a year
later especially when you've had
experiences that give you wisdom and
right now man the wisdom of your body
says allow the process to happen and get
familiar and disciplined and committed
with your rituals
done