got a really tough an interesting
question from one of our buddies so
here's here goes
he's had a friend with benefits
basically a hidden girlfriend you know
they're kind of friends in front of the
public in the public eye but undercover
they're smooching and kissing and doing
lord knows what right so he calls her
friend with benefits
now she's growing a bit more attached
emotionally to him you know at first it
was just hey let's experiment and uh you
know we're friends and my didn't let's
touch each other's private parts and now
she's a she's becoming attached the
problem is he and he likes her too
he's like well you know this is getting
deep whenever you share sexual energy
with someone especially someone that you
see on a regular basis it really draws
the relationship tight it's close
especially searching for a woman because
women open themselves up so whenever you
have sex with a woman you know
regardless of how callous she might be
she opened herself up to you and there's
a vulnerability there you know men it's
a little different but still you shared
your energy with her and you're growing
heart warming feelings towards her right
the problem right so that's cool yeah
what do you do you know you make my
girlfriends what do I not the problem is
according to his friends who don't know
that he's screwing her have making love
to her that's better way to put it cuz I
don't want you to screw this chick think
she's ugly right he said I mean that's
the word you used as ugly not
unattractive he's got warm feelings
towards her he's having sex with her she
wants to be with him but his friends say
she's an ugly chick you know cuz they
don't know that's his girlfriend so the
very first thing is the N and I
understand because you know he goes on
to say look I you know being a
principled person is one thing but I'm
young he's in high school and reputation
the way I look in front of people is
important and it totally is I get that
now I'm gonna give you one perspective
and give you one action one behavior
it's an alpha fucking attitude then we
share with you but you're gonna take
with you for the rest of your life the
very first thing is if your friends knew
how you felt about her they would never
say those things about her you know a
part of the reason why they may say
those things about her she's ugly and
unattractive maybe
because at an energetic level they sense
that there may be warm feelings towards
you you know with each other and they're
jealous right so they're saying mean
things about her and they see you're
friends with her it's because there's an
air of jealousy there right so fuck them
but another way that you're going to
approach this because that's just a
perspective just realize it you know
honestly it doesn't matter because if
people are retarded they'll say one
thing and flip there they'll flip their
station and you know what and it may be
a way for them to control you also they
see that you could possibly be happy
with this girl you know at a deep level
they probably it's probably not very
conscious but they sense it that you
could be happy with this girl and
they're doing everything that they can
to keep you away from her because
they're you know there's happiness joy
associated that people are haters
they're just jealous of you okay and and
let's say in reality let's say she is
genuinely ugly right and you know that
beauty is in the eye of the beholder but
let's say like you know oh you know it's
it's tough looking at her whenever you
have strength of conviction whenever you
put your foot down and you make a stance
about something you believe in people
will follow you no matter how crazy it
may sound you could say the craziest
most asinine shit and you lead an entire
nation to work on extinguishing a race
of people rights happened before you
mean it's happening right now you know
but anyway the point is yours your
strength of conviction you stand up
there like Barack Obama and you say this
is the way it is and this way it's gonna
be and you you daughter better fall in
line otherwise you're against us if
you're not with us you're against us but
you stand up there and you speak from
your balls you speak with that type of
conviction you let people know what you
believe in without being hysterical
about it being grounded about it they're
going to say yes sir yes sir yes sir do
you understand it's your strength of
conviction that gets people to yield to
your demands your commands and the
direction you're moving in life you've
got to be confident in your decisions
you got to sometimes literally brain
wash yourself to believe in the
direction that you're moving in so if
you choose to make this woman which I
think it would be the right thing to do
do you know she's opened herself up to
you you have more feelings towards her
you should at least give her the respect
offer her the respect of taking her to
the prom like you mentioned you know you
wanted to or letting people know hey you
know what I really like this girl I have
one feeling so her you owe her that if
she opened her body and energy up
towards you but anyway you know
principles aside alpha positioning alpha
pretentiousness up front you make firm
decisions and you put your foot in it
and you stare people in the eye when you
do it you say this is what I think this
is what I believe this is the position
I'm taking and you're either with me or
you're against me it is an attitude
about what you're doing it's not about
right or wrong it's not about true or
false
it's about your conviction when you have
conviction of strength you can take
anything any decision any direction
you're moving in and people will respect
you