so today we have a common but equally
disturbing question from one of our
friends who says he wants to start his
life all over again he says that he is
experiencing in his life this inability
to handle criticism he says that every
time someone yells at him a boss or so
forth he freezes and blacks out you
can't really speak up and an assert
himself in any particular way either at
work at school with friends with
girlfriends people just seem to like
walk all over him here's a strange thing
he's about six foot four he's a big dude
but yet he's like a big baby in many
ways he's saying that he just can't get
along in circumstances where he has to
man up I guess you would say and he goes
on to describe his childhood and I think
that's why this is a really critical
question to deal with and the reason why
I say that it's it's disturbing because
when I read your story my friend I
realized that there's a significant
reason why and I'm sure you're aware of
this reason why you hold yourself so
poorly why you carry yourself with such
a lack of vigor vitality and strength
and ability to be yourself and to stand
your ground in a world that will step
all over you if you can't do that he
says that he grew up in a home where his
parents constantly fought and were very
violent with each other his earliest
memories are sitting in a couch and
watching his parents just tear at each
other and he says this went on his
entire life I don't understand why these
people stayed together but essentially
he says he just spent his entire life
being almost a a referee peeling his
parents off of each other he has younger
siblings and he had to be the protector
in the home in many ways because he had
to protect his mother from his father
and vice versa because he was the oldest
the biggest one he had to physically
become engaged with this violence in his
home and and you could just imagine as a
small child you know maybe six seven
eight nine years old to have people
screaming and shouting and attacking
each other in your midst and you're
there vulnerable with an inability to
even understand what's going on because
your world is is is flooded with
violence it's shaking and quaking all
around you and you feel as if you need
to do something but you just don't know
what the fuck to do just imagine you're
nine years old and you're experiencing
this what do you do but this is the way
he grew up and now as a six foot four 23
year old man he goes out into the world
and he's a doormat the very first thing
I'd like to do is briefly describe the
nature of what you've experienced
physiologically a lot of the ideas I'm
going to share with you right now come
from Roberts care in a fantastic book
called the body bears the burden and you
know how much I'm enrolled in the idea
that the body is the mind and my friend
the way you're carrying your body the
way you're breathing the way you're
being from the neck down is something
that we need to consider far more than
what new stories we can tell ourselves
the experiences that you've had have
already happened but they're trapped in
your body and they're trapped in the way
you're expressing yourself and the lack
of ability to express yourself that
you're experiencing here's how this
happens to us all in some way shape or
form physiologically trauma loosely
defined by scare is experiencing an
event that is threatening in the face of
your own vulnerability meaning some
crazy shit just happened and you can't
do anything about it so this could be
from being real nine years old and your
parents are tearing it at each other
attacking each other and you're a kid
you do what are you gonna do you can't
fight you can't run so you freeze or it
could be as severe as being sexually
molested as a child seeing someone
killed in front of you when you were
very young it could be absolutely
anything that was hurtful in the face of
vulnerability and that that second half
in the face of vulnerability is very
important
because most of the trauma that we carry
with ourselves in adulthood come from
when we were most vulnerable that's
where your children and what ends up
happening and I'm going to describe
broadly and then go specific what ends
up happening is we carry in our bodies
in our implicit memory so when I say our
body I'm referring to our implicit
memory body memory the same sort of body
memory that allows you to ride a bike
even if you haven't ridden a bike in 20
years
the same sort of body memory that allows
you to walk you have to remind yourself
how to walk again
the same sort of body memory that when
you smell fresh-baked cookies you
remember grandma these are all things
that are not explicit they're not
declarative memory you don't have to
pick it out of the rolodex of your
memory it's in your body and the
experiences that we have specifically
when we are vulnerable we're in a
vulnerable state has the capacity has a
tremendous capacity to become trapped in
our implicit memory in our body in our
unconscious or our peripheral nervous
system these are all interchangeable
words to describe the intelligence in
your body that is not declarative the
intelligence that that beats your heart
digest digest your food grows a baby
inside you you have to understand you
have to appreciate you have to at least
consider if you're the type that wants
to dismiss many of the ideas they share
these videos that there is a significant
you know they say that we you know
they've used this example of the iceberg
and that just the tip of the iceberg is
what we can declare as our consciousness
and then everything else is our
unconscious if you look at our bodies
it's basically the same way this is the
tip of the iceberg down here is the meat
of the issue our peripheral nervous
system our emotion the implicit memory
all these things are found down in the
90% that we don't declare so again that
was very broad but specifically I want
to describe what happens to you my
friend physiologically when you
periods your parents your world tearing
itself apart when you were in a
vulnerable state as a child you have a
response called a sympathetic response
to any threat and it's called fight or
flight thank you you've heard this
before you know when you're you're posed
with a threat you'll either fight or
you're you'll fight you'll run those are
the two things that you that are
typically at your disposal when there is
a threat you girl you go crazy or you
boom and run but there's a third
response that we've come to know very
well and is very scientifically
documented and it's called the freeze
response the freeze response is very
very very critical to the trapping and I
use this term trapping that's my word
the trapping or the embedding of the
trauma into your implicit memory here's
why the fight or flight response is
sympathetic meaning that it's very
active you can run or you can fight it's
stress-related and it's active the
freeze is very parasympathetic meaning
you you stop completely
you freeze or you go into a the
processes that are that are less active
less expressively active in your body so
your parasympathetic branch of your
nervous system slows down your heart
rate it slows down your breathing it
helps you digest your entire digestive
system is run by this branch of your
nervous system it's all the resting type
stuff the thing is about that
parasympathetic branch of our nervous
system is as I described it's found in
our body implicit memory is found in our
body once again so here you have a
situation where you're experiencing a
freeze response and I guarantee this is
what happened your parents are attacking
each other and you're like because
that's what a nine-year-old is if it's
available to the nine year old to do
there's a threat and you're vulnerable
what are you can do you just sat there
and you watched when you were in that
freeze response it's a very interesting
thing what they've discovered is that
it's not just a passive freeze freezing
right because there's a difference
between resting or true parasympathetic
similar behavior would be sleeping right
resting that's truly parasympathetic
sympathetic is right a freeze looks like
this it's an active stopping of your of
the the physiological responses in your
body meaning you want to run and you
want to fight you want to do this and
run and get out of there because it's a
fucking mess in the house but you can't
because there's a simultaneous
stimulation of the parasympathetic
branch your nervous system that makes
you freeze so you know what it's like
and onto it's like and onto driving a
car getting into a car putting your foot
on the accelerator and the other foot on
the brake so imagine you put the car in
drive you step on the accelerator and
the brake at the same time right you
know what it looks like
ah there's a lot of shit going on but
you can't move once again let me remind
you that that parasympathetic branch of
the nervous system that forces you not
to move that is like the break on the
sympathetic response or the accelerator
is where implicit memory is stored what
that means is all that would have
typically happened in this
fight-or-flight response is going on
physiologically in your body you are
releasing adrenaline and cortisol the
whole HPA access thing is happening and
your implicit memory is absorbing it all
because you're not you're frozen
you've got the parasympathetic and
sympathetic going on at the same time
and one is going nuts the other one that
is stopping it from going nuts is
absorbing the craziness I hope you see
how profound that is how much of an
incredible discovery this is and how
with this understanding we can
confidently move in the direction of
releasing the trauma in your body what
happens in that freeze response is a
number of things but overriding all of
the more specific things that we'll talk
about in a moment is a form of learned
helpless helplessness learned
helplessness your fucking helpless right
what do you do you can't do anything
this is an evolutionary response by the
way that is very very very primal
meaning that animals do the same thing
in it and this is how these ideas were
dispersed discovered by Peter Levine
he'd watch animals in the wild and if
they were attacked in a situation where
there's nothing that they could do like
a deer right being attacked by a
predator oftentimes the deer would just
if it got tapped by the by the predator
it would just lay there now it's not
dead yet but it won't fucking move it
won't help itself part of the reason why
it does that and why we do that is
because it's self-protection
because if the animal decided to get up
and fight back or run the tiger seems
like haha fuck you I got you as opposed
to sometimes the the predator will just
sniff around and be like fuck you and
walk away or just figure you're dead and
then just drag you back to your to
wherever it wanted to go and maybe it
turns us back for a moment that you can
get up and run this is all very this is
all very primal this is all happening at
hour at a base level meaning the base of
our skull are are the medulla the
Chilean complex of the brain your brain
stem so on and so forth the the limbic
system also is highly involved here
because the amygdala is the part of the
brain that that is that stores that
implicit memory okay that's part of the
limbic system so what do you do my
friend now you're 23 years old you've
got this trauma trapped in your body in
your Paris of the parasympathetic branch
you're nervous or your your I keep
saying that but I mean the the central
and peripheral the peripheral nervous
system your body is trapped in your body
it's how you were breathing the way
you're breathing is associated with that
trapped trauma the way you're walking is
associated with the trap trauma the way
your eyes look when you look someone in
the eyes or your lack of ability thereof
it is a form of the implicit memory
trapped in your body due to the severe
repetitive trauma you experienced as a
child so what do you do do you talk
about it do you think about it you know
what one of the things that I I used to
think was available to us just toughen
up just get over it toughen up and get
over right easier said than done and I
know this because a lot of my language
sounds that way but I'm very empathetic
for all of this because I have a deep
understanding of what goes on
physiologically and what needs to
actually be done to get over yourself
get over that freeze response get over
in
sit trauma you're carrying with yourself
sometimes you just need to man the fuck
up and do something but doing something
means physically doing something
sometimes you are trapped in a traumatic
state and it's just a matter of look the
only way you're going to get out of that
fucking fog that depression is if you
just shut up and do something a lot of
times we want to talk talking and
thinking about shit is all declarative
I'm saying go implicit motherfucker get
in your body and do something what do
you do let's go home for a moment
because that's always my very first
invitation come home to yourself meaning
get by yourself or get with a really
skilled trauma release therapist or
bioenergetic coach to work you through
what physical actions need to be taken
to get the trauma out of your physical
body the type of therapy I describe and
invite you to engage and study for
yourself I give you plenty of resources
here and to find professionals who
support you with are not about talking
it's not about thinking it's about doing
it's about getting into your body and
allowing the demons if you will exercise
right think about that word exorcise the
demons out of your nervous system
exercises movement you've got to do
getting the demons out of course it's a
metaphor right I say demons but it's
trapped trauma it's trapped emotions and
when you come home to this it's going to
be scary it's going to be confusing you
know again like I say it's an ongoing
process so study find mentors to support
you this way watch my videos I stare you
guys in this direction this is these are
the directions that have supported me in
my life and that's why I share them with
you through these videos I'm not trying
to prove anything here everything I
share with you is something that has
been of support to me
and when I hear your issues I hear your
problems I hear your concerns all I can
offer is here's how I've dealt with it
what this therapy looks like what this
exercise looks like is very much what
you've some of the craziest shit you see
me do on video which is throwing temper
tantrums get the best way to start is
with the fucking temper tantrum you need
to allow yourself to completely release
threw a temper tantrum get on your bed
start moving your head side to side and
arms up and down and legs up and down
and let the sounds associated with it
carry you to where you need to go you
might break down into tears you might
you might break out into an expression
of confusion who fear don't judge it
don't think about it don't try to
rationalize it allow the thing to happen
in your body your body is intelligent
watch from afar
watch as if you are another an onlooker
and see yourself going through the
trauma
you'll get up afterwards and you'll just
feel like you took a shower that
cleansed your soul don't judge it if
you're if you're if you're objective
enough about yourself like I am
obviously to watch yourself go through
this shit you will end up on the other
end when you get up after you'll be
tired afterwards but you'll get up and
you'll feel as if you're floating on air
because you've released all the tension
in your muscular system that's holding
you back from saying yes to life and
know when you should put your foot down
those are really the two things you need
to gain back but if you've got muscular
tension associated with the implicit
memory of trauma you're not going to be
able to say yes with all of your yes and
you're not going to be able to say no
with all of your no you're going to be
someone who's pushed around
dawn and uses the doormat for the rest
of your life my friend
so that's it take some time to
understand the nature of all of our
pathology and it's all neuropathology
just to be a part of this civilization
just to live in this machinery to be a
part of this matrix our nervous systems
had to be damaged and I'm not judging it
as good or bad I'm saying that we're all
experiencing forms of trauma that does
not allow us to be the strongest version
of ourselves some more potent than
others yours my friend is very obvious
and very potent which makes it easy for
you to go right to the root of what's
holding you back from becoming the
strongest version of yourself study my
resources I'm in the midst of putting
together a book not because I need to
sell a book but because I need to put
all these ideas into one place so that I
can say to you read my book read it
because all my resources are in there
all the ideas that have supported me in
becoming the strongest version of myself
including what I happen to find be the
most important key the cornerstone the
foundation to becoming the strongest
version yourself and that is dealing
with the psychological emotional
energetic if you will processes of the
individual there's hope for you my
friend there's great hope for you but
you're going to need some courage and
you need to deal with the demons that
you're carrying with yourself and you
got to recognize that you can't talk
about it you can't think about it you
got to do it you got to exercise it
carry these words with you never give up
on yourself continuously grow stronger
if it's digging yourself out of a hole
or climbing a mountain you're always on
the move to bigger and better
and stronger versions of ourselves grow
stronger my friends
done