so a really tough question from our
buddy who I'll keep anonymous he goes on
to say that he's had a girlfriend for
quite some time
and he needs to break up with her the
problem is that she's suicidal she has
bipolar and other mental disorders he
describes it as recently her father died
from an overdose of heroin she's dropped
out of school he no longer wants to be
with her but the guilt associated with
breaking off the ties with a girl that's
this damaged with the likelihood that
she might choose to take her life you
know having such a devastating loss of
her father to begin with being
imbalanced mentally and then to lose
what he says is the only person in her
life right now but he's got to move on
because it's wreaking havoc on his life
his life is being destroyed by the fact
that he's carrying her along how does he
do it
oh dude probably one of the tougher
questions I've been asked and I really
had to think long and hard about it and
I I started remembering a movie that I
watched when I was a kid I may have
mentioned this in a video in the past
but uh it's a really funny but the movie
is called Harry and the Hendersons okay
and Harry and the Hendersons is a story
about a family you know man and his wife
and their children who were camping one
day and they they run their car into
something boo boo boo boo he figures
it's a deer he late at night he runs
into something he gets out of the car he
goes and sees what it is and what is
laying in front of him is a nine-foot
man-beast they call a Bigfoot all right
a sasquatch
those who are familiar this is like a
mythical creature I think but people say
they've seen it which is like just like
a giant half monkey half man that is big
and hairy and lives somewhere in the
woods anyway so the story goes that he
runs into this frigging thing and I
think they don't know what to do they
don't want to leave it there they're
freaked
scout so they bring it home and nurse
this sasquatch this animal this beast
slash man in their home and they say and
they take care of it and and they begun
need to begin to love this thing
it grows healthy and it sites in their
home and it's like it's it's creeping
around and it's it's weird it's funny
but it's loving and it but it's also a
beast it's also an animal that if the
neighbors recognize this beast this
animal living in their house all hell
would break loose they enjoy its
presence but it's making their life hell
the man has to make a choice he's like
my children can't be raised with this
animal in our home we've come to love it
but it's ruining our family it's ruining
what could potentially be a decent life
for my children and for my life and for
myself so it's got to go the whole movie
is about how much they love this thing
towards the end of the movie they got to
get rid of it and it's sad it's
heartbreaking and like you know you're
watching the movie I must've been about
ten years old when I watch a movie and
you're like man no don't get rid of
Harry don't get rid of Harry and the
dads like I gotta do it I have to do it
I can't keep this beast in my house
rightfully so
I get it so they drive Harry out to the
to the forest where they bumped into him
Harry gets out of the car the dad gets
out the car and the dad is like you have
to go get out of here go and here he's
like oh I love you you can't speak he
does who and the kids are in the car
crying and the mothers like wow if we
love Harry but Harry's got to go and the
guys like get out of here get out of
here and here is like my hair I just
want to leave so the man cocks back he
goes back punches Harry in his fucking
face and hair is like so disappointed so
broken hit the man his heart is broken
cuz he just punched in the face
something that he's come to love and
appreciate but can't stick around
because his life is going to be ruined
and Harry puts his head down and walks
away
I cried it's one of those circumstances
where your heart is torn and of course
I'm you know I'm likening your
circumstances which is about a human
being who's in dire straits that you've
brought into your home you've healed but
is now ruining your life with the with
the movie in a fictional creature but
the sentiments the same the essence is
the same and it's a good segue to the
sentiment of your actions the essence of
what your actions have to be even though
I'm giving you the the content of a
movie about a big mythical feature and
you and your suicidal girlfriend notice
how the content is just a story the
content is just the surface the essence
is what's important you I cried about
them about the stupid movie the essence
is the same
the roots are the same your you love
this thing you brought it into your home
but it's ruining your life if you kick
it out it could potentially be hurt also
out in the world but you can't keep it
because your life is going to be ruined
the essence the sentiment the spirit
behind everything really points to the
deeper reality of it the principles of
the circumstance however you want to
describe it the sentiment from which the
man preceded where he was coming from
when he punched Harry in the face was a
place of deep and profound love and
respect for the creature but also
self-preservation which is no less
valuable
you've got to preserve yourself to be
able to live in life it's our movie
safety and survival is our most base
it's at the bottom of the of the
hierarchy of needs safety and survival
if your safety and survival is being
challenged by a situation in this way
you're going to revert to taking care of
yourself and it's okay there's nothing
wrong with that in fact
it's great because that means that you
can go off and do other work this is
tough and of course you know not
everyone's going to agree with me I
don't expect you to these are just it's
just an idea of perspective perhaps that
might support you so with that
understanding and with knowing that how
you go about it is more important than
what you do who you are is more
important than what you do the essence
is more important than the circumstances
you got to kick her out obviously but
with love and prayer and that's my
advice to you you have to get rid of her
you know you have to get rid of her I'm
not telling to get rid of her you told
me you have to get rid of her I'm giving
you a way to get rid of her without the
guilt that's going to be associated with
it and with actually sending it up
sending her on her way with absolutely
the best thing you can give her and that
is a loving part parting even if it
means punching her in the face and what
I said I say punching in her face like
this meaning like you just have to be
harsh like what you've got to go
don't punch on the face but you get my
point and pray for her I know that
sounds crazy right
fucking Elliot what is he talking about
pray send out good vibes for her success
close the door behind her and say in
your heart I deeply wished the best for
this woman feel it in your body I spoke
recently in many videos past couple
weeks
about vibrations if you set out send out
loving feelings to her you're doing a
number of things you're cultivating
loving feelings within yourself and when
you do anything with love as the
overriding principle you can never feel
guilty
you can never feel guilty when you allow
your heart to dictate the the the
essence when you come from your heart so
you'll feel good about the choice no
matter what happens to her because and
you need to continuously do this because
you're continuously
sending out loving vibrations to her
loving feelings loving energy it's for
you and it's for her so whatever happens
to her out there know that you did it
the absolute best that you could do with
what tool you have at your hell what you
can actually do you can't keep her
you can't send her money you can't
protect her it's her life but you can
love her you can send prayers in her
direction that's what prayer is prayer
is sending your vibrations in a
particular direction thinking about
something being about something when you
can't physically do something about it
right prayer doesn't I'm not talking
worship prayer I'm talking sending out
your sentiment and when you send her on
your way pray for her and pray for her
again and when guilt comes in those
guilts going to come in pray for her
again and if she tries to come back keep
the door closed
and pray for her those who have ears I
pray that you hear me done