what's up gentlemen today we have a
question for one of our friends who says
that he's upset with the lack of
appreciation that comes his way
especially from people that he's helped
tremendously in their lives why is it
that I can extend all of my energy love
and resources in your direction and not
even get a thank-you from you I'm angry
now
hey and anybody who has children knows
exactly how that feels also and that's
where I'll begin my friend because I've
been in your shoes I've extended all of
my energy time resources to go above and
beyond to support my children in
becoming the strongest version
themselves right many parents will agree
they'll nod their heads they'll say this
yeah you know I I give my children 10
times more than I got I spoil them with
vacations and knifes clothing and digits
and gadgets and toys and things but they
act as if they don't even appreciate it
this is where we are and I know this is
your friend it's a bit different these
are people who you show you've decided
to share your life with although they
don't come from you they're not the
fruits of your loin when you have
children it's kind of like well yeah
it's your fucking cake you got to take
care of it but it is a deep primordial
human need to receive appreciation
especially in the direction that you've
offered your energy or so it would seem
here's how I personally reconcile this
and this is going to be my offer to you
my friend when you're offering yourself
to someone when you're giving them your
love because that's really what it is
you're giving them your loving the in in
the form of time in the tour in the form
of resources money in the form of energy
exercise you're using yourself to better
their circumstance in any way shape or
form you're giving them love you do it
not because of what you're going to
receive back and definitely not because
of what you're going to receive back
from that person but because of how you
feel when you're doing it I gotta tell
you when I spoil my
it's I feel great kids were going on
vacation they're like then they start
fighting with each other I'm like what
the fuck I just told you we're gonna do
something awesome and this but you know
what I have to separate myself from
their reaction to what I've chosen to do
you see you got to remember that you
chose to help your friend I chose to
have all these fucking kids and I'm
choosing to do things for them I choose
because I want to do it this is my ideal
this is the life I want to create I want
to do these things you help your friends
because you wanted to do it remember
that and if you can remember that you
chose to do it you know who soothes you
yourself it's a self soothing sacrifice
when you give yourself to someone else
like the alliteration they're just made
that up
it's a self soothing sacrifice when you
what I say serve someone else you do it
for you and the only way that you're
going to be open to receiving that
self-soothing is to recognize before you
even go into the circumstance where
you'll serve them that your self
soothing you're doing it because love is
happening in you and you want to
exercise it not because they're going to
send you a thank you card or pat you on
your back it's like this with everything
I say pat on the back will you look at
the achievements that you have in the
world as an entrepreneur you get used to
this as someone who works for themselves
you get used to this you have a success
and all you want is a fucking pat on the
back but you got to remember yourself
soother you did it because you want to
do it I wanted to do it I wanted to make
this happen
you know what I make these videos often
times and they're unappreciated well not
by all but sometimes I'll read through
the comments and it's Ellie your
dickhead face dick face asshole
Elliott you don't know the fuck you're
talking about Elliott I don't know why
anybody listens to you Elliott Bubba
Ellie Ellie Ellie oh you suck Elliott
Elliott you're why don't you two stop
making videos
I could very easily take that as a lack
of appreciation from a percentage of the
people that I seek to serve and stop
I'll never do it again this is what
people do I'll never do it again because
I have no appreciation you know what I
have come to grips with I just love
making these fucking videos I do it
because I like to do it I'm very selfish
in that way you think I'm doing this cuz
I love you I don't fucking know you I
make these videos because I love reading
the questions and coming up with very
interesting and entertaining ways to
speak to you about it I get a guy get a
tickle out of this
I'm self-soothing myself when I stare at
this Cameron I talk this way one of the
things someone says is this guy likes to
fucking hear himself talk ha damn right
i watch my own videos I fucking love it
you serve because of service you serve
because the act of serving the act of
giving the act of love builds you up it
makes you feel good
you'll sever yourself from those good
feelings if you take your eyes off of
yourself and place them on someone else
with greed about how they're going to
give back to you all I want is a thank
you you don't deserve a thank-you you
deserve all the good feelings you got
for doing the thing you did
done