bullying requires two participants so
the bullied is just as important part of
the dance as the bully so when we see
this as a situation where someone's
being bullied and the reason why I bring
this up is because my daughter came home
from camp yesterday and was being
bullied right like that so I got to
thinking about the dynamics of this
situation and the entire dance wouldn't
have taken course if my daughter wasn't
the believed and she had to play that
part in this dance and I'm at fault for
a lot of this and I'll explain the story
in the situation in a moment but one of
the things that I want to bring to your
attention is that the ability to defy
the ability to say no is the very first
and most primordial assertion of the ego
it's the very first time that an
individual recognizes its place in its
surroundings and it usually starts about
the age of two and a half three and that
the strengthening of that defiance that
ego strengthened that self-esteem
develops until maybe around four so
right through potty training you know
this is happening because the child
starts to say no no or throws temper
tantrums or literally defies ah no right
this is because there's an uncomfortable
feeling coming up in the child's body it
doesn't want the food you're giving it
it doesn't want to go to the grandma
odds it doesn't want to do the thing
that that you would like it to do and it
feels this in its body and it says no
we're parents generally do and what I
did to my oldest daughter because I
didn't know better at the time was I
squashed her ability to say no the
minute she began defying I did what my
dad did to me which was you don't tell
me no what I tell you you do you don't
ask any questions you just do what I
tell you to do I don't care if you don't
want to do it you're going to do it this
was the language that I use the language
that I was taught and this is how I
treated my daughter during the a
of ego development during the age of
strengthening her ability to say no
right my other children a little
different because I have evolved and I
treated them differently so my daughters
in school are in camp yesterday and a
little girl fix smaller than her comes
up to her and it starts picking on him
pushes her against the wall and goes to
choke her and my daughter doesn't fight
back she's being bullied and she's
playing the dance the part of the dads
ads the bully the bully and the bully
you need both if the bully doesn't play
its part by not standing up for itself
having it's know being squashed and the
inability to defy the situation it's a
perfect candidate for being bullied and
the bully knows this the bully looks
around and tries to find someone weak
ego strength and I hate to describe my
daughter that way but I know that I did
this to her so what ends up happening is
ambiguity rises up in the body of the
bullying individual because when the
feelings associated with defiance came
up as a baby or the child a young child
and it was squashed it was essentially
told to that individual by a parent or
an adult that your feelings aren't right
what you're feeling is wrong and you
have no right to express it shut it down
right now there's a fight in that
individuals body between the body the
body and the head the body feels ah I'm
gonna push you away no right but the
head because it was conditioned by the
parent and you know the parent knows
best and the child always wants to
please a parent says squash that shut it
down shut it down so what ends up
happening is you've got this hesitation
right and I know some of you have
experienced this and you probably
experience in many areas of your life
but what is when you're being attacked
do you find yourself like I want to hit
I want to go crazy I want to defy but
you're fighting yourself this is the
hesitation this is the fight the
ambiguity the the idea that I want to
express my body my body's telling me I
need to do this but it's not the right
thing to do because I've been
conditioned to shut down my negation
shut down my No
shut down my defiance shut down my
ability to stand my ground this is wrong
we can't do this to our children because
we make them pray for other children and
other people who are sharks who will eat
them alive you if you find that this is
your situation if you find that you're
an easy target or if you find there's
ambiguity with regard to your feelings
or hesitation practice practice setting
up your space use your hands and use
your body and say out loud practice it
on your own no no no this is my space my
space my space this is mine get away get
away you can practice that you can say
that you can do that you own that that
is the most primordial expression of a
strong ego is to say no practice your
ability to say no say no when no comes
up in your body don't feel bad a lot of
people who have this I feel bad so they
say yes situation going on someone tells
them hey let's go do such-and-such and
they feel bad so they go and do it it
means they don't have there no it is the
most important tool that an individual
can have to survive successfully in this
world and with your children I told you
that I did this with my oldest and I
regret it but I've got three others that
I know would not be bullied in fact my
second oldest daughter was in the same
camp and wasn't fully
I think the little girl that was a bully
and my second oldest daughter are
actually friends which was a little
weird
but she has her know when Emerson my
second oldest or Simone or my son
Benjamin is not really doing it yet go
no I'm not doing it to me I'm with it
III be with it I don't fight her on it I
might try to coerce her I might try to
use language that will ease her into a
direction that I know is better for her
I might distract her but I'm not going
to take away her no I'm not going to
take away her defiance in fact I invite
her to bring it up if she wants to defy
me and she feels and big.you us about it
I like her do you want to tell me no do
you want it's okay to tell me no this is
not what you want I tell her this here
yeah now don't tell her she went out to
the street cars are uncommon coming by
it's a matter of being a creative
parents all you commenters down below
we're going to say Elliot lets these
kids do open fluff they won not quite
it's about being sensitive and creative
something that a lot of people need to
work on hope it's helpful talk to you
next time
Elliot sit
[Music]