so our friend Michael is dealing with a
sudden heartbreak essentially a woman
that he's loved and she's loved him for
well over a year with the perfect
relationship in Michael's mind at least
he goes on and on and on about how madly
and deeply in love they were with one
another and if they weren't only 20
years old he would have asked her to
marry him the significance placed on the
amount of the heaviness of love in his
heart needs to be expressed here and
anybody who's been madly stupid in love
because really it's it's it's a letting
go of our head when we fall in love I
mean you totally become a different
person you're walking on clouds this is
I understand Michael wants us to
understand his feelings and and that has
to be brought to light
deeply in love but out of nowhere she
decides to break up with him right this
is this is all I got shocked to our
friend and he doesn't know what to do
he's caught between this place of who
I've been devastated a part of me has
been taken away something that I want
that I'm so attached to that it's been
serving me this relationship you have
been ripped out of my life so suddenly
that's painful especially when he's
fallen when you fall in love you're
you're literally resting on that person
if that person slips boom you fall on
the floor Michael is flat on his fucking
face because the love of his life has
left him not only is he confused about
what the hell just happened but
apparently his girlfriend or
ex-girlfriend is in a place where she's
describing the need to move further on
the path of her personal development
there are things that she needs to go do
or explore or achieve whatever the case
may be
in order for her to feel like a full
person and the reality is we've got to
feel full in our
before we can have a mature relationship
with another individual if you've got
two halves that are codependent and you
rip them apart then you've got two empty
people broken but if you got two whole
people right and it's all processed
we're never fully whole but two people
who were on the journey of becoming
stronger versions of themselves
individually and then decide to join
each other on that path you're in a far
more resourceful place than meatiness
right so she has this aching within her
to go and fill some other gaps that
she's right some other gaps not her
vagina that she feels are not being
fulfilled with you by her side okay and
my heart goes out to you empathy and put
the empathy empathy I want to read I
don't do this very often but I want to
read a just a paragraph out of a book
that I often reference Viktor Frankl
man's search for meaning this is
probably the best definition of the
meaning of love that I've read now I
there's so many different ways to to
look at love different angles that are
all resourceful this is a really good
one and I want to read it to you here
because it's going to is going to help
you beyond that that every experience
every challenging experience that you
have is a chance to grow stronger so I'm
grateful for your pain right I've said
this hundreds of times so if you've been
watching my channel for long enough my
assumption is that you know I'm gonna
say good you're feeling some pain huh
right because that's all going to
contribute to you growing stronger
you've got to have challenges there are
no challenges in your life there's no
growth so this is a good thing that's
the very first place you should proceed
from it is okay how am i growing
stronger through this challenge what do
I have to learn what can I learn through
this challenge what part of me am I
being shown or asked to strengthen
through this challenge always subjective
always go in first right always 100% of
the time with all of your dealings that
seem extrinsic meaning other people or
circumstances always go in
first that needs to be said before I
start reading stuff because I don't want
to just sprinkle some fluffy shit you
know some sprinkles on the poop in order
to make it look like it's something that
it's not right
we can't just beat around bush here the
fact is you're dealing some pain you
need to go in first right to figure
yourself out the second thing is to now
figure out how you want to look at the
situation with this woman love is the
only way to grasp another human being in
the innermost core of his personality or
her personality no one can become fully
aware of the essence of another human
being
unless he loves her by his love he's
enabled to see the essential traits and
features in which the beloved person and
even more he sees that which is
potential in her so you see the
potential you see the strongest version
of her in her when you see that person's
innermost right which is not yet fully
actualized but ought to be actualized
furthermore by his love the loving
person enables the beloved person to
actualize these potentialities right
through your love that person becomes a
strongest version of themselves by
making her aware of what she can be and
of what she should be he makes these
potentialities come true basically what
Viktor Frankl is saying here is that
true love is seeing the strongest
version of someone in them their
innermost core looking at that person
and seeing all they can be and then
centering your purpose for that person
around serving them to become that
giving all you have to support that
person in becoming the strongest version
of themselves that is your only
objective you're not in charge of her
you don't own her when you love someone
you don't
own them see that's that's a big mistake
that we have even with regard to
marriage I'm married but I don't own my
wife right when you're in a loving
relationship with someone you don't own
that person that person doesn't own you
what you've decided to do is to support
each other in becoming stronger versions
of each other
you've decided to open your hearts up so
that you can see each other at your that
their inner core I her at her inner core
and you and your inner core and then do
everything in your life everything in
your power to show back that person a
mirror reflection of the beauty that you
see in them the strongest version that
you see in them and then doing
everything that you can to help bring
that out of that person right that's
your only objective it's not to snuggle
and cuddle and hold on to its mu P mu P
mu P and own that person make that
person a plaything for you because
that's what we do
that person tickles me in a particular
way that makes me feel good and then you
know eventually that tickling goes away
and like you're no longer in love right
the fact is that the real truth of a
ritual relationship is not an ownership
it's in support of the other person now
if you truly love her right
and I'm asking you to do a number of
things here you gotta you got to go in
become introspective become a stronger
version of yourself first that's always
first become a stronger version of
yourself knuckle up knuckle up become
stronger and it doesn't mean become
callous it doesn't mean become cold it
doesn't mean become hard it doesn't mean
stuffing your tears in it means become
very subjective become very
self-reflective become very aware of
what's going on inside you become very
self-aware that's what this is my
invitation is always about here guys
it's going in and figuring out who you
are what you're all about that strongest
version of yourself so that you can see
it and make that come out right you've
got to do that first this might be a
good opportunity for you to take a few
weeks and say you know what babe you're
right I need to do some of that also
right you don't wanna be that needy
partner that's like no baby no baby
don't don't
me right because she will resent you
even more you need to actually do what
she's doing and it's to go in and figure
some shit out where you can become
stronger right she's showing you a
weakness in you right now by leaving you
and and feeling all this oiler ability
that needs to be patched up and then
support her and becoming the strongest
version of herself regardless of what
that looks like see a lot of times we
want them to look like a particular
image of a stronger version of
themselves that we've made up and the
way that is going to happen towards
becoming the strongest version of the
fucking image you have in your head we
like to make up but if you really love a
person you've got to let them go to
travel the path that their heart is
taking them on and to become that which
their heart desires it's going to be
very different for every single person
it's going to be tremendously different
for every single person no two people
are going to experience the same path
and their neck no two people going to
have the same end but if you truly self
love someone and you see that they're
doing it through purity of purpose and
groundedness right see a lot of you guys
are too
I used to trim immature because it's
just a misunderstanding you don't
understand Elliott Hulse when he says
follow your heart or invite other people
follow their hearts there's a difference
between allowing someone to follow their
hearts that's a pure calling that's
grounded and someone who's hysterical
it's like you know if she decides like I
just want to like kill raccoons and live
in a and a makeshift the cardboard box
right that's like okay babe that's
probably a little bit neurotic there's
something else going on there let's talk
right but then again I don't know you've
got to sense these things
you got to sense these things you've got
to get in touch with that person's inner
core and if you feel that she's moving
from her inner core on a journey that's
going to support her and becoming strong
excursion ourselves dude
you gotta let go
you totally got a Glencoe and if she
comes back
that means you were meant to be on the
journey further along together you got a
separate you got a separate to come back
together again you got to grow stronger
as individuals to come together again as
a unit right you don't want a needy
bitch on your hands and she doesn't want
a whiny pussy right lack of a man on her
hands you both need to become stronger
versions of yourselves
and that happens independently it
doesn't happen together support her the
best you can if supporting her basically
means leave her alone don't contact her
like she's asking you to that's fine the
care in your heart will allow you to do
that maybe watch her from afar say
prayers right that might sound strange
say fucking prayers right who the hell
tells you say prayers right I'm not even
Christian I'm telling you to say some
fucking prayers get on your hands and
knees because that is an energetic
expression of love that is you sharing
expressing and reaching out that feeling
that you have to her without actually
being there with her send her good vibes
it's another way to say meditate on her
okay and that's it man as best you can
do right toughen up and say some prayers
peace