hey what's up guys just coming off a
very powerful weekend where we had to
grow stronger experience and the non
jobs summit this weekend here in Tampa
in fact I just finished a blog post that
you could read down below if you click
the link in the description that will
take you to seven legendary moments from
this weekend and you'll get to see some
pictures from our experience so before I
get started today with our topic on
spontaneous manifestation how to get
what you want instantly just want to go
over a few quick points that were
discovered and experienced this weekend
so the very first thing i want to share
is our experience with the grow stronger
experience and that is that i spoke on
Friday on multiple different topics of
great interest to me and obviously great
interest to the people that were
attending especially since getting the
feedback so the first thing is that I
opened up and I spoke about death and
rebirth as a theme in life I also spoke
about the four layers of strength that
one is a great detail and practical
application both in my own personal life
and journey as well as tips and ideas
for people going through their journey
on how to use the four layers of
strength in order to increase your
physiology increase your strength
increase your mental capacity and focus
and anything related to empowering other
people right because that's our mission
to become the strongest version of
ourselves in order to empower I also for
the first time taught my core values the
strength camp core values we've got four
strengthcamp core values that were taken
I actually developed it for the new book
that will be coming out my new book
titled king that will be coming out
later this year but essentially I took
the outline from the book and expanded
on on upon it during my presentation
specifically as it relates to the
strength camp core values and that was
really uh it was fun for me to share and
like I said the participants really
enjoyed it the next thing that happened
was friday night after that we had a
meetup where all of the participants
from grow stronger experience
non job summit got to meet up meet me
and also meet a couple of my YouTube
celebrity star friends I like the name
star better than celebrity I'm going to
start using that so we also we had
Brandon Carter he and I chopped it up we
had a great time kicking some rhymes
together we also had my buddy drew
Phoenix who is a wordsmith he dropped us
with some real hardcore poetry
particularly with a spin that revolves
around being an ex-marine very powerful
stuff so he offers poetry as his as a
part of this in order to relay his
experience as a as an ex-marine and
finally we had my friend yo yo yo yo yo
his knees really I mi komi oh yeah
because that's his youtube channel and
he did some eaten in fact he was the MC
for our non job summit and he also
happens to be a pretty dope beat boxer
so we got to experience and hang out
with him on that you can learn more
about mine on jobs summit talks down
below by clicking the link also we an
awesome after party with great music new
friends we really kicked it that night
we had a great time and lastly I want to
share a really awesome story something
that I experienced this weekend it was
kind of a little la mystical if you will
but maybe I'm just superstitious I tend
to look into every experience of my life
and give it significance so during the
party Saturday night I was of course
dancing because that's what you doing
parties and having a great time outdoors
it's Florida it's still hot we're
dancing all kinds of great music having
a good time and I am drenched my shirt
got soaked because I'm sweating while I
dance and pose a little bit of a problem
I have no issue being sweaty but my wife
wanted a day I wanted to dance with my
wife I really wanted to dance with
Colleen but she just wasn't diggin my
sweaty shirt sounds like aah how can i
patch this up and make the situation
work where my wife will want to dance
with me i realized i needed a towel so I
went frantically looking for paper
towels nap
means tissues whatever I could find in
order to dry myself off dry off my shirt
and get back there out there on the
dance floor I went inside because of
course we were dancing outside it went
inside looking at various tables people
were standing at the tables looking at
all the tables for napkins and I'm
collecting napkins so I can ja but blot
out all the sweat on my body and I come
to one table and a gentleman is standing
there with a big white fluffy towel by
the name of Jerry and uh and our friend
happen to own a company that makes
towels that are a little nifty and he
handed me his towel as a gift this is a
child is a towel that I received as a
gift right and war for the rest of the
night as my part of my uniform I loved
it because I loved the gift so much so I
just wore it for the rest of the night
but what makes this towel unique is that
it has a little netting that you could
put on top of your put over your seat
when you go in the car so that you don't
wet your car when you're all sweaty from
the gym I thought it was ingenious and
and I was very grateful to have had the
spontaneous manifestation of exactly
what I needed and it wasn't as mystical
as it sounds in fact myself in the young
man Jeremy we exchanged emails several
months ago where he asked me just to
sign up for his email list in order to
help him support some charity work that
I believe he was doing for his brother
but anyway I'm pulling out my wife my
cell phone here because I wanted to make
sure that I bless our friend properly by
sharing his website it's oversized gym
towel calm where you can get one of
these super absorbent apparently towels
and and and also use it so that you
don't ruin your car I don't get any
commission or anything from that I was
just so pleased with my gift that I I
promised our friend that I would share
it in a video so that's it I'm really
excited to continue this journey with
you guys so many new things coming up in
the future like I said my new book will
be out later this year or early next
year and we will have a
of videos from this weekend going up on
this channel a next chat and my other
channel including an epic 30 40 minute
interview that I did with Brandon Carter
he and I really kicked it yesterday on
video and we want to share our
conversation I love with you so that's
it y'all talk to you tomorrow done