a question here from our buddy Alex he
meets this hot chick at a bus stop he
says and after texting back and forth
with her out over about a week he finds
that she's a little bit like demanding
in her choices about where they're going
to meet for the first time and he first
asserts that you know maybe she's just a
really controlling check-in anyway so
finally they decide to meet at a bar
they go to the bar and they start
drinking they're having a good time they
have great conversation he says that she
begins saying things like this I want to
teach you how to make my grandma's soup
and and also she includes this idea that
I'm tired of meeting and hooking up with
people and I'm really interested in a
long-term relationship he says hey
that's cool that's fine and uh and then
they essentially part ways at that point
you know not having sex that first night
which hey look it's respectable we all
get it you know he of course has got a
boner
what's the bang but hey sometimes it's
worth the wait right so you meet up
again ah this time she's a little bit
more trusting and allows him to choose a
place his place right what better place
and they start you know having a great
conversation again she lays down on his
bed and he lays down beside her now as
he lays down she warns him look I'm
laying down because I'm tired not
because I want to have sex
he says oh no problem babe next thing
you know clothes are off and they're
giving each other oral sex that's right
licking and kissing all over and in
spots that are usually beneath the
panties but they're not fucking yet and
I have a text he notices that uh of
course she says you know she doesn't
want to have sex but you know there he's
tongue fucking her but he knows his like
you know she doesn't seem really into it
she's really uncomfortable about what's
going on and and she says I'd like to
stop so they stop and our buddy Alex is
like okay cool little confused you know
say we got that Nate we got this far and
I understand that you know you want
long-term relationships and so on and so
forth but um he wants to have sex
obviously I mean come on
and now she's pushing away he's confused
he's like look I'm kind of into this
idea of long-term relationship also I'd
like to find the one but uh but this
chick is confusing the shit out of me
how do I go about it so I'm happy with
the details that you shared with me in
this in your long email here because um
which I think you already recognize her
if you red flags and the the overall
tone of the multiple red flags that she
gives you is that this woman doesn't
feel safe and safety and security
feeling cuddled up in in good feelings
feeling safe really is a super important
thing to a lot of women I'd say most of
course we've I can't say everybody but
safety and security is is priority for
women especially when it comes to not
only life you know women want a manikins
provide there's no question about it
they want safety and security in that
way or if they can provide for
themselves but they're not going to be
like you know wandering bum like most of
us could end up being you know because
we're cool that way they want safety
security and then sexually you know
Wilhelm Reich an interesting dude that I
often study what often it starts to the
fact that the sexual character of an
individual how they are in sex tells a
lot about who they are as a walking
character who they are in their entire
life
and and for whatever reason probably
based on experiences that she's had this
woman doesn't feel safe so when she says
things like I want to teach you how to
cook my grandma's soup that immediately
tells you that this woman wants warm
cozy feelings
grandma's soup I mean come the fuck on
ha first conversation yeah with her she
wants to teach you how to make her
grandma's soup ha ha ha that's that's a
dead giveaway that she wants to feel
cuddled up she wants to be feel safe she
wants you to essentially save her in a
way save her from a cold hard world that
is stopped on her and you don't know
what that stopping might have looked
like
yeah and it's often times it's
unconscious you know because we we stuff
down
we hide trauma from ourselves she could
have been sexually abused as a child
it's not unheard of in fact it's quite
common she could have been raped as a
child as a young girl she could have
simply had multiple bad experiences with
other guys who she made herself
vulnerable to because you can understand
this thing about women they open
themselves up not just physically but
energetically and and oftentimes I say
that the body is the mind so when she
opens her vagina
she's also opening her mind she's
opening who she is to someone that's a
very vulnerable place men we can fuck
all over the place and we never have to
open up to anybody it's like my dicks
hard we're good
women have they kind of need and again
this is not Olin but they need this
opportunity to yield and open up their
body and their mind themselves who they
are has to open to let in something from
the outside this penis attached to a guy
I just met and so they have to be very
careful in that way especially if
they've been in those rural durable
places have been violated try you don't
know you know in violation is very
subjective it could have simply been
that you know she had a boyfriend who
you know told her that she was a virgin
also he fucked her and said you know
sorry babe I had sex with dozens of
women Oh violation you know so and then
that can really close down her energy
and close down her sexual capacities
right so now her vagina just won't get
wet for anyone until now this is where I
move up from the you know the animal
reptilian behavior activities that we
want to gauge in right which is all
lower it's all gut penis balls to where
she's probably most rigid well however
having a cold dry vagina is a byproduct
of the prison that surrounds her heart
and she and she's made reference to the
fact that she wants her heart to be to
melt again grandma sue right and she's
even willing to be vulnerable enough to
take her clothes off with you but you're
not getting the
just yet I'm telling you right now that
what you need to do is cook some
grandma's soup with her I'm telling you
bro and I'm not telling you out of
manipulation you don't want a minute
manipulation is bad because it means
that our every action is measured by the
sentiment from which it proceeds I don't
say make some fucking soup so you can
bang her mmm that's not it what I'm
saying is you two need to become
vulnerable in your heart and allow her
to - first of all she was aware of this
but she began the relationship by having
her own little bit of control she needs
she needed to have that in the beginning
and you mentioned that you know it's
funny I think you know all this stuff
that's why you included those details
she needed to feel in control a little
bit because when you're scared when
you're afraid when you're vulnerable
when you've been violated you don't want
that to happen again so you kind of like
you're holding a little bit tighter
holding on is the opposite of orgasm you
can't hold on and have sex you've got to
let go and have sex and the minute when
she begins to let go
because she trusts you her heart begins
opening up she's going to be able to let
go and Diana's gonna open up just like a
nice little flower right a beautiful
thing
open for China because it says so much
about the energy of the individual of
the woman whole body opens up the pores
open up the eyes dilate the mouth
everything just opens there you are
-
participate with her in that but it's
going to take warming her heart it's
going to take warming her heart breaking
up her heart and I'm going to sound
manipulative manipulative in this but I
you know I'm giving you tips and
techniques ideas that will support you
and what it looks like when her art
heart opens - which are two things which
are very indicative of her heart
possibly opening up to you which are
spontaneous movements in her body
number one is laughter and number two is
crying if you can get her to giggle or
cry what you're doing is you what
happens when you giggle there's
vibration in here and it literally
physically you see I don't make too much
of a there's not too much of a
delineation between my metaphorical
speak in the literal translation of it
it breaks up her heart it breaks up the
the rigidity in her heart it softens her
heart vibration allows things to break
up break up her heart or sobbing deep
sobbing crying getting to the core of
why she's so closed ask her questions
about that you know a good way to
possibly approach this is to say to her
listen of course you know dating advice
from Elliott I'm romantic sorry let's
put away sex for a moment now I want you
to know first of all that I've got a
thick ass boner for you I'd like to bang
I'd like to ban you but I'm going to put
that aside for a moment let's pretend
like that doesn't exist because there's
a part of me that just wants to get to
know your heart and you say to her let's
set aside sex and begin where we started
with those conversations about your
grandma sue maybe our next date you get
to you can teach me how to make that
suit and then maybe she'll feed you some
of the soup and then you feed her some
of the soup and then you know what all
the romantic gobbledygook that's
associated with that you know what I
mean and uh and speak with her get to
the get to know her at a core level not
just know her with your dick and it's
going to take some time
it's gonna take some romance it's gonna
take some patience
it's gonna take some grounding from you
and when I say that I mean you first of
all you gotta set aside your dick for a
little while that's I mean that's
grounding in and of itself I mean think
about that term grounded you're grounded
it means you can't do fun shit ground
your dick and also move from a steady
place you're going to have to be
practical pragmatic calculative and
tippy-toe around her vulnerabilities and
if she starts acting weird don't you fly
off the handle you know what I had
enough with this bitch I just can't you
know what she doesn't want to fuck she's
always fighting with me right you can't
do that if she's worth you gotta ask
yourself this question she's worth your
time she's worth the fucking frustration
and she's gonna be frustrating in the
meanwhile jerk off or I don't know maybe
find a fuck buddy I don't know but if
you could set aside your dick for a
little while you'll be okay that's it
man you got it you gotta open up her
heart that's where it is it's right here
even when you talk to her and you say
something about the heart put your hand
on your heart
boy what a different gestures gesture
that is I know what we like to do we
like to rub our hips on her ass like I'd
love to just I love to do this but
instead take your hand and put it on her
heart or better yet take her hand put on
your heart and then you take you allow
her to take your hand and put on your
heart so you put your hand on mine you
could and this is like harp sex right
the energy moving from my heart to yours
and we both give and receive each other
and bring each other clothes and just
talk speak look just be silent perhaps
with your hands on each other's hearts
hopefully you can see me here hands on
each other's hearts
and breathe soften the musculature in
your face soften the muscles in your
shoulders soften the muscles surrounding
your heart stand firmly on your feet
knees slightly bent and have heart sex
with her first in a few weeks or pussy
be real wet ready for you done