I'm sifting through emails as I
typically do before I make these videos
and I come across about four questions
in a row that sound very similar to this
Elliot I'm in high school or I'm in
college and I love swimming or I love
music or I love art I love something
that is a bit contrary to what my
parents would like me to pursue as a
living now of course parents want the
best for their children and perhaps you
guys are a bit young in their minds to
begin making choices about what your
future should be so I totally understand
that but the thing is that it sounds
like you guys are all fighting against
your parents because they're asking you
to go to college either on debt or
they're even willing to pay for your
college some of you and it sounds like
you're engaging in majors in university
that you really don't give a shit about
so you happen to be a swimmer but your
mom wants you to be your dad wants you
to be a computer programmer one kid I
think he was into uh he was into music
makes his own music and his dad wanted
him to be an accountant and all these
different things that are their parents
tend to force us into because they want
us to be able to make our way in the
world they want to tell us exactly what
needs to be done in order to be a
success and perhaps in many ways the day
themselves don't feel like failures
right because parents I'm a parent to
four child children we often feel as if
our self-worth is tied to how our
children turn out right your children
are a reflection of you I've even said
that so we had better steer them in the
directions that we feel would best
represent who we are as individuals now
I was in a County your grandpa was an
accountant you had better be an
accountant and it's right and true for
you to do this because it is uh it will
allow your children to perhaps have the
same experience that you've had in life
I get it I understand one of the things
that I think we need to come to
understand is just how rapidly the world
is changing right now all of the
construct that we
have put so much vested interest in its
collapsing before your very fucking eyes
all of us need to recognize this look at
the wars upon Wars upon Wars and the
expansion of Empire and the death and
destruction happening all over the world
rebellion in the revolution as its
happies happening as we speak
look at what's happening to our currency
and all the fraud that has been exposed
and the collapse of nations and debt all
this shit is happening because we cannot
put all of our energy focus
concentration invest ourselves in a
fleeting phenomenon and our children
because they're so much closer to their
intuition they're bit closer to God than
we are because as adults we have to make
our way in this world so oftentimes we
close down the intelligence of our heart
and our intuition our gut in order to
make our way in this world so you're
shut down you don't even feel what you
feel you just have what you've been told
and what you begin to tell yourself and
then you begin to tell your children but
your children children young people
they've got a they've got their finger
on the on the beat on the on the pulse
of what's happening on the air in the
earth and they sense this and I think it
might be time that we as adults or as
parents begin asking our children what's
going on instead of we telling them
what's going on because we're trapped in
failing paradigms we're invested in
collapsing systems and the future will
be in their hands they're the ones
that's going to build a brand new world
you like the one that we live in because
most of us are fucking miserable do we
want our children to play out the same
exact miserable experience that we've
experienced or do we want to give them
room to create something brand new
because all this shit is brand fucking
new I'm talking to a camera that's going
to be able to reach tens of thousands of
people in a matter of minutes that
didn't exist when my parents are trying
to tell me what I might become now I was
lucky enough my parents are from a
different country they didn't really
understand the mechanisms of this system
so well so they didn't really force me
in any particular way they wanted me to
have a nice living and they had an idea
that you know College had something to
do with it but I couldn't have even
voiced my own desires to one day speak
to tens of thousands or almost a million
if you count my subscriptions in both
channels through a fucking camera
because there were no you know what a
camera looked like when when I was in
high school it was a big block like this
with like a thing sticking out so you
could hear it in the lens of that big
and you'd have to have it plugged in
somewhere meaning you know where camera
for right now here's my camera right
it's my camera carrier in my pocket I
made a video this morning from this
thing I hit a button and it reaches
thousands hundreds of thousands perhaps
millions of people my parents couldn't
have helped me figure that out I
couldn't figure that out what I had to
do is keep my finger on the pulse of
what's happening in the world about the
time I was graduating high school there
was this thing the internet war but we
didn't really have it in our home we had
to dial it up wherever we went to make
it a spare pair burp and connect to
something somewhere in the sky and all
of a sudden like we can communicate with
each other through this thing that's a
byproduct of evolution that's a
byproduct of what humanity's doing one
of the things humanity is doing is
becoming more collective in our
consciousness that's what the internet
in these videos and YouTube and Google
does to us it's bringing us closer
together it's separating us because with
everything good comes a bad separating
us because we connect to each other like
this oh but there are more ideas there's
more creativity there's more remixes
there's more evolution of consciousness
available to us because ideas are so
much more prolific so in a world that's
evolving that rapidly so rapidly that I
often times feel outdated and this is
what I do for a living you know I have
friends to tell me did you know that
YouTube does this now and you can
manipulate this and change this oh yeah
been like that for the past six months
and I'm like I can't keep up for me to
then tell my children now this is the
way it is and this is way it should be
and this is what you're going to do is
retarded it's asinine it doesn't make
any sense it's perverted way to go about
life but to protect our children and
support them is a totally different
paradigm than to guide them right we
want to guide our children your parents
want to guide you and of course I'm
talking you know I often talk to you
guys who are children who are young
people and watch my videos I'm talking
I'm talking to parents right now because
I have a parent also I'm talking from
both ends of the spectrum you know any
way to guide your children means I'm
going to use the parameters by which I
gave my life to get where I am at this
particular point with the idea that
perhaps the future will be somewhat the
same and imprison my children by that
you're going to do this because this is
what worked for me and you know what
again I'm sounding like a broken record
here this is a bit of a rant more less
than a cohesive conversation if you're
miserable right mostly I mean how many
of our parents are on pills to be a
little bit more happy than they really
are or have to drink every single night
so they can forget their problems if
you're miserable if shit ain't working
out the way you your heart and body
would have liked it to work out if you
can't breathe deeply and enjoy yourself
enjoy life smile laugh laugh was the
last time you laughed a big deep belly
laugh that brings tears to your eyes you
can't tell me that then why
guide your children down that same sick
sad depressing road let them go and see
what happens
support them and protect them that means
allow them to become whatever they're
going to become without any attachment
support them in discovering all of the
principles there are only a handful by
which you navigate life do you see give
them tools that allow them to go out you
know there are they're a handful the
principles that I call tools that you
can use no matter what I don't care if
you're watching Star Wars and we're
actually living in the Stars and driving
spaceships and there are death stars or
it's the principles taught to us by
Jesus while he was in a dirt hut
teaching his twelve half-naked disciples
its Empire either Roman or Darth Vader
we're either out of space or in the dirt
but they're a handful of principles and
if you if you take the time to study the
principles of living a successful life
and when I say successful I don't mean
trappings or traps of the world
I mean honoring your heart honing your
intelligence and trusting your gut we
recognize those recognize those
principles and we and we not guide but
support them by educating them with this
they will go off into the world and they
will create magnificent things and they
will be just fine they will be well off
and we protect them by being there for
them when they're hurt we shouldn't do
the hurting we shouldn't be the
oppressor there's gonna be enough of
that right we've got the government to
do that for us we've got the police to
do that for us right
the u.s. is becoming more and more of a
police state I remember the policeman
when I was a kid you know he had on like
a nice button-up thing and he looked
like a cool guy with a nice flat hat
they all wear riot gear now every time I
see an officer I'm like holy shit I'm
Titanic cuz they look they're all in
riot gear it seems the world is going to
press on your children there is going to
police your children and ultimately they
might fight back
but be there to protect them be there
when they do scrape their knees or get
their leg blown off or get their heart
broken as a place to rest once again
instead of beating a part of the police
state in the home with them we like to
think that our children are the future
and when I say think it means because we
come from a place where that means we
need to give them everything that we
needed for our own personal development
and to teach them our ways when that has
nothing to do with it that is that's
reliving the past that's creating a
future out of the past a future created
out of the past is psychotic
it's insane it just keeps repeating the
same sickness over and over and over
again but a future created from the
present by being fully in the present
being lined up head heart and gut in the
present will create a brand-new future a
future that we couldn't even imagine but
if we teach our children how to be
centered and grounded in their head
heart and gut who has to be creative
intelligent and beautiful
let them be parents give them a break
you might not like what they're doing
you might not like where they're going
you might not understand the things that
they love but give them room support and
protection and my invitation is that we
stop controlling and guiding them done