so yesterday I uploaded a video to my
strenght training YouTube channel and in
this video you'll find a warm-up routine
that I use personally every day and I
also teach my clients to use before they
workout and in this routine you're gonna
find some of Elliot's awkward exercises
where you know you're bouncing up and
down and making weird noises it's highly
effective very useful and resourceful
routine if your boss enough to do it so
as I'm uploading the video I'm preparing
myself for these small-minded gutless
comments that were guaranteed to follow
that sounds something like this
Elliot I can't do this at my gym they're
gonna kick me out or Elliot what will
people think they'll make fun of me if I
do this routine and so on and so forth
and not so many or much more words got
me thinking about why so many people are
followers why so many people are willing
to relinquish all of their
responsibilities and life force to the
dictates of other small-minded people
why do you live your life based on what
other people are thinking I'm not asking
you to go out and do anything ridiculous
crazy dangerous asking you to free
yourself just enough that you can do a
few exercises in front of your neurotic
neighbors and family and friends that's
gonna help you become a stronger version
of yourself alright so wondering and
this is just something that's completely
across the board and everybody knows and
understands that people are conditioned
they're socially conditioned to follow
the dictates of other others from the
time we're children for some reason this
irritates me I don't know why for some
reason maybe I'm rebellious for no
reason but I decide I'm going to pick up
my own fucking drum I'm gonna beat my
drum with my song and I'm gonna March
and as I march I know for a fact that
each beat is coming from the depths of
my being each time I speak that drum
it's like the beating of my heart
and with that strength people are gonna
March I'm not looking for people to
follow me the same way that they follow
the small-minded gutless people that
surround them in their days and lies
what I want to do is show you how to
become a stronger version of yourself
expand your mind expand your body try
things that you wouldn't normally do
that most people are too scared to do or
even think about what I'm inviting you
to do is to become a fucking boss
yourself if I've got to give you
permission then so be it
but what I expect from you is to pick up
your drum and start beating it let each
beat resonate deep from within your body
each beat of the drum is like a beat of
your heart and start marching to that
instead of what people in television and
your neurotic neighbors and the people
at your gym think fuck them there's six
sad and depressed anyway why would you
follow them do you really respect them
that much are you that afraid of how
they make judge you who are they who is
anybody except you you know your heart
you can pick up your drum you can start
beating and to the strength of your
beating and marching you will free other
people to pick up their drum and start
beating and marching and that's what
becoming the strongest version yourself
is about I'm just here to invite you
start marching by the beat of your own
drum fuck everybody else Eliot's in what