got a great question from our buddy
Jason who says he feels that he's
destined to do great things so he's
young and people keep telling him hey
man chill out don't worry about the
future enjoy your youth while you're
young and so on and so forth and Jason's
like no fuck that I feel like I'm
destined for greatness the only problem
is I don't know what I'm destined to do
and I could totally relate to that
feeling of angst associated with knowing
that you're going to do something great
but not knowing exactly what your next
step is going to be in fact I deal with
this all the time I felt that way for
many years as a youth and throughout
high school college even though there
are times where I felt very
underappreciated and and confused about
even how I will become appreciated at
some point but what I personally
discovered and something that a friend
actually embodied through this
particular phrase for me just a you know
a few days ago is this phenomenon
whereby if you consider and take care of
what's given to you right now and you
just have faith in the future what he
basically said was stewardship and faith
or trust but that's the way you
described it stewardship and trust you
can't help but go in the right direction
so that basic basically means instead of
looking forward to what you're going to
do and become great at you look at what
you have right now the people around you
right now your skills your talents your
faculties your hobbies the things that
you're involved in right now you give
100% effort focused concentration in all
of your blood sweat and tears at doing
great today right now and just trust
that it will lead you to where you need
to be and in my experience where you end
up is far greater than anything you
could ever imagine the technology
involves is such a great degree our
abilities to think and concentrate all
the things that human beings are rapidly
advancing to Awards are happening
such an extraordinary rate that you
can't even pinpoint you say that you
just graduated high school or something
you in ten years huh ten years you have
no oh it's gonna be available to you
when I graduated high school there was
no YouTube there were no there are no
video cameras to upload to the Internet
I didn't have an email address until
after college and this is how I am
serving to impact the world to do the
great thing that I thought or felt back
then was inevitable for me and you know
what I still ask myself the same
question how am I going to take it to
the next level how am I gonna serve even
more because I feel like I'm not even
halfway to the greatness that I that
that's bubbling up in my heart and this
is good means you're an advancing man it
means there's something great happening
inside you but don't get carried away
with that feeling and let it trip you up
by focusing your energy on the future
instead of taking care of what's here
and now you do the best with what you
have and you maximize your ability to
serve everyone and everything that
you're currently involved with and have
trust that it will take you to your word
towards your greatness good luck man