all right to go under like spiritual
stuff with you someone who is like I'm
sure about their religious place or
there's some sort of a philosophy in
general mm-hmm what do you suggest
indoors is like get that certainty and
then once you do get it like let's say
it goes against what your family
believes or someone who's really close
to you how do you convey that to them
without getting crucified yeah cuz we
crucify people so basically go against
everything else right literally Jesus
with crazy motherfucker he basically was
like look all this religious shit you
guys talk about bullshit and he went to
the political leaders put their tables
and gave the finger to the so he fucked
all the political at all the religious
leaders before they come spite of that
that's a rebellious mood right there so
few years where I think you might be
tripping over stumbling block certainty
there is no certainty and to confine
yourself to a version of yourself that
has adopted a particular idea that is
resourceful for the time and then
calling it certainty which means that
you can't navigate outside of it and you
just put yourself in prison in that
prison is the same person that's the
Muslim the Jew the Christian all find
themselves in and people like their
prisons and they don't want anybody else
talking about any other prisons they end
up biting each other so I find there
that abs are the same fucking prison as
questions it's like you're so be able to
just about being ages certain temp is a
dangerous worth it what's the line if
you don't have certain
please do like the person I don't know
like how he was talking about other
people to find you switch for free
because I wanted to know what I was once
human brain said that none of the labels
that were given no the labels that we
adopt number none of the names or forms
that we worship because we worship idols
idols meaning concrete concrete examples
or concrete expressions of that which is
abstract any time that we attach to
these things names what's your name
Austin you're not Austin Austin as a
name that's made up of symbols that they
call letters you're not in Austin that's
a name we don't worship when we don't
attach to we don't personally
identifiable austin casey we're like
going again the question is are you get
the certainty like here's the most
beautiful thing about life is that there
is no certainty that's what makes like
so freaking fantastic is that you never
know what's going to happen we want to
know what's going to happen because we
think that if we know what's going to
happen then we were navigating the right
path and then we're going to get the
right thing go right way but really
that's a figment of our imagination life
is so freaking dynamic we're just
talking about quantum physics before
we're simply the invention given to a
type of particle changes that particles
to say that there is a certainty in any
way shape or form not only this kids is
a figment of our imagination but it's
boring it's well if somebody gave you
every step that you're going to take and
all the experiences you're going to have
and the path that you're going to
traverse from now to the day you die so
that you're certain
that's that they have the person I can't
wait to see what's gonna happen all
right what you guys go to dinner for
this night I don't know what's gonna
happen I can't wait to see but you know
what if I already knew what was it
happen ah minute all right this equal be
some strange reason out of fear you want
certainty we want predictability but
it's it's under source one that's pretty
boring groundedness within your body
breathing into your balls having your
feet throw the ground awareness allows
you to traverse all the dynamic all the
dynamism on the world short wouldn't you
want to be sure footed you don't
necessarily want to be certain short
foot it means whatever happens like
Peter on the ground and I can deal with
this looking I can navigate I'm
responsible you want to be responsible
not certain certain means boring and
already and you're like most certain to
use will people certainty their
certainty is a projection of the future
of what happened in the past this is
what we love this will be more certainty
this is the way it's always been done
this is the way your daddy did it your
granddaddy did big grin that he did it
this is what the book says this is what
scientists say so basically Oh past
projected on the future past is dead all
that matters is that step and that step
and are you aware each time you're
taking a step and are you sure put it as
a reverse your path into the unknown the
world always wants their thing for you
we spoke about parents and children and
banging and not giving them your
thoughts you're a particular way you're
thinking a particular way you're going
to have your own children when you're
dealing with your parents my some shit
out of your parents have a particular
belief okay which is to gonna die soon I
don't think that's how humans evolve and
ideas ideas are the other food into the
future so that idea is going to die with
her that's okay grandma you're so sweet
that's nice over here doing what I know
the future holds what you're feeling in
your body is what the future holds
there's no need to judge it we like to
judge it and say like it's wrong
conservativism don't Traverse don't move
too far from the tradition right but
everything that we experience that's
good everything to enact any sense are
loosely everything that we experience as
progressive is in letting go of the
traditions it's not that the traditions
are bad or that good or under source for
that there are many structures within it
that we need to reintegrate lot of the
disciplines a lot a lot of the rituals I
think we become so progressive that we
lost the power of ritual you lost power
of myth you've lost a lot of the
structures
maybe religion very powerful in our
moving forward but I think I'm feeling
is going to come back it's going to be
vested in a different way they're all a
product of letting go a lot of times
you're letting go of is not the truth
it's not the structure it's not the
context of what's being used through
religion and philosophy it's the content
of it that's usually Doppler
superstition the content changes from
generation to generation you study the
story of Jesus and then you studied the
next several old like Greek religions
the story is exactly the same i wish i
could repeated here know exactly
historically good was but the gods prior
to Jesus were born of a virgin rose from
the dead walked on the water to same
exact story that context is the same the
content changed well this guy is called
such a session this one special session
was change so it's not even that is not
even it like we were completely
detaching from and squashing all of the
things from the past it's essentially
we're moving forward into a more
progressive reality now I'm starting
talking circles for shitting myself what
do you see what I'm saying and it's your
grandma did I thought it was like your
dad that's okay let them that's okay
they're allowed to have what they have
when evolution happens you're allowed to
have what you have to they're trying to
hold you down that's fine let them
believe it then you go into
he was right in your heart you have
children we want you want to kill the
master master I'll kill me as much as
you're willing to move forward a bit o
master yourself we've got to know when
it's time to let other masters they're
not letting other bastards grow their
anti life whether behaviors
anti-progress and in dealing with them
don't do just do they live with you
okay just not going as well what you
feel right