I still think it's amazing that I get to
see this every morning on my walk
sunrise that's where I want to live one
day some way over there air I forgot the
bear now I have the bear gotta go back
to school and bring the bear
what's up guys sup fellas what's going
on snapchatting you I needed I need to
quit snap quick snap chat who somebody
blendin I've had
that's called a snap-in twirl Walter was
telling me all about it yeah he's like
addicted to social media apps Walter is
still a reputable sources
banana so anything good a happy today
during the workout yeah good
conversations tis alright I like making
jokes having fun with the guys Merkel
jumps and then uh there's some snapchat
did some snap shag yeah
new video with my son beating people up
with sticks on the strength can't be to
channel I also almost throw up in the
video not because the workout was hard
though because I was sick that's why
it's a sick workout cheeks down youjizz
have all the time and believe
but when you get a massage going to get
a massage going to get a massage picking
up my girls from gymnastics oh there she
is red pants all the way in the back
doing step ups or some shit my daughter
is using microwave for the very first
time to heat up water push it and hit
the button that says beverage right here
hey just push it dark microwave magical
wizardry boiling water in one minute
walking in the rain my car's right there
although I gotta hit the button was ever
brain is a good thing
list
corn corn makes whiskey whiskey makes my
baby boo boo don't snap chatting drive
kids so bad that was a poor choice