so got this question that I pulled off
of my facebook fanpage wall from Trevor
Williams I'll just read the question
word-for-word I'm having trouble right
now of life it seems I'm always having
bad luck with jobs I always end up being
unemployed for months at a time
when I lose a job and right now it's
been the longest period of unemployment
for me in my life I always have ideas
when it comes to get rich quick schemes
but I have no money at all I'm 21 years
old and sometimes feel like giving up
like I have nothing to lose it's a good
place to be nothing to lose I am
honestly sick of the job thing and I
just wish I had a career that I loved
and can do forever do you have any
advice for me I'm somewhat desperate yes
I enjoy lifting weights boxing MMA and
most of all professional wrestling I
really wish I could get into that so
Trevor your your answer is inherent with
the question you're answering your own
question what you're missing is the
courage to take action in the direction
of your dreams because it's
irresponsible to do what you really want
to do or so we've been told so you're
having difficulty maintaining employment
or finding jobs and being unemployed for
extended periods of times it's because
there is a core or a primary disconnect
between what you're doing and what you
really feel on the inside and that never
measures up it never adds up it'll
always show up dysfunctional for some
people they just can't keep a job for
other people they keep the job but
they've just completely sold their sold
they're depressed they're upset they
have anxiety they they end up stuffing
their true love and character down deep
inside make it to about 40 50 years old
and then go through a midlife crisis I
think you're a little bit better off
because you're just so rebellious
against this or you recognize that
dichotomy that that tension between your
heart and your mind that you just I mean
you just don't do anything better place
to be then getting caught up and what
you're told you should do right so now
you also left the PS right PostScript
interesting how we put where we place
our heart interesting where
the point at which or the way we
position that thing that we actually
love peak PostScript everything else is
about how fucked up things are because
you're following your mind which is
basically the leash by which the world
has tethered you in order to follow what
they think you should be doing right got
a job motherfucker and you postscript
I love lifting weights boxing MMA and
and uh and really professional wrestling
I wish I could get into that there it is
that's it that's it you will never ever
again be at a loss for something to do
or drifting about in your life if you go
in the direction of professional
wrestling right sounds fucking crazy
Elliott Hulse you tell him it's 21 year
old man that he should give up his jobs
write his respectable positions with
with benefits and pension plans so that
he can earn a regular paycheck for
professional wrestling now Elliott
that's irresponsible
abso-fucking-lutely it's irresponsible
and it's the most important thing for
you to do right now in your life here's
the thing everyone gives you advice
based on their experience and most
people's experience are based on the
advice or the dictates of other people
so we've created this economic machine
whereby the most important thing for a
human being to execute is becoming a tax
payer now things are changing a little
bit now because the more you are a
leaner on the taxpaying system the more
powerful you are because then you vote
for guys like Obama but anyway the point
here is this system needs a lot of tax
payers so you got to do shit that gets
you quickly out there in order to pay
taxes you very quickly need to get into
a situation where you start filling out
paperwork so that they can take your tax
money if you go into something that is a
calling of your heart it means that
you're probably not going to get a job
right away you're not going to be a
respectable taxpayer right away right
and we're not conditioned this way we're
not conditioned in such a way and the
system is not designed and school has
not taught us and our parents are not
taught us on TV and media and everything
that completely brainwashes us does not
tell us that it's okay to bypass the
system for a moment the
head and follow the heart but what they
don't let you know what they don't tell
you and mostly because they haven't
experienced it but Elliott else has so I
can share this with you is that if you
just follow your fucking heart just
follow that strange thing that's
happening inside you you will end up ten
times better miles ahead miles ahead of
all those people who did what they were
told and those miles ahead are very
subjective it doesn't necessarily mean
that you're going to make more money
than them and you're going to be more
rich and famous than them but you will
be more at peace you'll have more peace
of mind you will be more in love with
yourself in your life the people around
you will enjoy your company that much
more you'll sleep better at night you'll
smile laugh you'll dance you'll enjoy
this life ten times better than if you
were to follow what everyone else sold
you to do let me just share my story but
of course that's what I do here so all I
can do offer you is my experience and I
give you perspectives based on what I've
seen and what I've experienced and I do
shit that most people don't do so it
might be a good idea for you to listen
football
football I'm doing what I'm doing right
now you see talking to you right now
through these videos and I get paid
pretty well but I started many
constructs because I studied marketing I
studied business along the way in order
to build a life around the thing that I
love to do most began with football was
the sixth grade my older cousin played
football and I saw what he was doing
with the helmets on it was shiny and her
bands playing and the whole pomp and
circumstance and I decided I want to do
that I want to be down on that field
like my big grown cousin I had bands
playing and everybody being excited
about me and I knew I was fast I knew I
was strong so I knew I could do that I
wasn't sixth grade I decided that I was
going to start playing football long
story short with regard to football I
became really good at playing football I
earned a college scholarship playing
football and I knew that my life was
going to revolve around football that's
all I cared about nothing else mattered
to me school it was just how can I play
football my grades were good enough so
like a play football I went to college
so I could play football nothing else
mattered to me I was dead set on the
fact that I was going to play football
rest of my life works to be somehow
involved in the sport of football right
you like professional wrestling right
that might sound a little bit stranger
than football but trust me you might
have a better chance becoming a
professional wrestler than a fucking
football player even though I was really
frigging good but the cards didn't fall
as such I can tell you right now I don't
even know who played in Super Bowl last
year football is the last thing on my
mind but I followed that calling I
followed that prompting in my heart
and it took me down a road where I
ultimately ended up studying strength
and conditioning because I got really
good at football by lifting weights and
I decided well I can be a coach if I
can't be a football player professional
football player and I actually enjoy
lifting weights more than actually
talking about the strategy of football
because I've never been a strategy
person I still am NOT but I know how to
get you to beast up on something
I know how to get kids really excited
about lifting wigs
so I studied exercise physiology so the
conditioning ultimately ended up opening
my own gym through trials and errors and
all types of heartache and discomfort
because I knew that one thing I knew was
like I was never gonna work for anybody
else even in the NFL was like you know
I'd have to be a slave to their system
I'm so much happier now that I don't
that I'm not or never was you know
hindsight is always 20/20 a slave to an
NFL system right cuz those guys are you
know they're treated like meat they get
paid really well especially not as a
coach and I'm definitely happy I'm not a
coach in a called collegiate setting or
anything I mean those guys don't get
paid very well and they work their asses
off that's not what I wanted another
thing that I wanted was a family
but anyway I'm going off on a tangent
here I realized through coaching right
so I'll start with football
then it became coaching strengthen
conditioning I opened my business
trending auditioning and I realized as
I'm training these kids you know and I'm
really good as a coach I understood I
really studied love the body how to
coach I have the best cues I have the
best programs
I got great results but my motion my
favorite part of the workouts while I
was training these kids was talking to
them about their schoolwork about their
girlfriends about the problems they're
having with their parents ha right after
their workout they stick around noelia
what do you think about this my
girlfriend cheated on me so and so my
parents they want me to go to this
college but really I want to go to this
college I enjoyed doing it
I'm my heart then at that moment went
from football to shredding conditioning
to mentorship of young men I didn't plan
this I didn't say I want to be a mentor
of young men especially through the
video medium because there was no
YouTube when I first specially when I
first became a coach where I could talk
to perhaps millions of young men
throughout the entire world via fucking
camera I couldn't have planned that but
I did one thing I followed my heart
every step of the way it looks crazy in
the beginning but it all starts to make
sense as you go down that path
that's why I say you have to follow you
heart not because of the thing that your
heart is telling you to do at this
particular moment but because of the
journey your heart will take you on it's
going to take you on a fucking
incredible journey the endpoint of that
journey or how you fare along that
journey will be filled with love and
pleasure and joy because your heart is
involved with the work I do what I do
here like this right talking to this
camera in my warehouse gym knowing
nothing about football
I could give two shits who is in the BCF
playoffs and the NFL and I don't know
any of the fucking players I don't leave
my football nothing but I followed that
prompting of my heart up until this
point I couldn't have planned it any
better
ignore sensibility ignore responsibility
listen to your body follow your heart
and you'll enjoy this journey of life it
won't always be easy but it'll be yours
and there's no greater pleasure than a
life of your own design then one filled
with the riches of slavery you know what
to do dude go fucking do it