this morning I get an email in my
facebook inbox and it comes from a guy
who wants to know how you should go
about dealing with a woman that he loves
that also seems to have a big problem
she's anorexic now our friend goes on to
ask me how do I help this woman learn
about nutrition and how can I help
educate her on what to eat so that she
can be healthy the very first thing that
I always do and this is very important
write this down if you can grab a pen
one of the very first things that I
personally do and that I offer you to do
is to look at yourself first when trying
to help someone else out you can only
help people to the degree that you can
help yourself and if you don't know
where you're coming from if you're not
clear about who you are what your own
limitations are it's going to be very
difficult to have a clear eye and clear
understanding unclouded vision when
supporting someone else so what I like
to do when you guys send me questions is
I like to go to your Facebook wall I
like to click through and see the about
page and fortunately our friend today
had a website a blog I clicked over to
his blog and he's a brilliant artist you
know I'm talking to you right now you
are a brilliant artist you know this but
I noticed something interesting all of
your art is of women the face of women
not their bodies but their face their
eyes are always full colorful bright but
sad and you know what I'm talking about
blotches all over the face almost like
tears as if someone had done something
horrible to these women you hold the
women in these pictures in a in a high
esteem you adorn their heads with
beautiful things and flowers and
feathers meaning that you there's a city
you understand a sense of wisdom you
receive a sense of
wisdom from these women in your pictures
but yet they look hurt you love them you
appreciate you respect them but they're
hurt and these this is what your heart
is is bringing out in your hands as you
paint these pictures there's a tendency
for us to relive or reenact the
experiences that we had with our parents
as adults and for you to seek out women
that are victims hurt women damaged
women now I'm not challenging your
feelings for this girl not at all what
I'm asking you to do is take a look at
why you're choosing damaged women to
help okay the type of relationship that
you have with your mom it might if I had
a guess I'd say that your mom was
someone that you really appreciated
admired loved respect respected but you
had a feeling a sense that you needed to
help her somehow she was damaged or she
was hurt by someone or she suffered from
depression something somehow your mom
evoked this feeling of neediness from
you help me my son is what I sense your
mom screamed it's evident through your
art it's evident through the women that
you're choosing don't look to help your
friend just yet explore these feelings
explore what's going on within you why
is it that you feel you need to save her
because if you don't save her I
guarantee you you're going to find
another woman to save and you're going
to hop from damaged woman to damaged
woman your entire life looking for
someone to save because it reenacts and
brings about feelings good feelings you
feel good when you do this I know you do
because you wanted to save your mom but
you couldn't save your mom you're a kid
your mom's an adult whatever she was
dealing with was way out of bounds for
you way over your head but you loved her
and you wanted to help her and so what
you're doing is you're trying to help
your mom
by helping these damaged women explore
these feelings explore these ideas I got
goose bumps right now dude because this
is coming from my heart I sincerely feel
that this is something you need to
explore first before you go and help
other women because the sentiment from
what you proceed like I've mentioned
before is going to color the entire
relationship because if she gets better
if she gets healthy she starts eating
right she's happy she's healthy she can
stand on her own two legs your
relationship will end because she no
longer will be giving you what you need
which is a damaged needy woman for those
of you listen to this and you know this
doesn't apply to you this is a unique
situation listen always always always
seek what's in your heart
first before proceeding towards anyone
or any activity where are you coming
from a lot of times it's difficult to
see this that's why I offer perspectives
for you where are you coming from what's
in your heart because what you do with
your hands don't matter nearly as much
as where the hands are coming from or
what the hands are attached to so my
friend continue to be the Immaculate
artist that you are explore the feelings
that are inside you that are causing you
to seek out damaged women that you need
to help where are there gaps in your own
self-esteem in your own psyche your own
feelings your own emotion that needs to
be healed
alright good luck
grow stronger
Elliott said