well today we got a question from maria
webber whose a young girl from germany
and she goes on to describe how she had
a young love affair with a with a boy
and everything was great but she cheated
on him apparently may have had sex with
another boy this caused turmoil in their
relationship they broke up she went on
to have another relationship that ended
up being really bad and they broke up
throughout the course of the bad
relationship her ex-boyfriend stayed
with her to support her emotionally and
now they're back together it's been
three years but she still carries a
great sense of guilt and a lot of pain
associated with the actions that she
made before so Maria what I like to
offer you first is a perspective a
reality that we've come to ignore due to
political correctness and the evening
out of the sexes and and so on and so
forth we've got to understand that
although men and women are equal in
every single regard we are completely
different not only different we are
diametrically opposed we are like a
positive and negative Pole right
completely opposite where the man
physically emotionally reaches out just
think of the penis the body has
stimulated energy Rises the penis
reaches out the man moves forward goes
forward expresses himself in the world
the woman physically emotionally
psychologically opens up where the man
hardens and reaches out the woman
softens and brings in and this is not
just penis and vagina talk and a lot of
times people want to know like Elliot
some sort of pervert this is the the
essence of the sexes this is the essence
of what it is to be a man and a woman to
understand that not only do it does our
body reach out or or or absorb or open
up or soften like the woman does like
her vagina does the emotions the
psychology the entire genetic makeup of
the individual of the opposite sex
is are going to be dominated by those
attributes just watch it men are always
moving forward moving out bigger better
more more more more more this is an
aggressive hard reaching out tendency
it's not the natural tendency for women
all they'll be we've conditioned them
because we live in a male-dominated
ominous where there's a patriarchal
hierarchy and everybody's shitting on
everybody else the female woman the
yielding quality of the softening
quality is not respected it's not
honored it's it's really in some
cultures squashed covered and in our
culture in the West transformed so women
are unfortunately for all of us women
are becoming more like men that doesn't
mean that they're growing penises but
there's more male there's more male
attributes to their character because
you've got to compete in an increasingly
penis dominated world so you're probably
wondering you know what the hell am I
talking about why is this relevant well
the reason why he can get over things is
because he reaches out he's moving
forward he's moving on you on the other
hand are holding a deep sense of regret
and I think the guilt and the pain that
you're feeling is not so much that you
hurt him because the man will move on
especially if he has a lot of masculine
characteristics he'll move on because he
found a place to rest in you that's what
the man does we go out and we look for a
place to rest there's like the penis
look for a place to rest and apparently
founded in you you betrayed him but I
think your pain is more associated with
the fact that you've opened up too
easily was distracted and opened up too
easily to several different mistakes
because the vagina is an opening of the
body it's also an opening of the soul
it's an opening of the individual and to
just let in especially to let in lots of
mistakes is damaging
to the spirit of the individual now when
I say spirit i'm not talking religiously
i'm talking about what's happening in at
a deep psychological emotional level for
the individual that's why it's easy for
men to go out and cheat all the time we
because nothing gets inside us doesn't
affect our heart our energy it's out
right skeet skeet skeet right we're just
we think nothing of it but for a woman
you've got to protect yourself I know I
might sound sexist here but the reality
is just look at the metaphor the vagina
opens you up you've got to not only open
up but you've got to soften and what
happens when you soften your body allow
it to open to men is you bring in not
only their body but you bring in their
energy and then the entire relationship
is associated with you yielding and them
approaching and if you find that you
made mistakes about opening up to the
wrong people which you have in the past
there's going to be a sense of guilt
that you have for opening up too easily
you're going to carry that the other
thing is that when you realize that
you've opened up too easily there's
going to be a tendency to want to close
down again because you realize you know
I opened myself up to this man I hurt
him then I opened myself up to another
man that hurt me and then this whole
opening up thing becomes confusing
distracting hurtful painful and then the
tendencies to close down so you may
experience now this is just all the
guests based on the information you've
given me you may experience now an
inability to open up to the one that
truly does love you to the one that is
worth allowing to rest in you that maybe
another part of your guilt my point here
is that the guilt is yours the when I
use the term guilt I'm talking about the
cognitive dissonance between what you've
done and what you're thinking the moral
judgment is one hundred percent yours he
trusts you okay you gotta understand
that that he got over it maybe that's a
better way to put it he's gotten over it
he's gotten over it and you got to get
over the fact that you
opened up too easily and now may be
closing down on him so what you got to
do is what is the busy is the essence of
femininity the feminine energy yields
let's go okay not telling you to be weak
because in in Chinese philosophy and in
martial arts in many traditions
throughout the world the woman is the
stronger character because it knows how
to yield to aggression you've got a
yield to him and allow yourself to open
back up again so that you can receive
the love that he's giving you once
you've opened yourself back up and you
allow him to rest in you you can now
develop a true relationship that is one
of integration I hope that's helpful I
wasn't too metaphorical for you you look
like a young girl maybe you know in your
teens early 20s but these are ideas for
life you're going to go through perhaps
many other men and you're going to open
up and tighten up throughout several
courses of your life but if you're going
to truly embody the essence of
femininity and live a life that is
worthy and have relationships that is
worthy of you the goodness within you
you're going to have to eventually yield
again I hope that's helpful I'll talk to
you next time Elliot's it
[Music]
you