so lately I've been getting a lot of
questions from parents wanting to know
what Elliot thinks about raising
children which is a little awkward but
considering the fact that I have four
children and I share my thoughts and
wisdom with you on a daily basis I can
see why the questions came in so before
I get started the very first thing i
want to offer is that i am not a
parenting expert you probably know that
the thing is i don't think there's such
a thing as a parenting expert simply
because everyone is going to have
totally different experiences with
regard to raising children anyone tells
you that they've got all the tactics and
strategies that you need to be
successful in anything and completely
disregard your experience with that
thing they're lying to you right so let
me share my story I not too long ago I
started working with a mentor who also
happens to be a psycho analysts he's a
good friend of mine now and when we
first started I think it was our first
session I broke down into tears and the
the reason why was because of guilt that
I had from an experienced earlier in the
day I my daughter was behaving badly or
poorly or just not up to what I expected
of her that morning and instead of
saying anything I went took something
that was very important to her I stuffed
it in the garbage can talk about being a
bad parent right taking stuffed in the
garbage can I was like when you start to
behave kindly to your sisters I think
she was just being mean then you can
have this thing back now the garbage can
was empty so wasn't sullied or anything
like that and but she was really upset
distraught that Daddy stuffed her thing
in the garbage can and you know we went
about our day we made up and the
feelings associated with that experience
most of stuck with me because later on
that day when I went and saw my mentor I
broke down in tears feelings of guilt
about you know being a horrible parent
and how I could possibly ever raise
healthy smart intelligent creative
children from stuffing their shit in the
garbage right
and he said something to me that was
very profound he said the most important
thing that you can do Elliot to ensure
that you are a good parent is to work on
yourself first and clearly you're doing
that so you affirm that you know I'm
doing all right and it got me thinking
about phrase that I constantly repeat
over and over again because I believe so
strongly in it that it doesn't matter
what you do the tactics and techniques
and the books that you read and what you
mechanically do with your hands doesn't
matter nearly as much as the sentiment
from which it proceeds who you are means
far more than what you do with regard to
being a parent so like I described in
other videos you can have two people
doing the same exact thing two hands
performing the same exact actions
seemingly identical and get to-- two
totally different results and that's why
anybody who offers you the tactics and
strategies for success is lying to you
they can give you their ideas they can
give you their experiences they can
share you with you some wisdom that
they've gained through the years of
doing the thing that you'd like to do
better they can't tell you exactly what
to do because who you are is going to
pervade it's going to color all of the
tactics and strategies that you act out
the emotion that you carry your self
esteem the years and years and
generations and generations of
conditioning that you carry within your
mind and soul is going to color all of
your activities so with regard to being
a parent I'm not telling you to stuff
your children's things in the garbage
like I have but take a step back and not
don't be so connected and focused on
what you're actually doing and think
about where it's coming from are you
coming from a place of love for you
coming from a place of generosity of
appreciation for life or you coming from
a place of anger frustration I know
early on in my parents
career a lot of what I did was just a
invitation of what my parents did I
would say things and behave in ways and
yell and scream the same way my dad did
to me and it wasn't because I thought it
was the right thing to do was because
that's what I was conditioned to do and
he probably just did what his dad told
him and doing or or did to him without
having to think about too much so
without thinking I was talking to my
daughter and daughters the way that my
parents spoke to me and then when i took
conscious control of it i realized that
this is not who I am that Hawaii wanted
be and I'm going to continue to proceed
from a different place place of empathy
which is really where I come from most
of the time when I'm dealing with my
children when I say empathy I
essentially mean that I feel what they
feel living in a world where everyone's
trying to control you squash you stop
you from being who your heart's desire
is for you I need to guide and control
them in certain ways so they don't get
hurt but beyond that hurting themselves
or hurting other people I try to have a
very little or minimal hand in and
guiding and controlling their behavior
this comes from my heart this is who I
am and it's not so much what I do I hope
this is helpful for you talk to you next
time