it's time to go it's time to go you see
we lay it all out there's two there's
two halves of a process there's deciding
to make a decision right this is where
all the thinking happens deciding to
make a decision this is where you gather
this is where you you mull over this is
where you think this is where you ask
questions but there comes a stark
contrast there is a time literally when
the axe drops food and decision is made
you've got two ends of it is not even a
fucking spectrum it is a clear
delineated black or white are you just
choosing something are you thinking
about something or have you decided
something there's a big difference and a
lot of people think that thinking is
deciding but thinking is still thinking
deciding and the other thing is some
people say they've decided but then they
think again when you decided to do
something that's it
you don't even need to think about it
anymore it's as good as done
it takes courage to do that not to
backpedal when most people's problem is
is they backpedal they spent a lot of
time look I'll grant you this time to
dance around and play with this idea
think about it you know you're tangling
you're dancing you're playing but when
it's time and you jump that shit is over
now all that matters is action all that
matters now is doing something what did
you say you're going to do you already
thought about it now do it but wait I'm
not so sure or I didn't expect that
don't fucking matter
you decided already now you do this is
where you build tenacity see there's a
difference there are a number of virtues
that are required here number one is
courage to say I'm dumb thinking and now
I'm acting but courage is only a virtue
that gets the ball rolling now you now
what's required is tenacity persistence
patience sensitivity awareness do you
see because now now you're really
getting your hands dirty over
here it's all abstract thinking over
here is boom Aristotle said that no
virtue is developed in a closet in a
vacuum no virtue is ever developed in
the absence of tangling getting
entangled courage is required to get
tangled up but now you're going to have
to because you're wrestling now now you
instead of dancing you're now wrestling
and when you're wrestling you either get
choked out or you figure out what to do
and that's when you're building the
actual character is when you're doing
shit that's what it's that's what's
meant by do the thing to get the power
because the power see the thing is
people want to be granted the power so
they take action right boom I got
courage I quit my job how many guys do
that because I heard Elliott Hulse say
quit your job I quit my job
but now the work begins because now
you've got to gain the power this is
where the power is gained not over here
you exercise courage great you're miles
ahead of most but now who do you got to
become to stand on that ground that you
just chose because you could take
courage and still be still be weak you
need to now develop the virtues
associated with standing on that ground
you just chose people think the job is
done once they've they've chosen you
know the decision has been made been
made and the decision is done but your
job just began