put a question from our friend lily and
it's a it's a tough one it's one that I
had to sit and think about for a little
while before getting on camera lily has
dated someone several years ago who gave
her genital warts STD and this is not so
uncommon you know STDs that they happen
the thing is that now Lily's still a
young girl and she is in a situation
where she wants to soften to a man she
wants to give herself to a man she wants
to have sex and it's very difficult
being dishonest about her STD she she
she refuses to do it and it goes so far
that she can't even come to kissing a
man and there are men that she has warm
feelings towards that tend to have good
feelings toward her but the minute she
brings up the conversation she knows
exactly what's going to happen next he
bounces and justifiably so if he
realizes that like look I don't want to
go any further with this if I'm going to
get infected with what you got tough
situation I almost didn't even want to
answer this because I don't even want to
say you know it's very difficult because
you can't get rid of this virus
apparently you want to bring somebody in
you want to soften you want to orgasm
again you wanna have sex you want to
feel like a normal natural healthy human
being without this scourge you want to
perhaps have children someday you want
to move on with your life you want to
move forward in your life but you've got
this problem that won't allow you to do
that which is the most natural thing
coming up in your body which is to have
sex with a man and move forward in that
sect relationship right what do you do
that's really the bottom line of
equipment really the bottom line on the
question is what the fuck do I do here's
what I would I came up with this is just
an idea it's just an offer it's just
something to all it took to shed light
on the bigger picture support you
emotionally and perhaps in many ways I
think will lead
you two getting exactly what it is that
you want which is a man who will accept
you and work with you through the pain
that you're dealing with right what I
would invite you to do safe take some
time and considering how you do this and
where you do it and with whom you do it
but go and volunteer your time to
support women or little girls who have
really bad situations I'm talking about
little girls who were born with aids I'm
talking about women who have been beaten
and raped by their husband and are now
living in a group home women in
particular but women who got it a little
bit worse than you women who not only
have a genital STD but perhaps can't
even have sex because they've been so
sexually mutilated and abused perhaps
even as children I know this is all very
heart-wrenching shit but go and find you
know even go to a hospice with with
children young children who are dying my
mom worked in a hospice my entire life
growing up and she would often bring us
to see the dying children in order to
give us perspective on how good our
lives were whenever we were complaining
she would say you know what why don't
you come with me to work today and these
children were either born deformed and
really mangled badly organs on the
outside of their bodies and you'd show
up and you'd see this or children who
are badly abused such that they were
mutilated by their parents horrible
horrific situations that when we went
back home and we couldn't get that new
Nintendo game the perspective on the
situation completely changed what that's
going to do is two things for you by
dealing with the situation by placing
yourself in the energetic flow of others
who have it worse annex you could be a
strong magnet
you can use this whatever strength that
you still have in you and I it sounds
like you've got a lot you're educated
you're smart you're doing a lot of
personal development you're you're
you're a good person that a lot of
strength there you've got a strong
energetic pole there are some women who
not only are physically physiologically
incapable but energetically drained that
would benefit tremendously from the love
care attention empathy compassion that
you could provide for them you're doing
a good thing by putting yourself in the
energetic flow of supporting inspiring
other people's we grow stronger so that
we can inspire other people what that
will also do is open up the pathway by
which compassion comes to you you know
they often say I'm trying to think of a
good example but oh spiritually one of
the spiritual ideas typically in most
and most almost all religious traditions
is to tie is to give right so you give
to your church and that in a way is to
is to open up the channel to receive now
you know it might not receiving the same
way the same channel but it's you giving
so that you may receive there's this
channel that needs to be open in order
to receive that begins with us giving
compassion is what you need compassion
understanding patience and love is what
you need from another human being open
up the energetic pathway for that by
doing it yourself and that's why I so
strongly recommend you go and find
someone who has less than you who is
less than you who has suffered more than
you and could use your compassion
because you're going to find that
perhaps no there are no promises there
are no promises but
it's worth a try you're going to find
that when you extend yourself in that
way that the world ie a man will extend
himself towards you in that way you will
be in the vibration of compassion and
when you're in the vibratory level of
compassion you tend to attract it to you
as well you're gonna find a man who may
be willing to just get genital genital
warts right me it's not that big a deal
it sounds all weird and gross and
Elliott Hulse tends to take on any
question that sends his way but it says
it sounds strange but what you're
looking for is a man who's willing to
give himself to you contract the genital
warts because apparently there's nothing
else there's no inoculation I don't know
apparently or maybe maybe there is i
don't know but a man who's willing to go
through this with you whether or not
that means he contracts the disease
right it's not the end of the world but
the thing is you've got to find someone
who's willing to give to you in that way
the only way you you receive from
another individual in that way is when
you freely given good luck