so we got a really tough question from
one of our friends here who has married
his high school girlfriend he's in his
20s right now he's been with the same
girl since he was in high school has
never been with any other women really
loves his wife you know they're married
now and and up until this point
everything has gone smoothly but he's
now saying that he was to experience
other women right and he asserts to the
fact that your men aren't monogamous in
our biology and he used that as an
argument with his with his wife to kind
of like convince her that I should go
fuck other women and and you're right I
get it
I agree with you in fact I created it an
entire video last year that caused quite
an uproar because I talked about how
love is far more expansive than a
relationship between two right and it
was an idea that I shared at that
particular time because of what I was
thinking
now I get your question and it's
basically you know you're you may have
seen that other video and you're kind of
saying look Ellie I get it you know love
can be spread in that particular way and
and I do love my woman I love my wife
but I want to experience other women and
he says that he used this particular
language of biology and you know kind of
made logical sense right know this that
you're using this whenever we convince
women most of the time when we have to
convince women it's doing this as being
logical because women feel more than we
do so oftentimes like they say like a
woman knows if she's gonna fuck a guy
within minutes of meeting him because he
doesn't have to convince her that he she
should fuck him because she feels it
she's just like women kind of send stuff
so when we have to like do this you know
convinced through arguments like we're
you know or in court with a woman know
that you're you're taking her away from
her intuition and you know I'm not
saying good or bad I'm just saying
notice what you're doing you're you're
manipulating her you know and that again
no judgment but just know that women
feel things and often times we have to
romance them out of it and but he's done
a good job congratulations man you
convince your woman that you you should
be fucking other women cool I totally
get it
you know the penis gets hard and he's
like you want to discharge
but you go a little bit further and this
is why I decided to take your answer I
take your question because he says that
well now uh now that I got to go ahead
there's this one girl in my class
alright she's taking classes and the way
he even goes on to describe her which I
won't do is very endearing and then you
go on my friend right now mind you the
language you use with your girlfriend or
your wife to convince her was I want to
have sex with other women I want to fuck
them he says but then my man just take
notice he goes to summarize this
wonderful woman this is the kind of
woman a man like me could easily fall in
love with
she's not just a fuck buddy in my mind
then he goes on he wants to know how do
I now approach this woman who I could
easily fall in love with for sexual
relationships and even you know starts
to the fact that you know I've never
been with any other women I mean really
that's the root of his question I've
never been with any other woman how do I
deal with this no you know share the
fact that I'm married with her and let
her know I have an open relationship and
and to be with them you know it's kind
of like I'm version in this way and I
feel the necessity to approach it from a
different place number one I want just
to bring awareness like I already have
to the to the to the schizophrenic
language the one hand you're saying you
want to go fuck other women on the other
hand you're saying there's someone I
could fall in love with but very big
distinction there's a big distinct
distinct in between fucking someone
right the penis is it's an organ I mean
we feel it throughout our entire
physiology when we let loose into the
depths of orgasm and explode and I mean
Oh sharing that with someone is great
but for men because we move out we don't
take anybody in we could just you know
you're fucking you just wherever you can
it's not that big a deal so it's kind of
a bodily function but what changes it
all is when you fall in love
now you're talked in a totally different
language man because remember how I
often talk about the three intelligence
of the human being the head right which
you're very good at using to manipulate
your woman your balls your gut your
animal you even said this to your woman
you know there's an animal part to me
your animal right but in between the
high cognitive spiritual abilities of
man and his animal Mis right it's balls
there is an in-between and that's his
heart and when you approach something
from the heart level you bring both your
mind and your animal to it that's why I
often say follow your heart allow your
mind to give room for your heart to
carry your animal where it should go
because if you could bring your animal
with you you're that much more powerful
and if you can calculate with the
cognitive abilities of this mind you are
a master mind you cannot be stopped when
you choose to spend your life with
someone you know you decided to marry
her right and fucking other people
wasn't a part of the arrangement but
then you convinced her using this that
I'd like to go and put my penis in other
women that I'll be careful I won't bring
anything back you also got to remember
that you're also implying and even in
your email that all of me might go
somewhere my heart might go somewhere as
well and now you're asking for problems
now I'm not saying what you shouldn't do
this it's not my that's not my thing
here I just want to kind of like if I
put myself in your shoes right and if my
wife says Eliot yes you can go and fuck
other women well that's one thing but
the most dangerous place that I can find
myself in is if I start falling in love
with another woman because now you've
got a problem with yourself because it's
like your tour often this is what
happens to the heart at least mine when
it is magnified in a particular
direction everything
or else everything outside of it turns
dark that's the power of focus and
concentration and that's just the way I
I act that's why I have the things I
have in my life because I focus and
concentrate all of my energies and
efforts into that it like I look like a
laser beam on the things that I want
right now you and I coordinate what my
guts telling me the passion of my heart
and the calculation of my mind to get
all the things I want and the problems
that I have in my life are centered
around that focused concentrated beam of
consciousness and energy if that beam
becomes split the energy is split and
I'm split and I can't bring a hundred
percent of myself to the handful of
things I've chosen form chosen to to
spend my life doing I'm spending my life
doing now we had a problem of a torn
heart boy you know my head tells me that
I should be with my wife because we
chose that way I still like fucking her
but my heart is also drawn over here and
boy I really like her because she's as
hot as I would like a woman to be and I
want to fuck her and you just feel like
this
at least I would be and in that split
effort you are schizophrenic and you
can't give 100% to either of them so
she's getting 50 and she's getting 50
and trust me women don't like to be half
of your attention shit my I feel like
I'm cheating on my wife when I go to
work right I feel like I'm cheating on
my wife when I when I take my daughters
out on dates right when I go when I
spent too much time without her women
won't a lot of you right I mean the
vagina is never-ending pit right what
happens when you go into the vagina more
come out you put yourself into it and
boy well here's another one and it just
doesn't stop right especially if you
have girls right I mean the girl then
makes more children more children more
children it's a never-ending thing women
are like the earth it just they just
keep it there insatiable and now you're
going to split yourself between two of
them
hey you know what if the shit is gonna
work and better go move to Utah where
they do that stuff I don't know if it's
legal there but they're kind of into it
just bring her bring the other one home
and say hey look babe here's our new
wife and you're all kind of then at
least you're there and all of it is in
the same home as opposed to yeah I was
fucking my other love this morning now
I'm coming home to love you as well it's
going to be difficult but look try it
out bro all of life is an experiment the
more experiments the best I'm just
telling you that you're choosing
problems and you'd better evaluate if
you want to deal with those problems
right I just described one of the
problems that I feel I might have it for
you you might not have that problem
right maybe that's maybe maybe i'm just
inferior in that way right maybe you can
love that many people at the same time
love and fuck and have them separate
from one another you know there might be
some merit to that uh Paula Gami
polygamy thing let's bring them into the
same home so the love can be shared
amongst us right and then how our
ancestors did and the tribes and stuff
but now you got your you got your away
bitch in your own bitch and your split
wouldn't work for me but hey again so
you're gonna ask yourself now and this
is where this is where being a very
strong man comes into play ask yourself
this right
set your heart and balls aside for a
moment and ask yourself what is my
mission in life what is my bigger
picture what am i working towards right
what kind of skyscraper am I gonna build
with my life and then when answering
that question recognizing all the vital
resources that you'll have to put into
it right because you'll be cheating on
both of your women with that thing and
if you're a man you're probably you
probably do want that thing there's that
thing men we just have this desire to
also fuck the world and when I say that
I mean insert our vital energies into
all of creation and build something
right that's why we have skyscrapers big
giant penises coming
the earth in New York City right because
that's men do we build monuments to the
penis and now you've got that your big
picture for yourself anything to share
yourself with two different women both
walk world have never-ending pits right
the vagina is never-ending pit you got
to never-ending cuts you got to deal
with both of them on an individual basis
and also they're not going to like each
other unless they're in their same home
and you want to go do your thing in life
so you got some big fucking problems so
you don't fuck other women because I
don't want other problems right of
course my dick will get hard if there's
a hot chick hanging out with me
sure I'd like to fucker but I don't want
any problems
hey I've chosen what I'm going to do
with my life and I made it choices that
support what I'm going to do with my
life
if what you want to do with your life is
be a gigolo or I don't know but you
gotta ask yourself besides women put
them away that's what men need to do
every once in a while
cut yourself off from both of them for a
moment and ask yourself what do you want
as a big picture and it had better
include your head heart and your balls
they can't just be I want my dick to do
whatever my dick wants to do right
because you'll be miserable because
you're imbalanced where does my heart
want me to go and how can I bring the
strength of my animal and the
calculation of my mind
so I don't have an answer for you I'm
not telling you yes please go and be
courageous single fuck this other woman
how I'm telling you no don't do it
because it's going to ruin the big
picture for your life and your
relationship with the woman that you you
chose to love forever just know what
you're jumping into accept the
challenges that come from jumping off
the cliff I often talk about jumping off
the cliff and you're jumping off a
fucking cliff right now make sure it's
the right cliff that you're jumping off
of and make sure you're ready for all
the challenges associated with it hey
you didn't way you're going to become a
stronger version of yourself because
you're gonna figure some shit out on the
way down good luck