most of the times when you decide that
you want to live in a different way or
achieve different goals or have
different values from the majority of
people what you got to realize is that
you've got to do things that the
majority of people aren't willing to do
right that means you've got to step
outside the bounds of the traditional
ways of life so for example but I
decided that I want to own my own
business right I had to quit working for
someone else because freedom is one of
my highest values I realized that I was
going to have to give up this idea of
security and in that I allowed myself to
explore what the absolute worst could
that could happen if I allowed myself to
to participate in my desire to go
towards living that lifestyle and the
thing I thought of was look I've got
children that need to eat and and I've
got a roof that needs to be put over my
head and I decided that that if things
didn't work out i would go pick oranges
now i live in florida and there is day
labor so I had a phone number for a day
laborer company i think it was called
able body in my pocket at all times
because I knew that if I couldn't make
things happen with my business I wasn't
going back to a career job I was gonna
do what I had to do in order to just put
food in mouth and if that meant I'm
gonna go do be a day laborer that was
fine because I saw that as a means to an
end most careers end up being an end in
themselves but if you for me to pick
oranges to me to an end the other thing
is that if I couldn't pay my mortgage I
was going to live in my van a lot of you
guys might remember my old 1988 van that
I drove for several years when I started
working for myself I decided I'm going
to go live in my bank van and send my
children and my wife to live with my
parents you know grateful that I do have
parents that would support that but um
but I was willing I wasn't going to
sir come to any of the demands or ideas
of other people I was going to live in
my car and pick oranges so the question
that I often ask you and I ask myself is
what do you really want you're clear
about that and then what are you willing
to do to achieve it if you really want
something you'll be willing to do
whatever it takes to achieve it Elliot's
it