yo Elliot What's Up Guys hey we've got a
question from our buddy Chris the shunt
camp online for him he's got a young
friend young female friend who was in a
car accident she didn't have her
seatbelt on and it messed her up pretty
bad he says that she now goes to a pain
management doctor and he doesn't like
the sound of this cuz you know pain
management often means like get addicted
to pain pills at least that's how it is
in our culture you know pain management
means I get you addicted to pills and
that's how you manage it and you don't
want that for his friend because it's
ugly I'm looking out the window here
because where my office is is and you
see them they're there pill addicts and
it's ugly so uh he says that although
he's not a doctor he does kind of sense
that she could potentially get out of
all this pain granted that she begins
physical therapy stretches and exercises
and he's basically hoping that she could
potentially be free from pain and move
on with her life without the pain
management through natural means and he
wants to know what you know I'm not a
professional in this I but I want to
inspire her to at least take a stab at
it how do i how do I motivate her you
know it's not like he's a he's a trainer
himself or physical therapists himself
what do I do well one of the greatest
tactics for influence is the third party
referral this is essentially getting a
testimonial story from someone who has
achieved the result you're hoping
someone else will be inspired to try to
achieve themselves so go online and I've
seen lots of them on on YouTube people
even send me their stories about how you
know I was in an automobile accident or
a motorcycle accident and things were
horrible my life fell apart but I began
exercising I began doing physical
therapy and stretching and now look at
how awesome I am
that story that storyline I was once a
loser or when I say loser I mean just
things weren't right things were bad for
me but I discovered something and now
things are good for me let me show you
how is the most powerful story line ever
created by mankind we've been telling
that story from the beginning the story
of the person who suffered great loss
the person who was down and out the
person who is depressed the person who
lost it all discover something and rises
to the heights of success you've just
got to find other people who have
achieved that and put it put her in
their sphere of influence videos are
good books are good there's so many
inspirational books on people who went
from down and out to magnificent there
are youtube videos like I said just
scour the internet man make that your
mission if you really want to help her
it's a matter of inspiring her breathing
life into her I love that word inspire
to like you know expires you know it's
die to inspire is to give life and the
best way to give somebody life is to
show them how they might have it giving
her hope
no Elliot sit what
[Music]