so as expected I've got a ton of
questions from people wondering what the
hell Elliot just did in that video
yesterday so the very first question I
want to address is where did you get
that idea from Elliot where did you get
this from so you know where I'm coming
from I've been studying body psychology
for about ten years and if you are
interested in learning more about the
science of body psychology or how the
mind expresses itself through movement
emotion means movement energy in motion
in the body I would begin with the work
of Alexander Lowen
he used a student of Wilhelm Reich who
was a student of Freud's and Wilhelm
Reich that really is the pioneer of this
idea in the West and he was a student of
Freud who decided that look all the
psychology all the talking that we're
doing is not helping because people's
bodies are tense people's bodies are
tight and he decided to bring exercise
into psychology Alexander Lowen is his
student who is also the mentor of my
mentor here's the lineage and he's
written several books that are very easy
to digest on the idea on the idea of
body psychology or what he calls
bioenergetics and the place I would
begin if I were you was with a book
called the language of the body by
Alexander Lowell and I'll put a link
down below so you can see the next
question is Elliot did you lose your
mind and the answer is yes I've lost my
mind but as I've said in other videos
there are three parts to your brain
you've got three brains in this model
it's very metaphorical but it's also
very literal and I'm going to show you
exactly what I mean
so when you asked did I lose my brain
the answer is yes I lost one part of my
brain so the metaphor for the three
brains is the head brain the heart and
the balls literally it's your neocortex
the cortex and the brain stem or medulla
so when we talk about the neocortex or
the new brain
man million brain this is the brain that
only human beings have that allow us to
think rationally have material
addictions you know we're very attached
to the material world and the neocortex
is so strong that it can actually ignore
the cortex in the medulla can completely
ignore the mammalian and reptilian part
of the human being financial gain
striving reading writing math and
analytical skills this is the brain that
were conditioned to use for the most
part in school it's a brain that's
computer like it's completely objective
doesn't contain any emotion in the same
fashion that the cortex does or our
memory and brain this is a lower form
and when I say lower form it just means
that it's it's closer to the body it's
closer to the heart like I described
before then the higher brain the the
spiritual brain right the analytical
brain but it gets not nearly the
attention that the neocortex does in our
Western eyes our Western culture because
it's not very analytical we're all about
analyzing love and emotions is
associated with this smaller older brain
passion care for others and also memory
to a degree much greater than our brain
stem or old brain reptilian brain right
this brain is like our unconscious it's
like our vegetative nervous system and
like you see in the picture it dries all
the way down into the peripheral nervous
system that extends into our balls into
our legs so the entire peripheral
nervous system really drops out of the
brain stem or the medulla the old brain
the reptilian brain the very first thing
that this brain was designed to do was
to take care of the 4x feeding
fight/flight and fucking right it's
instinctual it regulates sleep heart
rate
and I spoke a lot about breathing in
that video yesterday digestion and
elimination like I said it's the
autonomic nervous system or also thought
caused called the vegetative nervous
system in some tradition but autonomic
meaning automatic you don't have to
think in order for this part of the
brain to work now here's where all the
tension in our body happens when we put
all our emphasis and efforts and all of
our conditioning is based on the use of
the neocortex by itself the new brain
because like I said I mean they're
eliminating physical education in school
you're constantly having shut down your
emotion love passion anger frustration
all the emotion and passion associated
with the cortex and obviously the
fighting flight right you know because
so much of our lives are stressful but
we will run right it's not like a lion
is chasing us it's a lot of it is
perceived fucking whatever around
fucking everybody you know it's just we
don't do that anymore it's we are a
higher-caliber now as human beings we're
no longer just brain stem or reptilian
in nature so what happens is the
neocortex begins to ignore the cortex
and the brainstem begins to ignore
emotions and stifle shut down emotion
and it completely pretends as if the
autonomic nervous system doesn't exist
any longer we feed ourselves horrible
food our digestion and eliminations all
fucked up people are they've got GERD
they've got all types of acid reflux
they're constipated
no one's breathing properly and that was
a huge one with what I was trying to
describe yesterday stimulate the brain
stem the medulla the old brain the
autonomic nervous system by breathing
properly by opening up the body opening
up the body like I said this drives down
into the body down into the sex organs
open up the body by breathing deeper so
to answer the question come full circle
yes I lost my brain for lost my mind for
your moment of time but it was just the
neocortex so that the cortex and the
brainstem could do all the weird shit
that's been trapped deep down within it
enslaved and stifled by the neo cortex
this doesn't just happen to me this is
happening to you as you watch this kids
that like to play video games you know
what's happening you're watching and
associating through the neocortex all of
the fighting in the games all the things
that you're doing to move forward in the
game but your body is not expressing the
excitement associated with winning the
game or losing the game whatever the
case may be so you're sitting there the
brainstem the medulla the old brain the
autonomic nervous system your breathing
as well as the emotions associated with
your cortex are completely dormant wow
this guy neocortex is the losers going
on and on and on and on right same thing
when you sit in school when our
children's to sit down in school right
sit down shut up don't be too emotional
don't consider your body just think just
think mathematics reading writing
arithmetic arithmetic right so as all
those things get stuffed down in you in
me we've got to take time we've got to
take a moment today even there's 20
minutes and let it all out you've got
the best ways to start doing this and
I've shared this with you before and I
kind of alluded to it in the video is to
charge the body with breath focusing on
the out-breath I told you how to open
your mouth wide breathe charged the body
do the bow I've showed you this in other
videos where you open up your chest you
stretch the extra respiratory muscles
associated with bringing the breath down
into your balls watch my other channel
my strength conditioning channel I've
done several videos on my bioenergetic
warmup and also how to breathe deep
stretches for breathing deep then begin
so we've stimulated the old brain with
the breath then we want to bring forth
the cortex want to bring the pork forth
the mammalian emotional passionate brain
the best way to do that is to start
shaking the body
so after you've charged your body start
shaking your body and shaking your head
and eventually just let go when you know
that you've let you let go you know that
you've left the neocortex release and
relinquish its responsibility to the
body when you start really getting
erratic and then just use free
association saying words and just doing
whatever comes to you you're breaking
the neurotic I've spoken about this
holding patterns by breathing deep to
stimulate the old brain and shaking the
body to let out the traps emotion again
I try my best to keep this a short video
but study it on your own if this is
something that you find interesting I'll
try my best to continue to offer you
more information talk to you next time
BAM