hey so I've got a couple questions here
from guys who have obsessive negative
thoughts they say that a negative
thought comes into their mind be it
about themselves someone else
doomsday whatever the case may be but
things that don't make them feel good
and then they can't get it out of their
heads
it's just it becomes an obsession and
it's a spiral downward which will
ultimately lead to depression because if
you continue to harbor and entertain
these thoughts they begin to manifest
themselves physically in your body and
then in your world it's no poetic saying
that you become what you think about and
that the world is your mirror we are
literally creating our world through the
thoughts that we Harbor and it begins in
how our body responds to the things that
we think about and if you think
depressive things your body your energy
becomes depressed right if you're
thinking negative things can you smile
and laugh and tell jokes and go run
around in circles with children and play
and dance right you can't do it because
you've got depressive thoughts and if
you're really fucking excited can you
help yourself
like if someone tells you you need to
sit down and shut up and and bottle it
all in but you're like it's the night
before Christmas like a little kid tell
a little kid to sit down during like
Christmas like put Christmas presents or
presents birthday present in front of
them and say sit there they can't help
but the excitement's going to burst out
so your body responds to your thoughts
what's going on is going to show up in
your body
and this is just my reiteration of the
fact that the body is the mind and we
begin with the body so now how do we
control the thoughts coming in and out
of our heads negative thoughts that are
that you are now a victim of right
because the thoughts are victimizing you
they come in like a virus and they take
over just like you know any other
pathogen right right you get a stomach
bug and it gets
that's it you're fucked until he takes
medicine to get it out well
thoughts are an interesting thing
because like I alluded to before we have
to entertain them in order for them to
have any power now consider this term
entertain someone comes to your door
right you're your mom you haven't seen
your mom in a very long time or over an
old friend comes to the door your old
friend comes the door and he you invite
him into your house and now what do you
do you entertain you offer energy in his
direction hey would you like something
to drink
sure hey have a seat this is my favorite
chair I'd like you to try it out hey
check it out when you lean it back do
you see how comfortable that is Oh I'll
call my wife Colleen did some of that
dip that you made last night we have any
of that left we'd like to entertain our
friend with some nourishing food hey
what kind of movies do you like I've got
a whole DVD collection people don't have
DVD collections anymore we have Netflix
and Hulu have you seen that movie yet
let's let's sit down and watch it by the
way let's have a beer while we watch it
that's entertaining someone who comes
into your home a friendly person who
you'd like to have around for a while
and allow them to grow roots for a
moment there are certain thoughts that
make their way into the home of your
consciousness they knock on the door
your first choice is to either let them
in I mean before entertaining you gotta
let it in let the thoughts in or close
the door GU slam the door shut okay the
way that looks is I get negative
thoughts I get negative thoughts Eliot
house gets negative thoughts negative
shit comes into my mind sometimes the
weirdest fucking things it's like I
really don't know why this keeps popping
up here's one I keep having this one
that I'm gonna get into a car accident I
don't know why it's a new one but I keep
thinking that I'm not gonna be paying
attention when I'm driving and I'm my
car is gonna demolished for whatever
reason that keeps knocking on my door
maybe I should pay attention to it I
wear my seat
right maybe that's what it is it's
morning put on your fucking seatbelt and
don't check your phone while you're
driving take heed but I don't let it in
such that I start obsessing over car
accidents and I become a nervous fucking
wreck while I'm driving I don't start
watching videos about car wrecks and
when the news on the news when there is
a car accident I started could have been
me I don't entertain the thought I don't
go home and start talking about car
wrecks and potentials for dying in a car
accident with my wife and my friends is
the matter entertaining the thought he
came to the door I peeked I said oh shit
and I walked away he goes away now
sometimes oftentimes because I attract
them beautiful thoughts come in my goals
I'd like to achieve you know what I'd
like one day not because I need it not
because I'm greedy not for anything but
the fact that I know I can do it I want
one of those Mercedes G classes that's a
six-figure car looks like a jeep I don't
have to have this thing I'm not to make
myself neurotic but it's a nice thought
that when it comes to my do it when it
comes to my window I say huh come on in
and I look at pictures but I go on and I
see how much it costs and I try buy the
Mercedes dealership and I see it in
there and one day I might go in there
and I might sit and I say look sir I
can't afford one of you but boy I'd like
to sit in it
cuz I'm entertaining the thought guess
what
I'm smiling my body feels good I'm
receptive to it watch my videos long
enough I'll tell you what I have it and
I won't have to break my ass for it
because it happens just by entertaining
it moving with it adding energy to it in
the same way you've chosen with the
negative thoughts
the depressive folks what you've got to
understand my friends is that you are
completely empowered you have all the
control you are driving you're in the
driver's seat you have your hands on the
steering wheel of the thoughts you
decide to Harbor it's your choice
negative thoughts are going to knock at
your door but you are letting them in
and giving them chips and dip they're
going to come they're gonna come to all
of us they come to me peek recognize if
it's a warning just be aware and then
move on go about your life you know the
easiest way to move on is go do
something for someone else go do
something go wash the dishes for your
mom I do this when I find myself too
wrapped up in my own thoughts my to
become too self subjective you know
feeling bad about something because it
happens to me you know what I do I start
cleaning my house thinking boy colleen's
gonna be happy when she comes home and
the dishes are washed and all the
children are bathed the night and I
brushed my daughter's hair I help them
with homework I go and do shit for other
people so I can stop thinking about shit
that is self-centered and and self
depressing okay understand two things
you're empowered if depressive thoughts
are coming to your mind you say good bye
be in even more powerful ways replace
him with someone else he comes to the
door here comes hey here's cancer hey
there you know your might get cancer
instantly in your mind switch people who
just came to my door exercise breathing
deep walking in the sunshine walking
Beach how nice is it to walk on the
beach boy I live in Florida so instantly
cancer comes in my door I envision
myself walking on the beach looking lean
and sexy and the water splashing and
I've got my beautiful wife next to me
I'm just changing thoughts right
it's your choice that's number one
number two if you just can't stop the
keeps knocking at the fucking door and
he's being annoying right Here I am bad
shits gonna happen could happen
you're an asshole you're ugly you're no
good whatever it whatever he comes with
comes with all types of nasty baggage
usually specific to you in your
situation you know your dad never really
liked you he always resented the fact
that you were born you know your mom was
a bitch we never really respected your
dad oh they all could you know it
depends on you close the window and go
and do something for someone else
someone else not you not because it's
going to help you not because it moves
you forward and achieving and out of any
superficial goal but because you gotta
get your mind off this shit and you know
what makes you feel happier than
anything all of us human beings what
makes us happier than anything putting a
smile on someone else's face go knock on
your neighbor's door and you be a
blessing to her hey miss Wilson I
noticed you haven't raped your leaves I
noticed you got a lot of snow I notice
your plants need watering let me do it
for you miss will
listen miss Wilson's gonna smile and
you'll feel good because the world is
your mirror done