today's question is one that some people
might find a little disturbing but
before I offer a perspective on that I
wanted to share this with you I've asked
for your questions and you guys sure
have sent them some of them are very
deep I want you to know that I cannot
offer you a solution I cannot fix
anything all I can do is offer you a
perspective a way of looking at things
that maybe 180 degrees differently than
what you're used to from that
perspective you might find some
resourceful behavior to proceed with it
may be helpful to you but all it is is a
perspective it's a tool if you find that
it's unrestorable doesn't help you
causes you to feel offended then just
drop it I'm not right nothing that I say
is true it's just a perspective now on
to our question it comes from a woman
who sent me a Facebook message she goes
on to describe how she had a love affair
very short one with a man she once
worked with about ten years ago she was
young at a time and found herself in a
situation where she needed to reject him
she didn't really love him they were
having sex he didn't feel the same way
he was very attached to her loved her
deeply according to friends and family
who spoke to her after the tragic
situation one day she decides to go into
work and tell him that it's over we're
done I don't love you this was nothing
more than just sex and he in his
distraught state he took his own life he
decided to lay down on a railroad track
and committed suicide ten years ago so
our friend goes on to describe how for
10 years she's been living with guilt
experiencing guilt and is having a
difficult time going on with her life
without caring that cloud over her head
first thing I want to do is offer you
this
guilt is not an actual feeling sorrow is
a feeling I mean they we say feeling
because you actually feel it you feel
sorrow welling up in your body you feel
joy welling up in your body guilt is a
concept whereby a moral obligation a
moral judgment from the mind and from
the environment from other people is
being placed on an actual feeling so
guilt is actually a conflict of
interests you're feeling a particular
way but there's a moral judgment being
placed on it so for example when you're
a kid and you're you especially during
the the ages of 4 to 6 when you're
exploring your sexuality for the first
time you you feel sexual but your
parents tell you well don't touch your
vagina don't touch your penis or
whatever the case may be and then
there's a moral judgment placed on what
you naturally feel sexuality is a real
feeling you feel it in your body the
moral judgment placed on sexuality or
guilt I mean I'm sorry or sorrow or joy
is where the conflict arises so what
you're experiencing is a conflict of
interest between the ego and your body
what I would offer you and what I would
invite you to do is to get in touch with
the actual feeling what are you feeling
in your body now it's not about being
right or wrong about this feeling you
may be feeling joy about the situation
there there tends to be a thread of
righteousness with every form of guilt
and it stems from the fact that you
there's a party that feels well this I
should feel this do you feel joy do you
feel like you know he deserved it
he was harassing me and I and serves him
right again I'm not here to judge or
tell you what's right or true could be
right it could be wrong I'm not here to
judge you're feeling it if it happens to
be joy be
with the joy Express it fully not in
front of your friends or family or that
person's family go and look at a picture
of this individual and talk to him
you deserve this damn right and I feel
great
hahaha the evil laugh joyful laugh I
can't really give you a joyful laugh in
a situation like this but if you feel
joy it's yours feel it be with it be
with it 100% so that you can be done
with it and then the moral judgement
will have nothing to stand on there'll
be no more conflict if you feel sorrow
you deeply deeply regret what you did
you truly are sorry not because of the
moral judgment but because you actually
feel sorry you are you have sorrow
welling up in your body that is yours be
with the sorrow cry again do something a
lot of times emotions are very difficult
to evoke conceptually we've got to do
things to evoke them that's why I show
you guys exercises that seem a little
bit odd but because they evoke emotion
in order to avoid VOC joy pretend
laughing pretend to laugh until you
actually laugh to evoke tears sobbing
because of the sorrow that you actually
feel not that has been a potent posed on
you pretend to cry until the tears
actually come wail uh-uh-uh-uh-uh until
the tears come sometimes we've got to
fake it in order to actually release the
emotions that we're carrying their true
feelings that we're carrying so again
this is not a solution it's a
perspective I'm giving you permission to
feel the true feelings welling up in
your body you can no longer rebel
against them especially through a moral
judgment moral judgments of the head
your feelings the sorrow of the joys of
your body that mind-body split is what
destroys us the mind is saying one thing
the body is saying another we've got to
honor the body we can't
nice judgment on every single feeling
that we have there are times when you've
got to experience it okay some of you
might be saying Elliot well you don't go
out go around feeling all your feelings
in front of people this is true but find
a safe environment either by yourself or
with someone else you feel safe around
and get it out because it's trapped in
your body and you're fighting against
yourself you're eating yourself alive
life is good
continue to love others and continue to
grow stronger
Elliot sit
[Music]