it was so guys we got a question from
our buddy who calls himself Mike from
the US now Mike from the US has grown
very miserable his piece says his
kindness is going away because he's
found himself in a circumstance where it
on a daily basis he's having to share
office space with someone who is of poor
energy negative energy he goes on Mike
goes on and complains about all the
things that this guy does to his
customers the things that he does to his
wife and just as general lack of
consideration for other people Mike also
says that he will hurl insults in his
direction or ignore him doesn't pay his
rent on time apparently subleasing to
this guy or something like that and to
make matters worse although the guy's
lease is almost up he's decided to move
right next door so Mike if he's going to
maintain his business where he's at he's
going to have to live quite a bit longer
with this miserable miserable person
that's destroying Mike's character and
this is how he describes it this man is
making my life sick because when I go
home I can't even enjoy time with my
wife and family I'm so stressed out that
I can't even hug my wife and enjoy it
because I'm beat down depressed and
sickened by a day full of dealing with
this asshole so he wants to know what do
I do because now I live with this guy so
Mike the very first thing I would do is
invite you to watch a video that I
recorded maybe two months ago I think
it's called three types of people in
your life and I'll preface what I'm
going to ultimately say by this there
are three types of people in your life
watch that video well briefly describe
them number one he's either a mirror
meaning this is the person that has been
set here to show you something about
yourself that you otherwise wouldn't see
right and when you look at him you'll
either feel disgust because of what the
mirror is giving you back or something
thereof apparently it's disgust because
you're disgusted with this guy sometimes
mirrors are good people they show you
good parts of yourself then you've got
your crystal ball this is someone who if
you continue along the journey the way
you're continuing it you're going to end
up just like that person good or bad
it's completely objective if you can
continue down this path you might be an
asshole too or you might be a good
person depending on how it shows up and
then in angel and an angel is there to
show you again it's completely objective
either a good or a bad blessing bring a
good or a bad blessing into your life
but either way they come bearing a gift
of some sort to teach you something
about yourself or to help further you on
your journey right sometimes you go
further in your journey by getting a
kick in the ass backwards right so
that's something that you need to be
aware of beyond that and again watch
that whole video it's probably a ten
minute video beyond just that you've got
to also recognize that this is an
opportunity for your character to grow
now you mentioned in your email that I
have a friend female friend who had been
in abusive relationships with men in the
past men that beat her up and that when
she listens to you talk about this guy
the asshole in your office she says you
know you sound a lot like I sounded when
I was making excuses for my husbands
that beat me up now that's a red flag
especially coming for someone who's been
in a similar circumstance as you as you
are that there's something that you need
to work on character wise this is your
fault right
I sound harsh often times when I say
that you know your circumstance is the
shit that's happening to you it's your
fault it's your fault but you know what
being it your fault also does it gives
you responsibility and you know what
responsibility is total empowerment
meaning you can do something about it
you've got to go on the inside and
figure out what's fucked up about
yourself you can't change him and you're
in a place where it's very difficult for
you to change your circumstances you can
always change your circumstances but
maybe you don't want to maybe it's best
that you don't because you'll have to
take your eyes off of what's happening
out there with him and the circumstance
turn him inside and say okay where am I
going wrong where am I not being the
strongest version by
so that this shit is happening that's
very empowering I want it to be my fault
when bad shit happens I want it to be my
fault because now I can say what shall I
do about these circumstances since it's
my fault I'm empowered and you my friend
need to take a look you know I could
pack it through out a few different
scenarios
you know perhaps and I might be harsh in
saying so you're just a pussy you're a
big old pussy pushover and this guy is
there to show you as a mirror it's
you're a big old pussy pushover
he's a crystal ball to show you that if
you keep going down this route your life
is gonna continue the same way and he's
an angel he's your best blessing cuz
he's showing you your big ass pussy you
need to toughen up and toughen up might
look a little bit like this knock on his
door say hey how would you like to go
out for coffee this afternoon I'd like
to speak with you about a few things
right now that's a shot always begin
with a pattern interrupt now any respect
facts he knows you hate him
go bearing gifts bringing my gift bring
him the coffee hey Bob I was at the
coffee shop today I thought that you
might like one
I noticed that you often have the mocha
latte chart a chocolate latte with foam
on top and that's gonna keep going with
the ED you redo him and he's like well
goddamn it you son of a bitch fucking
thank you he's an asshole so that's how
he talks and you sit down and say look
Bob we've got to work together I know
that we were both in this office
together and you know I do my thing and
you do your things and there's been some
tension between us and I want to lay all
the cards out on the table
Bob explain to me what it is that I
might be doing that irritates you
because I get it I get a sense that
you're not happy being where you are or
at least I've made you upset at certain
points I want to make sure that doesn't
continue Bob so please let's talk about
that well you know what I can't fucking
stand it when you come in here
smiling whistling whistling all day long
you do fucking happy and it pisses me
off now see you begin the conversation
by figuring out what's going on with Bob
so you take all of it off of yourself in
this particular way and you give Bob an
opportunity to talk and maybe you find
out some things about Bob maybe he finds
out some things about you maybe you're
whistling irritates him I'm gonna stop
right there cuz playing this
make-believe is not too fun for me today
especially because I'm losing it so my
third video today and I'm fasting so
drying up here drying up physically and
literally literally and metaphorically
see I can't even say it drying up in my
in my my presentation skills and all
fucking dry here bottom line here is
dude man let me stop just finish up with
this put on your big boy pants watching
his office and have a mono e mono men
mad feet on the ground palm to palm I
die conversation with this guy and deal
with your demons because it's your fault
done