what's up gentlemen today we have a
question from our buddy Cameron about
the type of music he's listening to he
says that recently he came across one of
my videos where I said to be mindful of
the type of music that you listen to
because it can change your consciousness
it can brainwash you into becoming
something that you may or may not want
to become it's really our choice and he
says that I really enjoy listening to
very angry music in particular mmm and
nwa the type of music that he can really
become enraged with and when he listens
to it he finds that he becomes enveloped
by the music even mouthing the words and
he enjoys the cathartic experience of
allowing this angry music to to move and
he's wondering now Eliot I really
enjoyed this practice but should I stop
and is this a bad practice because
ultimately it may affect me in a way
that I wouldn't like to be affected very
first thing is I'd like to just clear up
any confusion about my judgment against
music I love all music in fact I grew up
listening to Eminem and mlwa mlwa
I'm much a bit older so NWA I mean I was
in sixth grade I think fifth grade when
I first heard NWA on a little tape
cassette I loved it
Eminem when he first came out with that
song the real Slim Shady real Slim Shady
I was I think that was his first song I
think I was a freshman in college and I
blasted that shit man I fucking love
that song
I like a lot of his music I love the
poetry associated with his music and I
also enjoy the melody the beat the music
I mean that's really that's really what
attracts us that's really what gets us
in a resourceful state so that the
messages could be embedded into our
consciousness it's not just the words
and you've got to understand this what
makes that music so appealing is what it
does to our bodies and you can't help
but to become moved by it right and as
your body moves and this is why I often
say that the body is the mind
as your body is free to move and you
begin releasing muscular tension because
I mean you can't dance unless you're ten
if you're tense well let's say one of
these guys they know the guys that have
to have like 17 beers and then they go
into the dancefloor and they just David
they do this with a stiff body thinking
that some woman might be interested in
their penis you know that's not what
you're that's not what you're after
you're looking after getting your whole
body relaxed and moving so that you can
absorb whatever is happening in the
environment and the music does does this
to us and it makes us more receptive
right
Dancing's kind of yielding it's very
feminine in that way right when I say
mad feminine and masculine I know a lot
of you guys get confused I'm talking
about the energies it's a feminine
energy right
so we listen to that music even if it's
angry music he's doing this right I mean
look you look at look at gangsta rappers
right he says gangster rapping is in his
email it's a lot of this right right you
know just you don't do that you don't
stand there and stiffly and and listen
to and put to make the music and you
don't stand there stiffly and listen to
music unless you're unless you're a
square a lot of those in our culture you
fucking move you gotta move
so with movement there is a yielding
quality and you become more receptive to
the messages coming in part of the
reason why I never did well in school is
because you're supposed to sit down
bottle yourself up but right and then
absorb through your eyes and ears right
where there's no bodily stimulation and
even if the content at the front of the
class if the professor is offering is of
value to you and you may even find it
stimulating and when I I hesitate when I
said we're stimulating because that the
word stimulating needs to stimulate
right what happens if you get stimulated
you're moving stimulating it's going to
be a bit easier because you start
getting agitated because just like whoa
this is excited when I start learning
shit that I want to learn and it's
outside of the realm of bodily
intelligence I get agitated right I
start reading a book and I fucking love
it I get up and I have to move and I'm
like oh I gotta go tell someone
I have to get actively engaged in the
learning process that's how I brainwash
myself with shit how do you guys wonder
how does it fit Elliott memorizes a lot
of things that he talks about someone
commented the other day that Elliott is
the way he is because he reads a lot of
books Oh contraire my friend Ron frenz a
how we say it's not so much that I read
a lot of books and absorb through my
eyes and ears I just get fucking excited
about stuff and when I get excited I
move my body and when I move my body I'm
in a rhythm I'm in a frequency based on
what I'm sure what's coming into my
through my mind into my mind right it
gets absorbed into my body my
intelligence is in here I'm a fucking
retard they gave me pills because I'm
not that smart I can't memorize that
well but I feel really well and all that
stuff gets inside me part of the reason
why a lot of people enjoy my videos is
because I'm so animated and when I'm
animated I can reach you at a visceral
level you see what I'm doing right now
I'm staring deep into your soul you can
feel me and that's part of reason why a
lot of people like my videos a lot of
people think it's trash a lot of people
can't fucking stand me those of you who
really get upset when you watch my
videos you can't stand all my emote
avala teas take notice as to where in
your body you feel your disgust for me
because it's still reaching you at a
visceral level that's the whole point
here the things that touch you at a
visceral level in your body that move
you are going to embed themselves into
your consciousness and that's why music
is so god damn powerful
so here's my invitation to you that's
all I ever do I offer invitations ideas
and information I invitations I very
rarely would like to offer advice right
because the whole world is giving you
fucking advice I don't give you advice
just an idea choose who you want to
become who do you need to be in order to
achieve the goal you set assets set
ahead for yourself who do you need to be
right now in order to achieve goal a do
you need to be an angry gangster to
achieve goal a because if you do then
listen on buddy keep listening to NWA
keep listening to Eminem's most angry
music let it absorb you let it envelop
you let it reach deep into your viscera
deep into your heart into your gut move
with it yeah with it be a part of the
music because it really root itself in
who you are because you need to be an
angry gangster to do what you need to do
now if you sell drugs and you're in you
live in a landscape where there's a lot
of violence and you got to fucking get
your shit right you got to be on point
you can't you got you you have to be
sharp you can't fuck around it just
happens to be your environment that's
just that's it
I make no judgments you had better be an
angry motherfucking gangster
don't listen to Bach don't listen to Bob
Marley Baba Lee will fuck you up
I let Bob Marley fuck me up ah
purposefully I tell you in a minute
listen that angry gangster music and be
angry fucking gangster but you've got to
be very clear about who you are to be
and what you're trying to achieve
because if you listen to music that's
not going to support you in who you need
to be in order to be cut and do the
thing you want to do then you get it all
fucked up right
if you're trying to have a warm
passionate deep loving relationship with
a woman
don't listen to angry gangster rap
because you're going to be angry fucking
gangster while you trying to get with
this girl listen to candy shop now I'm
fucking with you ha listen listen to
something that's a bit more sexual bit
more loving write something let me look
at my body right now cuz I'm so
transparent but look what I'm doing
right now this is this is the type of
music you want to listen to this is what
it should look like when you listen to
it right right you see the difference as
opposed to this right you do this you're
gonna be a premature ejaculator
guys are going to go to the club right
they get hammered because they keep they
have no fucking movement in their body
they can't they're so stiff and rigid
they don't even breathe they go hey they
gonna have 17 beers and do this you see
I'm writing I won't be everyone here and
they just they just what they think like
somehow some females gonna be attracted
to his stiff body and dick doing this
nah that's good if you want to be a
fucking gangster right now try get with
this bitch right good baby I want to be
a little bit smoother be a little bit
relaxed
you choose the music to brainwash you to
affect your nervous system to create a
response that you want that's what
source for for the goal when I first
moved to Florida
ten years ago my one and only objective
was to succeed in my career that meant I
had to become the top trainer at the
personal strength at the gym that I was
at and ultimately go out and build a
business and attacked the world with
everything that I had to offer so that I
could succeed when I do this it's
because that was my success right hey
angry gangster drug dealer I'm 16 years
old and makes $10,000 a day yo maybe
that success for you no judgement for me
it was building a business as a personal
trainer I wanted to empower people
through the body like I do now so I had
to brainwash myself and I didn't have
the luxury to listen to music that
although it was pleasurable offered me
no substance for who I had to become to
achieve the thing I wanted to achieve so
I listen to audio programs I didn't
listen to music for several months there
but a good year maybe year and a half
and I was into music in my car there's
no music in my car at all so when I was
moving down here I would listen to over
to Brian Tracy mostly and are all
Nightingale audio programs when I
decided that I was going to quit my job
and start my business all of a sudden I
mean I had all the information I needed
all the motivation I needed to take that
leap because of how I brainwash myself
with Earl Nightingale and Brian Brian
Tracy and I began listening to 50 cent
really angry 50 cent music like the type
of shit like I'm going to shoot you in
your face because I needed to be a
warrior I needed to be a just a fucking
go-get-'em warrior I was like nothing's
gonna stand in my way nobody and nothing
is gonna stand in my way I'm making this
shit happen
and for about a good year all I listened
to was fifty said I was a big old
50-cent fan right love it
angry the better in fact I hated all
that feminine music that they would like
I said candy shop before all the
feminine music I would skip those just
the angry shit because I needed to be
angry I needed I needed fearsome
attitude in order to get where I wanted
to get right make all the judgments you
want fellows I'm here then I got to a
place where the ball was rolling but I
started to burn myself out because I was
kind of overdoing it and I began feeling
as if boy I better back the fuck up a
little bit because I'm gonna kill myself
I even popped my bicep alright cuz I was
doing just I was becoming a professional
strong man - as I was building my
business bro strong as I was just I was
tearing up the fucking world you can't
tear up the wall world listening to
listening to Bob Marley but I got to a
point where I realized the whole thing
needed to come down a little bit because
I was going to kill myself I would have
ruined my my relationship with my wife
my family would have been devastated and
my business would probably would have
crumbled at some point because you can't
be all fire without burning out you need
cool down a little bit I live in Florida
I grew up in New York in New York
there's no country music no no country
music stations it just didn't exist when
I was there right I think they might
have one out I started in a country
music country music is all about Friday
nights and drinking beer in fact my
favorite song at that particular point
that I played over and over again was
the Zac Brown song called chicken fried
and the whole song was about I can't
wait til Friday night so I can drink a
beer eat some fried chicken and hang out
with my why women hang out with my
family that's the whole fucking song
that's what it was about and I basically
listened to a genre of that particular
kind of music for a while and it carried
me through carried me through it carried
me through carry me through I didn't
listen anything else for about three
years
recently this winter I began listening
to Bob Marley which was a step even
slower I started listening to reggae
like really conscious reggae stuff like
I said Bob Marley and then and also
classical music you know I'm not a not a
connoisseur of classical music but I
began listening to Mozart so I listened
to Mozart and Bob Marley and that was
all that played in my car and in my home
and I went into a I went into a place
where I felt I needed to go and you
watch my videos from four or five months
ago you'll see that it's when my hair
was was out of control
I needed to go into a place of deep
inner reflection I needed to be
self-absorbed for a while
I needed to slow down my speech just
watch my videos you see I needed to
become more grounded in the moment per
se so I listened to that music it's it's
it's sort of a chicken and egg situation
because I listen to it because I knew it
put me where my energy was going my
Energy's going this way you got to be
mindful one of the things I hope for you
guys pray for you guys is that you can
sense your own energy and where it's
carrying you
and although the world places its
demands on you you allow yourself to
yield into the energy that your body is
carrying you towards I have to show up
and make these videos on a daily basis
that's why you know I confuse so many of
you because whatever energy my body is
asking me to engage it how I body's
asking me to be I show up as and you
guys say whoa Elliott's getting weird
whoa Elliott's change Oh what happened
to Elliott I allow myself and I support
who I'm becoming who might my body is
telling me to become because you gotta
understand something life is not linear
you don't you don't achieve who you're
going to be you make your way somewhere
and it usually actually looks like this
you know there's charge discharge charge
discharge charge discharge
it's a you get aggressive you chill the
fuck out
you got to notice that about you I mean
it happens in nature so I'm Rhys sunset
winters summer it's just the suede is so
I yielded to that I began listening to
that kind of music I still do to a
significant point but now it's a little
bit more upbeat stuff you know I enjoy
reggae so I listen to like I ration and
tribal seeds and you know revolution
stuff like that but recently well
because a lot of you recognize the
change in my character and look if
you're sticking around get used to it
I'm gonna keep changing I'm listening to
jay-z I'm letting jay-z brainwash me
right now and I fucking love it there
are so many parallels of course I'm not
jay-z I'll never achieve to the status
of the status of a jay-z not that I even
care if it happens it happens not a Ford
or against it but I like his poetry I
like what he's saying I like the fact
that he busted his ass and became what
he really is now as a king and his
lyrics and the melody are resourceful
for who I'd like to become so I listen
to it my brain motto brainwash myself
with this particular music
I'm conscious about it it's not
arbitrary it's not because it's a pop
hit right your your urine really you're
really in trouble when you allow the
radio and the pop charts to dictate what
you listen to because now the world has
its hand on your steering wheel and
decides what you're going to think and
how you're going to be as opposed to you
choosing so that's it my friend my
invitation once again is to be aware of
how the music is affecting you and ask
yourself is this who I need to be in
order to reach the goal I've set for
myself and if they're not aligned make
better choices not better choices based
on what other people have told you is
right and true and good and bad but
based on how is it helping you become
who you need to become done