yo Elliot what's up guys today's
question comes from strengthcamp online
member as they all do austin klein che
an austin goes on to say that i've been
training quite a few of my friends
lately and they started to show a great
interest in functional training after
they've seen my results when she was
that i find it particularly difficult to
teach them to deadlift and squat their
beginners what are some of the best cues
that i can offer when teaching them how
to master these exercises without having
them get injured thanks Austin well
Austin as you know I'm a coach and I've
gotten great results with my clients but
what you might not know is that I've
been coached and and throughout my
career as a football player strong man
and in my internships mentor ships in
becoming a coach I've had some really
incredible coaches and I can think of
two in particular and the interesting
thing between about these two coaches is
that they said very little it wasn't a
matter of what they said or cues they
used it was a matter of who they were
being and what they expected of me when
I trained with them i'll tell you what i
mean so right out of college I started
working for a guy in Long Island and use
a very conservative I learned a lot of
my training techniques with regard to
the deadlift than the front squat all
this you know very very uh row how would
you say I'm conservative form through
this coach and the way he taught me was
by having me train with him said the
best way you're gonna learn this is by
you doing it with me so I he do it of
course like with any training partner he
do a set and I'd watch him I just
watching and then he'd say okay now I
want you to try the same thing and then
I do the set he wouldn't say very much
he might say good or pick your chest up
a little bit or
very few things didn't say very much at
all and then I put the weight down and
then he'd do it again and I'd watch him
and then over time just because I'd see
him do it and then I practice it right
after him I began to pick up on all of
the little my new show all the little
train in strange intricacies of the way
he did the movement it was because I was
doing the thing with him all the time
that I was able to grow my ability to
perform the movement right interesting
monkey see monkey do there wasn't much
monkey talking so quite frankly there
wasn't much cueing or talking going on
it was a matter of me doing what I saw
him doing and constantly trying to use
my own kinesthetic awareness which
everyone has you know the more they
train with you the more they'll be like
you and you know Larry there there goes
that was the coaching technique all
right so if you're training with your
training partners and they see you doing
it and then they go and do it and if
that you know the other thing is with
you got too many training partners it
becomes a you know shit show where you
guys are all exercising your jaw you
know talking about a whole bunch of
bullshit or check it out your iPhone's
and stuff but if they're actually
observing you and you're observing them
and you're working together it's just a
matter of osmosis being in your presence
they will gain strength and and you know
you're choosing the exercises and
they're in the routine and of course
you're choosing exercises that help
support the development of those lips
like accessory lifts they keep doing
what you're doing they're going to get
what you get right the other coach was
my strong man coach Tom Mitchell and you
know of course straw man is on the other
end of the spectrum that's why you know
it's kind of interesting the way I coach
is because I'm very conservative I
learned from my conservative coach and
then I also went did straw man i get my
hand straight and and he was very
liberal meaning like I don't give a fuck
what you do as long as you hurt yourself
cuz I ain't cleaning up the mess that
was his attitude and you know we're
lifting stones and flipping tires and
carrying kegs and putting a little
these big yolks you've seen these in
some of my videos and it was completely
oddball crazy odd object training and he
didn't teach me a goddamn thing he would
just point and say go ahead and pick
that up everyone the first time I did
stones he stood behind the platform
rested his arms on it right so he's
behind the platform I'm in front of it
with this 225 pounds Stone he's got the
platform here he goes going to pick that
up and put it on here and I'm like okay
I mean never having done this before in
my life you guys watch me in the open
gym videos where T I am teaching guys
how to lift the stone because it's like
well you're probably not going to come
back here very often and so that you can
continue to progress so I'm going to
give you a little bit of tips he didn't
give me no goddamn tips at all he just
said pick it up and I'm they're
literally struggling trying to pick this
fucking thing up oh my god this has got
to be impossible but meanwhile there is
stolen bike there I'm picking up a stone
and there are ones that are like three
or four times bigger over there and like
somebody's picking this thing up so it's
got to be possibly be done and I'm
struggling trying to figure it out then
eventually I figure it out i'm on i get
it on my lap and i put it on top I smile
and he says do it again right and that's
how I learned strong man form technique
that if you watch me coaching a lot of
times you I go from that conservative
deadlift to fuck shit up with that stone
so this is kind of a long way of me
saying my friend that you don't need to
get too caught up in the technicalities
of verbiage what are you going to say in
order for them to do what you want them
to do what you do what you want them to
do and then you have an expectation for
them to get it done you see that done
Elliot's it what
[Music]