sup guys Here I am at the park and
that's my Yukon in the back this
material things cuz I like material
things and I manifest material things
cuz I visualize my life
so yesterday I spoke about going to the
park during my lunch breaks and how I
sit down and I write out my goals and
visualizations how do Tai Chi and Qigong
I eat my lunch and plot for my future
while sitting on that park bench back in
2004 so anyway I figured it'd be cool
since I was driving past the park today
to do my video in the park in fact my
video yesterday reminded me of so much
love that I harbored for this park but I
decided maybe I'll come back today and
maybe I'll come back here more often I'd
sit at this bench eat my lunch right out
my goals visualize and then what I would
do is I get up it was always a shady
spot right there by that uh but I hill
and I would do my breathing exercises my
Tai Chi there's a lot of hot summer
afternoons some beautiful ones like here
today at this far
so anyway today's video I want to talk a
little bit about I want to kind of bring
us up to date yesterday we spoke about
how to set up your schedule during your
warrior mode crush it phase of your life
and on that that time to show up anytime
you could be a warrior mode at any time
your life doesn't have to mean when
you're young doesn't have to mean when
you're struggling
it can mean when you're trying to build
anything in your life so I gave you my
schedule of activities and that's why I
mentioned this part but today instead
what I'd like to talk about is your
choice of of how you how you use your
resources right because yesterday we
spoke about time I talked about the time
that I would spend at this part here but
the other things you gotta consider is
how you spending your money someone once
said to me if you want to know
somebody's core values their true core
values look at their bank account where
are they spending their money right so
when you're in your grind come-up mode
obviously you're not gonna have a lot of
money to spend and I know I didn't and
although I made the sacrifice to spend a
lot of money on food as you notice from
yesterday's post I also cut corners on
some things that many of you might find
essential right so I did cut corners on
spending but I cut it on two major
things that drain most dudes bank
accounts I cut corners on clothes
because I was buying all my clothes back
then at the Salvation Army whatever
clothes I didn't have from New York that
I brought down with me in a bag I bought
at the local
shots I would wear thrift clothes first
or clothes right how many willing to
sacrifice that on your come up how many
of you out warriors out there willing to
humble yourself to the point where you
will buy hand-me-down huge clothing see
the other thing I did with regard to my
clothing was I wore a uniform meaning I
buy a pair of clothes maybe couple pairs
of the same exact clothes and I just
wear it every frickin day over and over
and over again that way clothing was
never an issue to me I can focus my time
my energy and my resources on more
important things like my physiology my
health my mentality right so I went
cheap on clothing I also went cheap on
cars how do you guys get out there in
the world and you start making a few
pennies and you throw it at the fucking
bank every month for your car payment
shit I don't even have a car payment on
that one I saved up my money and paid
cash because all you need is a drain a
hole in your bucket when you're trying
to come up to drain you of vital energy
and resources and money is energy money
is your resources so I always drove used
cars my dad worked on auto body so in
New York he would come home with what
we're considered totaled cars meaning
the insurance companies won't pay for
them to be fixed because they're
considered pretty much trash so I drove
totaled cars shit in fact I think that's
my first car purchase up until that
point all my cars were totaled cars cars
that my dad would patch up a little bit
and give to me you guys know the story
about when I moved down to Florida and
the use of my van to build my business
that was a hand-me-down van that my dad
patched up and gates
so you gotta understand that spending
money on stupid things like you know let
me judge it that way today I'm wearing
sunglasses and so I'm acting like a
badass I'm not going to judge it that
way it's not stupid clothes and cars
ain't stupid but they're outside of the
core they're outside of what makes you a
stronger version yourself they're just
icing on the cake there are two things
though that I always spent more on there
are two things that I would spend
extravagantly and lavishly on and that
is like I mentioned yesterday food right
because it becomes me the food you eat
becomes who you are right you got to
understand something that when you put
that food in your mouth
it becomes the cells in your body so you
can't go cheap with it otherwise you're
building yourself a weak fragile body
and the other thing I never went cheap
on was education as I mentioned in my
video yesterday and as I mentioned in
several videos in the past I have no
problem even going into debt like I did
in order to pay mentors in order to go
to courses in order to buy books in
order to learn everything I need to
learn from coaches and teachers and
mentors in order to become the strongest
version of myself so today I flash a
little bit I make sure my car is
detailed
I don't wear hand-me-down clothes but
the road towards success requires
tremendous sacrifice make sure you're
not sacrificing the important things for
the bullshit
done