so I got two questions in a row that
sounds something like this Elliot I was
dating this chick for several years
things were great she was the love of my
life then we broke up which is fine but
now all of a sudden she's dressed in
real sexy foot with my friends and
generally trying to make my life
miserable by making me jealous how do I
go about dealing with her now without me
going on a long discourse as to her
issues with her and her daddy that is
causing her to behave the way she is I
want to give you some practical advice
about dealing with her but also dealing
with people in your environment who
you're drawn towards but consciously or
rationally would like to say and do say
I need to separate myself from you right
you've broken up but she's making you
jealous the reason why she's making you
jealous is because there's a part of you
your body that is still linked to her so
if you were dating her for several years
perhaps you were having sex I'm sure you
were and you were snuggling and cuddling
and breathing in each other's ears your
body your unconscious became very much
in twined with this other individual
there's an energetic union that's still
there even though the mind and our
choices have created separation there's
still a deep union there it's funny I'm
gonna tell you a strange story when I
was in college my wife and I Colleen who
still my wife we would break up you know
for a few months here and there or just
you know get in fights and I'd say to
myself I'm done I can't deal with you
anymore I don't want to do it but we
break up and then a few weeks or so
later I'd see her we'd be like you know
we just kind of happen to see each other
and my heart rate is going up and my
dick gets hard instantly it's like I
don't want her I don't want to be with
her but all of a sudden my whole body is
like oh but you can't help it dude
because I'm so much I'm so engrained I'm
so tangled up with her energy or sexual
energy it's very hard to break up with
someone who you're still energetically
entwined with and you're still obviously
energetically entwined with her because
if you weren't the shit that she's doing
would have absolutely no bearing on you
there are lots of other girls that dress
sexily that flirt in front of you with
your friends that you probably don't get
jealous about
and it's because of this this connection
that you still have with her they often
say that the opposite of love is hate
right so if you you can cultivate this
feeling of hate towards her because of
these behaviors right and they say
there's a thin line between love and
hate so it's like she's doing all this
shit you used to love her with all of
your heart body and soul my body and
soul but now she's acting like an
asshole and you can start to hate her
but hate is a funny thing because like
they say the thin line between love and
hate you by you becoming jealous and
developing hateful feelings towards her
you're not going to push her away from
you I know that's probably what's
happening you become infuriated enraged
guess what it is coming from the same
energetic root as love love and hate are
an interesting thing in this way I'm not
saying like racism haters things like
that talk about some other people in
your life particularly women or men if
you know opposite sexes who you've been
enrolled with you could love them one
day and a poor them the next because
it's the same energy taking on different
masks if you will the opposite of love
really is apathy the opposite of love is
just not giving a shit not caring being
unmoved completely so when you are have
totally removed your body from its warm
feelings that it still has for this girl
which are not wrong in any way shape or
form but they don't support what you've
decided for yourself when you've
actually removed yourself in the way
that's most resourceful for the decision
you've made you will just not feel
anything around her it won't be a matter
of pushing her away
it'll be a matter of her she's doing
this shit and I don't even notice but
she she's wearing some hot today because
I didn't notice how do you do this how
do you create this this circumstance
where your body is no longer pulling you
towards the circumstance that doesn't
support the choice that you've already
made
I've been speaking a lot about this
lately I you know a lot of the things I
say are exact there are always the same
in a way but I use different ways to
describe how to go about it or share
different methods techniques and ideas
that might support you and and recently
I've been speaking a lot about how to
use your conscious mind to embed
messages on your unconscious your body
is your unconscious you don't
consciously make your dick hard you know
you don't you don't like you know say
dick get hard and your dick gets hard
know same thing with your heart rate you
don't say heart rate I need you to go up
it's unconscious shit just happens but
there is a way to embed messages subtle
stories upon yourself if repeated over
and over again with enough intensity
that guide the unconscious to do what
you would like it to do you can
brainwash that's what brainwashing is
it's using your conscious attention or
the environment around you to embed cut
into embed messages to on your upon your
unconscious upon your autonomic nervous
system right see I say unconscious but
it's you know for many months I was
saying autonomic nervous system okay
right it's like I'm just using different
language to speak to different people
from different perspectives but your
autonomic nervous system if you will use
your central nervous system to talk to
your autonomic nervous system you can
use it to guide the behavior of your
autonomic nervous system I wanted to
tell you exactly how I did it when I
first found out that I was gluten
intolerant for a while and I wanted to
remove all all foods that I knew were
drunk from my diet this was many years
ago about ten years ago maybe even
longer
including gluten which was very hard I
mean I saw I see a cupcake or I'd see
bread or whatever it was and my
unconsciously i source a lot salivating
you know you see certain foods and it's
like you don't tell yourself you don't
say hey that food looks good salivate
mouth you salivate and it's like that's
why cravings you have cravings you don't
do cravings cravings happen in your body
but I knew that I had to stop myself
from these cravings so I started telling
myself the story
at cookies cupcakes and foods of that
sort or for women in children and I
really I made myself believe this I said
grown men don't eat cooked cupcakes
I mean honestly guys those are you guys
who do diet like you could say that to
yourself giggle right I mean that makes
you move in your body when you say that
because it's like yeah cupcakes what are
you fucking six year old put you're a
kindergarten or you're a woman that's
four women and children go to women and
children birthday parties right oh
you're eating a piece of cake with pink
frosting on it huh you little baby boy
hmm mama's boy want a cupcake what a
cookie hmm crackers so you can see what
I did there you can play this game with
yourself and I did that it was just like
yeah I don't eat I don't eat junk food
because it's for babies little kids are
you at a birthday party and it's for
women right of course you women that are
watching this you know babies say that
it's for men I have no idea but this is
the story that I that I use to brainwash
myself out of eating junk food now you
do the same thing with absolutely
anything that you want to remove your
autonomic nervous systems response to
your unconscious response to and you say
you start picking apart and then you
know it's not that this is real it's
just a matter of you better tell
yourself a story people understand the
story you tell yourself whether true or
not guides your life so many people
believe in stories that are not
resourceful for them that make their
lives miserable but if you can be
objective about the stories you choose
to enroll in and to to to guide yourself
with you're really in the steering wheel
of your light you really have the
steering wheel of your life in your
hands what a powerful place to be I'm
going to choose what stories I'm going
to allow to guide my life fascinating
right really important religion and this
is where religion comes in and you've
got to start considering what life views
do I want to support me in where I want
to be and who I want to be in life was I
born sinful and evil and that I'm going
to be condemned to hell
touch my peepee well hey look I'm not
good good I didn't true or false I don't
really give a shit how's that shit
working out for you
right you got anxiety you're sick sad
depressing your dick don't work it's
just not working for you it's a story
it's a fucking story
true or false really isn't the issue
it's a story rant done but stop telling
yourself a story about this girl
of course she might be beautiful but
you've got to start saying to yourself
boy like I just I really can't stand
that mole on her chin it looks like a
fucking alien about the pop out of her
jaw right now you can giggle at that
every time you giggle any time you laugh
any time you cry your body's getting
involved to make yourself giggle alright
of course she's hot but like just find
something a little bit nasty about her
that you can pick on and every time
she's around just feel like her breath
always smells like butthole or something
like that you know or maybe the way she
laughs when she laughs it sounds like a
fucking hyena that's getting raped by an
elephant just come up with something
funny but you can tell yourself about
how disgusting she is to your
unconscious to your body enroll your
brain wash yourself with these stories
and you'll find that over time now don't
don't build malicious ideas about her
you don't need to say that she's an evil
person and she's bad and she's going to
get run over by a truck and pissed on by
a raccoon like oh that's like you're
just being you're being vicious and
you're being a violent about it just say
you know her mo looks like that she's
got a piece of shit on her chin all the
time maybe she eats shit right you'll
have to tell it and what I would do is
avoid telling anybody else this stuff
right I say this shit in front of
cameras people pick me apart but that's
my job
don't go tell your friends that yeah
she's got shit on her chin that mole on
her chin just cuz she eats poop there's
now you again that's violent now you're
stabbing her in the back and you're
doing things to affect her this is just
for you this is just private privately
right so when she's around and you know
everybody thinks she's so hot and your
giggle
right giggle to yourself you'll
ultimately become free from your body's
entanglement with her I hope you can see
the the power of what I just shared with
you in the roots concern the root
invitation which is to realize that your
autonomic nervous system the beating of
your heart and the raising of your dick
is in many ways in a lot of ways under
the control of the stories that you tell
yourself just think about you know when
you jerk off right you ever masturbate
and it's like there's no woman here
you're not even looking at porn but
you're thinking about something right
guess your dick hard you can have a
fucking ejaculation just with the ideas
in your head you could think about
things that make you happy things that
make you sad things that draw you closer
and push you apart the idea here my
friend is that jealousy is yours you're
creating it now stop creating it in fact
all feelings are yours and it's up to
you to decide how to create separate and
deal with them you're not a victim of
them done