so whatever it is that you're trying to
achieve in life the critical component
is getting things done and getting
things done in a systematic way building
the character that's associated with
getting things done in a systematic way
requires that you become disciplined
right so oftentimes people will come to
me for advice on Fitness on building
their businesses and their relationships
whatever the case may be and often the
place that they're dropping the ball is
in bad habits or not building productive
habits because it's very difficult to
just get up and change your life just
change the way you do things people like
to say that all the time hey just stop
doing this or start doing that they like
to give advice but the the underlying
factor is that our friend our individual
whoever is asking the question is not
disciplined enough to actually put that
thing in action get that thing done so
the thing that I have always told my
students and my clients is to start with
a small win begin with something small
so for example if you want to lose
weight I often tell people just start
walking every single morning don't worry
about counting calories don't worry
about complex workout ideas don't worry
about anything that anyone is selling
you just get up and walk every morning
right now it's not the walking that's
actually going to make that person
successful now it will add to your
success because getting up and walking
fresh air and exercise is going to
support you in losing weight but we all
know that there's far more factors to
consider but what it will do is create
the virtue of discipline commitment
right commitment and discipline sort of
go together and the fact that that small
win associated with getting up every
single morning is under your belt you're
going to feel the courage the confidence
and you'll have the ability to begin
adding other things to your ability to
grow stronger so now that you know it's
been 60 days 90 days and it's like you
got that pattern down pat you get up
every morning you just walk that's it
you don't think about it it's become a
habit you now can use that tool of
creating habits and instilling
discipline with the next one which
should be a little bit more advanced
perhaps only drink water with your meals
don't drink any soda don't drink any
juice just drink water that's the next
one and then the next one becomes more
complex and the next one becomes more
complex now it might seem like this is
tedious and slow but I guarantee you
that after 90 days of tiny winds and the
revamping of your character you will be
the type of person that can get anything
done at any time and the longtime
perspective is going to be a successful
one for you start small have big wins
with these little things and then use
that new version of yourself that new
character tool to attack bigger and more
advanced things until you reach your
goal good luck