kind of question from Harley Wilson who
is in his second year of university and
he's wondering if he should continue or
not situation is such that his parents
neither his parents have college degrees
although his dad's fairly successful
he's built a property management
business and there's quite well
Harley wants to be a personal trainer
and he's wondering any studying exercise
science and business in school which is
it's cool man
those are things that you're going to
need to know Exercise Science is going
to support you and becoming a personal
trainer but as you know you can learn
exercise science through reading
textbooks
taking courses going to seminars things
of that nature workshops I mean you
probably learn more you will learn more
outside of college than in college but
college is building a foundation for you
and that's why you started but right now
he's conflicted because does he continue
with this university education even
though he doesn't feel like it's going
to support him and he sees that his dad
is successful without it here are a few
questions for you the very first one is
are you going deeply in debt in order to
get the college education because that's
really one of my biggest hang-ups with
college it's not that going to there's
nothing wrong with coming to school the
two things wrong with going to school
especially university education at this
number one is are you going deeply in
debt because you're an instant slave
when you get out instant slave the
minute you get out it's like alright
great kid now you always hundred grand
get out into the world alright they
patch you in your back and tell you go
about your life right knowing that those
are government subsidized loans so if
you don't pay it your kids will pay it
it's worse than fucking taxes so you're
an instant slave when you've got all
that debt you got to pay that shit back
that means there's no time for
creativity there's no time to take a
breath there's no time for anything
except get your ass to work kid you got
to pay us back
right most these kids can't even pay
their rent they can t move other parents
house cuz they got all this goddamn debt
that's that's one big problem the other
big problem is this idea that you can
rest on this degree like I've got it now
and you go into the world it's like
someone owes you some
nobody owes you shit once you got that
degree that's just that just says that
you did something for four years that
gave you a piece of paper and now you
gotta go and like really do something
you got to really go and make your way
in this economic machine that we live in
that piece of paper does not guarantee
you shaped okay understand that everyone
that's not my part but I am the biggest
proponents of education that there is my
big problem is are you becoming a slave
and are you so stupid to think that this
thing grants you permission to get
whatever you want in life because as you
see that's not the case now I think you
said you're about 19 20 years old if
this is being paid for by your parents
like if they're if they're cutting
checks and paying for it and it's not
putting them into dire straits and
apparently it's not then go for it dude
it's paid for you're gonna get out
scot-free
please do it anybody who's watching this
who's interested in Elliott's
perspective on education if it's paid
for go okay now as you go through and
when you get out realize that that
degree doesn't mean doesn't grant you
anything understand that it's nice it's
cool now in there are places where
they're going to require it not
everywhere right and as the economy is
changing and as businesses are changing
and evolving its meaning worth it's less
and less it means less and less right
there was a day where it meant a lot now
it's like yeah you know what there's so
many startup it companies that really
just want creative hardworking people
that array leads a great I don't I
wouldn't look for a degree before wanted
hire someone I'd be like I'd be looking
at how creative disciplined hard-working
this individual is and that would mean
far more and I know they're a lot I know
a lot of entrepreneurs that's what
they're thinking and I look they're not
thinking what colleges you come out of
okay so it owes you nothing it grants
you nothing in other words no one owes
you anything because you have a college
degree but if you're doing it if you're
if you want to leave because you're in a
haste you're in a rush to get out so
that you could begin being a personal
trainer and earning money I would advise
against it I'd say take your time bro
honestly if you're 20 years old
it might seem like life is moving
quickly but you have a lot of time
I mean I'm 34 and I think back to when I
was 24 it's been like that 10 years so
much has happened in 10 years I mean
that's a dense period of time you can
take your time there is no rush finish
two more years of university again if
you don't have to pay for it and you
realize you've got the correct
perspective I'm running rancid on that
on what it actually is and that's it man
so that's really the question for you
and that's really my invitation to
everyone
consider the debt associated with
university education realize the slavery
associated with it right and if you're
if you're comfortable with that which is
you know I did it I hope actually not
for me anymore because I had a
scholarship my payback a lot of him all
of it
only maybe about a year ago but I oh
shit oh for my wife she didn't use it
she stays home she's got a master's
degree from like a Ivy League university
no I'm paying that shit back she stays
home but hey look yeah I figured it out
but the bottom line is you don't want to
have to dig yourself out of that hole
alright and the other thing is just
recognize what it is actually worth
depending especially on what it is you
want to do with your life so that's it
dude good luck keep growing smarter to
grow stronger but don't become a slave
and believe that this piece of paper
grants you any permission good luck