hey what's up guys in today's blog post
I talked about the five by five training
program that my uncle put me on when I
was 14 years old and I first started
training and specifically the
modifications that he had to make in
order to correct some of the muscular
imbalances I was dealing with so I
thought about today's video and how I
wanted to approach it and I want to talk
to you guys about in balance
specifically muscular imbalance and as
it relates to the training programs that
we choose to engage in now before I get
started I know this is my Elliott Hulse
channel and I have a strength camp
channel it's all about strength training
and fitness and whatnot but if you're
watching this channel and you're on the
journey of becoming a stronger version
of yourself understand that the body
cannot be separate from this there are
so many gurus out there that teach you
meditation and or how to eat a
particular type of special diet right
and they all plan about these particular
ideas leaving out certain things my
approach is a holistic one you've been
watching me long enough you've heard me
talk about the four layers of strength
there are four facets to becoming a
stronger version yourself and the very
first one is physical health not just
your digestive health not just your
hormone health not just you know
physiological health in general when I
say that that's the second layer of
strength I'm talking about your actual
muscular system your body your shoulders
your arms your your jaw your legs your
feet your core and how they all
contribute to being a stronger version
of yourself in all areas your life so
those of you who are longtime Elliott
Hulse fans you probably know this and I
just kind of reiterate this for anybody
who's new to our world now today I
wanted to talk about modifying your
program whatever training program you're
on whether you're following my advanced
five by five program lean hybrid muscle
a powerlifting program a bodybuilding
program a yoga program which I'm back to
doing once again spending most of my
days doing yoga there need to be
modifications to support you
where you are right now the thing is
that most of the programs we follow are
going to be cookie cutter that's just
the way it is if you're working with a
coach on the other hand or if you're
working with a personal trainer or
you're working with a consultant they
can modify things such that it meets you
right where you're at but if you're
buying programs online or if you've done
like I've do and you buy DVDs and you
follow the workouts and things of that
nature you're going to have to know your
body well enough to adjust the
parameters and either add or subtract
things from that program to support you
where you are you've got to understand
this following a prescription for
exercise is a prescription for exercise
that's generalized cookie cutter is
great it's going to get you started but
it's not going to get you to where you
need to be so in today's blog post I
spoke about the modifications my uncle
made to my strength training five by
five program back when I was in high
school in order to correct the amounts
between my prime movers and my
stabilizers particularly particularly my
abdominals my abdominals have had a
tendency to go weak in comparison to my
prime movers this is for a number of
reasons number one my prime movers are
strong as fuck meaning I've got strong
legs I kind of was born that way I look
at pictures of myself as a child and I
just had big legs big strong legs big
strong shoulders I can move a lot my
back is very thick but if I don't play
conscious attention to the engagement of
my deep abdominal wall meaning the
stabilizer muscles in my abdominals the
pelvic floor transversus abdominus and
even the action of my diaphragm my
abdominals will tend to go limp and weak
and like I said there are a number of
reasons for that of course there are
four layers of strength so it's not as
simple as my muscles are just weak it's
also inflammation I personally have a
tendency to not digest certain starchy
foods very well it's just my condition
get into it now but for a very long time
now I've had a hard time digesting these
types of foods and it causes
inflammation now there's inflammation in
your gut and I gotta tell you most
people have some form of inflammation in
their gut because we eat a fairly toxic
diet you know if you're taking protein
shakes and pretty workouts and all types
of food meal replacements if you're
eating junk food someone on facebook the
other day asked me why I don't eat a Big
Mac a day in order to gain muscle what
our friend doesn't understand is that
it's not just calories you're ingesting
you're ingesting all the toxic sludge
that comes with a fucking Big Mac right
so your body has to deal with that and
oftentimes it leads to inflammation so
that's one of the reasons why I've had
to pay close attention to physiological
strength we should all as well as the
neuromuscular condition of the
abdominals in the abdominal wall so um
what I'll share with you are just a few
more ideas that would support you in
developing the core musculature in
conjunction with the squat deadlift
benchpress prime mover exercises that
you do and of course I've already begun
down the path of four layers meaning
physiology has to be considered when
you're trying to strengthen key muscles
particularly stabilizers your entire
your entire stabilizer system can be
sure that I mean stabilizers in your
next off shoulders can be shut down by
the foods or the toxins that in your
environment that you're exposed to
trying to understand and what your
muscular system presents either either
be it by posture or performance is very
much linked to physiology the health of
your organs in fact the only reason why
we have arms and legs and muscles of the
sort is to protect and move the organs
right we crawled up out of the sea so we
can eat well I don't know that's what
they say but anyway the point is that
when an embryo is developing
nervous system the organs develop first
and then the arms and legs extend out
out of it right our core is our route
that's where we come from and it's where
our focus and vital resources comes from
and should be recharging I won't get
into the energetic implications I tippy
toed in that direction the other day
without giving it a solid lesson on
energetic strength and the chakra system
by the way I've got videos where I've
spoken about it at length on my strength
camp channel I'd like to prepare a new
series like that for you guys here on
the elliott hulse channel that way when
i say crazy things like your body is
your mind and the way you think affects
your organs and your muscular system is
not it doesn't sound as guru or as
hippie like you know as it may seem it's
actually very scientific and then as far
as neuromuscular is concerned right
because that's the most obvious thing
dealing with the muscular system very
obvious it's right there you see it you
can touch it right can't touch your
organs to any great degree and your it's
like touching your soul trying to deal
with your mind the muscular system can
be conditioned your core can be
conditioned by number one making sure
that the tonic tight overused muscles in
your abdominal cavity and when I what
I'm speaking about specifically or you
like your so as so as muscles I spoke
about this last week you know it's a
giant muscle that extends from your
lumbar spine down into your legs so if
you you know you think about your
ribcage and your in your hips here you
gotta be a big strap muscle that that
innervates and and and is it highly
associated with that area not only that
but it's one of those muscles that tend
to grow tonic and if you're so as is
tight if it's tonic if it's rigid and
riddled with trigger points which most
peoples are I don't wanna say most
people's but I've experienced it and in
many of my clients I've noticed it then
you've got to do something
into condition the psoas I spoke about
this in various videos last week I've
spoken about this in many videos on my
youth on my Elliott Hulse I'm sorry I'm
my strength camp channel but today I
will just briefly say massaging it with
a small basketball or foam rolling your
belly has brought me great relief it may
help you to be cautious but then
mobilizing and then stretching the so as
the hip flexor muscles and also you
might need to strengthen stretch your
low back lumbar erector muscles also I
have a tendency to have really big bulky
obliques right these are all muscles
that need to be softened and stretched
and relax that way you can engage the
stabilizers of your pelvis and your your
abdominal region in absence of the prime
movers kind of what I talk about in my
blog post down below in relationship to
squats deadlifts and not using the
abdominals you can isolate the abdominal
exercises with various tummy vacuum
drawing in type exercises Paul check
describes some very powerful
rehabilitative exercises for your
transversus abdominus in his book how to
eat move and be healthy but you know
I've been through many of his courses
and in practice many of the exercises he
saw me on my cell phone my clients and
even working with him as a client he's
told me dude you need to do this so
there are some tips tricks tactics help
for you on your journey to becoming a
stronger version of yourself like I said
everyone is required to take great care
for their muscular system their body as
well as their physiology in mind when
becoming a stronger version of yourself
done