hey what's up guys Elliott Hulse here
and having uploaded a video to this
channel in quite a while but I'm just
going to hit the ground running we're
going to begin today with a question
that I have for you are you or have you
ever found yourself in a transition
phase in your life and when I say
transition I talk about I'm talking
about biological transition the obvious
biological transition of going from
childhood to adulthood you know
adolescence of course the obvious
biological shifts from adulthood to
middle adulthood middle adulthood to old
adulthood right you know when we're
elderly or wise and gray there are
significant physiological markers you
know like when you go from when you're a
child into a man right you grow some
hair on your balls you start smelling
different and and you have different
interests in a completely different
character right
a seven-year-old on a 17 year old you
know the mother they're worlds apart but
a 17 year old in the 27 year old world
apart also you know the physiological
changes might not be as significant
they're they're you know you're usually
a bit more manly at 27 and you are at 17
more testosterone more muscle more
experience and then of course every
seven years thereof there is a shift in
our physiology our psychology our
character and we can't help but to
change the circumstances our world
changes as we change often times we
think that circumstances get weird or
circumstances change or things are going
on outside but really what's going on
outside is far more consistent than the
shifts that are happening in you at all
times your dynamic you're never the same
even from year-to-year you're evolving
but there are some significant milestone
markers and often times we recognize
them as like I said becoming a teenager
but I find myself in a milestone marker
of transition from early adulthood you
know that time when you're grinding to
find your way and middle adulthood I'm
36 now y'all and where I find myself and
what would be
resourceful for me character-wise no
longer what was resourceful for me in
the past is no longer resourceful for me
today right because where I find myself
and some of you who may be middle-aged
or those of you who even evolved quickly
I'm doing this a little early one of my
mentors was like boy you're doing what I
did ten years earlier than I did it I
just happen to grow up early right I
married my high school girlfriend this
is what I do is just my past that way
but I find myself in this place where
transition is inevitable you cannot
resist transition you try to resist
transition that's when you fall into
depression that's when you fall into
anxiety confusion when you resist the
flow of nature now what I'm discovering
what I'm learning because 2015 has been
a huge transition year for me and a huge
awakening for me when I say that I've
learned a lot of things specifically
about myself
and the more I can learn about myself
the more I have to offer you through
these videos now of course my absence
from videos has a lot to do with the
fact that I have to grow personally in
order to have anything to offer you and
for the past year I you know it's just
been pretty it would be inappropriate
for me to make videos in this sort of
middle ground that I find myself in but
as with every dark season right cold
season winter time in going in there is
a budding there's a spring time and I
don't think we can dictate when that
happens for us individually but we could
look for the signs when it's about to
occur all right and I'm starting to feel
the flowers button in me right now again
so you know here comes the camera and
here comes some wisdom little bits of
wisdom but really you know part of what
my wisdom has accumulated is to ask more
questions rather than make more
statements so as I'm having this
conversation with you remember it's an
open dialogue and my question to you is
right I'm going to assert something and
I'm going to ask I'm asserting that I'm
saying it's a fact that
when you find yourself in this
transition period two things must happen
when you're going from childhood to
adulthood so on and so forth there are
two things that need to happen break
down and build up right those of you who
are familiar with my YouTube my struck
ab youtube channel who come here out of
my fitness gifts that I've given to the
world understand catabolism and
anabolism you understand breaking down
the muscle and building it up so there
could be stronger this is what has to
happen to our character it is what
happens to our character whether we
resist it or not we have to break down
destroy deconstruct die to old habits
old character old rituals old ways of
being that were once resourceful don't
get me wrong these were very resourceful
when you're a child to behave a certain
way when I was a teenager to behave a
certain way when I was in my early
adulthood YouTube grind make 10 15 video
10 15 videos a week care if it was
perfectly fine for me to do things like
sucked down tons of caffeine and go wild
on camera all day long
alright for Who I am and who I'm
becoming and what I seek to build my
vision which is very important for you
to have I can't do that anymore
it's unresponsible it's silly all right
that's for me to be an older version of
myself that's like here you go this is
like a lot of the adults who still act
like teenagers how many thirty year olds
you know we're still it's still trapped
in their 17-year old body giggling at
boobies and farts right like little kids
there's no longer resourceful to giggle
it booties and farts when you're trying
to become a stockbroker or you're trying
to work in real estate or you're trying
to build your business as an
entrepreneur got a growth fuckup right
same thing for when you and which you it
was fun to giggle at farts and boobs
when you were a kid don't get me wrong
again it's perfectly fine you should
when my when my children I have children
seven ages five to eleven they giggle at
farts and it's cool and I giggle with
them because that's where they're at
farts are still funny though especially
when they stink you have to just
laughing point so anyway my point is of
course I'm back on rant mode my point is
what parts of you have to die what parts
of you have to be deconstructed what
parts of you have to die and be
resurrected that's the second part the
second part to every death like the
Phoenix it burns up and then rises again
this is a cycle of life what new things
have to be grown in you is my question
what new habits
what new rituals do you need to
incorporate into your life and here's
the thing with these it's going to be
difficult to first choose what rituals
are going to support you in the newer
version of yourself the stronger version
of yourself and how to instill them
right so because I haven't spoken to you
guys in a long time
this video is kind of like self
explanatory but also conversational so
you know one of the things that I've
needed to do in order to manifest my
future vision in order to step into the
mature more grown version of myself is
establish habits that get things done
that support my vision right now so for
example I created a tremendous amount of
momentum by creating thousands of videos
over the past five years
it got me where I am but where I like to
be holds up much greater vision it
includes sharing my ideas through books
I haven't written a book or created a
product in about five years because I
dropped everything else and went full
YouTube grind I stopped writing emails
early in my career writing an email and
making a video was a daily thing right
and I went hard with it because I went
hardcore with the YouTube grind I
stopped making emails right stop writing
emails stop writing newsletters stop
writing to my blog now here today I have
to choose once again the rituals
associated
with daily writing and product creation
writing my book I've got a book that
were we're pretty close to being done
with Chris Barnard and I we're gonna
we've collaborated on it to create a
strength cook camp book and guess what
I'm writing daily it's a brand new habit
if you want Eliott on the daily five
days a week
write on the daily Louie Marco says that
you want Elliott Hulse on the daily get
on my email list I'm gonna put a link
down below where you can with it takes
you to my blog Elliott Hulse comm if you
don't see the link get on my email list
I'm not selling anything right off the
bat there's no hardcore selling when you
get on this email list it straight up
Elliott Hulse giving you his bits every
single day there's always a call to
action because I've always got cool
things going on like our live events
happening later this month here in Tampa
so I'll link to them but the bottom line
here is that this is a new very
resourceful habit that I've had to build
over the past several months by waking
up every day at five o'clock in the
morning and dedicating those hours that
hour to writing to you right
it's my extension of creative energy
into the world and hopefully you enjoy
partaking also I realize that we have a
relationship through video right you've
come to me you've known me and you see
me and we communicate through video I
had to take obviously I have it and had
to create a tremendous amount of space
between myself and video so that I can
adequately place it where it most
resourceful II belongs so you back in
the day I was doing videos all day long
I can't do that any longer for Who I am
today you know my family's growing and
for what I want to create in the future
so I've got to find a way and I think
I'm going to attempt it here with this
of one of the first the first of many
videos I intend to make that recap my
daily spark of creation email I call it
the grow stronger daily letter so what
I'll do is these are these are this is
my new ritual these are my new habits
writing on the daily and what I'll do is
I'll throw this camera up you know I'm
not satisfied with my
circumstances meaning like the location
I had to move to this office in order to
create space but so it's not a gym I
can't make these videos at my new gym
because there are too many people there
so I'd like to ultimately have a private
gym where I can make these videos but it
doesn't matter I'm gonna do it anyway
stand here in this office every morning
that I write an email and want to engage
conversation with you guys because it's
a ritual that serves my need for
creativity my need for communication and
adds to division I'm creating in my life
still trucks I can't get away from
trucks I gotta have to move my office
next time to like a serene outdoors
quiet area really there's not too much
of that here in Pinellas County so
that's it look guys I appreciate you
listening to this I appreciate your
patience part of the reason why I
decided to make this video is because
yesterday in the comments section on my
Trent camp channel people were clamoring
for Elliot because I haven't been in
many of the videos I've got good reason
I explained some of them here but look I
get it
it's not fair I hooked you right it's
like bait and switch I hooked you with
Elliott Hulse and then I'm switching you
with some of the coaches at our gym
Chris Barnard you guys love him you know
him he's my right-hand man
but I get it's not Elliott Hulse as far
as that strength cam channel is
concerned I want it to be a channel that
really features the gym that features
strength training features Fitness in
that particular way and and we'll have
to see how that evolves at the same time
the Elliott Health Channel is straight
up Elliott host and I intend to do these
I guess you could call them vlogs that
was one of the suggestions over on the
comments section in the Shred camp
youtube channel was Elliott just create
a daily Bob blog just create a daily
rant just talk to us and and I get it
and I appreciate it I appreciate you I
appreciate our conversation over the
past several years and I think it's only
fair right that we continue in this
particular way so that's it here's the
thing down below right because we're
going to make this a conversation y'all
cuz I've been conversating all over the
place on YouTube right in emails
be excited to talk to speak with you
guys in a fully engaging deep way down
below write a little something about the
parts of you that have to die who are
dying in the midst of dying right
sometimes we can't resist it it just
happens what parts of you are dying
which is normal natural there may be
some resistance to talk about your
resistance but what part of you has to
be grown and specifically what rituals
are you now exploring dabbling with it
and intending to integrate into your
daily life the thing with rituals is its
discipline you do it every day whether
you feel like it or not so there you
have it folks I love to speak to you
love to learn more about you love to
engage in this conversation talk to you
next time
done