so got a question here from what I think
is a young lady she's about to go into
university and she's got the situation
where she constantly she thinks she
thinks things thinks a lot of us I think
go through this
they just thinks a lot about different
things that are probably not very
resourceful they upset her and then she
gets to the point where a panic attack
is about to happen and this has been
happening you know all throughout high
school and now she's going to college
and she's she's scared that she's going
to embarrass herself and she's gonna
make a fool of herself people are gonna
like her and justifiably because she's a
nut she breaks down and she feels like
she's always on edge how do you deal
with this it's almost like she knows
she's doing it to herself I'm thinking
thinking thinking thinking like about
bad things and when I say bad it's
relative but things that are not you
don't like right or maybe there are
things that you do like but either way
the body becomes charged charged charged
charged and then you're just like a
balloon ready to pop and on that brink
of about being able to about the pop
wanting to pop you sit you sit right on
that edge you're on edge where you can
explode or go back down into a place
where you're a little less charged but
it doesn't take much to get it right
back to where it was before and you're
sitting right on edge right you call
these panic attacks anxiety attacks okay
number of things I don't know if this
video is before or after the one that I
spoke about depression and called human
rights but about how human beings are
dissipative structures essentially we
take in and we discharge we charge we
discharge the most obvious example is we
take in food and we take a shit you take
in food and we take a shit so that's
it's physical its physical so it's
obvious but it also happens mentally
spiritually emotionally very important
because if you say for example um you
see and you're walking down the street
and you see the old lady getting
attacked by a mugger right you see this
it's it's it's mental I see something
and you quickly charge up right your
body
with your hands your shoulders go up or
you stop breathing because you're like
oh my god this is someone's being
attacked at that point you can either
discharge that energy hey help help help
and you run over you try to help the old
lady or you pretend you don't see and
you walk away
the first example yelling help help help
and you go and try to help the lady is
being charged and then discharging Wow
holding it in is it's you're depressing
the energy and your body what you're
calling anxiety is is a form of
depression you're holding in that charge
instead of releasing the charge
we're dissipative structures we're open
systems we flow human beings are a
closed structure in our environment we
dance with our environment we take in
our environment we take it out one of
the things that are actually things in
many ways because of the way it affects
us physiologically our thoughts you
don't need to do much more than close
your eyes and think about a beautiful
woman the next thing you know you got a
boner right do it do it to yourself you
guys that fat that's a new word for her
masturbation right how many times to do
that you think healing mmm you could see
her luscious body and she's coming
towards you and caressing it's all
happening in your fucking head you know
what happens you're charging up you're
charging up you're charging up what do
you got to go do you go jerk off so we
also do it mentally to ourselves you are
doing it in a way that you're I don't
know what type of charger you're giving
yourself it could be a sexual charge
which is very difficult sometimes to
release if you don't have a sexual
partner or you don't masturbate whatever
the case may be maybe you're just
anxieties happening because you lack
sexual fulfillment in your life I'm just
using that as an example maybe you're
doing it because you quite frankly most
of us enjoy I myself enjoy feeling
charged up so you think about things
that cause you pain and frustration like
I don't have enough money I don't have
enough money I'm not gonna pay my credit
card bills I'm not gonna be able in my
rent but they're thoughts just like
seeing the naked lady or thoughts that
cause your dick to get hard
these are thoughts that are causing your
body to charge up charge up charge up
till you get to the point where if it
was sexual you would have had an orgasm
but it's not it might be anger it might
be frustration it might be sadness it
might be puke my mom does this my mom
watches my video she knows I'm so I'm
talking about her she likes watching sad
shit on TV ha I can't move like sad
movies I'm like mom why do you watch
this shit sometimes you know when I was
a kid I'd see that like she she watches
these things that she's like gripping
herself she's watching the movie and
she's like oh mom stop doing that to
yourself you're making yourself crazy
because you're charging yourself up
where are you gonna go and discharge it
we're an open dissipative system we have
to to discharge we have to fucking
discharge and guess what you're lucky
enough to watch Elliott Hulse who's
crazy enough to fucking discharge on
camera for you several times already you
need to go and have a bout of
bioenergetic release you are on that
balloon is about to pop and it'll keep
doing this every time you charge a
little bit and go down charge a bit okay
so relax breathe forget about it go to
sleep right have a drink
that's an easy one just get drunk smoke
a joint brings you down but you're not
too far from that surface you start
doing it again to yourself you get all
charged it up you're like oh I'm gonna
have a breakdown have a fucking
breakdown you need to have a goddamn
breakdown just like you need to have an
orgasm when you're sexually charged
right for lack of better terms it's it's
it's an orgasm you have to have physical
release because of the mental
stimulation you're charging yourself up
and you're not giving yourself an
opportunity to discharge there are very
many easy ways to do this easy or simple
but not easy because most people are
willing to but you got you got to go
into your bedroom where you go somewhere
where there's nobody that can hear you
and you need to fucking scream ah let
the energy carry you and express what
needs to be expressed if you need to say
fuck you if you need to say
off my back make the movement associated
with it get off i fat get off my back go
with it exhaust yourself completely
exhaust your body exhaust your mind you
should be sweating and breathing like
you just had the hardest fucking workout
in your life get it all out of your
system it might be as simple as you just
need to fucking cry then you know what
create a situation I've made videos
about this created situations where you
evoke the tears one of the things that I
do that gets me whining a little bit
sometimes I just need to whine I need to
like cry like I don't totally sob that
much anymore because I'm not on the
surface as much as I used to be it's
more like just releasing something
that's building up on me and it usually
sounds like for me I don't really sob
too much any longer but massage I
massage my feet I have a I have this
thing that I that hurts my fucking feet
I put it I put it down on the ground I
roll my feet because I know that it's
it's releasing physical tension
associated with holding back in certain
ways and as it hurts I go I make the
sounds associated with the pain
so I energetically release the pain
associated with the physical stimulation
but also it gives me a emotional
reprieve I also do it on my stomach I'm
a little little basketball I did earlier
today they'll lay on it and there's a
lot of muscular tension in the belly
right oh I don't let all the sounds out
you probably have a lot of it trapped in
your jaw this is just my assumption
because of the type of email you wrote
me you probably have a lot of it trapped
in your jaw you probably have a lot of
it trapped in your neck and shoulders
one of the ways that you can you can
release a lot of that energy is by
pressing really hard on your jaw muscles
opening your mouth and letting out a
scream
ah I get some of it there I'm not as
angry as I used to be so it's not as
much but you're gonna feel you're going
to feel the tension release and feel it
build up you're going to feel it explode
out your fucking eyeballs when you do
this so that's it you know you guys that
you know these panic attacks are there
as only express things that we're
experiencing all of our depression all
of our anxiety all of our panic attacks
are not wrong the problem is we keep
resisting them right now
it many people get confused when Elliot
says you need to go and express yourself
they think that I mean like you know
I've got a boner that means I'm gonna go
rape someone I'm angry so I'm gonna go
kill someone what you don't understand
is that there's a grounded form of that
expression which means go and beat up a
punching bag I mean take a tennis racket
and beat the crap out of your bed means
go somewhere the word you can scream as
loud as you want there's no wrong
emotion
the only wrongness is in the depression
of the emotion in the resistance of the
emotion that's where it festers and
becomes a cancer that's when it becomes
bad because repressed anger becomes fury
and then you snap out you snap at people
and that's what like road rage happens
you don't want to fuckin have road rage
go and beat the shit out of your pillow
go and beat the shit out of your bed
don't wait till you're so depressed that
you need to go to a hospital get the
shit out of your system what are you
holding back what it's usually two
things what are you not doing that you
need to do what do you need to get out a
lot of times it's as simple as speaking
to someone you know this has been on my
chest for a long time go and fucking
tell that person even if it's somebody
that you're angry with if there's a
person that you you have a beef with you
can create depression for yourself by
holding back that beef the most
interesting thing is that if you share
that beef with the other person in a
very mature way get it off your chest
a lot of times you both look at each
other at the end just fucking laugh
about it you go to your dad or your mom
or your brother your sister your friend
you say listen I I have to get this off
my chest
right don't take it personally but this
is something that's happening in me I
need to say it to you I can't stand you
you annoyed the shit out of me every
time I see you coming I just want to run
the other way get it all out all out you
know even if you like you just had an
orgasm huh if that person is if you
prepared that person for what you are
about to do to them right which is to
vomit all over them and they're mature
enough to handle it they will look at
you and they'll say oh that's
interesting I don't know you felt that
way and you look up because now you it's
all off your chest you no longer have
pent-up fury and anger it's been spit
out all over the place and you won't
feel it anymore
and you look at that person you'll laugh
Nev like you know what I really love you
ha ha and then you fucking hug usually
the best sex happens after the biggest
fight doesn't it you got to get this
shit out that's one of my biggest
invitations to everybody watches my
videos do not depress yourself get the
emotions out in a resourceful grounded
fashion I don't say be hysterical about
your behavior be ego grounded but let
yourself do it you have to do it
otherwise you end up on fucking pills
I'm done