Elliot's in what so on the radio they're
talking about three day weekends and how
many people want to have three day
weekends apparently a lot of people want
to have three day weekends so the lady
on the radio station says well I'm going
to run for president and I'm going to
create a three-day weekend now I'm
wondering why everybody's waiting for
the government to give them three day
weekends why are we waiting for the
government to tell us anything you want
a three-day weekend take a fucking
three-day weekend you don't have a job
that gives three-day weekends you might
get fired then find another job that
gives three-day weekends if that doesn't
work out then learn how to make money
without a job and take three day
weekends you don't need the President to
create a three-day weekend law Elliot's
it what