what's up guys we got a question from
one of our buddies here who says he
wants to know how to become more alpha
and even uses the term frequencies to
describe what he receives from me when
he watches these videos and he's decided
to describe me as alpha energy and
frequency and then he also goes on to
describe someone like Russell Brand who
in many ways seems completely opposite
of Elliott Hulse and when he says this
he means physically because he's in a
situation now where he's amongst new
people in the new school and I thinks
that in order to become alpha you might
need to build his body up or become more
aggressive and loud but then at the same
time he sees people who emit sort of
alpha frequency but they're not big and
aggressive and loud and in fact when you
watch me sometimes I'm big aggressive
and loud and sometimes I'm contemplative
and soft and slow right but yet this
alpha frequency seems to come out and
I'm gonna preface this by saying look
there are so many people that use this
word completely wrong in their
associations with what alpha actually
means it's completely skewed by their
own ego identification and what movies
and TV have told them about alpha these
gentlemen who go around talking about
alpha and being alpha as fucking and
your alpha and then he's beta really
don't understand anything and they're
very activity associated with pointing
out alpha and calling themselves alpha
it's actually very beta and I'll tell
you what I mean literally by talking
about frequencies in a moment so the
interesting thing if you take a look if
you just google it and look up the
picture of what frequencies look like
you've got a beta frequency beta
frequencies are very fast so on the way
you describe a frequency is within a you
know span of time you go like this and
then you see how many pitches and
troughs there are within that span of
time so beta you're gonna have a lot of
them that's a very active very active is
beta and oftentimes a lot of those guys
who think they're alpha because they're
so active they're rah
right there there's their ungrounded
being ungrounded because there's too
much stimulation in the consciousness
it's very beta beta doesn't necessarily
look like quiet now if you're quiet but
the activity in your mind is racing
because you're neurotic now that's beta
frequencies being emitted that's beta
frequencies that you're engaging in
there it's it's this over-aggressive
really it's an over aggression of
thinking and consciousness your energy
is too much that's really beta theta is
just look is within that spare time
there's big gaps there's big spaces in
between right so theta is like calm
relaxed meditation almost you know when
you're at your getting ready to go to
bed at night you know and you're maybe
reading a book even meditating and
sitting and you know before you're ready
to relax and chill the fuck out
very tender first one very aggressive
the other one very tender now so I love
that term tender aggression because it's
just so poetic and beautiful in this
particular way the alpha frequency is in
between right if you like I said so you
take a look the Alpha frequency isn't is
aggressive as these fools who've come to
believe that alpha is some sort of
aggression and it's not so laid-back
that it's uh it's not stimulated by the
environment because it's yawning and
getting ready to go in it is a
tenderness meaning calm relaxed focus
grounded confidence in yourself along
with a highly stimulated nervous system
that allows you to act and speak
appropriately appropriately at the
appropriate time right see I can't even
do it appropriately their appropriate
time so your your tender soft relaxed
flowing yen dark cold female right
there's an element of femininity to the
alpha don't forget that
you mean about that one there's a
significant element of femininity
present in the alpha male in the alpha
frequency Russell Brand is just you can
see it right away very feminine ways me
if you watch me closely there are some
feminine ways now I'm not comparing
either of us to Jesus right didn't you
have that one called Messiah Complex but
just look at how Jesus is depicted by
the best artists European of course
because we don't know
you know what his colour skin was white
is such a king look like such a woman
Jesus looked like a woman half the times
and if you look at the depiction of a
lot of our teachers our most alpha men
they kind of are especially they're
depicted in art a depicted kind of like
ambiguous like they're between they're
hermaphrodites they're like they're men
and they're female right because there's
a significant portion of feminine gene
energy tender energy associated with the
balance alpha frequency the theta is
overly aggressive so you've got on one
hand a premature ejaculator on the other
hand can't get it up and in between is
the alpha energy brother tender
aggression I've made videos specifically
about tender aggression but I'm going to
give you a few words of wisdom and
practical tips to support you on your
way to true alpha hood my friend okay
ideologically in your head because the
stories we tell are very important about
what happens in our body and how we
allow ourselves to yield into the
processes the spontaneous processes in
the body and that's what the two
energies are head energy is very
aggressive body energy is very tender
body energy is very yielding it's very
obvious because the heart yields to the
stimulation of the mind right right it's
it rubes orbs the body absorbs what
comes up up here so if I go and your
heart rate goes up that means you were
absorbing energy into your body and
takes action on its own completely free
from the processes of the head brain so
telling stories is one part of the start
of the deal telling stories and that's
what all of our information is I hope
you understand even science religion
fairytales motivational videos there's
stories
there's stimulation of the conscious
mind to produce a particular result that
we like which is oftentimes very
aggressive very yang the other half is
going to be in your body so I'm going to
talk to you about stories and then talk
to you about how to breathe into your
balls motherfucker because that's the
missing key for 99% of you betta bitches
out there who think you're alpha because
you're so loud and big ass or you gonna
have to tell yourself is that you're
good enough because confidence is
absolutely everything when it comes to
emitting and living in alpha frequencies
the reason why confidence is so
important and this needs to be written
down also it's not confidence in the
face of other people very important when
I say confidence it's not even
confidence in the face of circumstances
that are threatening it's not outward
confidence confidence is the confidence
in yourself to let go into the in energy
the spontaneity of your body you've got
to be confident enough to trust
everything going on from head to toe
I trust my body that's why I look so
confident I'm not confident in your face
not at first I'm not confident in the
face of adversity and challenges not at
first but you know what I do I go
and I let go of all attachment and
desires and fears and wanting to control
and I say I trust you body
I trust you spontaneity I trust you
unconscious I trust you the intelligence
that guides me meaning God I trust
everything that moves through me and
everything that happens in me do you
understand now I might come back up to
the mind and I might my head brain and I
might begin to analyze what's going on
in my body if I'm not breathing properly
in the face of an adverse situation that
means I've got to trust that there's
something going on I look at my body and
I say who I'm not breathing right what's
making me uncomfortable
I have to either start at that
conversation at the moment with those
other people or circumstances where I
gotta put that one away for later later
I gotta figure what the fuck was going
on there man why was your wire your nuts
all sucked up in your asshole tight come
on e what was that what wasn't about
that person of that circumstance that
made you lose your confidence in your
body but in that moment the very first
thing you do my man is breathe breathing
is the stimulation both energetically
and physically of the intelligence in
your unconscious and in your body and
your viscera trust it trust yourself
when people say trust yourself they
think it means trust the stories but it
goes deeper trust what's going on down
in here brother I trust my gut
I trust my heart you see sometimes my
head doesn't even trust my heart and gut
and I do things I do things in my heads
like oh boy don't do it but you know
who's more intelligent my heart and my
gut I know they're more intelligent
because they're tapped into something
that they had to know we see become an
alpha my friend but don't look outside
to compare yourself to what that
possibly means because
world's idea of alpha is completely
neurotic it's an abstraction and in fact
those who have been calling themselves
alpha are living in a sea of beta
breathe into your balls stimulate this
is a beautiful one I almost finished it
but I have to give you this one true
alpha is a man and woman who balances
the intelligence in his balls he has
three sets of balls mind you your
eyeballs trust them trust your linear
processing your analytical processing
it's good but in balance if he doesn't
trust the balls between his legs your
gut instincts feelings I'll tie the
heart to that one awesome trust your
balls between your legs dude grab them
and if they're too hot to grab them
because you're too much of a beta bitch
right say beta bitch it just rolls off
the tongue
you're so beta that your balls are hot
cool them off shake them off take off
your little panties your tight little
tighty whitey panties and let your balls
just little fan blow on them balls
they're physically too hot get in touch
with the intelligence of your balls and
finally stay on the balls of your feet
dude
remain grounded practical pragmatic
immovable but also agile done