introduce myself to your viewers I was a
part of the youtube.com slash whatever
group where we do crazy pranks and
picking up girls videos we have videos
where we uh we got like a dil-don't put
in her pants and I picked up girls with
fake boner that was a fun one I'm
proposing the random girls whooping up
to uh um girls and try to get their
numbers without talking yes just crazy
stuff and anyways it started to see lots
of comments people asking me hey how can
I become more confident and I was seen
by starting like the vlog channel and
one of my one of my fans Michael very
was hey you should check out this guy
called elliott hulse and I saw your
Sawyer channels really as far as like
wow that's kind of what I feel inspired
to do thanks Eva that's come my new path
and what I'm doing yeah it's good and
then I just want to say you've right now
like between your two channels have
reached 85 million views that's like
five million views that's great yeah
like just the positive ripples that
you've like created in your life is like
you probably can't even comprehend it
okay cool that's an animal so each prop
to that but anyways um I really
appreciate your vice because it's
genuine and um I feel like on any advice
there's always layers and the deeper you
go there's like someone's basic beliefs
about the nature of reality and just
like like when I wake up in the morning
I'm like what the fuck is going on like
why do I exist and i'm just curious
what's your like deepest beliefs about
just what's going on just the nature of
reality
one thing that I would like to say is
that I think we take it way too
seriously we've been taught to to really
to believe because that's what it is is
purely a belief that number one we're
separate from one another that we're
just this like this is it that's all you
get you know just as meat suit and it's
a big lie but I have so much fun
manipulating the variables of my life
knowing that the reality is i'm way more
than what you see and with that type of
freedom comes the courage to do whatever
you want to do see your you've got kind
of that courageous attitude about you
that's why you can do the pickup thing
and other guys want to do that well
regardless of what language you used to
describe it the fact is that you are
moving from a place of understanding
which says I'm not just this so I have
enough balls to just walk up to a woman
and do whatever I want because there's
way more going on here than just what
you're seeing yeah right because it's a
manifestation of your experiences you're
going to do the things that you do based
on your experiences and experiences are
where they're dead they're in the air
somewhere you're going to do things
based on your trust in the future like
where's the future know where it's in
the air yeah and if you can if you have
that type of ability to like detach
detach from our you know the physical
manifestation of what's happening and
realize there's a far greater reality
then life is so much more entertaining
because you won't take it so seriously
this is all is yeah yeah one of my core
beliefs I've been just experimenting
with is that you know like when you go
to sleep and when you dream um your
consciousness isn't just your body in
your dream but your consciousness is
actually the whole dream world you're
the other dream characters ult you're
the whole dream world and while you're
in the dream it feels so real like that
you're the character and then suddenly
you wake up and you realize you're
actually the whole dream world and yep
oh that's such a fun thought it's also
and to me beliefs are just different
lenses on how to look at reality there's
like who knows what's right or wrong
grades yeah but um so for me yeah
beliefs my whole life I've been trying
to figure out one of the most empowering
beliefs that I can believe in right and
I'm working for you I'm not truly the
question I asked you about their beliefs
like they're so attached to their
beliefs their personally identified with
them even though there's there's no
rational reason why but that's okay you
don't need to rationalize all you got to
do is say well how's that working for
you and if they're sick sad depressed
their wife cheats on them and their kids
don't respect them and you know those
beliefs aren't working for you bro yeah
try some new ones but they can't because
you know they might go to hell yeah and
I was talking to steve pavlina he really
explain about to me it's like belief
sent something to be attached to believe
somewhere of a toolbox and you could
take a belief and just look through that
belief and see what happens and if it
doesn't work I well if it does work cool
but it's not yours you don't have
ownership of the belief that you could
you could use it like like a tool almost
that's a so well one of the beliefs I've
been experimenting with that which is
really cool because you hit on this lot
like you last feed about like we just
ignore everyone is that I believe like
real life is basically basically like a
dream I'm a like I have I don't just
have control over just Mia but actually
everything in my environment is mia like
you're me right now you're part of my
subconscious somewhere that's reflecting
Mia I'm a part of your subconscious
that's reflecting you we're both real
we're both we're both real but we're in
like this mutual dream together and
we're like slowly like I believe on god
in the limited form and I'm waking up to
my true infinite powers like it sounds
like when I grow in this I have you read
conversations with god by Neale Donald
Walsch know you need to you me I don't
say you need to read it because you'll
learn something
I say you used to read it cuz you're
gonna be like oh yeah that's it yeah of
course I mean even the hopeful time you
nod your head you're just gonna be
you're gonna feel good because someone
else is putting into other words yeah
exactly what you're feeling which is
that we're not separate yeah it's uh two
people fighting are like a right hand in
the left hand fighting each other not
realizing that they're connected to the
same value hey that's it'sit's literal
and figurative masturbation yeah we're
just made with ourselves it feels good
but really you're playing yourself yeah
so that's what we're doing as I call it
as a race playing with themselves you
know and even being attached to the
outcome of the game is another form of
playing with ourselves cuz it's like
well you know what we're all gonna die
and we can become sad about that we
could be sad about people who are dying
because of the game but even then you
are now a slave to this to a belief that
it's like well do you really die because
that means that you feel that this is it
but so you feel here in touch is the end
of the game even though that's it
eliminate beliefs even the belief even
know they're gonna die is could be a
false belief who knows technology is
changing so quickly like rakers off he's
predicting like technology conveyance so
quickly the humans can invent
immortality in like 50 years or
something we have been way you sit down
with her brain and see like computer
system or make fake horses we could be
living for forever like for all we know
which is the most crazy thought in the
world to me then what would be the fun
because if you know you're gonna live
forever then it's just like what we'll
think about you gotta see what's next
well well what's next is that technology
is just going to keep getting bigger and
it's just gonna keep getting better
better and better and we could invent
literally anything to uh you know like
it don't you want to die its own port i
wanna die i want to see you like like
that's like a piece that's like telling
you an ice cube right like measure you
got a bunch of ice cubes yeah and you're
like you know if you're really bad
smells because then you won't be anymore
no ice cubes are like scared like oh my
god you know I won't be an ice cube
anymore what happens if like heat
happens and I melt it would be such a
tragedy but you know what happens in a
minute that ice cube melts it's
liberated from its form it's no longer
that fucking square now its water and
water cannons anything you can't contain
it it's all over the place it nourishes
it's amazing shit and I wouldn't be told
the water you know what it gets any
hotter in here you might become heir me
I won't be water anymore that would be
terrible that would suck yeah but then
as it happens it turns into air and it's
like whoa now am I not just limited to
this little swap of water on the ground
I can go everywhere I can be clouds I
can be do like I can I can do everything
and be everything at once yeah so to say
I want to stay in this flesh the rest of
my life is like as retarded as a fucking
ice keep saying I don't want to be an
ice cube yeah yeah great me i wanna i
wanna be water i wanna be ere yeah oh
shoot that shit is all about exactly uh
so i think that this is all all these
new mindset so just hit me with in the
last like three years and it's almost a
little bit he writes like oh what's
going on over here I feel like I'm Nia
like waking up in the matrix e now and
it's gone through my way of
experimenting with these beliefs was
like going around picking up girls like
that's like that was my way to get my
like if this is true i could go run to
pick up girls who and what happened and
now my motivation to like make these
vlogs as all right am I crazy now I'm
gonna end up in a mental hospital or
like am I really on to something you
know like so now I like we put you two
at de las olas you're actually saying
something that'd be fun you know today
because if you follow the rules you'll
end up like a like a politician or a
banker something on Alice like shit put
me in a mental is to at least like you
got interesting people to talk to one of
their circles in shed no couth yeah one
of my favorite videos that you did was
your brain slave no more video and I
really liked it because you
you show your craziness you early sorry
I could see us in that video you showed
your craziness you showed all your
offices and you're gonna like what the
fuck is going on you're shaking on your
bed that was fucking awesome legs I
think as a like so many people around
the world look up to you I think like
one of the biggest gifts like a guru
figure like you could give to people
this self empowerment I one of the best
ways of self-empowerment is just to be
fucking psycho it's very crazy like yeah
people said it resonates with so many
people there's this one line by Eminem
in a song get the name of song it's
probably a hot pocket song but you know
me uh he goes I I rap about the things
that you only talk with your friends
about in their living room the only
difference is I got the balls to say it
and he basically says if the reason why
I'm so influential is because I'll say
whatever the fuck you're thinking and a
lot of times I I hesitate but I'm like I
guarantee that what I'm about to say
although will piss a lot of people off
the greater majority are gonna say oh my
god i thought the same thing except no
one has the balls to say it no one's
trying to look at it in themselves and
they sure as hell ain't gonna tell
anybody else so it's a form like you're
saying it's a form of liberation I'm
basically giving you permission to say
you know this guy is a lot allowing
himself to be himself to be nuts yeah
then maybe it's okay that I am too yeah
I really like what you're saying with a
Frank yang like people I've like energy
built up in them
and right and a bit like one of the
healthiest things to do if your life is
to release that energy and yeah right
the best way to do that is you and I'm
missing something of your videos is
being vulnerable just like like and my
method being vulnerable is like I'm just
in a dream like everyone's me is so why
won't I tell people my true self you
know why I hide anything from anyone
because everyone's you know what you do
though you take risks yeah it may seem
at a little risk you know some people it
up a big deal he talks to girls well
some guys got a life-threatening risk I
mean the physiological changes in their
body when a women comes the woman comes
near is like it's almost as if like
someone put a gun to their head there so
they're so stressed out but you have the
courage to just do whatever your heart
desire and that takes a shit load of
courage and self transcendence and see
what's what's an even higher form of
courage to me is like being vulnerable
and sing up in things like she had on
like going up and talking to girls is
like that though I'm such an alpha male
like look at me it's almost like an ego
form of courage oh gosh it it's a story
that you're telling yourself it helps
yeah but when you're actually vulnerable
um my most popular vlog video right now
is a video where I talk about porn and
masturbation and I'm just rip all this
I'm like I've watched your shift on the
floor and sometimes I'll jack up six
times a day guys oh yeah like you know
what most people have to it was actually
really hard for me to upload that video
mic wave I got but uploading that video
was actually harder than talking to
girls and and like people are like
because I'm just opening up about
something that's I had all this energy
built up inside Mia about like porn and
masturbation and kind of some guilt I
just had to release that to the world
and just your video not releasing energy
really motivated me to do that it's like
gotta get this pressure out of me oh
yeah totally have to because life is it
is a movement and if we're not moving it
we're competing it and like to try to
happen through you the only thing you
could possibly do besides let go and
allow life happen is holding it and
that's monkey uncomfortable because
number one you're stressing yourself out
now you're old
shit and number two you're literally a
roadblock to God or the universe to do
it's fricking thing and God or the
universe doesn't make any mistakes
doesn't fuck up we think we're trying to
fix nature but as I go it's getting away
nature wants to do this through me as
long as I know I'm out of the way that
it's right no matter what anyone else
thinks or says yeah completely agreed um
it's cool because I've seen you go
through all these paradigms in your
videos and then while I'm living my life
the paradigms will come true it's like
it's like you're kind of my guide to
life I watch it I that's interesting and
I'll go out and like whoa that's like
I'll try out your your idea isn't big
that's true it works and another great
um yeah like your thing it's like
yielding to the universe to me like the
universe is like a river and the cool
thing about my picking up girls videos
is like my pranks is it's there's like
girls upstream and I'm like all right
I'm gonna puffle upstream to try to pick
up these girls and the funny thing is I
like all the girls i picked up in those
videos i like never had any chemistry
with it was weird and i realize i was
going against like God and nature you
know I was going upstream those you go
you're performing it was very good yes
but but it was actually going downstream
and to learn the lesson like going
upstream is going downstream to learn
the lesson in the future if that makes
sense you know say yes yeah I get it
you're putting forth effort so that you
can learn how to let go God yeah so
Elliot what are your biggest desires in
life right now I I had this conversation
with someone earlier today it's almost
like once when two people are dancing
you're dancing and I mean truly dancing
you're fully enrolled in the movement
independent music and that other
individual you don't dance with hopes of
an end you you don't express it that way
so that you can get to the end the
purpose of a dance is not to finish it
and we're constantly looking for ends I
do the same thing and I'm learning how
not to wear constant looking for a goal
you know they say it means to an end and
then this is basically a goal goal I
don't want it
and I'm not that interested in ends
right now what I'm really interested and
is this dance of life and growing more
and more sensitive to how the God that
I'm dancing with wants to take this
dance with me because it's part me and
it's part it so as the universe dances
through me and I let it and then I exert
a little bit we're just having this fun
entanglement nice and whatever happens
happens but it's going to be beautiful
so it's I know this sounds crazy but the
minute I have attachments goals and and
plans like your the word you use but you
know desires the future I feel like I'm
fucking out the dance yeah so I don't
have any right now I'm just dancing and
there's fucking dance is great ah nice i
love it a new way i like to look at life
is instead of see myself as a
protagonist like let's say there's a
play going on and it says see myself is
like a main character in the play i like
to think of myself as almost like the
director of the plan like how can i make
the most cool magical interaction with
in life right now and this is likely
you're saying about being in the dance
it's just a whole new perspective then
it's a way to let that God spirit
whatever's going on it's just a way to
allow that to work more with in your
life there are two sides of the coin you
know and in one of the parts is
aggression and that's we get really
caught up in aggression and aggression
is our ability to manipulate what am i
doing to do this but what we forget
quite often and in so many different
ways is that that's only fifty percent
of the game the other half is tenderness
and if I try to attach to fifty percent
of this coin half of the coin heads only
I really miss the total game which means
there's gonna be some allowing so you do
and then you allow you do you allow you
do you allow and really that's if you
just study the nature of the human body
it's kind of exactly the way we live you
put food in your mouth what are you
digesting it are you assimilating the
nutrients are you deciding what's waste
product
then what needs to be filtered and you
know how to to the peristalsis are you
actually using the muscles like you do
this with your bicep the peristaltic
movement in your colon as the shit makes
its way out of your ass no you're
allowing that part it's half us half it
no that's do you think you do you think
you're like your deepest nature that
you're an infinite being be intent that
so these are the top out by like scare
you and you're gonna shit your pants
gonna freak out yeah that's the nature
of human being we're a physical
manifestation of a cloud reality a
spiritual reality yeah