okay we got a question for my buddy ray
Jay who goes on to say that he has motor
tics basically they can be verbal or
physical but basically he's got like
these weird outbursts these physical
outbursts that he says that he totally
can't control sounds kind of like
Tourette's to me so he wants to know you
know he's saying that it's totally
destroying his lifestyle his you know
people are approaching him in a very
different way now that he started having
these tix what should he do okay very
first thing is I'm not going to give you
medical advice but I'm just gonna give
you some ideas that you can consider the
very first one is what medications are
you currently taking because I know just
through experience and watching people
who have taken different a DD drugs a
different psychotropic type medicines
medication you know from your doctor
that it causes this it causes like ticks
you know I've watched my cousin's you
know got like these weird texts and I
know that there are medication you know
that if you look at the pamphlets of
libraries medications there's a whole
slew of weird-ass side effects and a lot
of them are tix you know neurological
fucking ticks and that may be it may be
as simple as that maybe Tourette's I
don't know go get diagnosed or maybe
that you're just getting this particular
response to a chemical in your diet
there to be anything two things two
paradigms two ideas that I want to
support you with beyond that the very
first one is that the nervous system we
all know this I've spoken about this if
you follow me on strengthener vez system
is the energizing system of your
muscular system right it's what's
happening neurologically so you've got
that you got the brain you got the
brainstem you got the peripheral nervous
system you know it all works like an
electric system that shocks your muscle
to do what it wants to do now normally
there's a parent and efferent messages
coming out so you know how to act
appropriately based on the environment
right but perhaps there is an imbalance
between the a fair Janie Faron it's just
purely a ferret I think right bang
you're just doing shit you're not you're
thinking about doing it it just happens
what we can do because you're not the
only one so you might be more obvious in
you and it might be a little bit
stranger in you but we're all harboring
different forms of neurotic holding
patterns you know if you're watching
this right now just pay attention to
your body
people hold their feet tight a lot of
people hold their hands tight they don't
even know they're doing it my buddy
Chris is always tapping his knee every
time we're talking it stacked in this
fucking knee like what dude what are you
doing relax your knee I know a lot of
times I hold my belly tight I know a lot
of times I hold my eyes squinted like
this or tighten my jaw we're all doing
this and instead of a pretty
subconscious level it's pretty
unconscious you know we're holding our
bodies tight holding our chest rigid
we're holding our shoulders up at a very
unconscious level yours just happen to
be a bit more dynamic so the same advice
that I give people all of us every
single one of us that have neurotic
holding patterns is the one that i'm
going to offer you and that is you've
got to meditate right there are
different types of meditation the type
of meditation that i invite you to
partake in would be a dynamic type
meditation if you watch my channel watch
all my channels i'm always offering
different ideas about bioenergetics
shaking the body explosion just going
nuts getting it all out of your system
i'm going to upload a video specifically
about this on my strength channel next
week it's ready to be uploaded for next
week so express yourself get it out
because you're right you're just kind of
like a volcano that's boiling over and
it's just like it's boiling out and
spilling out into your nervous system
you're gonna get it all out hit up in a
bed with your their arms or with a
tennis racket scream yell throw a temper
tantrum go crazy get it all exhaust
yourself completely and then lay dormant
like quietly for a while and you'll
notice that hmm all of a sudden you can
chill the fuck out all your muscles are
going to be completely relaxed that's
that's what i invite you to do but
they're also you know sitting
meditations that may be a bit more tough
you know they're tougher for a lot of
people just sit there and shut your
brain off and meditate I find that if
you meditate through the body through
what I call body meditations you're
going to be far better off okay so
that's one paradigm let's I'm giving a
lot of ideas here dude the other thing
is it's a challenge and you've got to
recognize every single challenger in
your life as an opportunity for growth
now you may believe in God or universe
or a spirit or Allah you know what
choose to call it but I think its
resource about have a resourceful to
have a paradigm or to have some sort of
even it's a figment of your imagination
right God is a figment of your
imagination still a resourceful idea for
considering that that big coach you know
that omnipresent omnipotent coach is
handing you a challenge to see if you're
strong enough or you can grow strong
enough to overcome it every single
challenge in our lives everything that
happens to you no matter how tragic or
how menial because a lot of times
they're very trick these challenges come
in very tricky and sneaky ways you don't
even know they came every single
challenge like the one that you're
facing right now is an opportunity to
grow stronger whatever it is required of
your character in order to overcome this
is the trait that you need to or the
virtue that you need to strengthen so
for example maybe you can never get rid
of this maybe that's just what you're
dealing with right now but God universe
right nature what everyone call it is
challenging your patience ah is he
patient and resilient well no for him to
become the strongest version of himself
he will need to become more patient and
resilient well let's challenge this
motherfucker with Tourette's right now
you're forced you have no choice but to
grow stronger in your character
particularly the virtues of patience and
resiliency so that's it dude I hope one
of the multitude of different ideas or
paradigms that I shared with you or
resourceful to you and good luck grow
stronger Elliot what