everybody's sends me a message about how
disturbed he is that he recently
discovered that some people believe that
men are only motivated by sex he says he
write a blog post recently and the
author asserts that everything that
every man does in his life is motivated
by sex right what you probably don't
understand and what that blogger
probably doesn't understand is that sex
isn't confined just to genital
intercourse sexual energy is the ever
pervading force that creates everything
in our world everything is a balance
between positive and negative in in yang
up and down day and night winter and
summer this duality is expressed from
the origins of man you know Adam and Eve
if you will to the digital age that
brings us the technology that allows me
to talk to you through this camera we
call it the digital age because it's a 0
and a 1 its duality everything all of
life is expressed through the SU
allottee so to say that men are
motivated only by sex is to say yes
because all of the world is motivated by
sex sexual energy brings us everything
that we have the word sex is one of
those words so it's kind of like there's
a lot of negative associations with it
or confused associations with it it does
not necessarily mean that everything
that a man it does is motivated by
getting pussy right not everything that
a man does is motivated by intercourse
but it is driven by a desire to create
balance in the world so in the same way
that you see a woman and you want to
have sex with her that is nature
expressing itself through that
motivating force its it wants to happen
in the same way that when a a seed drops
from a tree it wants to absorb into the
earth so that it can grow it's just the
the animating force of everything that
happens in nature now we as human beings
are very interesting because we can
transmute eight energy
right there's this concept called sexual
transmutation where you essentially can
take sexual energy you look the shit up
its most profoundly expressed in a book
called the science of getting rich this
is where most people get it from but
it's very very old I think it's a Hindu
origin where you literally take sexual
energy and use it to create in other
ways you see so that same drive towards
the beauty participating and partaking
of the beauty of a woman is the same
energy that you can use you can
transmute ate and use towards building
muscle towards performing well in your
sport towards building a business
towards doing really well in school it's
the same energy that causes you to want
to complete that arc of energy that
positive and negative so I mean to wrap
it up because I want sound to be
confusing here is that there's duality
in nature and there's a necessity by all
human beings and everything in this
world to dance with its counterpart as
human beings yes we dance with male and
female but we can as men can also dance
with the world by creating things so to
say that you're motivated to build your
business because you will because of sex
is in the right context correct but to
say that you're motivated to build your
business so that you can get more pussy
is you're looking at it the wrong way
you're not understanding it properly