kind of question from our buddy Nick who
has been he's 35 years old he's dating
his girlfriend for 15 years now they've
been living together for three years
loves her says that she's his soul mate
other people comment on how well they
interact with one another I mean after
15 years was two people to be you know
passionate or even nice to each other is
difficult in our culture you know most
people look you know they're gone after
a few years and I know this has I've
been with my wife since we were 14 years
old and we still get giddy with each
other and tickle each other and laugh in
public and stuff and people are like oh
you guys just did married so I
understand I know what you're talking
about the problem is that this is the
only woman he's ever had sex with
they were virgins and they you know they
had sex with one another and that's it
that's been it and and he doesn't feel
like the sex is satisfying in fact he's
he's thinking about having sex with
other women and his girlfriend even says
you know what I get it that's okay like
if there's something else you want go
and have sex with other girls I'm not
going to go anywhere I'm going to stay
here I'll remain your girlfriend I know
that you there's some sexual fantasy
that you want to play out that I can't
provide you with she realizes this is
apparently she's not a very sexually
exciting person you know according to
their standards that's an interesting
thing because where do sexual excitement
standards come from they come from
something that we've created the
construct in our heads usually
pornography and television tell us what
sex should be if you watch sex in the
movies it always looks so like man these
people study Tantra and usually that's
that's not the case but anyway there's
something that that's eating at you you
share this with her and she says yes go
but he feels as if she will grow
resentful then she she might if he goes
and has sex with another woman so what
does he do so the very first thing is
that idea that I want to share with you
that you know you might just be making
this sexual fantasy thing up you know
the sex you're having with her might be
just as good as you probably experience
with anybody else you know media culture
has had
come to believe that sex is always going
to look like this like pornography and
that's not really the case the most
powerful the most expressive the most
satisfying sex that I have with my wife
usually doesn't look like pornography
and we have great sex she still makes my
mouth water I mean that's the thing I
think that's why we stay together still
for so long because she makes my fucking
mouth water we're still really sexually
interested in each other now there have
been times where if that wasn't the case
because you know either
we're busy or you know we're having
children I mean I've got four kids but
I've come to a place where the story I
share with myself about how sex should
be looks nothing more than that which I
receive every time I grab my wife's ass
so I built a story for myself around
reality you've never had sex with
another woman
and you see it in all the the glory that
that culture affords it to you and
billboards and commercials and you have
a story about what that might be like
now that's an itching that's eating at
you and it's not easy to get rid of
those itches you might have to scratch
that fucking hitch you might have to go
scratch that thing that's tickling you
and your wife your girlfriend is is
giving you your girlfriend's giving you
a chance to go and do that so should you
do it
I think it should I think you should I
think you should speak with her and then
you said you've talked with her for a
million hours you probably don't need to
speak with her that much anymore but I
think you need to go and scratch that
itch but remember that you're going to
come back to reality and reality is that
sex is just sex unless you literally
study Tantra and I study that should
actually read books about how to have
better sex I'm fucking weird but most
people don't
unless you've studied it's not going to
look like pornography it's not going to
be this ecstatic explosion of fireworks
every single time you've been dating for
fifteen years you've seen her body
you've been inside it not every single
sexual contact with her is going to be
but sometimes it's routine so that's it
dude you know hopefully I afforded you
just a few ideas that might be helpful
for you I think you've got a great woman
on your hands I think also that if you
go to this might size challenge but if
you go to sexual classes together
there's all types of sexual yoga there
are Tantra classes for couples do if I
can do it everybody so embarrassed about
stuff but I say it's worth saving your
relationship go to you know go
experience you got a scratch that I
think you got to scratch the fucking
edge yeah even you've been with one
woman your whole life it might be tough
go scratch your itch I promise you that
you're gonna be like that oh all right
when you're done you come back and say
listen babe okay good I'm with you we're
here again right I don't have to do take
her to some texture classes bro look up
classes for sexual classes for couples
on the internet they're all over the
place
go to a retreat you guys may tickle each
other in certain places you can blow on
each other in certain places and use
special oils turn on certain music
incense you ever try that yourself turn
on music really like I get into
role-playing and shit you know we've
done weird shit like that before
everybody every couple who
really loves each other really loves
fucking is going to find little weird
little ways every once in a while
to shake things up understand I think it
kind of goes against our nature as human
beings especially men to be with one
person our entire lives but hey this is
the way I'm not trying to fight society
and I want to fight with my wife but
it's not fucking other bitches it's just
not gonna happen
but for UI man she's giving you this
opportunity scratch your itch come home
and then work on it with her I think you
can do it but you're going to need help
so go to a class or something peace