earlier I made a video about how every
action is measured by the sentiment from
which it proceeds basically it's not so
much what you do but the place you're
coming from when you do it
so one of the things where this really
applies and a lot of people have some
confusion about or or discomfort about
is with regard to giving the charity so
ask yourself before you give to any
charity any type of donation if you are
giving from a place of guilt you feel
like you a lot of times people say well
I feel bad that's why they do something
or you're doing it from a place of love
like I really want to contribute to this
I really love this mission or I love
this organization whatever it is are you
coming from a place I'm passion and love
for that thing you give to people who
are homeless because you love to share
with people you want to see people happy
or you do it because I feel bad I feel
pity now those are two totally different
sentiments two people give and they can
both actions will be measured by the
place person's coming from if you give
out of pity you're coming from a weak in
place and that action is measured in
that in particular fashion so ask
yourself and be honest before you give
before you share before you donate where
were you coming from with it because if
you're coming from a place of pity
coming from a place of fear or lack
don't do it save your money
hold on to it when you're ready to give
you'll know because you'll do it from a
place of love passion and compassion
Eliot said what
[Music]