so one of my favorite quotes by Ralph
Waldo Emerson and you know I'm always
quoting Emerson is that the most
difficult thing for a man to do is to be
himself in a world that's constantly
trying to change him in fact that's the
very first quote that I read by Emerson
and why I fell in love with his work he
wrote that about a hundred years ago
over a hundred years ago and for him to
have echoed that sentiment when the mass
psychology of the time was not nearly as
intertwined as it is today the cities
were smaller
he lived amongst nature and there was no
internet meant that he felt the pressure
of conformity associated with putting
his art out there for people to enjoy or
to criticise and there was a large time
lapse between his creativity and that
feedback do you see so if he produced a
piece of artwork you know an essay that
he wrote or that he spoke he might not
get feedback until months later when
someone who reads it and maybe writes
him a letter
if you are a few living in today's day
and age regardless if you're a producer
of content like I am or not you're
engaging with people at a prolific rate
I mean it's ridiculous how expensive our
communication has become if you are on
Facebook if you are on Twitter if you
are on YouTube if you're using social
media email in any way shape or form the
communication the interaction with
people is instant and abundant and the
mode if the most difficult thing for a
person to do is to be himself in a world
that's constantly trying to change him
and Emerson wrote that during a time
when the world wasn't bombarding him the
way that it does today means that it's a
thousand times more difficult to produce
pure content pure art to put yourself
and all the transparency associated with
what's coming up in your heart all the
rawness and truth of your art out for
people to see if you're doing that today
you will be instantly either adored or
act both are demons that will destroy
your art I only say this because it has
been my experience to create a video to
use a piece to create a piece of written
art or just sharing my ideas see what I
do is I I enjoy ideas and I enjoy
experiences and I share my ideas and
experience with people through the
internet some people come to a door and
some people come to attack the thing is
that it's instant how do you deal with
being genuine and being true to yourself
when you're instantly attacked or adored
and I'm going to use that term an
overall term to describe that there that
instant feedback the feedback is so
instant and it impacts your
consciousness so quickly that it's
difficult to produce anything that is
truly yours it's always tainted with the
sentiment of how do I continue to
provide how do I continue to share and
and receive back these loving feelings
from the people who adore me how do i
manipulate my next piece of art in order
to satisfy those who attack me it's easy
for me to say because my experience is I
mean this is the life I live I live a
life where I put myself in front of
everybody I am my art if you will I
speak and I and I share that's what I do
I make videos you know like Emerson
wrote and he stood up in you know and he
was an orator that's what he's called it
in time he spoke to crowds may I speak
to crowds through my iPhone like I'm
doing right now and the feedback like
I'm gonna upload this and they'll be
comments so mine is an extreme example
so you know that I have to be thinking
about this shit
and figuring out how to deal with this
shit because it is my life you and the
other hand it might not be the case
you know you but I can guarantee that if
you're watching this you have a youtube
account you have a Facebook account more
than likely or Twitter account you're
engaged in social media you're engaged
in the Beehive mass consciousness mass
mind that's going on all around you and
it's
so difficult to retain your own
subjectivity and see the world
objectively so that you can protect
yourself and your rawness your
authenticity without the scourge of
attack or the hindrance of a dorrance so
what do you do
easier said than done but what I have to
do because I live an extreme example of
what you may be experiencing is you've
got to ignore everyone easier said than
done and something that I struggle with
as well but my invitation to you through
this video is that if you'd like to live
from York or if you'd like to experience
and produce raw authentic genuine art
and that which the spirit is doing
through you if you want to be true to
yourself without being sullied by the
opinions either good or bad negative or
positive because they're both forms of
slavery and you've got to ignore
everyone you've got to close your door
you've got to shut off your phone you've
got to shut off your computer you've got
to sit down and got to be with your self
and the muse or the spirit or the the
soul God the daymond so that you could
be at one with the omnipresent universe
and let it speak through you purely
become a hollow read unobstructed by the
opinions positive and negative of other
people I wish you the best