we got this question from our buddy
Bilal who has been deeply in love with
this girl who really wasn't paying him
any mind for several months and finally
he's been able to cajole her into some
sort of conversations they start text
messaging back and forth with one
another she says to herself well you
know what this guy's not so bad I'll
give him a chance they get together and
kiss and she immediately recognizes that
there's no spark and she makes that
clear to him she says you know what I'm
trying here but I just don't feel
anything for you we kissed and I just
don't have that same spark that I have
when I've kissed other men I'm sorry but
I have to move on and Bilal is
devastated I mean he's put all his time
energy effort his imagination has been
wrapped around what could possibly be in
the future with a beautiful woman like
this and when he gets his opportunity he
blows it or so it would seem right you
get the chance to kiss her and she says
done goodbye it's pretty fucked up and I
know it hurts bro but here are a few
things that I think might support you
number one you got to remember that love
is yours
it happens in you it's an experience
physiological energetically physical
that happens in your body and it feels
good because it is a letting go it is a
falling right so when you fall in love
that means you let go of many of our ego
constraints and it is just this euphoric
floating feeling that's why they say
when someone's in love it looks like
they're floating because they've let go
of their grounding in many ways you're
floating you fell you're vulnerable and
it's a good feeling right I mean that's
why people take drugs so it feel they
feel like they're loading if they feel
like they can escape for a moment love
is an escape and it's euphoric so the
very first thing I would invite you to
do is to extend gratitude maybe not
verbally or even let her know but say in
your heart say a prayer of gratitude for
the experience of
falling in love and gratitude for her
for the form that she is that has
allowed you that experience I know
you're a young dude and this is probably
your first heartbreak okay
so that's the very first thing be
grateful don't beat yourself up because
number two it's not about you her not
feeling the spark when you guys kiss
doesn't mean that you are a poor lover
it doesn't mean that you are yet bad
breath unless she told you you had bad
breath then chew gum but it really had
less to do with who you are and what's
happening inside you and whatever is
happening inside her happens to be what
is the more important circumstance for
that thing not happening right she has
we all have our own issues she's got her
own issues she's got previous
experiences with other men that she may
still be holding on to she has her own
self esteem and ideas about who she is
who she wants to become she's probably
watched Disney movies right and perhaps
has been brainwashed as we all have by
what this what love should look like you
know the guy in the Disney movies always
there look they look like beautiful men
with big muscles and they come and they
save their women and the girls always
look you know frail and helpless and so
on and so forth so there's cultural
ideals whatever the circumstances are
there's something happening in her that
didn't allow the Union to happen right
and again once again just because the
Union didn't happen doesn't mean that
the experience wasn't pleasurable allow
yourself to be grateful for that
pleasurable experience that you did have
even though it didn't move in the
direction that you thought it should
have be grateful in that way recognize
that it's not your fault and finally
number three do it again falling in love
is vulnerable and when you're vulnerable
you can get hurt and when you get hurt
you begin building calluses emotional
calluses thickening of your skin again
the experience if it were to approach
itself once again and this is where most
people end up living very grey dry
boring dispassionate empty lies because
after one maybe two strikes right
and it's actually our second and third
strike is the first strike is mommy and
so is our first strike mommy and daddy
issues that's always where our very
first experience of heartbreak so we
always we walk into the world with two
strikes left and most people after the
first order perhaps a second that's it
I'm not doing it again fuck these
bitches fuck these hoes all they want is
money and all they want is a guy who
drives a nice car and has a gigantic
cock so if that's what sour grapes so
you start making up all these different
stories about why you should never let
yourself fall in love and it usually
said it usually comes from this
perspective of victimhood bitches
bitches bitches bitches right I'm gonna
get a lot of this in the comment section
cuz a lot of you guys have had your
little balls hurt and now you go around
your life calling women bitches and and
never allowing yourself to be Google but
become vulnerable and fall in love ever
again that sucks bro
that really sucks because the feeling of
yielding into love that euphoria
associated with falling into love is
perhaps the most magnificent experience
that we can have as a human being
because it is it's this form of
detachment from reality that makes us
feel like we're floating you know the
most the most potent expression of that
is sexual orgasm because you've really
let yourself emotionally mentally
spiritually physiologically to yield
into the experience that you're having
with another person and that is one of
the greatest feelings that a human being
could ever experience but most of us men
and women you know just because you bust
a nut doesn't mean that you orgasm bro
you might have a little nice little
tingly feeling in your nuts but what I'm
talking about is a complete letting go
of your entire muscular system your
whole body
it almost feels like like you can fall
the scooter the scooters like this
fucking big that guy the guy's got to be
about 260 pounds and the scooters like
this big and it makes more noise than
anything I've heard in my fucking life
why this why does the scooter but you
have to make so much noise to go a car a
truck is bigger than that little fucking
cock rocket that the guy is sitting on
and I make half the sound you know does
he think that's cool I had no fucking
idea but anyway where was I going with
this sorry I got distracted yeah so
allow yourself to fall allow yourself to
experience love once again if you get
your heart broken pick it up and go
again and go again and go again allow
your heart to be broken a thousand times
if you need to in order to finally find
someone who understands you who
appreciates you who can fall with you do
you understand that's what you're
looking for but if you show up with all
your baggage because of your heartbreak
and you never allow yourself to fall
again you'll never really be able to
experience the most potent pleasure that
life has to offer
done