habitual psychic behavior you know your
your thoughts and your ideas become
feelings that literally trap themselves
in your muscular tissue and become
neurotic holding patterns so these
holding patterns ultimately become your
character for example if when you were a
kid you were told not to talk back you
can't speak up you're seven years old
and you you had something you wanted to
say you wanted to voice your opinion or
make your stand and you had an
authoritarian parent that was like shut
up you you don't speak when I'm talking
to you or your opinion doesn't matter
what happens is you then physically
tighten the muscles around your jaw and
your neck you know a person that has
this type of trauma because they're
constantly chewing their mouths or like
their lips or grinding their teeth or
chewing gum or chewing their fingernails
there's a lot of physical tension in
their jaw that is a manifestation of
that psychic holding pattern it became
physical so one of the best ways to
break up that physical tension so that
you can free your character so that you
can express yourself once again because
a person like this often has a hard time
speaking out in public or or talking to
others or voicing their opinions so what
we want to do is reverse engineer the
trauma by breaking up or discharging
that extra energy that's trapped in your
jaw right so that person who is always
chewing their lips are grinding their
teeth may want to use something called
gibberish discharge that literally how
cool our blahblah her Jewish girl gonna
talk cuz I'll get to be open to that of
that power yeah but I go I go I go I go
I gotta yeah yeah yeah yeah we all go
gaga gaga gaga Elliot said what
[Music]