good question for our buddy Alistair who
was a little bit clarification on a kind
of hope that I put on Facebook and
Elliott Hulse original quote I put on
Facebook just the other day I referred
to the ugly trap of comparison that many
of us get get lost in we go about our
lives comparing ourselves to other
people and never really get anywhere
because we're always looking on the
outside we're looking at appearances and
measuring what we think is ourselves as
most people are very not very in touch
with themselves measuring what little we
know of ourselves against what little we
see of other people because appearances
are never never never what they seem
and it is a very masochistic trap to get
in because you're constantly beating
yourself down and building someone else
up do you see so it's a terrible place
to be in my suggestion to getting out of
that trap in my in my quote was to get
in touch with your feelings honor
respect appreciate them and trust your
gut right Alistair is a little confused
he's wondering like what does that
actually mean how do I do that and why
would that break me free from the the
ugly cycle of comparison what you've got
to understand is that from a very early
age we begin conditioning our children
and we ourselves have been conditioned
not to trust the only thing that we have
the only thing you have available to you
when you are a baby because you don't
have any ideas yet you're not
conditioned yet all you have available
to you are your experiences and and you
experience the world especially when
you're a baby because you haven't been
brainwashed yet but all of us we
experience our the world first through
feelings not ideas ideas or symbols
right religion is symbols philosophy is
symbols they're all based on words
they're all based on other people's
ideas other people's experiences and
then they're they're driven into our
heads they have nothing to do with our
heart and balls but very early on when
we start becoming brainwashed with
the environments ideas and told not to
trust our feelings we lose touch with
who we are and then we become very
attached to what's happening up here
you're taught not to trust your feelings
right if you're sad you shouldn't be sad
why are you sad why are you crying why
do you feel that way you shouldn't feel
that way
this starts very early on but you
shouldn't trust your feelings all realms
of society do that to us our parents do
that you shouldn't feel that way right
religions tell us that you shouldn't
feel sexual right you got sexual
feelings it's bad they're wrong
your feelings are bad they're wrong they
shouldn't be trusted right and when you
begin negating the only thing that you
have available to you it's the only
thing you own is your feelings remember
everything else that comes through as an
idea they're all simply ideas you might
call them truth but still they're just
symbols your experience what's happening
in your body is true it's always true
someone asked me about hate before they
said well if you feel hate that's wrong
no feeling wrong feeling hate is what's
happening in your body so it's true it's
right violence is wrong the way you act
out the feeling in your body is wrong
but to place a judgment to place a moral
judgment on what's happening in in your
body creates a schizophrenic behavior
attitude character and when the head in
the body or split the head goes off and
searches for what it should attach to
and all I can do is see the forms
presented to us through other people or
that guy's got a really nice car that
guy's got a nicer voice in me that guy's
got a hotter wife than I've got that
guy's got a bigger house the head is out
there detached from the body the body
mate meanwhile be saying boy I really
just want to go for a walk I really just
want to go hiking I really just want to
play an instrument I really just want to
breathe right but we're so busy because
we're so detached from what our bodies
are telling us we're wrapped up in the
work on the adventures that the heads
going on that we easily get lost in the
world wind of life when you're grounded
in your body you no longer are carried
away by your thoughts you're no longer
carried away by symbols you're no longer
carried away by the appearances of other
people we don't know what they're
feeling I don't know what they're
feeling that guy might have a a
multi-million dollar house but he might
have ulcers because it's going
completely against what is hardness
balls one what I'm inviting you to do is
to don't force yourself to stop
comparing to other people start
breathing into your balls what I mean is
get in touch with what's happening in
your body trust your body because if
everyone is telling you that you need to
go and be a lawyer and you see all your
lawyer uncles and aunts and your lawyer
friends with what are the trappings of
success without really getting a
subjective experience for what's going
on in their bodies you can very easily
be carried away into believing that's
what I need to do and you're comparing
yourself to them on the same journey
they're all miserable
I guarantee you that 90% of people that
you're comparing yourself to are
miserable because they're not in touch
with their bodies when you are grounded
in your body you will be able to
navigate life through sensing what is
right for you
this all sounds very strange this all
sounds almost like demonic people will
have you believe right or earthly I
don't know what it is they use all types
of manipulative techniques to cajole us
into using our heads and not trusting
our hearts what I'm telling you is
forget the symbols forget what people
have told you forget what everyone else
is doing and feel your way through life
let your heart and your balls navigate
you this is very scary
this requires a lot of courage and a lot
of people are not going to trust you
they don't trust me because I say shit
like this Elliot that doesn't make any
sense what if your heart tells you bike
what if you hug your hearts wrong your
feelings are wrong what's going on in
your bodies wrong it's evil it's bad I'm
saying fuck that fuck you trust your
heart you might not have what someone
else who has an erotic drive towards
worldly success gets right seemingly on
the outside you might not get the fast
car in the big house but you still own
your balls you still own your heart
understand and to me and maybe obviously
I'm an eccentric crazy weird ass dude
right but to me it is far better to own
your heart and balls regardless of what
the external circumstances look like
then to sever yourself sever your head
from your body to be a schizophrenic
wandering about life with your head
being dragged in every other direction
then that which your heart should be
carrying you trust your feelings is the
first place to begin if you're feeling
anxious be with it own it look at it if
something feels good to you but it's
evil oh I shouldn't feel so good that uh
you know I shouldn't be getting an
erection right now with that girl
walking by because it's evil own it own
it don't play some moral judgment on
your feeling it feels good when I just
paint I just want to fucking paint I
just want to make finger paintings when
I put my fingers in the pink and I rub
it all over the wall and I take more I
splash it nice cream it just feels good
what's that gonna get you son I'm gonna
get you a good job and you're gonna get
your career what about insurance shut
that shit out they're forcing you back
into the arena of comparison shut that
shit out completely be with that feeling
if you feel great painting with your
fucking fingers on a wall go and do it
go and do it as much as you can
because it's gonna lead you down a path
your heart if you start trusting your
heart with the little things right
it might not cost you much to go paint
on your wall with your fingers right you
still got your job you still got your
all the the things that you've got all
your responsibilities but you're doing
one thing you're letting your heart
speak just a little bit do that thing
you're exercising your heart do that
thing and your hearts gonna lead you
somewhere else hearts gonna say you know
what it'd be really good if you really
cool if you put this on canvas let's put
it on a freakin canvas and you start
getting better at it you now to
manipulate your fingers better you know
how to mix colors better and you make
this thing it's like whoa that's really
fucking awesome I'm going to take a
picture of it and put it on Facebook you
take a picture that thing you put on
Facebook right this is what you do at
night when you go home from work because
you've nothing else to do but listen to
your heart and someone says wow that is
a brilliant fucking picture and they
share it with a hundred people and
someone finds it and says you know I'm
an art collector I'd like to pay you 200
bucks for that can you make one like
that for me in fact I have a whole wall
in my house I was trying to figure out
what to do with would you mind coming
I'll pay 500 bucks I'll pay a thousand
bucks I'll pay 5,000 bucks to do this
you go and do it well and this may or
may not happen but my point is that if
you follow your heart you'll be okay so
you get $5,000 for doing something that
you love you take a picture of that you
put it on Facebook and then you've got
10 people Plus that guy's referring you
to other people that you can go and earn
more money doing the thing that you love
there's always a way when you follow
your heart you do the things that are in
your heart and instead of comparing
yourself to other people and following
the path that they've brainwashed you
for all sorts of magical opportunities
open up right the difference is that the
traditional path has a ladder of success
you can look at it go to college get a
career which is you know no longer a
reality it's still it's a hope to wish
get a pension plan retire ba ba ba ba
there's like a linear approach when you
start following your heart there's no
guarantee you don't know where that
motherfuckers gonna take you your heart
will take you down some crazy freakin
roads I could guarantee you one thing
about where your Art's gonna take you
though is the path that you're supposed
to go it's a path that you need to go
because every single challenge that your
heart will take you to face is set there
to make you become a stronger version of
yourself not this bullshit path that
someone else has created for you so that
you can compare yourself to all the
other slaves
follow your heart so your heart can take
you to the challenges that are unique to
you if it means I only eat once a week
right then hey that's you're listening
to your heart that's where it's taking
you fine be with it own it don't
complain about it don't whine about it
don't tell other people that how
destitute you are you followed your
heart you own your heart and balls now
eat the cake associated with it it's a
problem people want to follow their
hearts but they also want the guarantee
of the traditional path of the well laid
out path there's no fucking guarantees
when you follow your heart people that's
a very important point that I want to
make because when Elliot hotels follow
your heart I'm not giving you pipe
dreams I'm telling you you will own your
heart you own your balls which is far
more valuable than this the quote
unquote security associated with working
for a corporation that can drop your ass
any freaking day and then comparing
yourself to what type of car you know
the guy in the cubicle next to you
drives get out of that trap all together
get in touch with your feelings do what
your hearts asking you to do go on the
journey that your heart is inviting you
to go on regardless of what it looks
like in regardless of what other people
say you will be cast out you'll be a
weirdo you will be eccentric it's just
the way of the heart but it will be your
way
good luck Elliot's it