I have this question from our buddy um
what is your name John from Latvia is 23
a 23 year old age again 23 lovely lovely
fucking age especially for men maybe for
women but I don't have a vagina so I
couldn't tell you anyway he says he has
horrible luck with love says he hasn't
had a relationship that lasted longer
than three weeks he says he's a
good-looking guy he's personable he
works out he has lots of friends
he's honest he has a good sense of humor
girls are attracted to him so on and so
forth he says he doesn't get too
attached to the girls this is
significant he says that he only gives
enough emotion share zone enough emotion
so that she knows that he likes her but
he doesn't get too lovey-dovey okay cool
but you know things seem to progress to
a particular point and then it falls
apart recently he's had an experience
with a girl who you know invited him
into her dorm room he massaged her with
some oils they had been you know texting
naked pictures back and forth to each
other they had the opportunity to be
together he rubbed her down and she in
more words than this turned him down and
and then started acting really cold
towards him and he's you know I guess
the reason why he brings us up is
because it's so recent but it sounds
like this is a pattern you know you
exert yourself towards women and then
they back away and he wants to know
what's going on I'm Lena this is going
to be one of those videos where a lot of
people are going to disagree with me and
you know and make all types of excuses
or rationalizations as to why we
shouldn't listen to Elliot when it comes
to love simply because he's you know
that I've been married to the same
movement for a very long time but it
doesn't mean that my heart and dick
don't still work
there's and doesn't mean that I'm still
I'm not still sexually active in a way
that is uh you know I'm not fucking
other women but I know what I know
what's going on energetically I know
what's going on in the body
I understand sexual dynamics so with
that being said you know if you want to
use that as a reason why not to take my
advice that's okay
but bear with me now and this is this is
not something that most people going to
say to you especially if you you know
you're looking for pick-up advice and
stuff like that dude let yourself fall
in love let go of the need to hold back
your emotions your feelings the the true
physiological and spiritual response in
your body that is happening that you
suppress it's happening in you you want
to love someone we all want to love
someone doesn't matter how phallic
narcissus you make yourself out to be
how damaged you have been by the world
or how much of a you know a stoic you
are in that particular way so you nobody
wants anybody's lovey-dovey I beg to
disagree I don't I don't agree I think
someone who is lovey-dovey want someone
who's lovey-dovey
I want someone to love now um of course
I love my wife but I know that the type
of person I'm gonna respond to best is
someone who just right here you know we
we say our heart and it's a metaphor for
a literal experience I want someone who
makes me go like this ah that makes my
heart flutter that makes me do hmm right
that's usually what women do because
women are usually more susceptible to
romance than men but if you open
yourself up Lao the emotion you know
you're 18 years old and you say you know
I hold back my emotion and have a good
way of using my mind to create to bottle
up my emotions so I'm not too
lovey-dovey right this is what you tell
me all you're doing is you're you're
impeding the flow of love that should
naturally go through you if you feel
like oh I'm in love allow yourself to be
in love now here is the thing you got to
keep in mind sometimes you're gonna get
your heart stomped on you open yourself
up see this is the reason why we don't
do this
mostly men the reason why we
don't let ourselves fall in love is
because we know what it's like to have
our hearts broken at least once it only
needs to happen once and according to
Freud it happens when our mom stops
nursing us now whether or not you agree
with that is not isn't either here no
there but we all have had our hearts
broken at least once it usually happens
very early on in our childhood
so we protect ourselves from ever
falling in love again and when you
protect yourself from love you don't get
love bro you get a shadow of love and
that's what most relationships fucking
are the shadows of love there are other
forms of dependency that we have on one
another and that's why most
relationships are fucking dysfunctional
you never let yourself fall in love I
love that term fall what's happening
when you're falling are your feet on the
ground you've slipped and you're just
what's gonna happen you complete it's a
gamble
love is a fucking gamble and what I'm
asking you to do is if you want to put
yourself if you want align yourself with
the flow of love in the world and I
guaran-fucking-tee you that if you get
in touch with that energy and you get in
touch with love in you there is a woman
out there that is going to fit you like
a lock-and-key he's gonna be so prepared
to receive the authenticity that you are
willing to give through your love that
it will be like a match made in heaven
it will last forever it will last for
that it'll be true love that's a that
won't be challenges won't be time not to
say that there won't be times where you
have to recalibrate your love and the
way you love another individual and of
course I'm talking about long-term
relationships because these are ideas
that I consider mind you I've been
married to my wife for 10 12 years we've
been dating since we were teenagers
we're not same people we recalibrate but
we always stay in touch with that
original energy that brought us together
that vulnerable that vulnerability
that vulnerable place of love my friend
you need to make yourself vulnerable you
need to fall down you need to get stupid
in love let it happen to you let it
happen to you go get hurt too and then
do it again keep doing it keep exposing
yourself keep becoming vulnerable to
love because even though you might get
hurt you experienced it and most people
never experienced love it's better to
have loved and lost than to have never
allowed yourself to love from the
beginning
done