we got a great question for our buddy
Daniel here who says that he always
feels as if he's faking himself if he's
with friends family strangers girls it
doesn't matter he always feels as if
he's faking who he is he's not allowing
the full spontaneity of who he is to
happen so of course this is causing him
some distress because they know he's
always suppressing himself and you get
to a particular point if you do that
long enough that you even begin
forgetting what your spontaneous
reaction is certain circumstances might
be because you're always putting on
you're always thinking always
calculating what the best response would
be in order to get a resourceful feed
resourceful feedback from the people may
uh in my environment and we're all
looking for validation in some way shape
or form so the best way to get
validation from other people is to give
them what you think they want I get it
because I stand in front of this camera
every day so two things I want to bring
to your attention or I have two
suggestions the very first thing I want
you to become aware of it's the fact
that you use your muscular system even
watch my videos for long enough you know
what I'm about to say you use your
muscular system to suppress new your
natural spontaneity we use the muscular
system to create neurotic holding
patterns in our face in our neck our
chest our belly a pelvic floor all which
reduce our ability to breathe deep when
you suppress your ability to breathe
deep you're you're really suppressing
the spontaneity within your body that
the natural movement that happens from a
visceral level right we we respond to
conversation we respond to people with
our body first our word second that's
why they say body language is so
important but when you are searching
you're using the ego you're searching
for the most resourceful words for a
particular situation then you've got to
shut down your spontaneity and your body
language becomes very depressed so what
I want you to pay attention to is how
you're doing this because it's it's a
it's a behavior it's it's something
you're doing and you've been practicing
it for so long that you probably are not
even familiar with your natural
spontaneity but anyway I want you to
take notice of how you're using your
muscular system to
hide yourself to suppress yourself
because the faking can only happen when
you shut down who you really are you
shut down that animal within you you
shut down your heart you suck shut down
your sexuality and that's essentially
what we're doing when we reduce our
respiratory wave through tightening in
the chest I happen to do it a lot in the
belly a lot of people do it in the jaw
a lot of people likely groped their
teeth and grind their teeth and I don't
hold the draw Tite because there's a
spontaneity that would proceed from the
mouth that would proceed from the job
right maybe you want to yell or maybe
you want to lash out but you can't right
I mean you can't fucking bite people
so you tighten your job some people do
in their hands they do it in their
shoulders a lot of people hike up like
this you'll notice some people excuse me
they hold their butt their anus
tightening you call out for some tight
ass like you almost like suck up in your
perineum and and that air your sphincter
take notice where do you feel the
muscular restriction that you're doing
remember this we create our own prisons
when you're in these situations now
course is going to be difficult because
you're you know the tendency is to want
to think about what's the coolest thing
that I could say the most resourceful
feedback that I could offer this person
right Witte how can I be really witty in
the circumstances what I'm gonna ask you
put that away just for a moment they
might think you're weird but really what
you're doing is possessing yourself once
again that's what I want you to learn
how to do possess it's called self
possession and when you possess yourself
you can embody your words you can embody
your communication with other people
instead of having to think about it
right go to the head and you'll
essentially create a prison for your
body and think about the most witty
calculated things that you can offer so
pay attention awareness is
transformative in and of itself simply
by watching your body you will become
aware of how you're making yourself a
prisoner of your mind or your brain and
muscular system okay and slowly over
time you
stop doing it don't force yourself but
if you notice that your your holding
your belly tight take a deep breath and
relax your belly and say hmm that's
fascinating interesting I didn't know
that I was doing that right we to do all
this shit becomes unconscious that's
number one begin doing that but I'm
going to put this process on hyperdrive
we're going to speed it up so the tree
can become spontaneous once again really
what you want to become is deliberately
spontaneous right and that's not like a
contradiction tender aggressive it's
really what I'm teaching you so become
tender by watching your body and notice
the rigidity in your muscular system and
then begin writing in a journal carry it
with you and take notice when you you
know if obviously you want to wait until
you have some time by yourself or sneak
off later on and write what you would
have liked to actually say you know like
what was really coming up in you in a
particular circumstance that you didn't
say because you're too busy watching
your body follow and it might even like
you're talking conversation with your
dad right we're all trying to prove
ourselves to our dads ah and you're
talking to him and you notice why I'm
starting to like clenched my hands
that's cuz you want to fucking knock him
out not saying that's the case but just
giving you an example you clench your
fist and you clench your teeth and
you're standing there like this and like
he's talking to you and you're thinking
about or normally you'd be thinking
about what can I say to this
motherfuckers to just let him leave me
alone or that I could prove that I'm
more witty or intelligent than him right
that's normally what's happening but now
because you're becoming aware of your
mechanism your hate you're gonna realize
all important my hands are tight oh boy
my jaws tight and then you just listen
partake of the conversation your best
answer usually is hmm okay
oh really interesting tell me more
you're off the hook when you ask people
to tell me more you don't have to say
anything we ask other people questions
I've made videos about this but anyway
it gives you an opportunity to make
space let that person talk and just
watch yourself as that person's talking
you're also going to notice that there
are natural tendencies that you that
want to happen in you there are natural
expressions that want to have happen in
you and they're going to they're going
to filter through into your
consciousness and later on you're gonna
write it down boy what I really would
have liked to say at that particular
time when my dad said such and such or
what I really thought about that girl
was such and such she's think she's
hotter than she is or you go and you
write it out in the journal that way you
start coming in touch with your
spontaneity what actually was happening
that you began suppressing you're coming
in contact with your ego and your
unconscious at the same time you're
letting go of your ego by relaxing your
muscular system and you're becoming very
keen to the visceral or spontaneous
reaction in your body and you're writing
it out does this make sense I hope you
guys follow we're all doing this on some
level as you become aware of how you are
creating a prison for yourself neurotic
holding patterns which was taught to you
I mean the world destroys our nervous
systems and come in touch with what's
actually what I really like to say what
is actually spontaneous in me you're now
going to own yourself that much more and
you'll be able to present as I just
described a form of deliberate
spontaneity it's not print is not
censoring yourself like a prison it's
being in touch with how I really feel
about this situation and then finding a
resourceful way to express it sometimes
you find that it's not so resourceful to
express it but you can sit there with a
smile on your face and they're gonna
wonder what the fuck is this guy
thinking got it good