you're now listening to the
later the number one podcast of all time
of all time make sure you're ready
because this is the podcast where you're
guaranteed to virtually every baby
today's show is sponsored by audible go
to audible podcast.com slash B C S
stands for Bryan Callen show and get
your free download I am a huge fan of
audible I Drive a lot and most of us
don't have time to read so I use it
constantly and I'll tell you what's on
my phone right now
John Irving's a widow for one year he
was my wrestling coach for a little
while he's a great American author and
so damn much money which I've been
talking about which kind of like is all
about how much money there is in
politics and what a disaster is by
Robert G Keyser and I've you've heard me
talk about this before but a very
important book in an amazing book called
Republic lost by Lawrence Lessig I can't
recommend it highly enough it gets to
the root of the problem that our
republic faces so once again go to
audible podcast.com slash BCS to get
your free download and by the way I will
be doing stand-up comedy in Fort
Lauderdale ladies and gentlemen at the
Fort Lauderdale improv June 20th the
21st not the 22nd not Saturday but I
will be doing it on the 23rd Sunday
how's that sound
kids let's jump to July bright where you
going to be in July we miss you well
kids I'll be at the Chicago improv which
is actually in Schaumburg Chicago July
25th 26th 27th and 28th wonderful it'll
be hot in Chicago no all right man let's
get this show started shall we
all right this is the Bryan Callen Jill
and I have I'm very excited because I
have Elliott Hulse on on the phone here
and he is calling us I think you're in
st. Petersburg Florida right oh yeah
yeah that's right
from his from his gym where he trains
high school and college and sometimes
pro athletes to be you know better than
they can be so I'm but what I guess the
reason I wanted to have you on my friend
is less about the fact that you are an
expert in all things physical strength
and but we'll get into that but I I was
so fascinated I started listening to
your YouTube videos and just watching
them and by the way if any of you guys
want to know anything anything about
strength anything about recovery it a
thousand of the topics just just type in
Elliott Hulse
HUL SAE Elliott Hulse into YouTube and I
got to tell you man
I know you've been doing videos and
effort since 2007 and it really is sort
of a treasure trove of knowledge I mean
I love I know I always think of myself
as knowing a lot about fitness or you
know just nutrition and stuff there's
something about the way you present
things but I want to start I want to
start with what really captured my
imagination and one of the reasons I
wanted to get you on the podcast and
that was that you were talking to a guy
named I can't remember his name he was
going in the military and you base and
he said I'm worried about I can I'm
strong and I'm fit and I'm just worried
about my mental toughness and one of the
things you said that I have always
talked to other people about but not in
as clear terms as you did was mental
toughness is is by far something it's a
question of letting go and shutting your
brain off to stories real or imagined
about who and what you are and just
being in the moment and I want to just
kind of like maybe we can start with
that as a topic because it feels like in
some ways that's almost the whole deal
when it comes to trying to accomplish
something
yeah there's this such confusion about
sexuality in our culture and I say
sexuality might seem strange that I
would bring that up but there are two
animating forces in all in our lives
personally and in the universe and you
know if you go to the east a state
called like the yin-yang and you see
like the half of it black half of its
white a little bit of white in the
blacks and that contrast displays itself
in all areas of our life when it comes
to being a man right because really
that's what the question came down to
what our friend was you know I I'm a
tough guy but I'm going to show up
somewhere where there's even a tougher
guy maybe me spitting and screaming in
my face how do i man up and handle that
and what I ask them to do eventually
essentially was to become more female
right because basically I asked him to
yield and that yeah yeah to be tough to
be really tough to be really strong you
got to also be able to yield you've also
got to be able to be soft because how
many really really tough guys are
listening right now and they're like nah
fuck that there's no way I'm not
submitting to anyone or anything
well it's your sphere that's not
allowing me to do just that so I would
say that someone who has a capacity to
be a little bit more feminine is
actually stronger of a man than someone
who is way too overly welcome and as you
get older you realize in some ways this
notion of what tough is is so um
compartmentalized my you know that I
always use the extra the example of some
guys can fight anybody in a book you
know six guys in a bar but they can't
quit a job they hate they can't get out
of a relationship that's not fulfilling
etc etc so fear courage are our umbrella
terms that are very relative depending
on where you are but but but I I guess
what I love about what you're talking
about is you can step out of that
equation there is great strength in
surrender
and and and I love the way you couch it
in male/female terms because you're
right I mean that is what so many and we
have a culture that that prides
aggression that sort of you know esteems
the notion that you're you're a brick
wall and just batter batter through and
there there is a place for that in in
life but certainly I don't think you can
get to the next level and anything you
endeavour at without having more of that
yein energy if you will or more of that
female energy right you've got to just
embrace it
oh and absolutely every regard if you're
if you're talking in terms of training
working out or or anything physical you
gotta understand that your nervous
system your what you call your autonomic
nervous system part your nervous system
that does all the shit without you
having to think about it eating your
heart and digesting your food is broken
down in the same particular way there's
those two halves again it's funny how
those two halves just keeps showing up
back that contrast
you've got your sympathetic branch to
your nervous system and you've got your
parasympathetic branch of that nervous
system and the sympathetic branch is
that one that's adrenaline that's go
harder faster stronger hotter more
aggressive more male and it's you I mean
just imagine look at the world we live
in
everybody is going harder bigger faster
more and at the same time there's more
and more disease and sickness
dysfunction depression and it's because
we don't allow and this is language that
is going to be a bit more grounded for
most of the people listen listen
especially if you're into fitness and
exercise
we don't allow the anabolic branch of
that deal to happen feminine in soft
yielding resting digesting is all more
anabolic so because we don't use our
bodies and live our lives in a way that
stimulates more growth hormone
testosterone all the things that build
you up which are a byproduct of letting
go we end up having to use and what we
have to end up using synthetic steroids
so all the drugs and all diseases
disease that were experiencing a lot of
it is due to this imbalance between
sympathetic
and parasympathetic or too much yang too
much mail too much of question and not
enough softness hmm and and when did you
you know I wanted you that this is an
example of how knowledgeable you are and
just how you have a really good way of
sort of being describing the issue at
hand but when what was the seminal
moment when you sort of came to this
because you're a big strong guy who
played football on a high level you know
I mean you walk into a gym and you're
you're the automatic alpha male I mean
you're dead lifting most more than most
people and all that stuff but when when
did you so your life has been you know
around steel you're around a lot of you
know there's a lot of hyper sort of
masculine hyperaggression aggressive
energy in the air but when when was it
what happened how did you learn this
when when did what was the moment did
what did you read that were you exposed
to a teacher who taught you this what
was it your thing it easy for me to sit
here and say that we need to balance our
lifestyles balance the way we approach
everything in life but the fact is and
if you're anything like me you got to
actually like hurt yourself first before
any of this shit makes anything and I
yes he's so true man
it's so true you got to fail hard and
then you got to go what the hell is
wrong with me I think most change comes
from some form of crisis I mean oh yeah
right I mean you know when you just look
up and you go man this shit isn't
working I'm kind of fucked here and I
don't know where to go and and that's
those moments that that's why those
moments are so important to carry
through you've got to just recognize
those plateaus and recognize those dips
and understand it's a huge part of
becoming successful right I mean oh not
only yet man I crave it like you want to
have crisis you want that break that you
want that shit to happen because it
forces you to look at what you're doing
it forces you to adjust your behavior so
that you can continue to grow stronger
and move forward in life well a lot of
times again it's that fear we we are too
scared to subject ourselves to potential
failure injuries hurt and in that ways
we never approach any real challenges in
a
hmm yeah you don't you don't you take
shit to make a flower man I mean that's
that that's sort of I'm paraphrasing the
old Buddhist sort of saying I mean you
you just it is there is not a lot of
great lot the lugs the wolf at the door
is is luxury it is comfort you you've
got to stay uncomfortable right I mean
you even as a as a trainer you you have
to continue to confuse someone central
nervous system so that they continue to
grow am I right about that yeah oh yeah
absolutely there's no question about it
and the same applies to even the things
that I talked about again I don't ever
want to position myself and the person
you need to go to to learn what to do
my invitation is always get out there
and do something get out there and
experience life because that's the only
time that you put flesh on the words
that I'm describing right now that's
when the word becomes flesh when you
actually do this shit so I'm talking and
it's in full abstract it's all poetic it
all sounds like I might dazzle you with
my ability to describe this thing but
really the invitation is go do it
go do it that's right man I mean you
can't you can talk about fighting all
day til you get the ring and somebody's
hitting you in the face you're not gonna
learn how to fight the only way to learn
how to fight is to fight that that's the
bottom line and that's a metaphor for
everything man you want to be I mean I
was stand-up comic man you want to be a
stand-up comic you got I'm sorry you got
to perform I'll see you in 10 years I'll
see you in 10 you everything takes that
long it's and and I love that's the
other thing that I really kind of
gleaned - when you were like I hear
talking some young dude who's asking you
about steroids
and then he's asking you about this and
one guy wants to lose 100 pounds and
you're like listen man you got to start
thinking in terms of years this is not
oh this is not a you know 10 day
transformation that is all bullshit and
and and anytime you see anything like
that it's always a lie it is always a
lie any lasting change has become it's
got to become habit and and it seems to
me that you from what I would I you know
watch here your videos you are you're in
a large way you have solidified a
philosophy
ah that you have moored yourself into
you you have solidified not just a
physical a notion of physical philosophy
but a mental philosophy which seems to
make you such an effective coach and and
and trainer I mean that that's kind of
what I was drawn to you speak in these
sort of you know almost like you know
it's it I don't know but I feel like
you've read a lot of Joseph Campbell and
and the the the thinkers that certainly
influenced me as a young man so as I
hear you talk I go this dude this dude
is not just talking to your muscles he's
talking to the complete person and how
to approach how to approach success
you know over the long over the long
term oh yeah well it takes one to know
one
so obviously yes Joseph Campbell and fit
a big Park and I love this stuff Alan
Watts also Ralph Waldo Emerson and ah
fantastic fantastic yes
and and you brought up my man search for
meaning which I thought was great -
you're obviously a well-read guy and I a
lot of people lot of young men listened
to this podcast and I always tell them
how important it is how important it is
to read to immerse yourself and the best
has been thought and said that's so
important man because whatever you think
you've thought as somebody else has
thought about it as well and and on a
deeper level so oh absolutely why not
learn from the Masters I mean that's how
we got here the racist human being we
passed on stories of course it familiar
with Joseph Campbell so you know the
power of myth but we passed on wisdom we
passed on stories we passed on the
accumulation of experience from
generation to generation I think it's
only been perhaps the last hundred years
or so it definitely not any more than
two generations that we've abandoned the
wisdom of the the wisdom of our
ancestors
oh so many wait taste at home yeah
that's right that's right
it's so that's right we don't have I
actually think Eliot I don't think we
have a culture that makes us feel good
about ourselves I really don't know IIIi
don't think we have see so many so many
cultures even today and I grew up all
over the world so so I I didn't move to
this country until I was 14 but
the things that you you find whether I
was living in Pakistan or in India or
Saudi Arabia or Lebanon or or Greece
those cultures have been around for a
very long time and they come with their
drawbacks but they also come with
benefits and one of the benefits is that
when you grow up in a certain culture
and with with those very and cultures
are very resilient with strong lines you
you there is not a whole lot of
confusion about what your role is as a
man as a woman what your role is as you
have example there is a great deal of
emphasis on tradition and that's one of
the reasons tradition and ritual is very
important because it is a cornerstone in
the guide now you can step out of ritual
you can step out of you know whatever
mythology has been imposed on you and
maybe you should but certainly we pay a
price for not having any kind of a
cultural through line to guide us I
think in this I I notice I travel so
much in this country I notice how lost
people are especially young people
they're just not given any kind of a
manual or a guide save save a religion
like Christianity or Islam or Judaism or
whatever I mean but those things seem to
be a little bit too abstract for a lot
of people or there isn't there is no
longer the the infrastructure the
scaffolding to bring people through
their lives with those kinds of those
kinds of ethos and myths you know so
yeah absolutely I think one of the
things that we've done almost many other
things is the greatest science has been
with its ability to bring us the
technology and force to look at the
world objectively it has caused us to
adopt a paradigm where we not only
rightfully question everything but we no
longer retain the sense of poetry in
anything so we've got one into the
spectrum where scientists and the whole
idea that the world is purely matter
right which is fine because we're
playing with that now
that whole idea is just that it's just
an idea something we're playing with
there's nothing definitive because if
you look at where they're reaching now
in fire they're sorry they're coming
further and further back to where we
were before saying look we're not sure
what this is
we can't pin it down we can't name it if
we think we have it but then it
disappears it basically sounds and looks
a lot like what the ancients were
writing down when they described the
creation of the world the difference is
now so we've got that into the spectrum
you're talking by the way by the way
just a just that you're talking about
quantum physics here you're talking
about the subatomic level of physics and
string theory and stuff just for some
people who are might be a little
confused I think that's what you're
touching on the absolutely yeah how laws
on the quantum level sometimes are the
in the direct opposition to laws in the
ether we live in so there are two sort
of there at least two realities two
dimensions but keep quantum sorry right
yeah absolutely quantum physics and you
recognize that words are symbols so
they're using words to describe that
which in many times it's undescribable
so we've got that end of the spectrum
and that's a fun game to play with
recognize it look at it objectively
don't anyway and then we have the other
end of the spectrum where we've got the
ancients and we've got the religions of
old and the traditions associated with
it and here's where they messed up they
messed up because all those stories of
talking snakes and burning bushes and
things that literally do not make sense
on the physical plane why people don't
die and then come back again it just
doesn't happen still dying you're reborn
regardless I mean you can call it
whatever you want but it just doesn't
happen people don't walk on water the
problem is that we get too attached to
the content of the story and not
recognize the brilliance in the context
of the story what is that story trying
to tell the dissemble the symbolism
versus the the reality that which you
can measure measure with a ruler and
then and then the symbol the symbolism
of what it what it's sort of the
inspiration behind the story right
exactly so you've got to
you go too far either end of the
spectrum and they end up playing the
same game trying to be right and trying
to prove what they're saying is as
definitive and you can't get to that the
whole thing is still a dance and
everybody's trying to get to the end of
the dance instead of enjoying it well
man listen you know that's that's a
you're talking now like the romantics
you're talking now like those that had a
rebuttal to Darwin's notion of just
science the fact that we're just smart
monkeys I mean this is where Ralph Waldo
Emerson this is where Henry David
Thoreau and and William James and Henry
James all these guys came about the this
was their answer yes we believe in
science I think it was Henry James or
William James I'm not sure who said yes
yes perhaps we are we started as
protozoa and then became monkeys
hominids and then we branched off into
people yes yes I give you that in your
science I suppose that's true he said
but but there was something about that
monkey that inspired it to Greek there
was something in that monkey that
inspired it to do things for beauty's
sake create the Acropolis right right
Shakespeare Beethoven Mozart and all the
things that we stay alive for great art
beauty form symbolism there was
something that pushed that monkey to
create all these things that in in many
ways a culture considers its cornerstone
that that's you know he also said it's
like it's kind of like saying a human
being
it's kind of saying when you break a
human being down - it's just pure matter
as you're talking about that which you
can met just a scientific matter and you
know and you give no room for the other
four for that sort of intangible it's
like taking a guitar and bashing it into
60 pieces throwing it to the ground and
saying that's a guitar it technically it
might be a guitar but actually a guitar
is that mysterious strange box when
touched right makes beautiful musical
you know I mean I like I like living in
that universe I I prefer the mystery I
prefer the romance and I and I I think I
was drawn so much to your videos because
you clearly adhere to that school of
thought
I don't see how it could be any other
way I mean to take one way or the other
to move too far in either direction it's
you miss out so much why not both I
don't know why there aren't more people
that are arguing for both it seems like
you've got to choose a side and you got
to defend which one is right but when
you really boil well adapt to it it
begins at our conversation the beginning
of our conversation was about dualism it
was about feminine and masculine energy
it was about yin-yang and if you look at
even today I mean you and I are we are
able to talk to each other through the
technology of the digital age what is
the fucking digital age it's a 0 and a 1
it's all symbolized by this contrasts
with duality this is 0 & 1 you can't
have all ones and no zeros and expect
digital to work you can't have all day
and no night to expect lights to work
you can't have all aggression you can't
have all science and you can't have all
exactness and expect to enjoy appreciate
and yeah you're talking about here you
can't expect to be balanced expect to be
balanced
I think balance is you know a huge a big
word that we have to strive for I think
it's very very important you know well
that's real balance but yes who balance
like that
yeah yeah and and get Elliot here's what
I'm gonna say by the way on the podcast
I can't believe you've not yet got your
own show somewhere on a network and I
think and I'm gonna make a prediction
now I think it's going to happen for you
somebody's going to see your videos and
and and and you know and somebody's
going to do something about this because
um you know you just the way you speak
and just the things that you know I mean
you touch on too you do touch on that
duality on the physical and the
spiritual if you will I hate using that
word but you know in a way that's that
that seems to be what your strength is
what was your childhood like man how did
you how did you become somebody how'd
you become such a searcher and how did
you
new position where you actually change
people's lives which you clearly do it's
funny it started when I was in
kindergarten essentially you know since
the time I went into the world which I
know when we start schools when we go
into the world and we got to find our
place I began asking because other
people were asking Elliott what are you
you see so I grew up in a mostly white
suburban suburb of New York City and my
parents are both immigrants from Belize
and believes of the country where there
was a lot of race mixing so there were
the natives and then there were the
Europeans they came with their African
slaves basically everybody was screwing
everybody else gorgeous ha ha ha and it
comes out comes Elliott Hulse ladies and
gentlemen 250 pounds yeah so here I come
showing up at you know a school where
mostly white kids and they're a couple
black kids and they know who they are
they know what they are they know their
place and then I show up with big lips
and blue eyes whoa not a bad thing man
not a bad thing I couldn't figure out
what your race was either I was like
this guy is the composite man over here
you know and on top of the fact that you
you were obviously a very gifted athlete
I mean you played football you played d1
ball I played one double-a same times
University New York what position ah
funny man I went in as an undersized
nose guard and I won MVP I was Rookie of
the Year I led the team in sacks of the
fastest and strongest nose guard but I
was also about a foot too short for the
position I just happen to be able to
play because of my athleticism I'm built
like a running back right but in high
school I was never given the opportunity
to play on in fact so when I was in my
junior year and all the running backs
got injured the the logical thing and
the right thing that my coaches did was
take their frickin nose gunner and give
them the ball ha ha you are built like I
yeah you look it seems that your build
definitely friends a half pack you know
yeah so I ended up that season I ended
up leading the team in
and touchdown Wow but someone way it's
like let's play football yeah yeah yeah
yeah and did you ever have aspirations
to go pro it's funny let me backtrack
just for a moment even when people ask
me what did I play in football I just
don't know I never have a definitive
answer for what I am or what I do if I
understand I I do understand I
understand that it's kind of what you're
here for though man and and what give us
give us um you you mentioned Paul check
as one of your biggest influences and
teaching you how to eat Elliot I think
nutrition is a huge part of being
healthy and maybe you know the biggest
part in some ways of just you know being
a vital human being what who are who are
your gurus who are your nutritional
gurus where should be who should we be
reading what should we be eating well
Paul Paul is very interesting and
definitely a big influence on me because
he was the first person in sitted so
mind you you know I grew up asking
myself what am I
so at like h10 I'm reading philosophy
book by Apollo May and trying to figure
out holiday try to figure out who are
you you like man search for meaning when
you're 12 years old is is a byproduct
not knowing who you are but that's that
going on but I also had incredible
athleticism growing up and they just
always happen to be a part of me to
search for meaning as well as a search
for building a bigger stronger faster
body and when I met Paul check for the
first time he he was all about in his
strength it was a little bit how to
balance your body physically out of
train your muscles how to create create
correct muscle imbalances and then one
day you know this is as far as I knew of
him when I first started studying one
day he gets up and he starts talking
about God and he starts talking about
the universe and he starts talking about
and then he's like making the contrast
between the moon and the Sun our
autonomic nervous system and I'm like oh
my god this guy just blended my two
worlds too
get it he took everything that I've been
talking I'm thinking about as well as
the thing I love more than anything
which is training the body and he showed
me how it's one and the same your body
literally is your temple so you sold me
at that point
hmm Wow and what what do you I know that
you talked a little bit about eating for
your metabolic type I went out and
promptly read that book but what what
what what do you think all of us should
be eating is there is there something
all of us should be eating is there
something we should all are doing wrong
for the most part I mean what are the
things that you see most of your clients
doing wrong most of America do you have
a point of view on that or not or is it
all over the map nutritionally the very
first thing I see is people are
dehydrated people do not fucking drink
water I'm shocked at how many people it
being young athletes to adult suits
should know better come to my gym and I
look you know we start talking about
their nutrition that's like okay well
how much water do you drink eighty-five
percent sometimes more I don't drink
water well what's stopping you drink I
have more juice and coffee in the
morning or fill that Gatorade it and and
amazing what are you call sugar a sugar
and caffeine man Oh energy drinks that's
what most people the others yeah I had a
Red Bull today we woke a so but how it's
working strength already like water
that's usually the first one is thought
I don't know if I could talk to you
about organic food or metabolic type of
you anything is you're dehydrated
there's a made up of water yeah yeah
very very doctor water mm-hmm
yeah you a lot of people are not
dehydrated and a lot of people just
don't sleep a lot those are the two
biggest things that I when I talk to
people who really know their stuff that
those are the two biggest issues dude if
you're not sleeping in drinking water
they're nothing else I don't want to
talk to you about anything else yeah
good and what about what about you know
III is breakfast the most important meal
of the day or does it depend you know
with nutrition it's funny because you
read metabolic typing and we're all so
very different
basically the philosophy
is with regret and this is why metabolic
typing will never be a fad diet it will
never make a it will never be a
something that everyone's going to want
to appreciate and use because it takes
responsibility and I don't mean
responsibility in the way that we're
typically taught like you should and
shall not do it takes responsibility
meaning that you need to be able to
respond to how your body is behaving
based on the season based on your stress
level based on your oxidative ability
you know so there are people which would
you would call these people like slow
oxidizers that do well with our
breakfast they just you know they don't
eat breakfast depending on their stress
level depending on their menstrual cycle
depending on the position of the moon
the situation is such that breakfast
won't be that important and then there's
some people like myself at oxidizer and
it's like if I don't eat breakfast I'm
gonna be pretty pissed off and I know
it's not the best choice for me right so
the answer is yeah well I live in a I
live in a town where you know you're
either in the paleo or you're a vegan
I mean it's there's no real there's no
balance man that there are just
orthodoxies and if you know if you're a
crossfitter then you're doing the zone
or you're doing the Paleo diet and and
you're a fucking idiot otherwise and if
you're you know what I mean any of your
if you're on the other spectrum you're a
vegan because you know no other animal
drinks the milk of another animal and
there's all these orthodoxies that you
hear man in this very little wiggle room
we take everything to a goddamn extreme
in this country it's just it's just
incredible yeah no balance no fucking
balance you're a dumb dog you eat bread
you fucking idiot you know it's all uh
but it goes back to responsibility
nobody wants to take on stability it's
so much easier I was just talking to
this book with my own my coaches here
because you know people really just want
to be told what to do just do this and
the more the more specific you can be
about what they are supposed to do and
what they're supposed to think the more
comfortable they feel because there's no
need to think there's no need to pay
attention there's no need to be aware
just step in line and follow
my rule yeah it is crazy yeah there's no
need to gauge and to be feeling yourself
and be engaged with yourself in real
yeah I'm sorry
and then you well you're absolutely
right and then we have to we have to
defend that because to yield your
responsibility to give your
responsibility over to someone else is
it's sort of an act of sacrifice and
then you're vulnerable when you do that
and other people recognize it if you
know if they're aware and if you're
aware if you're consciously aware that
you know you just basically just gave
over personal responsibility of your
life to this idea or this person so you
become very defensive and you have to
protect that and that's how the cults
begin because it's like okay well now I
give the responsibility to the paleo
diet right and I don't have to think
anymore because if somebody asks me what
I am I am a paleo eater yes and from
henceforth I have to make sure that
that's defended because it it personally
identifies me now because I don't
identify myself I've allowed that idea
to identify me that's right there's a
very interesting thing that human beings
do it maybe it's just this culture I
don't know but people like to define
themselves along very strong lines and
that's usually a mistake I do think that
you need to know what you're willing to
fight for I think that's how you define
yourself to an extent that's where a
philosophy comes in that's where
principles come in that's where morality
and ethics come in but people I think
you just hit it on the nose and I've
never really heard it put that way you
are allowing I think you said an idea or
or a thing a thing where you have
brought into your life to define you
along very strong lines and and that's
that's when you miss out on a whole
bunch of other stuff Eliot give us give
people who want to take responsibility
give me three books on nutrition if you
add just three books to recommend what
would they be
the very person would be nutrition and
physical degeneration by Western price
and not because it's a diet book but
because it is probably the very last
probably the only
and very last study of what our
ancestors actually ate and the physical
ramifications of what that is in
contrast to what we eat today
doctor what's implies was a dentist back
like you know right I think between the
world wars you know in the early 1920s
or 30s and he noticed all of a sudden he
was a dentist for many years before that
did it all guy by then he noticed that
like all the sudden all my patients are
coming in with either the the adults
were having rotten teeth and or the
children were coming in with what at the
time they called facial deformities they
didn't exist back then today we call it
uni braces but back then it was very it
was very rare and it was and is starting
to become more prevalent like I've never
seen so many kids born with with
deformed faces basically faces that have
crowded teeth shortened palate and a
need for reconstructive measures to
straighten these teeth out and he knew
he had a hunch that this had to do with
the change in the way we started eating
around that time and he set out so you
know all the data to support that and
this was like okay this is what's
happening he made an observation and
then he set out to travel the world like
a wealthy doctor would do to study what
he called traditional societies
untouched by white man spoons and and in
what he meant by that was foods of
Commerce basically refined sugars and
grains mostly the denatured food that
you know basically make up most of what
you see in the supermarket today along
with poor farming Havoc's that are that
have shipped a lot of our quote-unquote
natural foods of the minerals that were
traditionally in them that you know the
way the creator made them to be so
anyway so he went first to the Swiss
Alps and he studied a European tribe in
the Loess Valley and these folks didn't
really get to partake of the white man's
food because it was so
deep in the mountains that their trucks
with cookies and crackers and jellies
and oils you know hard hydrogenated oil
couldn't make it up there so they had to
suffice by eating what they brew and the
majority of their diet consisted of
homegrown grains like very Hardy breads
that they would actually worship yep and
butter yeah
Black's with lots of butter tons and
tons of butter and these people were not
only beautiful and none of them had any
dental maladies their children's faces
were structured beautifully wide
sweeping palettes they were also happier
people and he started he did a lot of
x-rays and shit just studied like the
bone structure of the head and how it
affects the brain and shit like that but
anyway he went on to study a few tribes
in Africa he went to Australia study the
Aborigines he came and studied some
Native American tribes in the Seminoles
in Florida as well as Eskimos up in the
Alaska and he drew it up driving studies
he devised a set of principles Dietary
principles that he recognized completely
objectively is just what he saw there
were certain dietary principles that
were consistent with those tribes of
people that were happy healthy strong
and free from many of the diseases and
deformities that the civilized people
had right right all right yeah and okay
so that that that's that's another I
think Gary tab and good calories bad
calories takes a look at indigenous
cultures like that the Sioux Indian bond
to the Bantu belt in Africa and stuff
who the primarily eating you know a lot
of those people were just eating meat
and and we're very healthy I mean the
Inuit tribes in northern like Alaska and
those places where they basically were
living off the food that was available
to them certain grasses didn't grow like
barley and wheat and things so they had
to live basically off of animal protein
but the way they did it and the kinds of
animals that they were eating provide
them with all the sustenance they
needed you know but I love that I love
that the butter too we had Dave Asprey
on on who wrote who has a website called
the bulletproof executive and he talks
about going to the Himalayas and they
basically would create make a tea with a
I think it was the the Gurkhas or the
Himalayan whatever the tribe is up there
and they they would take yak butter and
put it into a make a tea with yak butter
and barley and it sustained them pretty
much all day long so it's it's stuff
like that it's just fascinating to me so
we got Weston Price we got Weston Price
who's who's the next guy well to take
what Western slice discovered and just
move a little further into breaking it
down scientifically there's a really
good book called biochemical
individuality again it's not a diet book
it looks into the roots of what human
were designed to eat and what he what he
shows you in this book is that it well
let's entitled black and the the two
main nutrients that price discovered
were available in all the healthy diets
or vitamin A and vitamin D they threw a
fat soluble vitamin so even tribes that
would eat mostly plant-based diets like
90 percent based diets they still went
out of their way to find foods typically
from the sea you know fish fish oil fish
livers things of that nature to eat and
especially to give to their nursing
lactating women and children Wow
so Wow yeah because that's how people
are being made right we're being made
through the sort the woman is the soil
woman is the earth and the man is the
seed we drop the seed enough now is good
imagine if that soil is depleted of
vital nutrition for the plant you
wouldn't expect the plant to grow no yet
we're dropping the people all the time
we're wondering like why our kids are
weak and depressed at the age of seven
yeah yeah I mean I also noticed how
unhealthy a lot of women are because we
live in a diet culture this sort of the
notion of low-fat high-carb or
high-fiber diet and
that there isn't a lot of scientific
evidence for and certainly women tend to
eat from what I've seen less not as
nutritionally you it's hard to find
nutritious food you know it we have an
industry that caters to basically the
corn lobby and and you know and and sick
chickens and and grain fed corn-fed beef
you know cows are ruminants they should
be eating grass etc etc etc it feels
like the way we in this country is a
form of madness as civilized measure as
we have it's mass madness I'm telling
you we are undernourished you know we we
live on sugar and refined carbohydrates
and packaged foods that you can sell
well and easily because they've got 15
different ingredients in them I you know
look Michael pons done this work on this
so I'm not the guy but yeah yeah so okay
so say so that that book once again is
biochemical engineering individuality I
wish I could remember the author's names
I don't have it here okay ah and and
third book and then finally the one that
you you mentioned which is a metabolic
typing the metabolic I think diet again
these are not these are not fun sexy
books with like beautiful women on the
covers and a step-by-step plan for you
to follow these are books that contain
ideas that force you to be responsible
about your diet most people read these
books in their eyes gonna glaze over and
they're going to fall asleep my
invitation is always to take
responsibility and responsibility for
you to be able to take responsibility in
anything you've got to have clear vision
you've got to be able to to be aware of
what's going on and what these books do
is they bring awareness to use that way
that way if you make the wrong choices I
always say I'd much rather make the
wrong choice knowingly and be ignorant
and fooled into choosing you know well
that that's right you want to see people
you want to read primary research you
know hard measurable science right
people who've done the work and looked
at what's worked in the past what what
are they having read all these things
what are the foods that you find all
human beings can't tolerate well what
are the what are the foods that all
human beings
right well I couldn't tell you what
every single person's going to tolerate
well simply because we're all so
polluted and damaged I mean the
digestive system if you're born with a
genetic makeup that is that says that
you should be able to digest assimilate
utilize cow's milk really well but when
you're four years old and you get a cold
and your mom gives you antibiotics but
it's a huge dose of antibiotics that
destroys all of your intestinal flora
now you're in a situation where your
entire physiology has changed and that
what your DNA has been structured to
allow is no longer the case I know for
for myself for example that I grew up
just like the rest of us eating you know
cereal and and and bread and like Wonder
Bread and all that shit and I was fine I
was cool until one day in college yeah I
got really I think I got really sick and
I took like so massive antibiotics and
all of a sudden I can't I can't digest
these foods anymore I'm getting stomach
aches headaches from farting all over
the place
and I'm like what's going on and it's
just it dawned on LaDonna me someone
taught me something gave me the idea
that perhaps your digestive system has
been compromised
due to using antibiotics and now you've
become intolerant to certain foods
well the advent a the advent of now
science it's really interesting to hear
these these scientists talk about the
fact that they're going to start
managing hour by hour bacteria the
bacteria in and on our bodies the way
you would manage an ecosystem and and
that we are made up mostly in fact of
bacteria which was fascinating to me and
when you throw that when you throw that
bacteria out of balance with antibiotics
sometimes you need antibiotics obviously
but when you throw it out of balance
you'd better take measures to restore it
somehow because you can really throw
yourself off for you know and do really
crazy damage and one of the one of the
examples is in fact yeah destroying all
the flora in your intestine and they're
not sure if your bacteria comes back the
way it was and when you take certain
antibiotics you know oh you're back so I
mean the whole the term anti
biotic anti-life if it kills you you get
literally kill parts of you and expect
to come back the way it was before sure
you know you'll regain something but
it's not going to be the same well then
again if you have chlamydia or gonorrhea
and you're in college and it burns when
you pee or syphilis god forbid take your
antibiotics dammit don't spread it but
right and that's why it's so tough to to
have a definitive answer for anything
anybody who's a zealot anybody who is
controlling convinced of any one
particular idea I think is a fool
because you've got these little say
never take antibiotics well yeah that's
easy to say and it's very romantic idea
and you did it you have all these the
backing the proof is to say that yes
your ideas valid but well again why
don't you get gonorrhea and tell me what
you're gonna do you know put rub some
cream on yeah good luck good luck okay
good luck take some tea tree when our
brother see how that works it's so true
man it's a complicated world it really
is man and I guess when you're training
somebody a lot of what you're doing is
just you're kind of watching them and
trying to figure them out because
everybody is their own puzzle yeah I
think the greatest gift that I can give
my clients and the people that listen to
me is the invitation to awareness just
pay attention to what's happening in
your body and happening in your mind
don't take anything for granted
just be aware be aware yeah which which
is which is being aware of not just your
aggressive side but your soft side as
well nurture both well you'll know
you're in balance even I mean you see it
but you're going to steal bad you know
if you're in valise you're the thing is
but the next invitation and it's the
kind of you know one of the same is just
be aware but also respect and honor
appreciate what you're what's happening
in you trust your body you know so many
times we go so far in one direction in
such an end unbalanced way simply
because we never listen to our body when
it
started talking to us mmm that's
interesting yeah that that they say that
takes a long time they say that people
yeah you gotta listen to your body eat
when you're hungry eat what you crave
sometimes it could be chocolate could be
meat whatever but what any kind of
religion
Zella tree is going to run you into
trouble man well you know what it is
it's the worship of false idols because
your idea is just that ideas are
abstract beliefs are abstract they're
just ideas they're just words they're
just symbols but we worship them not
realizing that it's our experience that
is teaching us you know so many people
talk about you know listening to God and
they think listening to God means
reading books those are the guys are
reading fucking books listen to God is
feeling what's happening in your body so
that you could respond appropriately man
I I just I can't believe you just used
it idolatry is it I I talk about this
all the time you just said it when
worshipping false gods is comes in so
many different forms it comes in so many
different forms and and that we live in
a culture that you know when you've got
a bone structure that cuts light well
people will look up to you even though
you've never accomplished anything in
your life I'm not gonna you know I mean
there are a lot of obvious examples of
that Kim Kardashian and things like that
whose I'm just using her I'm sure she's
a good I've met her a couple times she
seems like a nice person I'm using her
as an extreme example of that sort of
notion with a lot of young girls look up
to her just because she is shiny because
she represents something called glamour
or whatever that is and that is
worshipping a false god and and and
you're absolutely right God is is is
that voice inside think most people I
think we are we all know the answer I
mean I think for the most part if you
really stop and listen to that voice and
take responsibility like you said we all
know you most of the time people know
exactly what they're supposed to be
doing and the rest is just
procrastination and Men
and this procrastination take on
beautiful and wonderfully distracting
forms idols it's very easy to convince
yourself that you have to do this when
you should be doing that and all of us
have that struggle all the time and and
and and I'm always fascinated at how
you've got to constantly remind yourself
you need reminders and maybe reminders
is another word for inspiration but you
need inspiration you need reminders
about what the straight and narrow is
what the path is right I mean that by
the way which is one of the one of the
things I really appreciate about your
videos it seems to be what you're you
are in a role of service and you just
put this information up there and you've
been doing it for a long time and it's
just so refreshing because you're just
kind of giving it out to us you just
give it out you just started doing it
and before you know it people start
paying attention and I just I don't know
how I found you I just kind of happened
upon you by accident I see this this
jack motherfucker talking in these just
you know these bold kind of bold strokes
that sort of resonate they're just
resonating in my skull and I'm telling
you man we got to get you we got to get
you out there you're not a Tony Robbins
we're not gonna do that to you but we
got to get you out there so man because
you've got a lot to say what is it
you're a young man I think what are you
33 34 right now yeah 34 what is your
what is you you got a lot of life to
live what is your goal what is it that
you want to do are you doing what you
want to do do you want to just continue
to do this what what what what are your
what are your aspirations because it
seems like you kind of arrived but you
know for whatever that means
take taking this doing what I'm doing I
mean I'm in my river and my only
aspiration is to do it bigger and better
it's the same thing out being a coach
growing stronger and inspiring others
and answer it I'm a coach that's what I
do these ideas they you know they come
across as poetic and philosophical but
really to me they really feel practical
they really feel pragmatic they really
feel like you can navigate your life
based on this and
that's what I really aim to do not to
talk about it and that's why I answer
questions in my videos I don't I don't
stand up there with a chalkboard or I
don't pontificate what I'm doing is
showing you how this is practical
philosophy okay good you've got a
problem here here's an idea that will
support you I am a coach that's what I
do yeah but there's no question about it
man that you you really you really do I
mean answering those questions that's
exactly right you're not up there
pontificating at all you're you in the
way you say it I love you go I want to
share a perspective with you and you
share a perspective and that's that's
exactly what it is man you are you are a
breath of fresh air my friend you really
are and I hope if you come out to LA you
come out we can we can meet in person or
maybe I'll come down to st. Petersburg
and you come out to a show and and and I
can I can glean some of your knowledge
in the gym and show you how I could
deadlift over 220 pounds pounds oh yeah
we gotta work on that
I'm a weaker come on man I don't have
I'm built for dance I'm not built for
war the way you are come on you know I'm
very live that's cool man that's your
biochemical individuality make the best
of it there it is baby there it is
Elliott Elliott Hulse ladies and
gentlemen thanks for thanks for joining
us man I really appreciate it you're
special dude oh this was a lot of fun
thank you so much for reaching out it's
quite an honor
look man I'm telling you right now you
can come out anytime you want you can
get on come on on the show anytime you
want I just love having you wait we
could talk for hours I know that so but
I don't take too much of your time but
but you are you have a standing invite
my friend standing in tight boys well
you're in trouble so they got your phone
number now so this should happen please
take advantage of that anytime and you
you're you are there need to be more of
you my friend thanks for spreading your
love
and your knowledge you got it all right
man I'll talk to you later take care
take care that's a Italian house what I
would a great guy man I love that dude I
go to his videos and stuff and thanks
Lily Oh sounds fun I like it bryan
callen show about you've been listening
to the Bryan Callen show be sure to
visit Bryan Callen comm for information
about this episode as well as past and
future episodes you can follow Bryan on
Twitter at Bryan Callen and like him on
Facebook go to facebook.com slash Bryan
Callen comedy thanks again for listening
we'll see you next time