here's a question for my buddy Victor
who's crossing it in the world as a
warrior but he's burning himself the
fuck out let me explain
he goes on to say that Elliott for the
past six seven months I've literally
asked too much of my body and my mind
and now I suffer the consequences of not
being able to relax or stop for a moment
he continued continue saying that he
works for fifteen hours a day he's
training he's going to school he's
working two jobs and the success is
piling up because he says that he is
miles ahead with regard to income and
achievement then his three roommates
he's literally out there with his sword
and he is attacking the world and he's
bringing home the meats he's making big
shit happen the problem is he's not
finding a way to balance it and it's
starting to wear on his body it's having
problems sleeping breathing he's got
anxiety he somewhere describes how his
stomach is always in knots he's got
butterflies ultimately gonna get an
ulcer with us what I had and uh and he's
gonna break down it's not going to last
long and I don't know how old you are
young warrior I'm assuming you're
probably in your mid to late 20s you
know you said you you're live with some
roommates and stuff you're in the heat
of the warrior summer the problem is
that you're getting to a place where
bringing home the meat from your
endeavors is costing you more than it
should and you're starting to suffer
from too much heat too much warrior your
sword is getting pretty dull and you're
not taking enough time to sharpen it and
when I describe the sword it's a
metaphor for who you are your body this
is our weapon that we bring to the world
this is our machine gun this is our
sword this here everything that we do is
a byproduct of how strong our tools are
and your number one tool is not your
MacBook it's not your iPad it's not your
your jackhammer it's not your sword it's
you
you know take the metaphor and make it a
bit more literal and you ask a warrior
to a true soldier in the army that has
one of the best pieces of equipment in
his hands to destroy the enemy or
whatever the case may be but if he's not
there if he's not focused if he's not
centered if he's not grounded if he's
not breathing if he's not healthy
doesn't matter how strong the weapons
are and didn't matter what he does
because it's coming from a weak place so
you might warrior need to sharpen your
sword when I use this term warrior I
don't want you to get confused with the
literal translation of someone who is
who's out there killing people or taking
over lands or is a an agent for the
government I'm talking about 1/4 of
what's required to be a fully self
actualized and balanced man I've
mentioned this in other videos but I
really love this metaphor of describing
a balanced man as a king a warrior a
magician and a lover and what I'd like
to do briefly is describe each one of
those and then talk to you about where
you're receiving this in balance so that
you can continue to be a warrior but in
a much more intelligent fashion very
first thing is each one of those
represent something that you need to a
quality character that you need to
develop in yourself so that you can
continue to proceed in life with
strength with focus with concentration
with creativity with peace of mind with
joy and pleasure see these are all the
things that need to be an equal
proportion for us to really enjoy our
lives and to be self actualized to be
the strongest version of ourselves
beginning beginning with the king in
fact I'm going to leave the King to last
because it's one that I'm just
discovering what he's all about now and
I'm where I am in my life being an older
warrior you see I just turned 35 and
I've I've I've got the scars I spent a
lot of time and fought a lot of battles
had a lot of sleepless nights and ulcers
like yourself during my warrior stages
but I'm becoming a king and
becoming a very very good King and I'll
tell you why in a moment the lover is
the one that I'd like to begin with
beyond warriorship because I think many
of us understand what it is to be a
warrior and I've spent enough time I
think most of my videos come from this
warrior mindset because it's who I've
been and I think where most young men
who watch my videos are the lover is the
part of you that can come to know
appreciate and taste feel savor the good
things in life be it a warm embrace a
deep kiss and sexual intercourse with a
woman or enjoying the taste of a aged
Scotch enjoying a really fine wine
chewing on a piece of steak and allowing
it to melt in your mouth cook just right
savoring every piece of it listening to
music with your eyes closed and allowing
it to take you off to distant lands
because of just how yielding you are
into the sounds of the music I had a
great weekend this weekend where I
really experienced a lot of what I've
come to cultivate in the lover of me in
the lover that's within me I tell you
what I won't become the king but I'm to
become if I don't cultivate the lover a
king or a warrior who becomes a king
without his lover becomes a tyrant and
he burns himself out and he destroys the
worlds or his kingdoms around him part
of what I experienced this weekend which
was my birthday weekend my 35th birthday
and I actually posted some pictures and
videos let me share them with you really
quickly I posted this picture where you
see I'm wearing a t-shirt that says
success die for success I also posted
two summons my warriors I said to all my
warriors out there what do you pick
when you place your sword down pointing
to the fact that beyond just exerting
yourself and fighting for everything
that we want to thin nail blood sweat
and tears you've got to pick up
something else
every once in a while you've got to put
down your sword so that it can be
sharpened on its own
your sword sharpens itself if you care
for it you put it down and relax for a
moment and pick up something else and I
picked up this other I put up this other
picture where I'm smoking a really good
cigar that I enjoyed and I'm sipping on
a twelve-year-old scotch
now if you would have asked Elliott
Hulse the warrior even a year ago
probably you know 18 months ago about
cigars and scotch
I'd say fuck that fuck you I'm too busy
I'm picking up my sword I ain't got time
for that
you see I gave up all pleasures I still
don't even watch TV I don't watch TV I
don't watch movies I don't know watch
sports
I don't engage in most of what people
find entertaining or pleasurable because
I think mostly I'm more eclectic I
choose things that I can come to
appreciate because of Who I am I tell
you what I enjoy good cigar good music
there's another thing I experienced this
weekend and I put a picture up of which
I'll share with you now is my good
friend Shawn Harper playing some music
for me by a fire and I swayed to his
music and I enjoy that fire and I smoke
my cigar and I was in full lover mode at
that moment I know it sounds crazy when
you've got two swords in your hands and
you've got the sweat dripping off your
chin you've got scars on your body and
blood dripping down your eye so ever
imagine closing your eyes swaying to
some music sipping on scotch and smoking
a fine cigar but you've got you at some
point and sooner rather than later begin
to engage in the things of the heart
things of the lover because if you don't
you will be an imbalanced King because a
king with no love destroys his kingdom
he burns himself out
he destroys his kingdom because he can
appreciate the love that comes with
everything that he spent all his years I
spent a decade I call it about a decade
I'm 20 I was 25 I'm 35 now it's taking
about ten years for me to become a king
I'm just learning what it requires to
become a king and I'm gonna continue to
expand my empire I'm going to continue
developing the strength as a king
warrior lover and as a magician as I
continue to progress as I continue to
meet and collaborate with other kings
and their kingdoms and continue to take
over my world but it won't happen if I
don't set door down on the sword and I
don't pick up a scotch and you have to
do it now I'm not saying you've got to
pick up scotch in a cigar but whatever
it is that allows you to relax and enjoy
yourself a lot of guys commented in that
in that picture that I described earlier
but they like to smoke marijuana a lot
besides just being legal illegal I can
totally dig I understand why because you
get to put down the world for the moment
some guys pick up video games I
understand I've ranted about against
video games because I think there tends
to be a you get lost in it but if you
can use it just as a moment for pleasure
pick it up listen to good music not
mindless shit that the radio plays and
you listen to simply because it's on
choose the type of music you listen to I
invite you to look into classical music
get a learn to appreciate good music
classical music I personally enjoy Bob
Marley reggae a good country song and
when I'm in warrior mode it's usually
jay-z jay-z is one of those warriors who
knows how to be a king right now
that's how I develop the lover in me
your magician which I don't want to
spend too much time on at this moment is
the part of you that has to develop a
particular skill that will allow the
warrior to do the work that he does you
see for example a part of my magician is
making these videos and I have to
continue making these videos or else my
midget magic skill my another way to
describe it is my wizardry gets weak and
a warrior with a sword and no wizardry
no magic that he could bless the world
with and take take care of you know his
kingdom with his useless you're just an
angry now here check this out if you
don't spend time developing your skills
and abilities in your craft you don't
spend time developing your love and
appreciation for the finer things in
life even if it's just a beer on a
Friday night cold beer on a Friday night
pair of jeans that fit just right
Zac Brown and you go from being a
warrior to what is ultimately the the
natural progression for a warrior into
becoming a king you're going to be a
sick sad depressed imbalanced king who
will have a heart attack a divorce his
children won't respect him and
ultimately his kingdom will fall apart
you've got to think balance in the in
this regard and right now it's a matter
of developing the lover in you I said
this once before and I truly mean it and
it means more now for you than ever and
I've come to embrace it
most most recently over the past year
and it's a part of the reason why it
seems like Elliot changes and fluctuates
and it's like one thing one day and one
other thing another day because you're
constantly reinventing yourself based on
who you're becoming and the
circumstances you now found you said
find yourself in and you couldn't have
said this to me when I was lifting
stones and and
attacking the world through straw man
and becoming a professional athlete and
building my business and building my
family because it didn't make any sense
but I'll say this to you jot it down put
it in your pocket and pick it up later
or watch this video later and you'll
come to understand you've got to become
a pussy to become a stronger man a
warrior needs to become a little bit of
a pussy to continue to keep his sword
sword sharp and so that he becomes a
balanced King because ultimately that's
where you're going my friend put down
your sword for a moment breathe pick up
a cold beer sit in a rocking chair have
a good conversation with a friend chill
the fuck out and you will grow stronger
because of it done