got an interesting question from our
buddy Nick he is kind of a witty brainy
dude and he says he's somewhat
good-looking he calls himself a seven
out of ten
but anyway his real gift is his
intellect and his wittiness and because
of that he can attract to him very witty
intellectual girls right these happen to
not be the hottest girls but he really
knows how to work his way into this type
of woman this is his description
you know brainy witty type girls very
easy for him to be with them now the
thing is he finds in his neighborhood in
his town right there are these types of
girls that he can easily create an
abstract sexual relationship with do you
see what I'm doing here you're you're
the foreplay that you're having with
them is with their mind that's why he
describes like you know they'll talk
about political things and giggle or you
know poetry and stuff like that and he
gets them real open with his head this
is all very abstract it's all happening
with words and ideas right that's the
type of person you are it's kind of the
type of person that I am and your
foreplay is all abstract it's all words
and ideas now the problem is he says
he's 17 years old and he says you know
that's great no and I'll probably have a
wonderful relationship with a smart
witty girl and we'll have you know a
very responsible good life together
but the thing is I want to have sex with
the dumb witless women basically says
ones that are really hot and dumb that's
what describes it I won't have sex with
hot dumb chicks and for the life of me I
cannot get through to these these you
know knuckleheads so he tries the same
abstract approach with the poetic girls
with the dumb hot chicks and they're
like there are faces glazed over in
their life and I guess they go watch
honey boo boo or something like that but
anyway the point is you want to have sex
with these chicks but you can't get
through what you've got to understand is
that you're playing on two ends of the
spectrum one is very male and in mind
you the women that you're attracting
through your abstractness through your
spiritual qualities or thinking
qualities have more of a male quality to
them and you guys you play with
each other on that on that field the
other girls are a bit more in their
femininity right and it doesn't mean
that femininity is it's dumb and and
masculinity is brilliant its masculinity
is a bit more abstract it's more ideas
it's more thinking it's more big picture
or femininity is more grounded it's more
earthy it's more the feminine energy is
more sexual right because it's closer to
being animal like it's more human per se
more fleshy and what you got to do is
the other approach that type of woman
from the flesh you got to approach her
with your sexuality you have to approach
her with your body where this foreplay
is abstract this one has to be physical
so you've got to get physically closer
to these girls you could probably like
have great foreplay over the phone with
these chicks but these girls we actually
I have to actually like get close like
she's got to feel your manliness she
needs to feel your body
she needs to smell you she needs you
need to put your hand on her when you're
talking to her you need to show her your
body this type of woman right and you
call her dumb but you know it's not
always the case she's just more into her
femininity which is you know it's kind
of rare in a society that that you know
praises masculinity to such a great
degree will be far more opened up it
will be far more attracted to you if you
approach her physically with physical
energy with sexual energy that arc of
Attraction is not going to happen in the
abstract it's going to happen on the
ground touch her get close to her let
her smell you those things are far more
important they're more visceral than the
ideas that you share with the other
types of chicks good luck