hey what's up guys very first thing I
want to do this morning is talk about
how excited I am for this weekend those
you who know that it's a strength camp
challenge coming up on Saturday you also
probably know that they're going to be
about 6,000 spectators traveling from
all over the world to join us here in
Florida for the Shrek cap challenge 2015
second annual and we've also got 200
competitors were giving away over
$10,000 in prizes and we're holding were
throwing is you don't whole shit like
this you fucking throw it a giant
after-party at Jackson's and Tampa which
is one of the biggest most beautiful
venues here in Florida so I am overly
excited to watch the competitors battle
it out meet many of the spectators and
party up with the YouTube celebrities
who are going to be here to race us all
with their presents awesomeness and
party skills so those of you who are
gonna make it excited to meet we'd meet
you meet up with you and those who are
within a 12 hour drive of Florida get in
your car and get here all the
information you need is down below you
can click the link about the strength
camp challenge and you can watch one of
the videos I put up on my strength camp
channel yesterday inviting everyone to
our afterparty and even if you can't
make it go watch that video because it's
a lot of fun and I talk a lot about the
the people who are going to be attending
the party and a little bit about the
history or the strength camp challenge
so I'm happy to provide that with you
now part of my letter today revolved
around the gratitude that I have for the
people in my life particularly those who
helped make the strength camp challenge
and everything associated with it a
reality and you could read about that
down below and you know it's it's always
a good idea I want to say it's tradition
to say thank you to people who have
supported you in your and making your
dreams a reality
all right you know the fact is that
nothing that we create in life nothing
that we have in life nothing experience
in life life in it
self it's never experienced by ourselves
below no man's an island team and as
much of a starch self-reliant individual
you might think you are we really got to
step back every once in a while and
realize that nothing that we have comes
just from us you know we like to pat
ourselves in the back sometimes and you
know especially if you if you listen to
a lot of rap music you know artists to
talk about I did it me I was mine I
don't need anybody help block gets on
you fools you know shit like that which
is cool it's fun it's entertaining it's
poetry but the bottom line is from the
time your daddy dropped the seed in your
mommy soil you have been the
conglomerate of every soul you've
experienced them in in this life one of
the things we tend not to do one of the
things we almost throw into the shadow
or have disdain and animosity towards
are the people who shape us through I
don't want to say negative experience
but experiences that we would rather
have not had at the moment what I'm
talking about is people that may have
heard you in your life I'm talking about
people who ever may have doubted you in
your life people who may have left you
laughed at you anybody who seems to have
been a detractor or an opponent to you
becoming a stronger version yourself
it's very easy to cast them into the
shadow say fuck those people I don't
need them
there's nothing they're no good they're
useless and I'm better off living like
never seen them ever again we could we
could believe that we can make that a
reality but the fact is whether we like
to acknowledge it or not all those
negative experiences all those people
who have hurt us ignored us laughed at
us and given us pain in our bodies as
we're trying to climb our ladder towards
the strongest version of ourselves are
critical these are very important people
in your life and you know I like to
think back at some of the
teachers and some of the coaches some
so-called friends that I've had growing
up and the mean things that they've said
to me mean things they've done to me um
a lot of the things that for many years
I was very resentful and held a lot of
animosity towards them for I now realize
needed to be there and I needed to have
them and I'm grateful for them because
they shaped me all the people no matter
how horrific the abuse they may have
laid in your life no matter how much
heartbreak they may have brought you no
matter how much of a detractor or a
naysayer or a laugher at you they were
they contributed to the character that
you carry today that makes you who you
are that makes the world you look at and
experience what it is now you might not
be happy with what you see but that's a
different story
when you look around your life and if
you find that there's only frustration
that comes up and a lack of gratitude
that's a choice no matter how dire
circumstances are we can always choose
gratitude we could always choose
happiness joy pleasure and peace if
you've read or if you've read Victor
Frankel's work man's search for meaning
you understand that even in the depths
of severe imprisonment stripping of
dignity and slave labor you can still
find peace and happiness now I can't say
it gonna be easy I can't say I'm gonna
find it the minute something like that
happens to me but in retrospect
oftentimes we can look back and say damn
good thing that teacher doubted me good
thing that girl dumped me good thing
that Coach didn't think I had what it
took because today things are fucking
awesome and if it weren't for those
people it might not be the way it is
right now so
I'm supposed to have my phone with me
there's a quote from Ralph Waldo Emerson
that I want to share with you guys it
kind of wraps up this whole idea that
essentially when we step back and look
at our lives right and I'm 36 years old
so I can look back at like maybe the
past 10 years right but it'll continue
to happen right as you grow older as you
evolve as you're growing wisdom and
experience you can kind of look back and
say me you know all those things that
were bad they're not so bad after all
all right
they say hindsight is 20/20 I'm gonna
instead of trying to go get my phone I'm
gonna try to paraphrase Emerson's quote
here he says something to the effect of
life like a train is a string of
multicolored beads all right so now that
sounds strange right what the hell is
this guy talking about life like a train
if get about a train has many different
compartments compartments right they got
many different cars on a train I mean
you could have 100 cars in the Train he
says life is like that train if you
think of that train in each individual
car as a multicolored bead there's a
different colored bead raised one of
them and life is the passing through of
each one of these cars that offer us the
cue of the color and the view that we
see outside the window of it and it's
not until much later that we can look
back and realize the beauty of the
string of beads that has become our
lives so I share this with you today
because I'd like to extend an invitation
this weekend if you're not hanging out
partying with us to look back on maybe
the past year look back at and it might
be too close I know it's it's been just
enough time for me to make sense and
reconcile some of the experiences I've
had over the past year
there's you've been following me know
that it's been kind of a roller coaster
ride and in a year is kind of enough to
look back and put things in its place
and say hmm you know good thing I had
that pain in my life good thing I had
that fresh
and confusion and fallout in various
acts areas of my life
good thing I'm growing stronger and
breaking omelets breaking eggs to make
an omelet and say what I mean
so look back a year this year 2015 in
review if you will
I always review my years at the end of
the year we're getting close to the end
and even perhaps look back at the last
phases in your life if you're coming out
of high school if you're coming out of
college if if you've got children if you
get you whatever the case may be look
back the past fit at the last phase
phase has come in many different sizes
right a phase could be one year a phase
to be 5 years but look back at those
multicolored beads and do your best to
cultivate some gratitude and say thank
you for those things that have happened
although they were painful at the time
which have ultimately brought more gifts
blessings and pleasure into my life
today if you look hard enough you'll
find the silver lining in every one of
those gray clouds or you'll find the
beautiful colored hue outside the window
of your train done