fellow publisher friend of mine in the
fitness industry writes a blog all about
how to get the lean Hollywood look
that's his position he writes books
writes blog posts about how to be lean
and sexy like the people you see in
Hollywood so he says things like don't
squat don't deadlift don't lift heavy
for the lower body because it'll make
your waist thicken you're not going to
look like Brad Pitt in Fight Club that's
his position and he does a wonderful job
serving the people that enjoy his
information because he helps them look
like Brad Pitt and Fight Club but
obviously some of the things that he
talks about is diametrically opposed
completely different than the things
that I talk about because I serve a
completely different niche I train
baseball players football players power
lifters strongmen people who want to
actually lift heavier weights increase
their squats increase their deadlifts
get thicker waist so they can handle
more weight and smash the shit out of
people in their sports so when he says
things like don't squat and deadlift a
lot of the people that watch my videos
or read my my blog will say this guy's
out of his mind it does make any sense
well he and I get along really well
because we're both serving people in the
way they want to be served although very
different his people love him my people
appreciate the things that I have to say
so it was just very interesting and fun
to see my mitt my name mentioned on his
blog the other day he wrote a blog post
about why squats and deadlifts are not a
good idea and at the end of the blog he
says hey but my friend Elliott Hills has
got legs the size of size of tree trunks
they work for him if that's what you're
into then fine I thought it was cool so
I said I posted it on my Facebook wall
just giving him a shout-out for giving
me a shout-out thanks dude for
mentioning me on your blog I appreciate
it well anyway after posting it on my
blog I went to sleep I woke up the next
morning and they were obviously about 45
different comments about how this guy is
a nut and Elliot how could you ever be
associated with somebody he says don't
do squats and deadlifts one of the
comments was hey Elliot you look like an
idiot by having your name mentioned on
this blog so the very first thing I
wanted to do to address that comment in
particular and it doesn't and I'm not
reaching out to the person who put that
because he's just expressing a sentiment
that needs to be addressed and this is a
sentiment that pervades all of society
that we should do our best to not look
like idiots very first thing that I want
to offer to that sentiment not to that
person is that if you think after
watching my videos I've been making
videos for five years if you think that
I'm concerned about looking like an
idiot then you have not been paying
attention the second thing that I want
to offer in this video is number one
permission because that's what we're all
waiting for aren't we we're good little
boys and girls who have been walking on
the line hand in hand following step by
step all the rules in the book ever
since our parents and teachers have been
conditioning us to do what we're told so
I'm going to give you permission because
for the most part 90% of people are not
going to act unless someone says yes
you're free to act Elliott Hulse is
giving you permission to step outside
the bounds of the mental slavery that
you're holding on to that was imposed on
you by your parents the teachers society
and all the institutions at large
they want to keep you mediocre bland
vanilla a square person in a square hole
I'm giving you permission to be an idiot
for once now I'm not saying go out and
drunk drive and get into an accident
what I'm saying is express something
creative be who you are from the depths
of your heart regardless of what anybody
else thinks because they're going to
call you an idiot they're going to call
you weird they're going to call you
eccentric they're going to tell you
you're wrong
they may even chastise you to the point
where you end up be feeling like a
criminal you're breaking all the fucking
rules all their rules all their
conventions I'm giving you permission
because those days of step by step
follow the line get a good job get into
a good school get a retirement pension
are all
over my friend it's the age of
creativity if you're still following the
rules in waiting for permission you are
going to crumble just like the
institutions around us our economy is
cut is crumbling the institutions that
educate us are crumbling the old style
of corporation and business model is
crumbling and the way you've been
conditioned the mindset that you have
the paradigm through which you proceed
your entire life is crumbling before
your eyes and that's why you're becoming
obsolete it's not because there's not
enough jobs it's not because the
government isn't creating jobs it's
because you're stuck in an old mental
slavery that has nothing to do with the
new age that is currently upon us that
most of us don't know it yet it's all
about being unique being brave
courageous being creative bland vanilla
is done mediocrity is done those days
are over and you're going to die with it
if you don't stop following the rules so
not only am i giving you permission but
I'm going to give you an invitation
today go out and do something idiotic
ignore everybody else's rules for you
and create your own rules we're a
dynamic race the human beings we're ever
evolving regardless of what religious
tell you we are growing we're becoming
be a part of that change instead of the
fucking anchor like most people Elliott
what
[Music]