[Music]
videos about it okay you know
instructional Fitness is just that you
rent it out so it's like the best of all
worlds thank you pretty much all it's
actually how do you maintain that
confidence you've had you have a
presence where you know automatically
you command respect how do I get to that
point where I'm like that and if you
seem to have it and I don't know if you
developed it over time or if you
sometimes don't feel that way but how do
you you know have that contract I think
it's a great thing you know because no
matter no matter who encounters you they
have to respect you even if they don't
like you but this that thing that being
sued is like you know what this guy is
you know so how do you get
do you remember can't clean up so right
away I'm leaving all right these guys
give a dude and I have to like pretend
like I know what I'm talking about
so part of it is its nature I mean
nurture you know it's like those kids
and if you leave my little brother
together to do what I want to do by it's
kind of like position myself because I
was out a little bit but there's a sense
of responsibility that I think we've all
had and today more so than ever we were
living I don't think we realized just
how tumultuous how much change is
happening not so much on a physical
plane because it's like it's obvious
what's happening you know if you look at
the empire that we're spreading as a
nation if you look at that how many
hungry people there are compared to how
many people are living in ridiculous
like stupid well there's so much
contracts available but I think at a
spiritual level I think the deep
primordial level the DNA buddies that
termite Ibiza loosely the DNA of the
human race is evolving rapidly right now
and for that
Lucian is information oh my daddy's so
excited I think that house information
is changing the human race and deep
primordial level because from the dawn
of mankind the sharing of idea is
through pictograms pictographs
calligraphy has always been the most
highly praised of all and most valuable
of all skills and knowledge the ability
to read see me all breeds would take the
grandeur but I heard you give syllables
in the case and hundred years ago was
like that's not okay I read a book was
it the book that I gave you 50 by um
Paulo Coelho and in it the book is about
the prophet Elijah goes on so on and so
forth there are lots of historical
references in the book and talks about
the development of this new technology
that will literally change the world
that the powers to be the religious
support of the powers to be it wasn't a
different agenda that is that did not
want this technology to leak and they
were doing everything that they could to
stop it out they were killing people
they were erasing entire tribes and
doing whatever they could to stop this
technology that was spreading because it
was so pounced and they call this
technology the alphabet right because
prior to the alphabet there was there
were so many different languages what
the alphabet did was it kind of took
everything and brought it into one one
place where all of the different
languages could sort of come together
and there was some symbol to represent
what they wanted to say right and and it
was that hard throughout the course of
time up until the datum to this day it
is gone from keeping the out
down two books are only available to
certain people and know what the others
are not allowed to read - I watched
something like a History Channel that
were the printing press was first
developed that to the ideation in China
and a guy that you're creating the first
printing press to the books that were
easily distributed to the fact that the
American Revolution was started by a man
probably literally eyes like pen common
statutes is a book that was written by
Thomas Paine literally sparked the
American Revolution penny that night I
can't like the public fucking feather
and then use the printing press to
create you know hundreds of copies of
this thing the horseback
give me the rabbits of thirteen colonies
but not everybody reads somebody anybody
know how to read
they've gotta find somebody to fucking
read to get the book and then I'll go to
the church and even the word for the
town center and reading so the people
would sit there and go oh it's a
powerful idea to today where we go it's
just you got something in assailant we
don't know just the world look at what's
happening in northern Africa in the
Middle East these countries that the
revolutions that's why you know when you
buy this week they helped me to
basically censor the internet the world
was like shut the internet down we're
different than trying to get out there
witness they want to shut the internet
down but good world I don't want to be
able to say do she now you guys are fun
because he is are the power that are in
our hands now and it's available at such
a ridiculously back rate
and it's fucking shaking up and
exploding because of the internet comes
back to what I'm selling able to be so
confident because I have a deep sense of
responsibility to get whatever it is my
ideas tonight I'm not married to my
ideas I'm not religious about my ideas
but I know that there's that I can
impact people with my words and ideas
because I'm shocked at times I meet my
brothers and we have a conversation so
we take for granted a lot of things that
we don't know babies in our DNA when we
talk to our parents from the jungle
maybe it's jungle now I don't know but
when we talk to people like that you
know people don't know this you know and
then I get feedback from you guys
through comments stuff like Ellie
changed my life with that one thing like
I don't know how's that possible
so I feeling a responsibility that
regardless of what anybody else thinks
because there's only dissenters right
they killed Jesus
all right the guy just say coming love
each other he said don't worry about the
fucking government just love each other
but you know they kill his ass because
it's got to be now you just tell my
bunch of people in his neighborhood so
there's always what we do they hate you
and you've got to get over that because
you know how important what you have to
have you're questioning your very
powerful man that's a questionnaire
because the question says what who is
what leads us down paths to wisdom but
has Socrates become the wisest man top
Socrates was told that he was a wise man
it is in the city he basically said nah
fuck that I not figure this out he
wasn't he questioned
and I guess it was like an Oracle or
something totally you know why is this
man in the city he was like let me think
about that that's how powerful it was if
you never anything about Socrates it's
because he does not settle question
question question question question
create a credit question question
question powerful man powerful ideas
doesn't matter what you look like what
you sound like how certain people
respond to you is your fucking
responsibility but the skin that you
live in is only worth you getting out
and sharing your message so it's not
like it's real nice
what Elliot does is real nice that's
really fucking cool I wish I can do it
is you have to do that it's your
responsibility live in this day in time
you live in the most powerfully
transformative time and of course I make
sure that when it's it's powerful and
you're just going to sit around watch do
you like worry about like people don't
like me cuz my skin people don't like me
because I'm good looking up it's not
about you I think that's a big part of
it to make it over it's not about you
it's not about me hey it's about these
words have taken power of their own
that's why information is so powerful
that's why what we do is so powerful
because when you unleash word and you
reach the truth they literally have a
power of their own I was telling
croissants so Amelia on Facebook today
with a line it was a picture of a lion I
forgot whose quote it was but it said
the truth is like a lion the mini zoom
Unleashed when you unleash it into the
heavens itself it doesn't need to be
defended
something like that it's like only July
is like
flying like lions she's going to take
care of itself when you move into the
tree is literally like a lie
it's going to go and tear shit up
because man who you are
you