questions from a heavy-metal Baga bond
I'm going to read it here or paraphrase
basically he wants to know why is it
that he can't put the skills that he's
developed over the years to any good
right he goes on to say that he recently
graduated from university with honors
and economics yet he can't find a decent
job he plays the guitar relentlessly for
the past eight years yet he hasn't been
able to put together a band to use those
things he wants to do and when working
out for three or four years he's getting
stronger but he's not putting the the
new strength to any use I want to
approach this probably a little
differently than what you would expect
because you're probably wanting to hear
me say just get up and do it just go and
do it just go and do everything that you
set out to do but I'm going to invite
you to be at peace with what you've
achieved up until this point right and
let go of the neurotic idea that we
always have to do something we always
have to achieve something be somebody be
of some particular use in the world
right I said these things and I'm just
offering a different perspective
something that maybe will be resourceful
to you and this time it's good enough to
be you and to partake of all that life
has to offer
ie learning new skills playing music and
building up your body
those things are ends in and of
themselves you know what I mean so
people say there's a means to an end so
basically you're looking for the end
then the means is I'm going to school
the end is I'm going to get a job the
means is I'm working out so I'm going to
have more muscles so that I can get more
girls right the means is that I'm
playing the guitar and the end is I'm
going to be in the band but if you look
at it this way the way I'm inviting to
look at it you'll see that the means is
the end studying in school and this is
the thing with which school in education
because it's gotten so fucked up we look
at education as a certificate that you
need to get so that you can go and do
something when education really is the
development of your character you
yourself because you want to be educated
you educate yourself because you want to
fill yourself with new things brand new
ideas and this feels good you play music
not so that you can get to the end of
the song you don't play music so that
you can reach an end you play music
because music is beautiful and soothing
to your soul you play music because you
love to play music you lift weights not
because you're going to get a girlfriend
because you look better with more
muscles you lift weights because you
love the feeling of the pressure against
your body you love the way it feels to
lift up heavy weights you do the thing
that you love to do because you love to
do it not necessarily because it's going
to get you somewhere what I would invite
you to do is to relax and be at peace
dude I know I sound really like a real
liberal and Buddhist lately and and
maybe that's just the mood that I'm in
but I think that we've got our
priorities all screwed up we have these
neurotic holding patterns and this Drive
that makes us very unhappy we never
reach our happiness because we never
know how to be with the thing that we're
doing play your guitar dude you look
enjoy playing the guitar immerse
yourself in the playing of that guitar
because you love to play the guitar I
put up a video not too long ago on my
strength ology blog of Alan Watts
talking about doing the thing you love
to do not because of the money not
because of the end but because it's in
you to do this thing and if you fully
immerse yourself in something that you
love you're going to get good at it just
out of pure love you're not going to be
crappy at playing the guitar or lifting
weights if you love it because you can
put all your heart and soul into it and
then what's going to happen is you're
going to become an expert and you'll be
in high demand you won't have to go
looking for a band band will come
looking for you because you're so damn
good at playing the guitar when you
start playing that guitar it's almost
like your soul leaves your body and you
just become a guitar playing spirit it's
just it will take over
anybody who knows who's played sports or
does anything of any repetitive fashion
practices recognizes that there's a
point when you don't have to think about
doing what you're doing because the
nervous system I said soul and spirit
but basically takes over because you're
so good at it get good at the things
that you're doing for the sake of the
things that you love and that's good
enough Elliott said what
you