hey whats up guys yesterday we spoke
about the arduous and sometimes long
time it takes between where we are and
where we want to be in other words
reaching your goals sometimes takes
years I know a lot of us in our
fast-paced culture want things now but I
gave an example based on my own
experience about how it took me five
years of working consistently self
sacrifice sometimes it was worried out
in fear on my journey to gaining over
million subscribers on my strength camp
youtube channel I showed you a graph
where it seemed as if the Sun would
never rise and for years it didn't until
boom there was a skyrocket in subscriber
shitting I think that graph just
exemplifies one of the principles of our
journey of our heroes journey becoming a
stronger version of ourselves and today
I wanted to talk about one of the
elements of your journey but before I
get started just wanted to share some of
the ideas that I spoke about it my grow
stronger experience this weekend
especially as it relates to the hero's
journey and why I always use that as a
map or a metaphor for your own personal
growth and for my own personal growth
you see the hero's journey pattern in
all types of epics all types of
mythology and you even see it in the
most popular movies in pop culture it
seems to be a archetype or recurring
pattern of how human beings evolve and
at the grow stronger experience I also
likened it onto or use the example of
cell mitosis and how a cell goes from
being one being by itself being calm
cool collected everything's all right to
the process that allows or creates
turbulence or chaos within it remember
this from biology class it met
interphase prophase metaphase anaphase
telophase this now cell reproduces or or
becomes more of itself a self becomes a
stronger version of its
essentially because it is by itself it
has turmoil chaos and then all of a
sudden there's a splitting from the
inside a tearing apart from the inside
you can watch a video about cell mitosis
on youtube if you want to actually see
what it looks like but then the tearing
apart on the inside causes a situation
where the cell then splits into two it's
reorganized at a higher order this is a
theme in biology it is a theme in life
it is a theme in your life so you're
always on a hero's journey in some way
shape or form at various levels because
you're always growing stronger you're
always becoming a stronger version
yourself at least that's my assumption
some people devolve we evolve so one of
the elements that I wanted to share with
you comes from one of my favorite books
depicting a hero's journey and that is
the alchemist by paulo qua hello i'm not
gonna say his name right because i'll
never do Cole hello Coelho think he's
Brazilian anyway The Alchemist very
popular powerful book I've read it
several times I think anybody who's
watching these videos should read the
frigging book it's incredible but what
element in our the young boy of the
story the boys story that stuck out to
me and I began looking for it in my life
and I begin pointing it out to others as
they consult with me and that is
beginner's luck so I'm going to read a
quote from the book here so sort of
depict it and then I'd like to talk
about some of my own experiences with
beginner's luck and where it led to and
then perhaps have you share some of
yours so I'm in the book it goes every
search begins with beginner's luck and
every search ends with the victors being
severely tested the boy remembered an
old proverb from his country it said
that the darkest hour of the night came
just before the dawn so I gann thinking
about what this beginner's luck
is all about and of course I find
significance in things and the way I
look at it is it's almost as if God or
the universe has tapped you on the
shoulder and said yes go in that
direction with this bout of beginners
luck right so for example in my life as
a fourteen-year-old I'm meddling with
all kinds of things right let's do most
14 year olds because we're trying to
figure our selves out we're discovering
sports and our bodies right we're
starting to grow we're suffering
discovering girls we're discovering all
new types of ideas that could lead to a
career or a vocation we're highly
involved in many aspects of growing when
we're at the better at the dawn of
adolescence right 13 14 years old and I
was about that time that I found weight
training barbells right just like
anything else that would have come and
go into my life barbells showed up my
dad bought me some barbells and my uncle
taught me how to train in fact my blog
post today that you could read down
below talks a little bit about it and
man I gotta tell you it wouldn't but a
few weeks after me lifting these
barbells at the age of 14 that I
accidentally looked into a bathroom
mirror and concei could see my back and
for the first time I saw all kinds of
Whipple's and bumps and muscles in my
body that I had never seen before I felt
euphoric I felt excited I felt like I
had found a vein of gold that would
enrich me for the rest of my life I call
that beginner's luck not because of the
yields gained it gained because of the
activity the gains yield yield gains
right I'm saying that right not because
of the thing again but because of the
significance of what it meant to me at
that moment it meant to me that I could
actually achieve a goal it meant to me
that I could actually do something it
meant to me that with consistent effort
in a particular direction that I could
have something that I want and by
looking in the mirror I saw it it gave
me self-esteem it gave me the impetus to
keep going in that direction because it
was exciting and that's what beginner's
luck is for you when you start out in
something when you start out on
something when you're out on your
journey and you've got that exciting
feeling you feel filled up in euphoric
about a particular event a circumstance
or something that someone said to you
and you feel like you cannot lose it's
because you're on the right path be
mindful though as the quote says
beginner's luck precedes tests and this
is essentially where God or the universe
says okay good gave you that little
blessing so that you know that you're on
the right track but now I gotta see if
you're worthy of it was just how God
talks to me I gotta save your worthy of
this I know I want to see if you could
carry this gift I gave you a little bit
of taste of it but are you able to carry
it and those tests you know I'm 37 years
old and I'm still being tested in the
realm of weight lifting weight training
physical training athletic sports
performance in my health I next the
direction I was going to go in and God
has completely molded me with it so the
darkest hour precedes the Sun coming up
meaning there going to be some dark
times but if you stick with it you'll
ultimately rise like the brilliant star
that you are done