[Music]
we little boys we've watched the big men
we mocked their moves because we
depended on them
their bodies were big and their hands
were strong your skin was tough and
their fingers were worn when daddy would
talk the whole room would shake
I felt his deep love but my body would
quake so aggressive was this vessel that
shared tender care that it confused my
young mind that I loved or was it fear
so confuses our youth not knowing how to
be should a man rule with violence was
their strength when I yield to ignore
this deep question seemed the best thing
to do so I trained my blunt knuckles to
protect me from you I challenged many
men to see how I would fare to see how I
ruled with aggression and fear feel my
deep strength and your dreams I am there
when you see me awake you'll stop waking
stare I am in power I am in charge I
rule this land come near or move far it
is me that you feel where you're alone
scared at night
hide your weak children and protect that
sweet wife you smell me you see me you
feel me you dreamy I dominate your
thoughts so much that you need me until
they last the pain is so sharp your
backs against the wall and your hearts
grow and pitch dark you yell out and
paying your voice is so weak you say
that you'll move me but your claim has
no feet you know that you're doomed last
attempts are so meek so sit your ass
down little boy grown men speak what you
call a challenge I call a cry which you
think is toughness I see is lies but if
you want to do this I'll let you try
because I still love you now tell you
why I was a boy once I felt what you
felt I've kissed his gray beard and
benbrook with his belt I still have the
bruises and kisses on skin
I felt his red fury but shared meals
with him here's what I learned as my
young body grew strong that sometimes a
man's war cry it's also a song the
little boy you can't hear busy trying to
belong finding your place in scary world
that feels wrong so you bring your
challenge you bring your mic you try
this grown man your
heart filled with fright see how deep my
strength runs discover you might that
grown men verse little boys it's never a
fight
keep snarling keep barking scared hair
on your neck stairs up high so little
boy while you're running in circles I
just smile and sit by
[Music]