we are brother Aaron is a music teacher
things you've taken singing lessons
organum and then a big part of singing
this is fan this fascinating I'm
listening I'm reading a book it's a
boring it's Puckle it's taking a while
but it's called changer boys change your
life
and the reason why I was attracted to it
is because a lot of the exercises in it
are bioenergetic exercises like the
stuff that I talked about my study
fascinated with how there are neurotic
holding patterns throughout the body
namely in extra respiratory muscles jaw
even behind the eyes the jaw over here
across here the belly the pelvic floor
there's holding atoms of tension there
and that tension is is the manifestation
of emotional baggage idea that I'm
reading a book called the gates of fire
I mentioned it in my on my blog this
week about half-full loggia it was the
science of fear might be that the
science of fear and this is what the
Spartans would do to young soldiers who
were fearful so this you are going
breathing and fear are diametrically
opposed their fear is fucking up your
breathing working on your breathing like
a like a singing coach would offer you
is going to help you get rid of it
it's funny that if we heal the body how
do you feel now
did I do this Eikenberry no I got into
realize what he's saying up taller he
feels better about himself right which
me a feel better about it because he's
carrying himself differently his body is
going to evoke the emotion with you the
fear is secondary and this is what the
idea of apology of the fear is secondary
to the bodily manifestations of the
field so you've got to exercise that I
know this is your question you've got to
exercise out the fear this is where I
think that term exorcism comes from it's
interesting that they're exercising out
it spinning around exercising out the
psychological emotional demons right and
it's crazy this is going to sound which
you better do is exercise too deep you
got a goddamn demon out of your muscle
right so I can offer you an exercise and
we can do it right now
but as a practical means of both
improving your skills as a singer and
improving who you are as a person
becoming stronger version of yourself
which they'll both facilitate each other
they'll both work against you become a
better singer mark my word you become
as you breathe deeper you will be a more
fearless courageous beautiful person now
anyone want anything else except
deepening your breath so that you can
say it's amazing but it's like killing a
bunch of birds with one stone so here
here's an exercise it's very comfortable
once it shoes all that you do and you
probably see shares before this is it's
called a ball and this is what I'll say
below and called it take your socks off
or something and it's designed to put it
up stretch on all the extra respiratory
muscles and deepen your breath I found -
this is where like ancient exercises
like Qigong Tai Chi Yoga are so
fascinating because it's like you know
just like it's old and brilliant
they have chigo it's very similar that
looks very similar to those weird
let's get you on this platform here good
and I don't want you to look at that
because you're going to be just look at
your venture knees slightly have you
done it support okay good take your fist
bottom up put them right above your butt
pinch your elbows back okay then what
you bend your knees a little bit more
and need that
open your mouth why you can like
uncomfortably wide and start to breathe
and you might find we start vibrating
singing is vibration all weekly talk
about Baltimore
yeah they're going to feel like we're in
your mouth
I can cry for
did you notice all the tension in your
mouth and your neck yeah you're like a
different person if you because you're
the second meaning you need to do that
you just broke up you just released some
emotional shit did you like em agree
with me right do you feel it okay get
that to you guys
I should just fucking Brady tell me what
are you simply in your mind by doing
open up your breathing dissipate the
fear but it's going to be uncomfortable
I promise you because that was
uncomfortable physically but also as you
start anew every you were coming out you
were coming out there you what you can
also do to facilitate you coming out is
as you charged your body and you're here
you I let it explode into write whatever
comes up for me there's a lot of range I
can go crazy for you might turn into
tears you might be there and if I turn
into it it's breaking up whatever
emotional shape you've been holding on
to heal body heal fear it's a helpful
I would invite you to begin practicing
with that and
- well watch my videos begin with that
and then express yourself let it all out
deep resonating sound allow the breath
deep in itself through your sounds
breathing and shaking shaking breaks up
neurotic texture it breaks up case in
point
what started happening when there was a
stretch on the tension if I have to keep
going you're going to completely right
you can do that awesome you break it up
like shaking and breathing you see so
practice here I wanted to give you like
tangible ideas do the bow every morning
in a safe environment where you can let
go whatever comes out comes up you know
just let it happen
and practice the Kundalini meditation
video I've done where there's music and
you just shake if you search my channel
my Elias and watch out and what's the
big like in the fall I created one
called
Kundalini meditation and it comes from
yoga
Oh show okay and and there's music
associated with it
it's an hour-long meditation that will
be helpful and my assumption is that you
don't have money to throw around if you
can invest get us a singing coach
because a singing yo just going to
correct to teach you how to breathe
deeply yep and to relax your jaw and to
give you stretches for your neck and
your shoulders there's a lot of tension
up here and giving you some of the
sounds that Eliot was talking about that
resonate more with singers so opening up
the back of your mouth a lot and letting
that freedom out yeah yeah all the
tension was right there yeah or you said
the first thing started
was this if watch a baby right for baby
cries
that's those are the muscles will be all
tears back with all that are stopping
back here so when you know the tensions
building in a baby what like I watched
small salon cries her she starts doing
this like that chin start like like
dipping and shit away cry that and death
so what you just described as breaking
up the the neurotic holding patterns and
attention that approach that you focus
on that and the fear will disappear with
the tension okay yeah
it's something
Oh
hi
five
you need to do you need to open your
body before you mean like we have an
audition or something yeah don't wait in
the same way that an athlete stretches
his body before he goes into his sports
right I'm not a singer and you can
attest to this I'm sure that I'm right I
don't because I've seen it I watch the
background before
you can't go into your singing situation
text you can't go into it nor I can't go
into the holding pattern you literally
just take an hour or 40 to go into your
situation and bow breathing shakily it
all out because what's happening is
they're reading up against yourself
there's what you want to do and then
there's a resistance against you doing
it and you're doing both the muscular
tension is yours
and what you like that happen is doing
and it's almost like it's like nask ism
it's like you're just beating yourself
up
it's the muscular pattern that's beating
down the you that wants to be expressed
you've got to break out the tension
before you go into the situation to
these exercises it's the exercises that
are going to support you you say that's