what made you want to get on on YouTube
six seven long years ago it's been like
what made you want to uh like how did
you take that first day who knows what
the fuck this is going here's the thing
when i first started my business it was
based on personal training I trained at
I train people I trained just break up
the people at first my first moved down
to Florida and once a regular people
people that are an athlete athlete's I'm
an athlete I host Morgan trained
athletes so I didn't have enough money
to start my own business might quit the
gym where I trained regular people so
what I did was I filled up a van my dad
gave me with sandbags and tires and
literally jumped you know that I look I
discovered you can actually training
board who's a Kevin Nash friend of mine
get a website all about I've trained
people garbage because like shit i do
our kind of happened so I filled up a
better from Park to park at I do
waterfall strength cams the name I t to
my first youtube channel is strength
care and we train can equal garbage I
study markings I reveal I know what
could happen tensional setup you've got
to be able to position yourself properly
like damn right I train people garbage
and you should all join with garbage to
check out how fucking cool it is alright
very important have that kind of
conviction especially if you have
strikes against you know morning no gym
a lot of artists how
so the way to make itself is my video
taping and show me cool isn't it is cool
whooping tires & Dragons / ho mates they
were pushing my band and stuff I got all
the global news and it was because I put
up videos of him pushing my van and
stuff we're loading them on YouTube
right away we were pretty much right of
the guy back there is trying to my he
use it my first workout that's actually
making my first workout and it's on the
very first video on my channel 2007
because I realized if I put videos
myself training people in this
particular fashion that they would see
it and they be attracted to it than they
would come in my gym tours all to train
people at my gym with the internet you
realize which is evidently the amount of
people that are here that there are
those from all the oral that will see
your videos so I started getting
comments and questions and I it just
kind of steam roll from there I realized
and questions from Bangladesh and
questions from Austria and Siberia New
Zealand so I just started answering and
that's all in the same way I spoke to
the kids a trained in my gym it's the
same way I flipped over the camera and
answer questions to the world right
we're now at least two videos a day but
it's good i'm doing the same exact thing