got this question here from our 16 year
old buddy Matt he says he's 16 years old
for the last year he's had the perfect
girlfriend that saved him
really she helped change his life from
being a drug addict he says he was
addicted to drugs who's selling drugs he
was surrounded by constant domestic
violence so supported him when the home
environment wasn't healthy he had lots
of port appearances ahead of him he was
suffering from suicide attempts and
self-mutilation completely fucked-up
life but his girlfriend he met a girl
that took him in and really cared for
him at a time when there was no one
there he goes on to even say that she
was the first person to actually give
him a birthday cake he says he's never
had a birthday cake before in his life
and you know things must have been
really tough at home and she baked him a
birthday cake for his 16th birthday I
suppose I mean that's incredible that's
awesome
she has gone out of her way to to help
you become what is now a very
resourceful version of yourself because
he says now things are going well he's
back in school and he's uh it for in his
terms he says things are going great and
I'm getting ready to fuck shit up he's
working out Oh
all the great things that are supposed
to happen to a 16 year old are happening
right now and she is a perfect girl she
says that she's beautiful she plays
tennis so on and so forth but he felt
recently that she was getting in his way
interesting right so he broke up with
her he broke up with the girl that saved
his life and he says that look you know
I've got these big goals and aspirations
and dreams for my life now that that
I've been supported I can go forward in
that way and I feel like she's an anchor
but there's guilt associated with
letting go perhaps even pushing away the
person that gave you everything that you
now have and he's feeling bad about it
one of the things you got to recognize
is that guilt is a is a manifestation of
moral judgment placed on spontaneous
action in the body it's basically when
the head based on what we've been
told is right and true demonizes goes
against and battles with the natural
instinct your heart and your gut and
your heart your gut led you to making a
decision then now your head is there's
this dissonance this cognitive
dissonance between the two of them right
so that's the guilt feeling in our body
you made a good choice by breaking up
with her and the reason why I say that
is because it sounds like you followed
your instinct
the only sin and the only thing that you
might feel guilty about or you should
feel guilty about if you choose to feel
guilty is lack of gratitude towards the
young woman that supported you and your
time of need you see there are going to
be people she's not the first one but
there going to be people throughout your
entire life that you're going to use
there are people that are going to be
means to an end that's just the way the
world works
there are people of higher vibratory
energy people who have more vitality
that will pull you up or you will
essentially use as stepping stones for
your evolution and when an opportunity
poses itself for you to grow stronger on
the back of another individual you don't
owe that person anything except
gratitude she's perhaps a really good
girl like you said which is probably the
best girl which will probably ever meet
in your life
but it's time for you to move on and
it's not bad that you're moving on
that's okay it's what we do we you were
supposed to use each other and if we're
one of those people that's being used we
should be grateful for our the
opportunity that we have to be used to
be stepped on because we're supporting
someone else and collectively the human
race in our evolution and that's okay
that's great it's a magnificent place to
be and in fact she's a saint in that way
the best way to approach this from here
on out knowing that you stepped on her
or you used her yes you used her is
express towards her and in your heart
and even pray if you do gratitude for
the opportunity that she's shared with
you that is the highest form of payback
that you're going to exhibit towards her
I personally believe that a heartfelt
letter expressing all of your deepest
sentiment toward and giving that to her
is perhaps the greatest purge of your
heart from its heavy feelings and
perhaps the easiest way for her to gain
a perspective on what's going on inside
you and the magnificent role she played
in your life she might not get it right
away and she might cry and that's a part
of her journey that's a part of her
evolution as a human being she's gonna
need to go through this because this is
gonna be her pattern she's gonna be a
helper and it will offer her a
perspective on her place in life and
also she will need to come to grips
maybe she'll send me a video question
and I'll make a video but she'll need to
come to grips with that's her place in
life and to appreciate it love it and
continue to do it that's how she will
love that's how her life will be a gift
to herself to the world and to others
but you my friend feel no guilt towards
the decision you made don't feel guilty
when you see her cultivate and express a
deep feeling of gratitude and carry that
gratitude with you when you see other
people that you could perhaps support on
their journey pay it forward
done