Elliot what are you question I've been
asked ever since I was a kid in school
and to this day it's a question that
people ask me in YouTube and Facebook
and justifiably so they look at me and
they wonder is this guy black because he
doesn't seem so much but he might be as
this guy white because he might be but
his nose and lips are just a little bit
too big for that and perhaps he's
Hispanic or Puerto Rican but damn he
doesn't speak Spanish so what the heck
is going on there so it's not only a
question that other people have wondered
but it's one that I have had to ask
myself especially growing up in a
community where was predominantly white
but you had a few black kids and
everyone knew where they belonged except
Elliott Hulse and when you're six years
old and people like who are you what are
you where do you belong they try to
categorize you you you embody that it
becomes a part of your your own personal
consciousness so it's a question that to
this day I am always asking myself and
those you who are attracted to me
because of my attitude towards
self-reliance and personal development
and being yourself the reason why I am
this way and you may be attracted to my
message with regard to that is because
of my scorn and gift of not knowing what
I am so I'm grateful for it but it is
also afforded me the opportunity to see
the pain that people experience through
racism and when I say racism I mean
prejudice of every sort if it's because
you're black because you're white
because you're gay because you are
Muslim because you are Jewish whatever
the thing is that makes you different
from everyone else could be a position
of pride can cause you to feel good for
yourself good about yourself because you
know where you belong you know who you
are but at the same time it creates
division separation and people who label
you put you into these categories
we'll have all sorts of associations
tied to what it is that they think you
are
and I say think you are because we are
far more than the color of our skin and
the ideologies that we accept do you say
so not knowing where you fit in causes
you to try to fit in as best you can
when you're a kid and this is what I've
done and growing up I'm 33 years old
right now
I have personally identified with white
people as a child and and I've gained a
vantage point from doing so there were
times when I personally identified with
black people and there was a vantage
point that I gained from that experience
the and I say Puerto Ricans because I
grew up in New York and you know that's
what they say when you're Spanish you're
Puerto Rican even though there are lots
of different Hispanics Hispanics are
funny because there's some of the most
prejudice against other Hispanics but
anyway never really fit in with the
Puerto Ricans because I don't speak
their special language and we speak
English so through this experience of
acceptance but also prejudice coming
from every angle and not being able to
settle into a single place that you
could call home has created the
individual that you see here today in
front of you
but like I said through those
experiences I've been able to gather
Intel as to the attitudes associated
with racism and Prejudice and the very
first thing that I want to start with is
if you have experienced racism in any
way shape or form and I'm not talking
about violence violence is wrong no
matter how you justify it right you
don't hurt other people physically and
and really emotionally but that's a
totally different story I'm talking
about just mere prejudice where someone
doesn't like you because of the color of
your skin because of the religious garb
that you're wearing or or known ideology
whatever the case may be it's not about
you it absolutely is has nothing to
with you when someone is treating you
poorly or perhaps thinking of you poorly
it's a better way to describe it because
we feel people's feelings
you know the looks on their eyes and the
energy associated with their attitudes
towards you right so if someone feels
ill towards you the very first thing
that you have to recognize and this is
not just Airy fairy magic talk this is
reality based on the perspectives that
I've gained it has nothing to do with
you they don't hate you because you are
a particular color they don't like you
because they're scared of you they don't
understand you and as human beings that
which we don't understand always causes
resistance we don't we don't get it we
don't understand it so we associated
with everything opposite of us so that
we can gain a vantage point so that we
can gain perspective as to what's going
on here
I am a this and he's not of this so he
must be at that and that that is always
opposite ie evil right so there's fear
associated with it
there is fear and there's also a sense
of pride I've recognized this from my
gaining perspective on every angle of
race you know I've been able to finagle
seek my way in just enough till I kind
of to get to know what people are
actually thinking and they're proud
white people are proud of their
whiteness there's also a sense of guilt
associated with it right and this is
neither right nor wrong but the
situation situation is such that they
should feel proud for for who they are
and we should all feel proud for who we
are but there's also a an air of fear
like I described but guilt there's white
guilt I've experienced this I watched
them and I listened to them talk and I
see their attitudes and behaviors and I
realize you're guilty that you want to
feel proud but you shouldn't because
it's not politically correct and it's
unfortunate because guilt is a form of
resistance that causes resentment right
so then there's
egman towards blacks and and browns and
I say Browns because I put everyone else
in that category and the same with
blacks there is a sense of pride and
there should be a sense of pride for the
culture the heritage the pain and I'm
talking specifically about African
Americans the pain associated with their
history and being able to move through
and get to where they are today
there's a sense of pride and there
should be but there's also a sense of
resentment tied in to that so you've got
fear pride and then resentment these
feelings of pride guilts fear and
resentment belong to the individuals
that are that are proceeding in life and
don't belong to the opposite end of the
spectrum ie
it doesn't belong to the white person
that is uh that that's that's receiving
ill feelings and attitudes towards him
it doesn't belong to the black person in
the same situation it is owned fully 100
percent by the individual that those
feelings are coming up in so if you end
up being one of those people who are on
the receiving end of this form of racism
right recognize that that person is an
individual also they have feelings also
they may be ignorant about how to deal
with the with how the feelings are
coming up in their body it's very
difficult for people to be objective
about their feelings and objective about
themselves it's just one of those things
that I've been able to do because of my
situation I always have to be detached
because I can't be too tied to this
version of Elliot or that version Eliot
because really none of it is Eliot so
when I say this just understand that not
everybody has that perspective we're all
very subjective we all we only know
where we're coming from and it's very
hard to gain a perspective for the other
person be objective and your attitude
when you're on the receiving end is to
carry yourself humbly that's my
invitation with
this video because I experienced this
and you could be angry
right but that serves no one especially
since it's that person situation and not
yours you can give it back to that
person and that just escalates the
problem or you could just walk firmly in
your own footsteps and treat others the
way you want to be treated regardless of
their energy towards you when I say walk
humbly I don't mean put your head down I
mean be self-confident self-reliant
understanding of yourself and objective
about what you're receiving from that
other individual when we can all do this
when we can all look through the eyes of
another individual especially those
riddled with fear guilt and resentment
we'll begin to understand each other
much better and that is the seed of love
and when I say love I don't mean the
romantic love
I mean unity and understanding and
getting along with one another it begins
with you