so we got a really good question from
our friend he's an Indian guy he calls
him he describes himself as a medium
brown looking guy says he's not a freak
but he'd rate himself between a 5 and a
7 on a scale of 10 anyways 21 years old
he's moved to Hong Kong from India about
10 years ago now that he's at age where
he's you know he's trying to engage with
women he's having lots of resistance and
I mean you see like he leaves me a long
message there describing all of the
things he's tried reading about the
psychology of women and uh and then he's
got different techniques I asked him out
once to lunch and rehme and nothing's
working he says that he's growing
narcissistic towards women and that he
in essence is starting to feel as if he
needs to give up like what does he do
what does he have to do to make this
thing happen so the very first thing I'm
gonna of just an idea that I can afford
you and I don't know for sure I've never
been to Hong Kong I've never been a part
of the Chinese culture but I have a
feeling right just through media and
even speaking with Chinese friends that
the Chinese culture is a bit closed to
other cultures so you show up in Hong
Kong and again I don't know this is just
me saying this you show up in Hong Kong
and you know you're a little brown dude
from India and everybody looks Chinese
you're going to be met with a bit of
resistance they're not going to be super
attracted to you right away because
you're kind of an outsider and I'm sure
you've dealt with this and that type of
prejudice is probably something that
you've experienced and since anyway and
you may be bumping up against that right
so the cultural situation just needs to
be considered you know and there may be
ways and there are ways I'm going to
share them with you to melt those
barriers between you and in a different
culture as well as you and the opposite
sex now the rules are going to be the
same because we human beings respect
human beings that are respectable right
and it doesn't matter if it's because
it's there's a there's a race racial
difference religious difference sexual
difference whether the case may be
our spectable human being is a
respectful respectable human being even
no matter what they look like you ever
meet somebody who like at first glance
you're like oh that person's weird but
you have a conversation you're like hmm
very opened to this person because
they're respectable they're thoughtful
they're doing something they're
interesting so my invitation to you in
approaching and all guys in approaching
women especially if you continue to get
rejected is to become the strongest
version of yourself first right that's
Elliot's number one rule in almost
anything become the strongest version of
yourself
first and that looks very different for
different people for you apparently it's
not going to be about your looks you
said that you're a little fat and you
know you're kind of a funny looking guy
I'm just those are your words so don't
focus so much on that that might not be
your feature but I guarantee that you're
pretty freaking awesome at something and
everyone's awesome at something everyone
has a gift everyone has a jewel deep
within them it doesn't matter how ugly
the coal is on the outside the most
superficial shit
there's a diamond on the inside of every
human being
you've got to excavate right is it the
right word find it discover it in you
and sometimes it's harder than others
but if you're committed to that bringing
forth that diamond and shining it in you
becoming the strongest version of
yourself wherever you go the light of
that diamond is going to shine where the
reflection of it will be what will
bounce off of people's eyes wherever you
go so the very first thing I would
invite you to do is to step away from
trying to approach women turn inwards
and manifest the strength within you to
become a stronger version of yourself
find out what you're great at now this
is very interesting especially with
regard to women women are attracted to
men who are out we're moving out who are
proceeding in the world who are
extending themselves I talked about this
board just like the penis extending
themselves into the world what are you
doing out this is why we're by the way
this is why women love men in uniform
because they're busy they're doing
something right man in any uniform a man
in uniform is attracted to women because
that's a man that's doing something
right you want to be perceived as a man
that's
doing something and the only way you can
go out and do something is if you got
something to give
so cultivate the strength within you and
then go and it doesn't matter if you
become like a great philanthropist right
and something that you can do within a
short period of time right you're
serving people may in a in a soup
kitchen right I'm going like far down
one end of the spectrum you're serving
people in soup kitchen and you just
happen to be like the best fucking
server of the poor people in the soup
kitchen and it's like man this guy just
oozes with passion to serve people in
this particular fashion that's where
your diamond shines is in that type of
service you will be attractive to people
or if you decide that you know you've
got you use the term narcissistic but if
you've got this narcissistic drive to
become the like the next CEO of a giant
corporation that takes over the world
Hey both guys are out there doing
something this guy's out doing it in one
way you're out doing that way either way
that power associated with that right is
attractive to other people it's
particularly women this is advice for
everyone if you want to be attractive to
other people you've got to strengthen
your magnet and there are certain key
elements to having a strong magnet and
one of those is becoming the strongest
version of yourself and serving others
or inspiring others in whichever way you
feel most inclined to so that's it man
work on yourself forget about the women
they're going to come to you when they
see that you're a man that's up to some
serious business good luck Elliot what
you