it's we got a question here from a buddy
sojourner who says that he's in school
studying to be an electric engineer so
that he could ultimately go to Africa
and he says he wants to build wells feed
families plant irrigation systems and
deliver people from oppression etc very
admirable he's in college though and
he's studying electrical engineering as
a means by which he will ultimately
fulfill this goal and his passion to
serve those who are who are oppressed in
that particular way but he feels as if
schools stifling his passion it's
getting in the way and he's studying a
lot of courses that have nothing to do
with his ability to be an electrical
engineer or to serve people in the way
that his heart is calling him to serving
so he's caught in this dilemma where I'm
energized to go and serve the world of
my passion but I'm held back and stifled
by this necessity to obtain a degree at
university and and what do I do
look I'm not gonna tell you what to do
because if you've watched enough my
videos I'll say damned if you do damned
if you don't that's always the case
ridden matter what you do is who you're
becoming but I'll share a perspective
with you that's been fairly helpful to
me and many others I believe it was
attributed to Mark Twain and he goes on
to say that I never let schooling get in
the way of my education schooling
education who do totally different
things because I can tell you that if
you decide to buy a one-way ticket to
Ghana right now you'll be educated you
can get all kinds of fucking education
and you can go to school and not
necessarily be educated because
education is a form of it really is a
form of subjective learning its
experiential what we call education
really is schooling which is
memorization and manipulation its
conditioning for society's conditioning
for what the demands of civilization
which is rooted in a economic machinery
and set forth work set forth for us
you can be very successful through a to
a course of education that is subjective
and eclectic or choosing those things
that really serve your ability to become
the strongest version yourself and
inspire others without schooling now the
economic machine that we live in the
matrix if you will will require that you
have certain you have met certain
standards they are standards in order to
present with a form of competence but
they would like you to have you know and
most of the ability to present with that
level of competence ie a piece of paper
that says you're good enough really
requires a lot of jumping through hoops
and doing and a lot of masturbation work
like you say you're in you're in
engineering but they're making you take
classes that have nothing to do with
engineering because it's supposed to
make you well-rounded as if you know you
didn't go to high school and these
things and that's his complaint anyway
so my invitation is to consider that
you're going to grow stronger as long as
you're subjecting yourself to potent
experiences that you are oh that you're
navigating with a level of awareness
that allows you to learn from your
experiences in fact I truly believe it's
the it's the most visceral the deepest
form of learning is through doing you
know um we sit in classrooms and we were
we receive information an idea through
auditory and visual means you know and
then we're asked to use only one of our
mental capacity capacities which is
mainly our ability to memorize it so
much of it is memorization some of it is
you know analytical skills but really
very very little of it is kinesthetic
very little of it is creative very
little of it is experiential in this way
so I again I don't I don't care I don't
know what you need to
do you know my invitation has become the
strongest version yourself but through
any means by which you feel compelled
but don't feel as if you have to do
anything because the world has led you
to believe that you have to do it and
that you will be lacking in some
particular way or in some authentic way
if you don't you might lack a piece of
paper that certain people say you need
to have but you will be lacking in your
the authentic growth of your character
who you are and your ability to serve
people there are more and more
opportunities today to serve people
without following the traditional path
of debt and economic slavery but they
rope you into the minute you step out of
high school than ever before you want
you want to liberate you want to
liberate oppressed people we'll start
today by liberating yourself from the
oppression of debt and economic slavery
that every single one of us are
subjected to and if you think you're not
try not paying your taxes right that
student loan that you got try not paying
that back your grandkids will pay that
back you're a slave begin by Liberty
emancipate yourself from mental slavery
and then by and by you'll inspire other
people and if you use some of the tips
and techniques that I've shared with you
in these videos you're not only will
liberate your mind but you will impel it
towards the calling that your heart has
set forth for you and without even
knowing how you're going to navigate
that path where it will lead you you
will find yourself doing just what your
heart has set out to to produce or to
create and how to serve you just have to
have the courage to do it that's really
the I find to be the most lacking of all
the virtues and personal growth that
that our friends struggle with its
courage so whatever you choose to do man
put your foot in it do it 100% and know
that as long as your hearts in right
place you're going to win done