Elliot's it what here's an interesting
paradigm shift your body is smarter than
your brain it's been said that your
brain could only handle about three to
five thoughts at a single time if that
but your body is producing about ninety
percent of the activities maybe more
that are happening inside you things
like digesting food pumping blood
breathing in the exchange of oxygen
these are things that you're not
thinking about what this spring so when
people say follow your gut or listen to
your instincts or have some balls
there's a lot of wisdom to it down in
your balls and your gut and in your body
those instincts are far more intelligent
than the brain it's in your head
Elliot's it what