so we have a question from one of our
anonymous friends he says that he was
madly in love with a woman at one time a
girl I think they're in college or high
school so deeply and madly in love with
her very vulnerable in this spot because
we all are when we love someone were
very vulnerable and she took a giant
shit on me I don't know what that looked
like right what a shit look like but the
fact is that he became very vulnerable
to this girl and she broke his heart
fucked him up in many ways it's hurt and
those feelings of hurt are still with
him but the situation is now where she
wants to make amends she's sorry she
apologizes she feels very hurt by her
decisions she wants to come back that's
the point she wants to come back our
friend still deeply in love with her but
immensely hurt feels as if there's
something wrong with him because I love
her I want her back but I want her to
feel that pain that I felt he says that
he's not a physically abusive guy hmm
but I want her to feel the pain that I
felt and he goes on actually in his PS
to say I know this is fucked up and it's
crazy but how do I deal with this and
all the rationalizations he used a
couple of Elliot hoses type
rationalizations this is going to make
me stronger blah blah okay cool but I
still feel this shit right sometimes I
give you guys ideas that might help you
at this level but really what I'm trying
to have you do is heal what's happening
here right so sometimes it's good enough
to say hey just use this perspective to
help you get along but sometimes the
perspective doesn't heal you know you
can tell yourself any story you won't
just like I still feel like I want to
fucking kill this bitch but I love her
right it's all happening right here so
this is first of all this whole
situation the question my answer it's
all very ungrounded narcissistic
egotistical hysterical you know but it
is what it is right so I want to support
you right where you're at
so all stories and judgments aside what
are you gonna do what you really want is
not to see her in pain okay what you
really want is a deep visceral response
from her you want her to feel something
now you felt pain you but your body was
very charged up and broken down boom
your bubble was pop she burst your
bubble that's the underlying that's
that's the the root that's the basis the
foundation of what happened to you she
charged you up and popped your bubble
right and you want her to have a very
similar experience the thing is that you
want to be able to have enough power to
do it to her you see because she had the
power to manipulate your charging and
discharging or the bursting of your
bubble she built you up and chopped you
down right with her hands with her body
with her love she built you up and
chopped your ass down she holds the
machete now
the fucked up situation is that she had
enough power to do that to you
its power that you're after because you
want to be able to do the same thing it
doesn't have to look like hurt as in I'm
going to beat this bitch it doesn't have
to be hurt as in I'm going to make her
cry with a lot of sadness the power
you're looking for is the ability to
have a gonna create a visceral response
in her where she builds up and you chop
her down okay so there are a number of
ways to do that in a very loving fashion
I know this sounds crazy but I promise
you you will feel better about the whole
situation without really hurting her
because you yield or you wield the power
to do what you're about to do to her
number one this is the easiest said this
is the one that's the most visceral this
is the one that if you can do this you
really wield up a certain potential of
power right depending on your skills
you'll be able to carry this with you
you will feel really good about yourself
you will feel relieved of the pain
associated with what she projected upon
you and you will forgive in a way
because you will now have the power to
make her orgasm this is all very
narcissist narcissistic I know but if
you're stroking in such a way that
there's tender aggression right and
that's very important I use that term
before not anger this fucking bitch is
gonna feel me what happened she's not
gonna orgasm too angry there needs to be
a sense of I love you so much that I
want to see you squirm you see the
difference there
ah you say you want to have sex with her
in such a way that all of your
aggression but love your tenderness
comes out the stroking isn't necessarily
as important as the intention behind it
and you can't be a tender aggression is
a funny thing
you can't be caught up in the in what's
actually going to happen you need to be
very in the moment while having sex with
her you want her to feel all of your
tenderness and aggression while you're
having sex with her and you want to see
her face scream you want it twisted ah
with orgasm to the point where her head
looks like it's gonna pop full-blood ur
head will be all red veins coming out of
her neck ah that type of orgasm you you
will feel so powerful you'll feel so
strong and you will forgive her at that
moment cuz you're gonna be saying to
yourself that's right baby
whoo
holding the power now do you see not an
easy listen it might take some practice
right and look there you can study sex
you know we tend to think that it's like
yeah what the fuck your dick gets hard
you put it in someone you can study how
to have sex in such a way that you can
depending on the woman nothing's a
guarantee
make her have the orgasm of her life
your everything will change at that
moment I promise you and you will see
the pain on her face that will quench
your thirst for revenge promise because
when you bring someone to the point of
orgasm you are in full control of so
much of their physical physiological and
energetic life right they have to open
up she literally has to let go and allow
orgasm to carrier and you're the stroke
behind the orgasm okay cool so that's
one idea it's a very good ones it's the
best one free you from all of the all of
the need to see her in pain because
you're gonna see her in a very good kind
of pain she's gonna thank you for that
pain or you create you take her
somewhere or you create an environment
where she just is head over heels for
you you know what I'm saying take her on
a date to like New York City to like the
most extravagant restaurant that you can
afford
take her out by her a piece of jewelry
and the whole night she's gonna be putty
in your hands
oh oh I can't believe this oh this is
amazing oh this is great you treat me
like such a princess so you're sort of
controlling her at a visceral level at
that point also remember its power that
you want and by you using by you
creating an environment a situation
gifts whatever the case may be you have
the potential none of this is guaranteed
you have the potential to now have the
hand on the steering wheel of her
emotion right you don't have to break
her down
the breakdown is in the orgasm it's in
the crying right and then the third
which is is probably the most retarded
but hey you know I put it out there for
you guys have done this before
put create perhaps a fake situation
right I don't know how you would do this
I think I think that movie uh Billy
Madison with a Adam Sandler he did they
did this to some degree but anyway you
create a situation where she's in date
and seeming danger you know have to have
someone by coming like it's like
snatching her purse alright it's like
it's gonna take her away and you come
and you save her right I know this is
all this is you're probably not gonna do
this one but you see where I'm going
with it
she's very charged up with an emotional
situation where she's in danger right
right on the brink of orgasm you're in
danger when those tears are about to
come up danger when she's freaking out
cuz someone's pulling her purse we're
trying to pull her into a car and you
come and you save her there's going to
be a feeling of power inherent in your
activity and a feeling of gratitude for
you okay and this is not new you know
guys have been doing shit like this all
the time and probably see it on TV more
than an actual life but this is how it
works again it's it's all very
egotistical ungrounded hysterical
narcissistic it's all power power grab
eventually gonna have to get over it
you're probably young I think you know
you guess that you're like probably 17
18 years old you're probably young and
that in the whole power thing your heart
was broken and you want to get revenge
you really don't want to hurt her but
you want power back again you want to
feel like you're in control at some
point you're going to mature in your own
self esteem on your own self-worth and
who you believe yourself to be and
you're no longer going to need to exert
that type of power over people unless
you're a serial like a sociopath like
most of our politicians and a lot of
public officials and people of that
nature a lot of them are sociopaths
I mean they've said that I think
something like 95% of all politicians or
sociopaths they just like having control
over people you know they're probably
the kids that chopped off
look kittens heads and stuff when they
were they were small because they have
been controllable for weaker beings you
don't want that's dysfunctional you just
don't fucking want that but something
happened you were hurt you want to get
revenge do it in a way that makes her
happy to have you around okay and then
as you evolve you'll see how silly the
whole thing is but it's not silly when
you're in it and that's why I decided to
take this take this question it's very
serious what you're gonna grow out of it
so that's it dude make her orgasm she'll
love you just as much as you hate her
done