so I have a couple questions here coming
from different perspectives on dropping
out of school one is a college student
who doesn't want to get into any deeper
debt so he's thinking about dropping out
and then one actually is from a mom I
saw my facebook wall that her son 17
years old I think maybe a maybe a little
bit younger either a junior or senior in
high school wants to drop out and play
hockey and so you know wanted to know
what is Elliott think about this idea of
dropping out of school when everybody
else says that you shouldn't and from
the perspective of the mother she
doesn't want her son to drop out of high
school you know and here's this crazy
dude that he watches on YouTube says hey
I'm dropping out of school might be a
good idea depending on your circumstance
one of the first things I want you all
to recognize especially those who take
that to heart when I say that you might
be better off dropping out of school is
that no matter what no matter who you
are if you're watching this is a good
chance that you're already you were born
into a socio-economic machine we are
born in a matrix if you will it's a game
it's a machine it's a game it's a
fucking matrix and it all revolves
around money right and if you want to
participate in this game you had better
figure out how to make money that is the
only rule for playing this game
quote-unquote successfully right and
that's that's if you're attached to the
game okay you can drop out of the game I
mean that's we're invited to drop out of
the game all the timing guys like Jesus
that's why he hangs out with bums and
stuff you know so say look you know it's
easier for a child or a bum to get into
the heaven get into the into the into
the kingdom than a rich man all right
the reason why I says that is because
the rich man is attached to the fucking
game it's very difficult to let go of
the game once you become attached to it
right you start doing real well in the
game start making money and then and
then opportunity Rises where now your
heart is asking you to do something else
and you can your heart is where heaven
is that's what the kingdom is that's
what Jesus is inviting you in that
parable not somewhere in the clouds
fuck worm in the clouds anyway
and when you're attached to the gain to
the matrix you can't you can't let go
into your heart you can't let go into
the heavens right so a lot of my
invitation to you guys is to not get
attached to this fucking game too
quickly and don't let them grab you
right out of it you're just running out
of your house all right and they grabbed
me to put you in the game that's dead
right because now there's no opportunity
to follow your heart and if you do
really well in the game again the rich
man it's so difficult to let it go so
follow your heart so you're already in
the game and if you're gonna do okay in
the game you're gonna get by in the game
because you're gonna want to get by in
the game you want to do okay in the game
cuz you can see other people in the game
with shit that you ain't gonna have if
you don't have money right you want a
cell phone that costs money unless you
live in America cuz now our government
gives away cell phone you you want to be
okay just come here because taxpayers
people would actually do shit so that's
a part of the matrix is that we're all
batteries and and you fuel the Machine
with tax money and you know the more
people that they have dependent on the
machine because of those who fuel the
Machine the bigger the machine grows so
you want to fucking do nothing and live
live nicely come to America right get
all types of benefits here that for
doing shit doing nothing but anyway you
know that's neither here nor there the
point is that you've got a choice to
make if you are not going to participate
in the rules of the game because you
don't have to you still have to know how
to make your way in the game see I don't
my invitation is never really to escape
the game I'm not really in this escape
this game I kind of fucking like it I
like making these videos I like serving
you guys in this way and guess what
that's the key to winning or doing well
in this game is the only key to doing
well in this game is serve people serve
people serve people and you will receive
right and I kind of like it it's cool I
enjoy I enjoy air conditioning I enjoy
driving a car
I enjoy warm clothes and food on my
table so I'm gonna play the fucking game
I'm gonna be a part of the matrix
you get it but the only way that happens
the only way you can make your way in
this game which has nothing to do with
college or high school and everything to
do with are you good at something can
you serve people in a particular way
that they're willing to reciprocate can
you make enough money to least enjoy the
fruits of this game I understand it has
nothing to do a here's the thing if you
stay in school you drop out of school it
doesn't matter it does not matter if you
stay in school drop out of school can
you offer the world something right most
people can't offer the world shit except
they're fucking their labor right their
flesh the prostitutes of sorts right
they show up and they go to work and
it's like a fucking monkey could do it
that's why everybody's getting replaced
by robots and machines you want to be
worthwhile you want to be valuable go in
and discover what your gifts are we all
have them and serve the world hold
heartedly through that gift
so should you drop out of school look
man I don't know high school kid you're
gonna drop out of school what are you
gonna do that's really the question see
my dad had no problem with us doing
dropping out of school he just said you
had better go do something you had
better go do something and you had
better be good at something otherwise I
mean we were kicked out of the house
none of us got kicked out cuz we you
know look we figured out how to do good
shit
but essentially school is not the thing
the thing is are you going to make your
way in the world are you going to be a
part of the matrix and make your way
through it we're going to drop the fuck
out and there's nothing wrong with
dropping the fuck out like I said guys
like Jesus they invite you to drop out
give Caesar what is his give me about
what is mine hey so you can drop out I
mean you can go and be a volunteer in
Africa and and grow trees and shit you
know and trust me you're still part of
the Machine anyway because not for
profit still would need to receive money
from people who have extra to give so
about fucking money and I hate to sound
that way but look
you've got to put shoes on your feet you
got to put food in your belly what are
you gonna do
you can't even grow your own fucking
vegetables without owning a plot of land
what are you gonna do right you still
gotta pay taxes on that fucking land you
can escape but look you can be a bum on
the street but still what do bums do beg
what do they beg for money so they can
put a morsel in their mouth can't get
out of this fucking thing you're already
in the game figuring out how to play it
well whether it's through school or some
other service you're in this okay unless
you want to sit and meditate under a
tree but the owner of that land that
tree is on probably kick you off or you
got to get you got to get a permit from
the government to sit under that tree so
fucking there's no Buddhists today ah
Buddha ain't sitting under the Bodhi
tree over here because he's gonna
there's an ordinance against him he
needs he needs a license from the city
to sit under that fucking tree or if
it's privately owned the owner of that
land is gonna kick him off you're in
this thing forget it you're in it
do the best that you can serve people
don't lose your heart don't lose
yourself and you'll be just fine