so guys we've got a really good question
from our buddy Stottlemeyer anyway
that's your user name and he's 16 years
old and he goes on to say that there was
a bunch of different things here he
tenses up and punches walls because he
gets very very angry he essentially
doesn't like people it's pretty angry
with people angry with civilization
angry with himself to such a degree that
he's contemplated suicide he wants
solitude he's sick of living with his
mother he wants to get out of the home
but he's under 18 he's just really tense
fucked up and angry at the world and
himself but he's clearly a very
intelligent kid and he's spending a lot
of time studying psychology and
philosophy and physiology society
sociology all these things interest him
greatly
so as the 16 years / 16 year old is
putting all his time and effort into
studying this shit while he's dealing
with this anger now I'm gonna make an
assumption and you can correct me later
on but whether or not this is true hear
me out there's no father figure in your
life that's my assumption if you do have
a father
perhaps that's in the home he is not
fulfilling the fatherly or the
patriarchal role to the degree that you
need him to right this is a completely
an assumption but hear me out so every
man every boy because an actor 16 years
old you're becoming a man has to have a
a male figure to contrast himself
against grow with would also fight they
say that the master the the student has
to kill the master if you're familiar
with Oedipus Rex that of his complex you
are familiar with how Oedipus kills his
dad marries his mom this is a very old
idea that's deep-rooted in our
psychology and the fact is we live in a
patriarchal hierarchy it's a society
that you can't stand that you're
fighting against a civilization as you
describe it is a patriarchal hierarchy
so the ways
civilization is built up is such that
there's always someone dominating you
you know we
police the government your boss whatever
the case may be outside the home the
world is set up so that there are a lot
there are a lot of angry fathers
watching you and even our God is a big
father in the sky watching you when you
take a shit in the UK you can't go
anywhere without Daddy watching you
right and you call this a patriarchal
hierarchy so without a father figure
actual father figure in your life that
you can kill per se in order to fulfill
the obligation of this oedipal complex
you are now wanting to kill civilization
because it represents the father through
this patriarchal hierarchy
so just to recap there's no actual
father figure in your life for you to
fight against in the natural way that
every boy has to every boy has to reject
his father in order to become a man
himself right this is just a wave this
is the way we operate
so you're projecting that need to fight
against a father figure on society on on
civilization which is a better way to
describe it and this shows up in you
being angry and punching walls and
having tunnel vision breaking shit and
wanting to hurt people what you need and
the invitation is to go and find a
mentor father figure that you can go and
talk to so that you can fight him so
that you can get this out energetically
through the relationship with a male
rather than fighting the world because
the world's gonna fuck you up you can't
fight the world right you kids I mean
they got drones and shit they'll find
you and bomb you so they did to the guy
in California right that uh the decided
to fight the police he was a cop he
realized how fucked up the whole thing
was and God has asked you can't beat
civilization you don't even try I know
you want to be by yourself but it's the
most dangerous thing that you can do you
describe solitude if you go into
solitude you're without resolving this
Oedipus oedipal complex within you
you're simply going to carry it in
to later stages of development and
you're going to be thwarted in your
personal evolution you're 16 years old
right now so this is the perfect time to
reject daddy daddy's not dead there so
find a mentor if I go like to the big
boys club or if you have an uncle or a
an older male figure uncle's are usually
the best to do this with because they
care about you they love you but they're
not necessarily heavily invested in
keeping you down because you would
supersede him like the father-son role
so look for a man that understands male
evolution that understands psychology if
you can afford it or if you have
insurance get find a very good
psychotherapist psychoanalyst that you
could work with because he psychoanalyst
understand this
I mean Freud introduced the idea of the
Oedipus complex
oedipal complex so a psychotherapist
would understand this that might be the
better bet if you can if you can work
with a psychotherapist that understands
the oedipal complex and your need as a
boy to fight him and for you to
recognize that you're gonna be fighting
him right because you're gonna reject
him we play this out often I mean over
and over and over again in our lives
with other male figures you know some of
us are more male than others so we fight
with a lot of men that seem to be above
us in some way shape or form if you're
aware of what's going on and you work
with a therapist or a mentor and you
both understand that you're going to
have to fight him at some point in order
to assert yourself in order to grow up
you need the challenge of going beyond
that male figure you're going to move
out of this stage of development that is
currently pathological you're going to
come out on the other end as a as a
stronger version of yourself as a man
who's on his way to growing in maturity
so that's it my friend good luck you're
not you're not a bad person you're not
fucked up there's nothing wrong with you
you need a male figure in your life to
emulate to fight against and then to
have as a mentor as you grow stronger
and OH
more mature in your own life good luck
buddy