what the fuck are you doing today that's
not a runway that's all of fun you're
late just lost I'm in one of my favorite
places right now in st. Pete one of my
favorite people my buddy ryan we meant
like 10 years ago when I first moved
down here through strongman training and
stuff like that but uh we both evolved
over that time one of the things Ryan
has evolved into is a men's fashion
expert he's really uh really teaches
dudes how to dress well but not just how
to dress well how to dress particular to
your character to who you are cause a
bad boy style yes brother well ya like
like you always talked about the you
know the archetypes king or in tradition
lover I kind of acquired that and
started looking at that from like more
of a style angle and really trying to
pull people not so much make them dress
into something but see who they are kind
of pull that out of them and it started
working really well with a lot of like
clients i had and people are just giving
advice to you and even with myself but
one thing I learned was basically how an
outfit that you put together and we're
directly correlates with the type of
girl that talks to you or the type of
guy that talks to you and all these
things when you're learning style and
learning you know fashion like they were
really interesting to me because you
know if you're trying to make more money
get a better career you want to attract
the proper people into your life right
if you're trying to get laid or meet
women you want to attract a certain type
of woman into your life and that may or
may not be a woman I just want to sleep
with you maybe you want one that's
career oriented goal-oriented right not
whatever whatever you're wearing is
going to attract the type of team to you
yeah so what you're saying but not
everybody is going to be comfortable
just saying oh well you need to wear a
suit so you gotta wear a suit right
sorry wants to do that I don't like
wearing suits personally I have a worn
one ever really but I know how to dress
up so with certain aspects of that
there's like basically two archetypes
she's like you know yeah like king and a
magician and lover with fashion is like
bad boy and Wall Street so you know the
guys that wear suits all the time and
the guys that kind of work cool jackets
tighter jeans like badass shoes and
they're like singing up on stage women
are like oh we love you so I wanted it
like a
rid of that like I wanted to be like oh
he looks like he's a boss makes a lot of
money but he also looks badass like
every girl wants to talk to him hmm so I
kind of like something right in the
middle I've you can go far less and go
straight suit wear that all the time but
know that there is a lot of people with
that it's very expensive you got about a
lot of suits or else you are in the same
suit every day which if you're on a
budget that's probably not your best
option but what about like so yesterday
I didn't video this young dude he's in
college he's real focused on his grades
he's trying to go to grad school to
study neuroscience he dresses like a
fucking bum nobody and check some out
look he doesn't have a lot of money
either to two things I got two questions
for our man so I'm hooking you up dude i
made a video for you yesterday and now i
got my expert boy here hooking us up
with some real real solid information
number one yo how does he develop a
style for himself how does like somebody
who's trying to be the strongest version
of themselves honor themselves be
different but also stand out and not
sell out when I say sell out meaning
like I don't want to wear this I want to
wear something I want to wear how do you
develop a style about around what you
wanna wear what really represents you
and how do we do it without breaking the
bank that's the other thing cool well
number one is everything I'm about to
tell you is probably if your guys sit at
home and you're that guy wearing
sweatpants it's gonna be way outside
your comfort zone so no matter what
you're about to do what you're going to
buy we're gonna wear it's gonna feel
weird as shit at first so just know that
going in because you felt weird we
started dressing better do not be honest
you just got saved my life in a lot of
ways a great friend when I say saved my
life I mean basically I had been wearing
basketball shorts and strength camp
shirts forever since I met you all you
were yeah that Georgia wetter I was no
better yeah we're kind of blue
we were at but um as my business started
evolving as my relationship started
evolving as my family started growing it
was almost like will you pointed it out
to meet it was like you know your kind
of selling yourself short by not
dressing a little bit better to
represent you know who you are where
you're at and even your core values why
don't you try something a little
different and when you introduce me to
some types of clothing at first I was
like sweet dude I'll never wear that
don't even point to it I put it on I
realized wow it really does make me feel
better so yeah it's like so if you're
sitting at home watching it's like no
then it's gonna feel weird so even
getting out off your couch going to the
mall and maybe shopping in different
stores it's going to be weird you're not
gonna be comfort with it but no just
like weight lifting and personal growth
you got to get out of your comfort zone
to do cool shit so that's number one
just know that going in so everything
but if you're trying to develop your
personal style don't just try it like I
said don't try to just wear a suit just
because you think that that's what you
should do like that's not you that may
not be that may be who you are that may
not be who you are but one thing you
want to do is think about it like you're
what are you into you what are your
sports what are your hobbies like so
let's say you're really in the football
well you don't want to dress like a fan
you want to dress like the top football
player in the week what is he oh wow no
doubt like so if you're a football fan
instead of putting on a football jersey
you look at what they wear when they're
giving press conferences no doubt okay
that makes sense check out the actual
player and see what he's weapon now
there's some you know don't go to into
that because Amy we're a big gold chains
and flash like a good expense are you
get expensive and you might have to wear
fake stuff but that might not be your
style either so you want to kind of just
say oh well you know he wears a lot of
like you know well cut like jackets and
like maybe some nice Jean you tell he's
got a nice shirt on most likely all
their stuff is tailored so it's like
look at these little points with people
that you see and kind of say okay well
maybe I could take like the jacket from
that guy and then like let's say were
kind of like watching basketball too
let's see what they're wearing or when
they go when they walk up cuz basketball
guys have really good style when they're
going to the game right thank you just
like real nice but then still have on
sneakers yeah just look at how they're
dressing and kind of marry that into
like your own style and take okay what
kind of music in my to do I like country
music we're punching music is more like
cool cowboy boots and like some
like frayed jeans and maybe like a nice
tailored but enough okay maybe you can
take a nice jacket from your basketball
heritage indie like yours button up with
your jeans and your cowboy boots and
you're looking pretty good I mean those
are just short examples but like I like
take about ten you know like do like a
personal I don't know the value a shin
of like your interests and hobbies cuz
for me like I grew up riding bikes and
racing BMX I didn't want to always had
that athlete vibe so I didn't want to
when you so when a guy comes to consult
with you the first thing you do is
assess him getting what his interests
are what his values off what his
aspirations are and instead of trying to
fit him into a style yeah you just try
to blend it around here bring it into
him I mean and the now obviously some
things are going to be a little
different if they're like dressing like
the guy that asked a question and is you
know basketball shorts a t-shirt pretty
much you're doing it all wrong so we got
to start from a blank canvas here so
then you ask okay well you know what
sports you into what hobbies you like
what music you into and the big question
is what do you want to portray right so
like that's the big question so none of
the else could matter was like what do I
want to portray if you want to portray
rich successful making a lot of money
well you have to dress nice there's no
way around it now you can there are
people that like I wear what I want
because I have a millionaire well if
you're not a millionaire you can't do
that so um yeah because you know what
you can't afford 8240 that's the thing
so yo let's let's rap about that though
too because you know looking good
doesn't have to cost a lot of money
right i mean there's options for so you
want to get a jacket maybe you taught me
that maybe you could buy a cheaper
jacket but take it to the tailor for 10
bucks and have it hooked up a little bit
what are some tips for getting our hands
on clothes that represents us that we
love but is also affordable yeah the
number one is there's some kind of two
rules that I tend to go by and that's
first it's got to fit you perfectly and
a lot of people have this stigma with
Taylor and they think it's really
expensive well I maybe spend 20 bucks at
most at the tailor and that's if like I
have to like redo a pair of pants to fit
me hmm but most of like your guys that
work on Wall Street most year you know
really wealthy people that were really
well fitting suits and clothes all the
time they're all custom-made for them
well that's really expensive so it's
like well you can take a shirt that
maybe cost you twenty bucks go to a
local tailor and spend 10 to get it made
for and then that shit look like it's
made for you it looks like it's made for
you it cost you thirty bucks yeah so
mostly don't even know that that option
exists so that's like number one is like
make sure all your clothes fit properly
some people follow our lucky and they
fall into a body type where it actually
fits companies very well so I they don't
need that dude cuz clothes companies
don't really make clothes for guys that
lift to know I mean what's the a lot of
times I'm having to get my I'm short as
well so I'm having to get my pad
tailored for my quad size for the length
also upper body we tend to be broad so
if you a lot of the guys are watched as
they lift so if the situation is that
like yo you go to the nice you buy a
nice piece of clothing or something that
you want aware that you know we look
good but it can't fit you know ten bucks
fifteen maybe by the next size up take
it to the tailor and have her you know
or hit her him whichever might the girl
i use is like an asian lady and she just
she's like a magician with that shit
she's like I get it back two days later
and it's like this bit so fit is number
one at fit is number one and like I said
if you can't afford tailoring just try
to get the closest you can you don't
want extra fabric on the sides you don't
want to like your shirt like blowing
over the top of your belt if you if
you're you know you're pulling your
pants up and just make sure it fits you
nice and uh you know not a lot of extra
fabric mm-hmm so uh what about where to
shop to buy clothing like how do we get
clothes that doesn't cost too much well
these are where like going backs on
getting out of your comfort zone you're
probably going to start shopping at
places that you might not necessarily
know exist or ever thought to walk into
I know the guy asked the question I
don't know where you are from in the
country or world mmm so there's a good
chance you probably have an H&M and H&M
is very they call it fast fashion set
over here bother it's it's very cheap
yeah it's it's very cheap that's where I
would start because most of their stuff
is really it's already pretty tailored
but it's not going to last you a while
so you're going to buy clothes there
there last you like 3-4 months you have
to go back get it again so there's shoes
like disposable clothes but that's
pretty dope like if you know you're
gonna go out and just once yeah if you
won't have you like man I gotta look
good for this I have this event in there
there's gonna be like you know I'm a
budding neuro scientist or the other
neuroscientist there I got to look good
well H&M has suits for like a hundred
bucks let me ask you a question though
so why do you want to stand out like
you're gonna be a bunch of other dudes
in your niche meaning neuroscientist
students entrepreneurs maybe not
businessmen but people who are of like
mind they all tend to dress the same way
right well do we want a dress to fit in
with our title like a lot of times that
means dressing down or what impetus do
we have to dress up or to be a little
bit more significant than our dress than
most of the people in our niche our crew
our cult you know oh yeah so like you
were saying one of the things that I
thought Elliot when he first started
dressing better is is if everybody's
dressed in a certain way but leave made
a video on being memorable you don't
want to be too memorable you don't be
the guy that's like you want it in trick
yeah you don't want to show up at the
beach wearing a suit that's just weird
like you don't be that guy so you want
to be what I call one level above every
where you're going and to do this you
really just take a take a mental note
like okay I'm going to a fancy dinner
when you say fancy what's everybody
they're gonna be wearing are they gonna
be wearing because you know casual the
brown slacks and the avoiding up not
Taylor right this is what they wear it
normally when I watch this cuz now I pay
attention so I have on the brown slacks
maybe some boat shoes didn't like the
button up my dad calls it hillbilly
shirts but they're plaid yeah so that's
how a man when I go to like the birthday
party like I go to kids birthday parties
for my children or eventually caught
that's how all the dads dress so I end
up going to like dad events yeah they're
all dads
and uh and in order to sort of be one
level above I gotta take off the
business casual yeah I ever wear wear
some fitted jeans wear like a nice like
solid color t-shirt wear some nice shoes
I just go like a little extra not too
much but just a little bit so that's
like one thing um and that's all like I
guess geographic or demographic base
because if you're living in New York
City it's very hard to go one level
above unless you have a lot of money
right if you're Petersburg Florida all
right so like if you're living in like
Idaho you probably don't have to try
very hard right like because most guys
are wearing t-shirts from high school
and cargo shorts and like Nike Nike
sneakers that aren't even full nike
sneakers so why you just look at okay
where am I going what's the average
dress gonna be there and then you just
go one step above that so just for
example if it's a wedding a lot of he'll
go to weddings and no idea how to dress
I call it the average wedding guy suit I
hear it's like baggy like dress pants
they always have anything that always
ill-fitting ill phanie they always say
that I'm down the center yeah um they
always have like their old brown loafers
sometimes they don't even match the belt
so it looks real weird and they have a
shirt that's like what it has called
male muffin top so when you tuck it in
it like lil orzo bags oh I hate that and
all that comes up yeah and then the back
it makes you look like a marshmallow man
so did it that's like average so you
just want to go okay well let me just go
get a nice pair of like dark dark jeans
nice pair of dress shoes get my shirt
tailored boom you're good now if they
happen to be wearing ties you go instead
of just wearing a regular time been
worse let me tie with a tie bar just a
little bit different not eccentric not
over-the-top not something where you're
kind of drawing attention to yourself
like a peacock yeah you don't want to do
the peacock getting a lot of people get
stuck in that they want to wear like a
cowboy hat or like it's like no I've
done that yeah a lot of I got dumb shit
there's this fun to do that sometimes
you know they say that the dress makes
the man but the way I used to stay in my
videos and those you watch my videos you
understand what I say you put on a cape
you're gonna be like fuck
Superman right so the way you carry
yourself deep your closing is an
extension of your posture even the way
you carry yourself way you dress where
you present yourself not only affects
other people and how they're going to
react to you really what it does is
affects your core affects how you carry
yourself how do you feel about yourself
and your own self-esteem so I think
conversations like this ideas like this
the information that right and I are
providing you guys with today is
essential to becoming a stronger version
of yourself to be a king which you are
represent yourself like it came by
carrying yourself like a king and paying
attention to your clothing is not
shallow paying attention to your
clothing and dress is that something
that you do because you're trying to be
better than anyone else or prove
yourself or or anything beyond just
express yourself fully be fully you be
dignified in your own character and be
the strongest version yourself so check
it out Ryan has got a YouTube channel
handsome is it handsome guys now it's my
name still Ryan McGee no doubt that's
perfect just Elliott home I think it's
where I'm again calm though wave you
searched my name on you but anyway I
want to put a link down below he puts up
tips everyday now I even got four to
four to five days a week go to five days
a week traction tips shit that you guys
will find useful if you're trying to
dress on a budget and you want to design
a style just for you ryan also has some
products about how to design a style
just for you style basics I think these
things are important for you guys know
about there's a link down below to see
that also it because you want answered i
see chris is my main
good so that's it I brought you my best
friend today to hook you up with some
fucking clothing tips so that you guys
can walk in the royalty that surrounds
you you are kings just like done