this is how I learned one of the most
powerful principles of living
successfully on earth this and you can't
teach this to anybody you can't tell
this to anybody you have to fucking
experience you got to go out and do
something that puts you in a situation
where you you're in dire straits in
order to see this magical happening dude
I kid you not I would live up until the
last day of the month with zero ability
to pay the rent I don't have the money
my credit cards are maxed out I don't
have a new client I don't know what I'm
gonna do I would say to Colleen okay we
start preparing I'd say okay so the
first thing we're going to cut off is
the cable right that we just don't need
TV anymore turn that off you know I was
like thirty dollars a month whatever
then we'll turn off the electricity then
we'll turn then and so there are certain
things like we'll stop paying this bill
will stop paying that but we had a plan
it was like okay cuz we're coming up I
don't have any fucking money there's no
money I never Fred it was never worried
it's always like okay cool this is the
way this is the way it is this is how
we're going to proceed every single time
I kid you not call it God call it magic
call the universe call it fucking luck
if you want but every single time the
money just appeared it just appeared
essentially somebody would call me hey
Elliott
I'd like to come to your gym today I
want to see what it's all about they
would sign up oh and I want my wife to
sign up too or I want my child to sign
up too boom just enough money pay the
bill every fucking time dude I don't
it's unbelievable how magical that shit
worked then it got even worse because I
was in such debt that I was about to go
bankrupt and we hired a company to to
help me avoid bankruptcy and the guy was
like okay bro you're gonna have to pay
it was something like three grand a
month three grand a fucking month that
was more than my mortgage and my M I ran
he was like this is the only way we
could do it Elliott do you think you can
make it happen
well I'm like in my mind I'm like I
don't have fucking 3 grand a month bro I
can't do this just I'm gonna have to do
the bankruptcy and he said Elliot can
you do this
said yeah I can because I knew at that
point I had experienced just enough I've
experienced it enough times to know that
if I commit to something if I say yes
it's going to happen it's going to
happen and it's going to happen fucking
magically I put in the effort I put in
the intention that this is what's going
to happen and then I go to work and I
don't know how it's going to work but it
just fucking works every single time
call me blessed call me lucky I don't
know what the fuck you want to call me
but when I set my mind on something when
I have a clear intention and I say yes
this is going to happen if fucking
happens that's the God's honest truth
and the most difficult thing for me at
this point in my life is figure out what
I want next conviction intention and
conviction intend what you want and be
so convinced that it's going to happen
that it just fucking happens and I wish
I could say I wish I could be like oh
here's how I made it happen see that
would be I'll be really pleasing to my
ego and it would be very pleasing to
everybody watching these videos like ok
boom let's get let's hear it out of it
step 1 what you do step 2 step 3 step 4
there was no fucking steps there was
this is what I want this is what's going
to happen now I'm going to do whatever
work is available to me right now
something else made that shit magically
happen
call it whatever you will
I take full credit full credit
hardcore credit yes like fuck Abama
talking about you didn't do this I did I
take full credit for 50% of the fucking
game the other 50% something else Allah
don't care call whatever you want
something that I had no hand in
supported the other 50% you just put
your you put your fucking work and you
do your half the other half will be done
for you problem is most people the
number of things happen for most people
they never get clear about what they
want so there's no intention there's no
intention whatsoever they say oh I'd
like I like this I like that this would
be nice
boy I wish they never say this is what's
going to happen that's that's usually
where most people fuck up is that very
first step this is what's going to
happen which is your intention and then
conviction that it's going to happen I
knew it was going to happen it was just
a matter of time so that's that's one
part of it one part of it is people they
don't get very clear about what they
want second part is they never put in a
full 50 percent I say give 50 percent
not 50 percent of your effort you give
100 percent of your effort but you
fulfill 50 percent of what has to happen
knowing that just by doing your part
you're setting off the domino effect in
some cosmic way that the other 50
percent is going to be taken care of so
you have to have faith you have to have
faith that the work that you're putting
in is fulfilling your half and then you
step away and allow success to happen