buddy Mike's got a question about how to
handle a best friend that he's had for
the past 10 years who is diametrically
opposed are completely different from
one another so now that they're kind of
growing up it's been 10 years they've
been friends forever his friend tends to
be more antisocial introverted and he's
very extroverted right social he's
reached a point where he wants to he
feels this is for his friends holding
him back because he wants to go out into
life and he wants to go meet new friends
you wants to be social but his friend is
kind of like let's go to the movies
let's stay in let's play video games
anyone to know what to do like how do I
deal with the situation because I love
this guy he's my best friend for 10
years but I want to go out this is an
important question because you're going
to face it a lot of times in your life
this you're just facing it now you're
young and you got your friend but when
you have a family what you're going to
experience is that you've got children
when you're an adult especially adult
male hanging out with children isn't
always your idea of a good time right
this has just been my experience I've
for children and I don't always want to
play with my little pony dolls right I
mean I'll do it because I love my
daughters and they want to like curl the
hair and stuff and daddy needs to come
in like okay daddy could you be this one
and gallop and it's like well I'd rather
be smoking cigars with my buddy and down
the block you know I'd rather be playing
pick a basketball at my gym right we
just got a basketball hoop so even play
basketball every every day I'd rather go
train you dope really the type of person
I'd I am is to go out and do other
things then rather than play my little
pony with my daughters but because of
the love that I have in my heart for
that person right my daughter's a person
your friend is a person I reserve time
for them so what you're going to have to
do is because you love and appreciate
your friend you are going to look for
and offer him reserved time for him now
when you use that reserve time when you
offer that reserve time for him do what
he
wants to do do or find a common bond
that you have if you if both of you
really enjoy a particular video game
that's your video time video game time
together with him if you guys enjoy you
know dressing up like Star Trek geeks or
whatever it is that that common thing
that you have together right you
obviously you've grown right obviously I
smoke cigars and play basketball my
daughter doesn't but you can't bring
that in over here right I can bring
cigars and basketball to my daughter you
can't bring your social butterfly pneus
to your antisocial friend so you find
that you either yield by doing it out of
love as long as there's no animosity if
you feel animosity while you're doing it
you're ready you're better off not doing
it when I'm brushing the princess
celestia's hair I'm fully engaged in
brushing Princess Celestia's hair right
because I love my daughter and I'm
engaged at that moment because I've
offered that time for her and I don't
bring other shit into it with your buddy
you can keep him you should keep him you
guys have a long history together but
don't compare him to your other social
friends don't expect him to do the other
social things don't expect him to even
want to talk about it leave it out and
then focus on the person that you have
committed to for that particular time it
shouldn't be seen as a sacrifice it
should be seen as a time a time of
growth in that relationship you're
growing that relationship where you're
maintaining that relationship nothing
really is maintaining its always growing
and because you love that dude you're
going to give it to him good luck