got a good question from one of our
buddies who has been a really good
mentor to he's 20 years old so he's been
a really good mentor to his younger
brother he's also the type of guy that
tends to have it all together you know
he's a strong individual in many regards
and because of his strength and Magnum
unity right his magnetic qualities he's
able to attract and support other people
in becoming the strongest versions of
themselves and he feels really good
about this the problem is now that he
needs someone to pull him up and one of
the problems with being really strong is
that no one ever asks you if you're okay
no one ever comes to you in the same way
that you generally reach out to other
people and I know because I've
experienced this I tend to be the rock
that most people lean on and even
through my live through the videos that
I create it's always Elliot supporting
other people in becoming the strongest
version of themselves where is it and
how is it that you can find someone that
can pull you up it has been a challenge
of mine and it's something that really
used to bother me to a really at a real
visceral level for so many years I'm to
the point where I wanted to cry because
it's like who can I lean on and I know
that's your problem I know that's what
you're dealing with in your asking me
how do I go find a mentor how do I find
someone that could support me because to
everyone in my world I'm always the
strongest what I found is that there are
two types of mentors that have been most
valuable in my journey to becoming a
stronger version of myself number one is
that through books you're going to find
that there are certain individuals who
have written written volumes and volumes
of text that will support you in almost
every area and endeavor in your life
alright so for example Ralph Waldo
Emerson has been dead since you know the
1800s but in my mind he's a mentor of
sorts because whenever I am struck with
a problem when I'm struck with
what how should I proceed in life I
always seem to find the right words in
his essays they just resonate with me
I've been lucky enough to have found
that type of mentor but he's a dead man
right and thankfully left behind all of
his ideas to support so many other
people in becoming stronger versions of
themselves that's one type and and
that's one that hopefully I provide for
a lot of people through through the
videos that I create you know I'm not
really there right here you don't know
me I don't know you but through the
words and the ideas of an individual you
are uplifted right and hopefully you can
find that in someone and now I'm happy
to be able to serve you in that way so I
know you watch my videos but you also
need someone who's there with you who's
talking to you who you can touch and see
you know what I'm saying a natural
tangible individual who's going to
support you and it's not easy to find
that type of person in fact those that
are greatest that are more able to help
you than others in that regard probably
are really busy their time is spoken for
on so many different levels because
they're that type of person I found that
the only way that I can get close to
that type of person is by paying them
when I say I have mentors and I go see
mentors it's not that I was so lucky
that some older man took me under his
wing which will happen there will be
some older guys in your community in
your church in your community you know
organization whatever the case may be
that'll help you but they're busy too
they probably have their own families
but to get the undivided attention of
someone who you know has that magnetic
strength that we mentioned earlier that
you have right to give you that
undivided attention for the period of
time and for the kotl issues that you're
dealing with you're going to have to
trade a portion of your energy with that
person so that they can give you that
because their time is valuable
I pay hundreds of dollars thousands
sometimes for coaches for mentors for
people that I can that I need to get
there under
at attention I need to to gain insights
and wisdom based on their experience and
the things that they can see that I
simply can't see excuse me
so that's my invitation to you my
invitation to you is to is to find
people who are abstract obviously
through video or ebooks but also
understand that you're going to have to
trade something you're going to have to
pay somebody to take you in the
direction that you would like to go in
particular realms of personal
development or business yeah I might
have a mentor that's that it helps me
out in psychology but I also have one
that will help me out in business
development that's going to help me out
with spiritual parts of my life that
will help me out with the physical parts
of my life
trainers do you see so and none of those
people come across because if they did
then they would be drained from every
angle and wouldn't be able to support
those who really invest in them so go
and invest in a mentor that's my advice
good luck buddy