we got a question about fighting from
one of our buddies in Dublin he's 17
years old from Dublin Ireland
so there's walking cross street today
and I had my headphones on I noticed a
big force smacking me hard on my head
forced my uh my headphones will fall off
then I looked up and saw people
hysterically laughing on the other side
of road I had been hit with a potato
from these lads my age and and I walked
away I knew that I'd never win a fight
between five or six lads but at the same
time I don't want people like that
trampling all over me of course while
having a great laugh well stinking of
punching the guy who did it in his face
if I see him again but I'm not sure if
that will only make things worse he
lives in my estate what should I have
done what should I do
really good fucking question I've had
this experience before I'm gonna share
an idea with you that is that's a bit
radical but it's old school you know I
think a lot of our problem is that we've
let go of the old schools are just
traditions that our great grandfathers
did and one of the things was when two
men had a problem they dealt with it for
him to throw that potato at you and
giggle with his little friends and
scamper off was really fucking cowardly
you know it was cowardly and you made
the right choice by not approaching them
in that particular state for a number of
reasons number one there were five or
six of them you're right they probably
jump you and kick your ass and it would
just escalate and you gain no respect
whatsoever by by doing that you just be
like that douche bag but they can pick
on more now right so you walked away
good choice the other thing is if you
approached him you would be probably
from moving from a very ungrounded place
you're emotionally attached you got
smacked in the face with a fucking
potato dude you're gonna be happy
very unrestored you'll find as you move
through life to react in the moment
because you're ungrounded when you're
ungrounded you're not you're not
conscious of what you're about to do and
whatever activity is produced doesn't
come from your true essence doesn't come
it doesn't satisfy you because like if
you did punch him in the face
you might feel really fucking good for
the moment but then you come to realise
that that wasn't you that was anger
doing that that was an ungrounded
version of yourself which
it never allows you to embody your words
or your actions so you really don't get
any satisfaction from it right it didn't
come from your balls just came from your
fucking fists but good thing how's the
lighting here Suns been moving but
you're in a good place right now because
you've taken your time you've thought
about it you came to Elliot host a
little bit of advice and what I would
invite you to do is to approach him
perhaps when he's with his friends and
just offer a situation that he might
want to engage in right and you set the
rules for this opportunity okay
you woke up to him and when he's with
his friends and you got to eat the thing
is your energy is very important you got
to approach him from a very I'm
breathing got my hands in my pocket
maybe you know not looking to fight I'm
not ready to do anything right now you
know you're kind of like you look
everybody in their eyes don't look angry
just look kind of matter of fact he said
hey you guys threw a potato at me the
other day right they're gonna be
completely yeah what motherfucker we're
gonna be completely ungrounded you're
gonna be hysterical doing me crazy and
their crazy fucking mob and you've got
to be you've got to be aware that's why
you have to be ground you got to be
aware of their fucking their energy they
start acting up by the way you know that
they're they're hooligans there's
there's nothing manly about them they're
a bunch of fucking little children who
are getting back at their daddies right
bear with the noise so you've got to
take notice out there they're
particularly meaner when you do that
because if they're all if they're a
bunch of hyenas then just step away say
hey look I might need to speak to you
guys about something but right now is at
the time I mean let me rethink that
because if they're acting like fucking
hooligans
you got to be strong enough to bring
their energy down and you might start
with hey guys I'm not upset with you
especially the ones that didn't throw it
that's a better approach because you
can't win if they start act like
hooligans you can't run
that'll make things worse you gotta have
some balls here dude say guys I'm not
upset with you not upset with you I just
I want to ask you a question I wanna
share something with you you say it to
the guy that you know this new community
that threw it to you said I didn't like
when you threw that at me
and I would appreciate if you apologized
right there's two parts of this
appreciate if you apologize and give
them that opportunity you know say if
you apologize these you know we could be
done and then there's no harm done I'll
forget shake hands on it that's all
you're looking for you just looking for
acknowledgement just acknowledge that
you did this and you know I I didn't
like it I'm not upset with you but I'd
appreciate if you apologize but closure
to it looking for closure if he
apologizes dude walk away
say thanks look guys no harm done I'm
not angry at anyone just remind them
once again thank you for the apology and
then walk away hopefully you won't do it
again tell him not to do it again please
don't do it again you've got to be
really you've got to be really in your
balls to move this way and if you do if
you move this particular way regardless
of the outcome but if you move in this
particular way you're growing stronger
because this is a circumstance that
you're being posed in order to evolve in
this particular way so you pose him that
up that option say look you know no harm
done but please I'd like an apology now
again notice their energy but if he
refuses to give you an apology it's like
no motherfucker I'm not apologizing a
potato was meant for you
then you lay out the rules of the
engagement that you're about to get it
say all right well then I think maybe we
should fight you and I let's put it down
on the table and finish it squash it
right here you and me alone and you look
at his boys and you should probably
bring your boys with you too or have
them sit in the car or well I don't know
but if they're going to jump you you
might just get fucking jumped no
sometimes that's the risk you take
but you invite him now you give him
another invitation you and I let's fight
fist fight lay down the rules no weapons
bare fists are you interested in doing
that if you've got a problem with me
then you might be interested in taking
it out on me he might be bigger than you
might kick your ass but he'll respect
you I'm not saying that this is going to
win for you it's going to be a win in
other words the the external outcome is
going to be one that you want they might
they might fucking jump you but you will
have owned yourself you have gained
yourself you would have something
yourself respect is the most important
form of respect you might not gain their
respect you might there's a better
chance of you gaining their respect by
doing this than by doing nothing or by
like just punching him one day randomly
in the street from behind that's some
pussy shit I know they hurt you and they
were pussies but you want to be a pussy
too and if you approach them from a very
respectable place self respected place
and it doesn't turn out where he gives
you the apology or you whip his ass and
then it's you shake hands afterwards and
it's done very old-school shit right and
a lot of people gonna argue with me not
my hood Elliott that shit ain't happenin
my hood hey do you want to walk around
scared all the time
you might be better off getting your ass
kick you might be better off getting
your face punched in then walking around
with no respect for yourself and no
respect from them this affords you at
least the opportunity to gain some
respect for yourself
we've got to approach these boys and
this is the best way to approach him if
you say nothing you'll hate yourself and
they'll think you're a bitch so that's
it dude look I've been in situations
like this before and it hasn't always
worked out for the best but you have to
do it you got to put yourself in these
situations in order to grow to know
yourself and to respect yourself so
that's it dude
wish you the best continue to grow
stronger that's what this is all about
done