so the youngest of my four children is
my son Benjamin he'll be two in July so
it was still very tied to his primal
instincts and his nature you know he we
haven't conditioned him Tenny great
degree yet so he does things that are
that come natural to him when he becomes
upset like throws a temper tantrum
whenever we take something away from him
or you know tell me they can't have
something he gets very upset and he runs
towards the first inanimate object that
he could find with his hands like this
and it's not like this and goes to bite
it so if it's a table you'll go and try
to bite the table you'll try to bite the
couch and it's like it really doesn't
matter what it is it's just that his
mouth goes open his teeth show and it's
like whatever is in my way is gonna get
bitten he's tried to bite us before and
it's like we gotta handle that can't
bite people yeah so it got me thinking
about the significance of the mouth
because in one light the mouth can be
used as a organ of tenderness you're
kissing your lover it's soft it's
relaxed it's receptive and it brings
pleasure but it could also be used as
aggression are you bite just tear people
apart with your tongue even just say
things that really hurt people's
feelings but specifically physically is
what I'm talking about kissing or biting
the thing is that if we don't fully
express certain negative or aggressive
emotions that become trapped in our
muscles and that's why a lot of people
have really tight jaws tight a lot of
tension in their face and what that does
also is it it stops your ability to
relax into pleasure and to offer the
organ for tenderness because you're you
know you're stiff lipped that's where
the term comes from so I'm not making
this shit up stiff lips really tight ja
you ever noticed was really tight jawed
that's because there's they want to bite
essentially they know you can't bite
people but that instinct to bite to be
to aggress
especially through anger has been
suppressed and gets trapped in the
muscles so we don't want to share
something with you today this is really
important because if you want to be the
strongest version of yourself one of the
things that might be nice to access is
the tenderness of them out want to be a
good lover right without the aggression
tightness in your jaw and inability to
receive and give pleasure so you got to
get that fucking tension out of your
jaws right I showed you other exercising
things in the past that you can do hey
this guy what's fucking truck should go
bite him but um i'm going to show you
what i should probably do now what
you're going to do grabs a towel i got a
t-shirt here work up a charge first I've
showed you how to do this you know with
the bow or grounding anything like that
I've got other videos that you can take
a look at work up a charge or if you're
angry as it is you're already fucking
charge grab your t-shirt bite it and
that might release some of the tension
in your jaw just go fucking bite grab a
towel grab the teaser haha rip it apart
another thing that you can do is take
your fingers place it right about there
so in front of the ears some what were
the jaws muscles of the jaw open up your
mouth as wide as you can this one works
for me a lot better than the towel press
hard against those muscles because
they're very tense it's almost like
you're massaging it while you got the
mouth open and you make that aggressing
sound
ah
ah the more you let go and give in to
the exercise as opposed to watching
yourself from the outside of being
neurotic about your behavior the more
you'll get out of it you'll feel a bit
like headaches you can get headaches a
lot of its jaw tension try that exercise
release some of the tension in your jaw
will have less headaches you'll feel
better about yourself and maybe be a
better lover Elliot's it