hey so we got a really good question
here from one of our buddies who wants
to know how to be a good father even
though he didn't have one he says I grew
up without a father figure in my life I
look for substitutes wherever I could
find one but as you can imagine this led
me to some dark and ungrounded places as
I look for others approval at any cost
now I have a beautiful daughter that
means a strong father but how can I be
the father that she needs when I never
had that father figure in my life to
teach me what a man is and how a man
acts I looked at Elliot they look to you
Elliot for support because I know you
have three daughters and one son cool
I'm happy look to me for support but
just I want to warn you that this is all
an experiment and I think every single
parent at some point realizes that their
journey and Parenthood is all an
experiment we have certain ideas about
what we want to have happen we have
certain experiences that we're trying to
avoid for art you know we've had in our
childhood that we don't want our
children to have we also have the
challenges of the day which differ from
the challenges that we had when we were
children so for example I have a pretty
strong dad in that way he did a great
job of doing what a father should do in
order to support his children but the
challenges that he had with us are not
the same challenges that I have with my
children today you know for example when
I wanted to - you know I'm a boy so I
had to call little girls houses if I
wanted to like you know I'm smitten by
the little little girl so no 13 years
old and I could hold the fucking house
and speak to their dad like hi mister
so-and-so can I speak to your daughter
oh who is this oh oh do you go to school
together there's this whole totally
different dynamic then now my daughter
is gonna be 10 years old and although
it's not connected to the world she has
a little iPhone right we gave her one of
her old iPhones and I realized that at
some point you know we're gonna connect
it and she's gonna be text messaging and
boys are gonna they're gonna call me in
a text message her it's a totally
different one I know a lot of you guys
can relate to that because you're a lot
younger than me you know the technology
is different the values are different
the world is just different so how do I
keep up with the way the world is
surfer in a way that yeah there's a
lined with currents life and and where
we're going as a culture and retain a
lot of the values that I feel supported
me in my evolution that my dad instilled
in us I mean let me put it this way my
dad we didn't even have cable TV in my
house and it wasn't cuz there was no
cable you know it did exist and I wasn't
could we couldn't afford it my dad was
just like no fuck that you're not having
cable you know totally different world
what do I do I mean there only is cable
now for a television you know although
we don't watch very much television we
only got one in the house it's uh you
know we can they can watch any movie
that they want at any particular moment
so just the things are different but
there are principles and that's a
beautiful thing about getting to the
core of how to live life that's that's
really like the the foundation of all of
my studies and really Mike my thirst for
wisdom comes from how to live life and
what are the core fundamental principles
that you can use to navigate life no
matter how it changes if you study
Joseph Campbell and his hero's journey
book I mean the guy was brilliant he
will show you how there were certain
principles that were upheld and
propounded by our ate our ancestors you
know he makes mention of Jesus you know
in that mythological way Jesus and and
and many of our other ancient
philosophies and religions and then
makes reference to George Lucas and the
Star Wars trilogy now one is like old
stories from our ancestors shit that
happened like before we had shoes maybe
not and then George Lucas who happened
to be highly influenced by Joseph
Campbell created the Star Wars trilogy
and if you look at the characters look
and also the matrix is another
interesting one it's always this how to
live as a person underneath the tyranny
of an empire right and it's always been
that way
be it the the the Roman Empire or the
the Egyptian Empire or the Mayan Empire
or
the American Empire I mean it's a global
Empire now it's a global empanada
economic Empire how do we live like Luke
Skywalker did how do we live like Jesus
did you know during the Roman Empire
Jesus
we're in Star Wars it's the Empire this
is called the fucking Empire you know
Darth Vader who turns out to be his
father interesting one there you might
want to look into the psychology behind
that patriarchy Luke I am your father no
shit
look it's Luke Skywalker the stories are
about how to navigate life in those
particular days but these the principles
and the construct is exactly the same
you got to understand you got to see
this
history does this the the details are
different but the thing is exactly the
same and the principles are exactly the
same the spirit exactly the same so I
often look to ancient ideals or
mythology old religious ideas philosophy
to discover these ideas that I share
with you guys and they're just a handful
of fucking principles there's not that
much that you really need to know
because everything else is just detailed
as long as you have the foundation
principles anyway as it comes to child
wearing and and an egg curry anything in
your life there are a handful of
principles that are gonna support you
their core values as opposed to tips and
techniques about how to manipulate your
world and your children and and I found
a really interesting book a really good
book because I looked for exactly what
you were thinking about which is a book
called strong father strong daughters I
mean you knows before my daughter was
even born I bought this I was like oh
boom I got to get it and I truly believe
that this book has some very sound
principles about how to use core
principles in order to navigate the
development of a young daughter through
the hands of his/her father in this day
and age right so the tips and techniques
again are secondary but the but the the
principles are those that you might even
heard me talk about in other videos I'm
just going to read the actual I'm gonna
read the chapters to you here so you can
see exactly what's gonna go on if you're
going again I give the book by wreck
I would say go get it if you have
daughters chapter number one you are the
most important man in her life and for a
long time and perhaps forever you will
be in your particular way know that
ultimately she'll move on that's the
world who live in but you are the most
important man in her life know this
number two she needs a hero number three
you are her first love
number four teach her humility chapter
five protect her defend her and use the
shotgun if necessary Chapter six
and by the way this was written by a
woman go figure right Chapter six
and this was probably my favorite of all
chapters it's called pragmatism in grits
two of your greatest assets and
pragmatism and grit is real really the
way she describes it in the book and if
you study the differences between men
and women the energetic differences
between us
studied energetic differences between
men and women you will come to come to
realize that one of the strengths of men
right because we have to be honest here
folks men and women are not the same
we're equal but not the fucking same and
you know it's it's a good idea to take
notice sense to the differences that we
have and then build up recognize and use
the tools that each one of us has at our
disposal and one of the things that men
have a better prepend encinas idea of
pragmatism and grits we're a little bit
more analytical more heady all right
that's why they say the man is the head
of the family I mean that he's a head of
the family like in front of the family
he's the head of the family just it just
tends to be our particular nature and
when there are decisions to be made
pragmatism you know just looking at
things pragmatically being objective
women are far more subjective subjects
objection is is kind of a female thing
feelings are associated with an internal
a lot women's intelligence is more
internal Brian ours is more outward
right just look at that again look at
the nature of the penises which I know
one takes in the other goes out but
anyway recognize that and use that there
are times we have to detach from the
emotional turmoil of the situation her
and her mother so on and so forth and be
very pragmatic and if you have a woman
and I tell you what you need a good wife
you need a good mother for her to work
with you in this way you're solid
teammates you got to be on the same
fucking page because if you come in with
your pragmatism and grip and you have a
woman who's very emotional but also very
strong-headed to it becomes a dick sword
fight between you and your wife and you
don't want that to be the case so I'm
all this I should have prefaced by make
sure you got a good woman a good
teammate on your side here and I am
grateful for mine in so many ways
chapter 7 be the man that she want her
to marry great one ask yourself is the
behavior that I am displaying my
character which I am proceeding towards
her with the type that I would like to
see in her husband Jeffrey teacher who
God is one that might be a little
uncomfortable
some of you guys look God is a concept
it's an idea it is a story but in very
many ways it is a resourceful one if you
know how to use it properly right god is
not a not something that you should be
using to manipulate other people and or
to proselytize and force other people
it's very violent God is not something
that you use to spread by killing others
or with your demanding ideals and ideas
that is a relationship with the the the
ever-present omnipotence energy of the
world as what it is and and and the
woman who writes this book happens to
come from a Christian perspective
perspective which you can appreciate but
also realize that uh you know there's a
lot of value to it right I don't
identify with any religion but I but I
do identify with the mythology of a god
that has supported our consciousness the
stories that support our consciousness
from for generations
chapter 9 teach her how to fight chapter
keep her connected and when she says
that basically to nature when she gives
stories about you know going camping I
take my kids camping or watching the
Stars things that keep her in touch with
her nature and that's it do so look not
having a father is definitely not a it
doesn't disqualify you you're going to
have to work a little bit harder on
recognizing being more self-aware than
most men
in fact like we all should be more
self-aware cuz sometimes I catch myself
just beating my father and if I'm not
self-aware then I'm like I will repeat
the things that I didn't like him in him
you know when I'm with my children but
um but even for you you know there
weren't too many of those examples for
you so be aware of the way you're
behaving read read this book it's going
to be helpful continue to look to other
men as mentors in that particular way
about how you would like to be I still
do this we will be doing this for a long
time I love reading biographies because
it gives me examples of men that I've
come to admire and how they dealt with
circle
stances in their life you know I
recently listened to Ralph Waldo
Emerson's biography and he had three
children his son died his oldest son
died when he's probably about five years
old and you know I even cried during the
book when his son died so to see what
kind of father he was with them was
helpful to me very different than than
my father you know my father grew up in
the third world country and climb trees
and fished with his hands and Ralph
Waldo Emerson went to Harvard you see so
it gave me different perspectives
continue to do that and that's it man
you're gonna be a great father and the
reason why I know you're gonna be a
great father is because you asked that
question you care and that is half the
battle the fact that you care about
doing the good job means you're a great
dad
done