I have a question here from a young lady
named Quinn and she tells the tale of
several heartbreaks that she's recently
experienced and a subsequent run away
that she's decided to embark upon long
story short she had a boyfriend for
several years they broke up things
happen don't want to get into the story
but shortly thereafter she met someone
at her job and fell in love again and
they broke up only this time the
break-up was not as amicable it's the
word she uses as the first one this one
was a it was a lot more violent not
necessarily they were beating each other
up but there was so much more passion
and and heated arguments associated with
their breakup there was a lot more hurt
associated with this rebound
relationship so much so that she decided
I'm pulling out and I'm going to take
care of myself
I'm gonna go and do something that I
want to do because I can't stand this
pain and she left the country I think
she lived in San Francisco somewhere in
California I believe and now she lives
in France now she's doing some work in
France where she's teaching English to
French children or something like that
but anyway it's been several months now
that she's escaped the tumult of pain
and heartbreak in America she's in
France and she's starting to question
her motives and want it as is
questioning herself with regard to
whether or not she should go back to
Carlos which was the last boyfriend look
for new love or just focus on
strengthening herself becoming the
strongest version of herself but then
also there's this conflict between what
my heart wants or what my head is
telling me and if I ever do fall in love
again will I be able to deal with the
pain associated with the inevitable
breakup and heartbreak and the the
entanglement between me and another
person there's so much pain associated
with falling in of and breaking up from
circumstances of love also know what she
should do and and and I take this
question because it's not that unique
you know we when we're on and our
ventures out into relationships with the
opposite sex we're very vulnerable and
in our vulnerability we open ourselves
up to another human being who's probably
carrying around just as much hurt as we
are but they too become vulnerable and
then you've got these two warm soft
hearts willing to give themselves to
each other but yet carrying baggage of
hurt and ultimately at some point red
flags go up or there's a there's a
moment of pain that arises between them
and the whole thing falls to falls apart
goes to shit then in that pain
especially if you're still wounded you
can go out and with a inkling of hope
that perhaps you can experience once
again those warm feelings that you had
with your previous partner
there's the rebound and the inevitable
hurt once again only this time it
compounds it builds up more and more
pain associated with the vulnerability
and inevitable hurt breakup and then you
start going cold and callous then
there's guilt associated with not making
yourself vulnerable again but also a
form of self righteousness and self
protection starts to arise where I you
say to yourself at an unconscious level
I won't let that happen again
but in protecting your heart and not
letting that happen again because you
don't want to go through the pain you
also forego all the experiences that are
only available when you're vulnerable so
what the fuck do you do fright that's
why there are so many songs and poems
written about love one of those issues
I'm going to step back for a moment and
give you a brief overview of some ideas
that are Freudian I still believe that
Freudian psychology holds a lot of
weight
when it comes to the the relationships
that we had with our parents and the
inevitable heartbreaks that we
experienced both pre oedipal and post
edible and what that means is when I use
that term there is a stage of
development early on where we're firmly
entwined with the energetic processes
physiologically and muscularly you know
our skin our body our physiology and our
energy our psychology is very rooted in
our mother right we we come out of our
mother our mother is our soil in other
words one of the reasons why women refer
to people refer to women as their earth
you know you've heard someone say that
this woman is my earth this is my earth
woman is very earth-like as a metaphor
and literally you know where do you drop
seeds into the earth very cold dark
nourishing as opposed to the male anyway
so the experience that we the very first
heartbreak and I've heard it described
this way in a very interesting book
which I don't remember the name of right
now you get you get three chances at at
getting your heart broken three strikes
and you're out
and this and after that third strike
essentially you start becoming very
callous towards the experience and you
develop what you have even described
what was your name again I like to get
it right Quinn
what Quinn experienced as muscular
tension associated with the pain the the
the snowball effect of pain that she
started experiencing with the later
boyfriends starts it starts to actually
physically grip you your muscular system
can become a physical prison for your
energetic expression for love to expand
in your body you can really constrict it
very first heartbreak that is that we
all experience every single one of us
experiences it some take it harder than
others some it's a smooth transition
most of us it's very hard especially if
you're living in Western civilization
and civilization you know when I say
Western civilization I mean contemporary
you know the way we live today probably
most of a lot of the world and that is
the moment that we are pushed away from
our mothers either from nursing or from
sleeping in the same bed or from any any
any detachment from the loved loved
object relationship that we have with
our mother is a hurt to the child it's a
pain to the child now you're a baby
you're an infant most most likely so you
don't you don't think about it you know
you know you don't want to write a love
sonnet about it you're not gonna write a
poem about it you not going to get
depressed about it
you're an infant you're a baby but the
cells of your body
the cells of your body have a have a
form of memory associated with all the
experiences that you have in your life
and that pain is in you your body
doesn't forget
do you see your unconscious which is
rooted in your body or your autonomic
nervous system it branches out out of
the neocortex no that brain that
remembers shit or can be recalled
cognitively goes down into the body and
the body doesn't forget the unconscious
doesn't forget stuff it's in there it's
in your nervous system it's just not
right here or callable right that's why
we can't remember one more babies but
the experiences that we have when we
were babies
for most so that there's that first
heartbreak which is inevitable now of
the three strikes one it's down second
strike is what Freud calls the oedipal
complex and this is where the little
girl will fall in love with the father
or the little boy fall in love with the
mother and it's a little bit stranger
with the boy and the mother B namely
because both sexes come from the mother
so there's like a double heartbreak from
the same woman with men with boys little
boys but anyway without going too deep
into that essentially there's the
another love object relationship with
the opposite sex and the little girl
begins to see the father as a as a love
object falls in love I and I've got four
children I got three girls I see this
I've seen it happen
socially my third daughter Samoan one
day she'll watch this and laugh but yeah
there's there's there's just this bond
of love she wants marry me right how
many little girls want to marry their
daddies right you scoff at it as adults
but this is a physical experience that
they're having I want to marry you daddy
she'll put on a dress and come down like
that are you ready to marry me
and it's it's it's normal this what
happens but ultimately daddy breaks her
heart also I've broken my daughter's
hearts
I can't marry my daughter I mean I don't
even know how you resolved the thing
boom two down you walk out into the
world and as you become an adolescent
and you want to experience really what
your Trek you're seeking to do is to
regain that lost puzzle piece from the
pain associated with the early
heartbreak usually from that second
opportunity with with the parent of the
opposite sex you go out into the world
and you start looking for boys hopefully
you make it long enough before that
inevitable third heartbreak and from
there on out what we begin doing and
this is where most of us end up and you
know I'm perhaps I'm just telling
stories and being poetic but most people
can attest to these six of these
experiences we go out in search of love
that very first time usually when we're
teenagers or in our early 20s we have
that first breakup because you know it's
working just one of those things and
from then on out I sweat and I want to
refer to the situation specifically in
the femp from the feminine standpoint
you want to become vulnerable but you're
scared to become vulnerable and you no
longer give your heart to anyone because
using contemporary language of
individuality you've got to be strong
you've got to be independent a strong
independent woman don't you well you
know what there's something to be said
for a vigilant village vigilantly
vulnerable woman a vulnerable woman
and when I say vulnerable I don't mean
rape me I mean allows herself to soften
to another man even though she's been
hurt in the past has far better sex than
a independent woman because there's not
as much armor built up this whole idea
even for men for us to be so independent
and strong and callous towards one
another really diminishes our capacity
to experience any type of pleasure in
life
so here you are in another country now
separating yourself from all the pain
that you you've experienced associated
with the heartbreak giving your heart up
one last time and then you even ventured
out to patch up the wound with another
love and it just got too painful and you
use this language of becoming strong and
independent you know if I could pull out
the exact words here myself I dentists
do I build my self-identity or do I try
to regain what I've lost someone and so
forth
what do you do I'm going to go out on a
limb here and I'm going to give you some
very dangerous advice and when I say
dangerous it means that you're probably
going to be hurt over and over and over
and over again
and that is to be vigilant in your
vulnerability give your heart up once
again it doesn't mean ignore the
promptings of your conscious mind your
intellect when it says okay this guy's
an asshole get the fuck out of here and
it doesn't mean give your body up open
your vagina
to every single man that warms your
heart but it means allow yourself to
experience the vulnerability that's
associated with which is the root of
pleasure in life and the best way to go
about allowing yourself to do that is by
healing the hurt in your body right
because it's one thing to consciously
consciously understand something it's
one thing to tell yourself good stories
but it's another thing to to heal the
memory of pain in your in the cells of
your body like I said your body doesn't
forget your unconscious doesn't forget
you can tell yourself all the stories
you want you can rationalize all you
want about well you know I'm gonna be
I'm gonna get over this right you could
say I'm gonna get over this but really
you which is all of you doesn't get over
it in your heart your body is still in
pain I'm gonna invite you to do a series
of strange exercises very subtle
exercises but ones that might begin to
to break up some of the rigidity within
the region of your body associated with
warm feelings your heart warm feelings
loving feelings come from interesting
that you know that mammals the mammalian
brain is associated with community
seeing ourselves you know with mammals
are the eyes came from here to here
right Birds have eyes here mammals have
eyes here but one of the things with
mammals
and with community and love is that our
facial expressions what happens in our
face really contributes to the type of
relationship that we have in the
availability that we have to one another
right you can tell someone who has a
very cold hard face by the expressions
that they don't allow to happen in the
face their face becomes very hard and
rigid this particular area I say from
the thyroid process up through the chest
into the throat and the face namely this
particular area right all associated
with communion between ours between us
love love happens here literally lay on
your bed I've described this in videos
earlier this week layer in your bed with
your knees bent slightly this time what
I'd like you to do obviously open your
mouth and your eyes as wide as you can
so you're laying there knees are bent
feet are flat right it's crazy
stretch those muscles because these
muscles become very tight with our mask
of protection stretch the muscles in
your face then take your fingers and
bring them right over your heart so
you're here like this
and over time you're going to you're
going to develop a sense of anxiety
you're going to feel it coming up
because you're going to want to breathe
continue to breathe deep but your
muscular system is going to fight you
what it's actually holding back are the
tears associated with the pain that your
heart feels see we've become very rigid
in this particular area because guess
what this meant this area is also
associated with crying if you watch a
baby when a baby begins to cry the very
first thing it does is goes all right
watch it baby it's very strange with my
chill
I know when my daughter is trying to
hold back her tears cuz she goes like
this right she becomes very tense in her
jaw and her chin that that goes right
down into her chest I can see it I can I
sense it in her so when she's about to
cry she doesn't want to cry and I want
her to cry because I don't want her to
build up that the bars of prison
muscular prison that will did that will
not allow her to have pleasurable
experiences later on in her life what I
do is I bring her closer I bring her
chest her heart right to my heart and I
allow her face to go over the side here
and I say open up your mouth open your
mouth and let the air out you know what
happens right because she's still very
young and pliable you I think give you
very and plus you don't have someone you
know if your daddy I'm still daddy to
hold your heart and to invite you to do
this shit you've got to do it the way
I'm describing it to you now but I'm
giving you a story so that you
understand the implications I hold her
heart close to mine I my hand on her
back so it's right by where her heart is
and I ask her to open her mouth and let
out and breathe but also let out the
sounds associated with what she's
experiencing this would all sound like
ha ha ha
this is what she's her faces over my
shoulder and it was just continued
ah and then boom the tears will come out
and it'll she'll break down it's what
you need they're no different than a
four year old girl except you've become
very far more rigid right you explained
to me about all the pain that you have
in your neck when you when you started
going through that second breakup it's
all in here
it's where it all is so what I'm also
inviting you to do is to begin making
sounds that are also associated with
what you're experiencing so while you're
here begin it begin going through
different how would you describe it's
scales I guess it you know doremi facile
go high go low find fruit find that one
that feels really good and then break it
up as you start losing your breath ah
and what you're trying to do what we're
essentially causing you to experience is
the breaking free of the tears that
you're holding back so your muscular
system becomes soft again you need to
cry I know that sounds crazy but it's
like you just need to cry you need a
deep sobbing not a tearful cry but a
wailing sobbing loud cry like a baby
does like my four-year-old does when I
remind her that she's allowed to cry
and what that will be is a form of
self-soothing that's patching up the
pain from the loss in all three strikes
of heartbreak you're patching up
decade's worth of pain when you allow
yourself to be soothed through exercises
I'm describing right now it's very
difficult to when you're when you're
suffering from these this pain its
neurotic holding to allow yourself to
soften to another human being another
man right because you're dealing with so
much pain and it's because of the
fucking men so to bring your heart close
and allow that to happen with each other
so you're gonna have to do it yourself
you're gonna have to self-soothe another
exercise I would invite you to do as you
explore this one explore the sounds
explore the you're gonna you're probably
shake a lot a lot of times I know when
someone's really holding a lot of shit
back when they do this when they hope
they do their breathing with their
mouths open and it goes like this right
if you do if you find that that's
happening to you as yours you perform
the exercise stick with it stick with it
cuz you got a lot of shit that needs to
come up so I love when I see that and
I'm working with someone and I'm like
okay do some my breathing it says I
watch them I just watch this area more
going on here the more baggage has to be
dropped so be mindful of that another
exercise I would invite you to do that
might evoke a bit more softness which I
had something here with me find a bowl
up a towel get like a hand towel ball it
up and as you're laying there and you've
been breathing for a little while hold
that towel in front of you and look at
it this is an exercise that my mentor
has done with me and I've broken down
into sobs doing this one
get the look at the towel and pretend it
is the heart your heart when you were
four years old now don't try to remember
anything about being four years old
except perhaps what you may have looked
like
let's see yourself when you're four
years old look at that heart and tell it
what you would like it to know what your
four year old heart would like to know
what you like your four year old heart
to know about the world and it's another
form of self-soothing because I don't
want to tell you what's going to come up
because whatever suppose come up will
come up but ultimately what you might
experience is that you're going to talk
to that little girl's heart in a way
that sounds like it'll be alright it'll
be okay you'll survive and invite her
encourage her to remain vigilant lis
vulnerable heartbreaks going to happen
over and over again but that's life you
still want to subject yourself you've
got to understand is hard in that way
life is like life is going to be painful
in that way but if you buy yourself from
the pain you buy yourself from life it's
far more resourceful in my opinion to
live life in pain than to not experience
life at all because you're better off
dead
that's it good luck