yeah I've got two mattes glass seven
monsters all right mostly did like
bodyweight exercises so like dips you
know into that and content is pretty bad
so seven months now the typing push-ups
you don't pull up into anything at this
one so I'm kind of like just I've been
working out for several months so I was
wondering I'm going to a physical
therapist but I'm going to tendinitis
both sides elbows oh yeah so and both
sides and I've been going to you know
physical therapist and what do they have
you do you got some sweeper or something
I put like that
cocoa butter okay yes I'm gonna use for
call for to something so have you met
any exercises they got me doing my
scapular stick with it like you have a
block to why I guess thing and or elbow
tendonitis yeah apparently she said that
if I get my shoulders right as far as
getting strengthened and different rates
emotions it probably helps you know I
guess less and attention it's a both
elbows yes and ulcers and this one your
side I do
how long do you start experimenting
seven wants it the thing is I noticed it
I think it's a nice what so far I'll
give you two I'll give you two idea
first one is I was over there so I'll
talk physiologically there's
inflammation whether it's a chicken or a
in other words there's inflammation so
there's pain or there's what's your
balance that's causing inflammation is
neither here nor there
do you fish oil yeah okay keep taking
visual
oxidants anything that could support you
with information sexting and since I get
a header line you don't need that what
you what I would what I'm going to do
for you if you email Colleen because
Evan he's going to email me and say send
you actually my buddy jet Smith he Ricky
tears phone books in half his nails and
she you know Jade right that's what he
does like definitely and when you tear
phone books and bed nails for living
like comparin he battled elbow pain all
the time he wrote an entire manual on
wrist and elbow pain and there's some
cool-ass exercises that even when I
started getting some elbow pain and I
did and it almost like instantly
garlicky got really how would they take
I mean I remember he had a bicep injury
so bicep - oh yeah I don't you know you
still looking really close to me yeah so
busy logically there are supplements
like what it include that's a good idea
bye subscribe there's one exercise if
you know like the big five-pound jokes
for protein it won't like a big protein
thing in oh I think I know that excites
on my pajamas and you put your hand in
there and you try that is I'm ain't
doing on probably everything under the
book I'm not like cycling and it hasn't
been work so I got it's got better but I
guess why do I can't label down
we open chain exercises that it doesn't
hurt so much of on-campus curls the one
in closing push-ups pull-ups are
something that's when it dies when you
something so it's kind of kind of
spoilery process you I have a tendency
to the wider my elbows and this is just
me I'm stating to by mechanics of it but
I also I just know from my own
experience that what I'm doing pull-ups
the more let my elbows flare and the
more that these two fingers are not
involved like a lot the more I'll end up
okay the more I tighten the outside
fingers the more I draw my elbows in a
little bit the less torsion and main I
have a wide middle - yeah I'm squeezing
more here like fun goon pull-ups you
want to try it a trifle and you're
having pain right actually I'm not six I
like when I put in a spotlight like oh
yeah I don't feel it but also that okay
do push-ups there yeah
my invitation right now is to pay
attention to what's happening in your
hands we have a tendency to overuse surf
muscles in our the light talks about
your hand right you don't be Muslim
Fitness you need to strengthen these
muscles in your hands I don't know the
danger the way talk is not sexy so my
hand but they affect what's going on
throughout so when you do push-ups also
be mindful good of how you're pushing
through your hands spread your fingers
out a little bit more just sperm out as
much as you can and think about pushing
evenly throughout the palm of your hand
and each one of your fingers and do
push-ups that way extend those fingers
yeah this is extend that
real associate almost like spider-man
hands together they're not touching I
can tell you got all kinds of muscle
imbalances here and good get that out
yes can you maintain that while we're
going to push up on all your fingers
yeah yeah you see how you have to keep
adjusting yeah you feel the difference
keep pushing those hands eight more
hands you feel different so you have the
most strains of my fingers yeah hear how
he helped yep
again it's good that's up to the two
things I'll be mindful number one thing
you might love is just your form we
talked about other things we'll send you
the book and then supplemented come
close to me my elbow yeah
what's going on with your hands you're
doing push-ups and you're not even
mindful of the fact that your fingers
that doing this what's happening in your
fingers is an expression of and perhaps
the root cause of what you're going to
experience and feel here yeah guys
noticing I want to read is that this
bear the next kind of like mostly please
take something and do push-ups right but
be very mindful of what's happening in
your hands I did a video on this yeah do
your push-ups but be mindful nobody is
going to tell you be mindful your
fingers get filled up open your chest
you know but I'm telling you
fuck your chest focus on what's
happening in your fingers there it's
going to play it's going to play a
dramatic role and how rest of your body
feels even when you're doing pull-ups
you might look what you're doing at your
hands we have tendency to think our
hands are just like just they're just
looks like you do if you walk your hands
the fact is the analysis of your hand
are going up that the rest
so you've got three things
physiologically perhaps some subtle
estelle neuromuscular li you can use
those corrective exercises there n28
soft tissue work on you I didn't like
literally what they do is for like cocoa
butter and I go spike cotton
I guess Busan is scar tissue or
something somebody who actually gets in
with their fingers and feels going on
and can manipulate and right do you have
anybody doing that you actually want a
first us together again on the spot ever
see that's them
so they dug deep in here you know
probably couple months back this a good
thing and and then now then you know dig
deep in there it doesn't hurt so now
it's kind of harder than Aesthetica okay
well it's enough it's not hurting you so
I guess you know I see how those so they
don't feel any muscular analysis when
they do this by then be mindful of how
you're doing the exercises because
that's probably sounds I guess them to
the third of them right that's the one
you probably weren't thinking about too
much that's probably the case guys yeah
there's been some times where I work out
young is more than thick yeah okay how
you doing it how you doing it yeah right
good
no let you know keep me posted
Conover but let me know how you present
it
you have squeeze with different fingers
certain ones you do a loser shoe club
that might be