hey whats up guys its Elliot I'm back
and if you've noticed past couple weeks
i haven't uploaded any videos for a
number of reasons none of what number
one of which is I've needed some time to
sharpen my axe and what that means is is
if you're always chopping chopping
chopping chopping working in any
endeavor that is you know expression of
who you are you'll find that you grow
dull after a while now you might not
notice this but I noticed this so
sharpening your ax is a concept by which
you take some time off to hone your
skills to develop yourself to go in
especially if you're always going out
and making these videos every day is a
pure expression of me letting my
energies out so taking some time off for
myself has been beneficial and I as I'm
going to describe within the next few
minutes I also invite to you to take
some time off from whatever it is that
you're doing you can't it can't be
summertime all the time if it's always
summer there's Sun will scorch the earth
you need winters you need falls so that
you can have a prolific spring and these
times that we take off from whatever it
is that we do I don't care if its
strength training I don't care if it's
school you need these times for winter
for recovery for rejuvenation for
sharpening your ax and like I said I
invite you guys to do the same thing and
that's what I gleaned after several
weeks of reflection on what it is that I
actually do in fact what it is that
holds the foundation for our
relationship with one another because as
strange as it may seem I'm talking to a
glass lens and you're looking at a
freaking computer screen or a tablet or
your phone but there's still a
relationship because we're interacting
with one another and I've had some time
to think about what did what are we
doing what are we up to why do I talk to
you why do you listen to me and I come
to a few different ideas that I wanted
to clarify because I've been doing this
for so long but also
point or highlight so that we can
continue to move forward so that we can
do this and have a symbiotic
relationship so that we can all grow
stronger because that is the goal
everything that I offer you guys comes
in the form of a invitation and the
reason why is because i have nothing
permanent nothing true nothing right
nothing concrete to give anyone you see
I am I have low self-esteem me sounds
strange Elliot you're so dynamic you're
so prolific you're so motivating you
have the courage to get on this camera
every day you have a lot of interesting
things to say but how is it could your
self-esteem be just as low as mine the
reason why I do what I do the reason why
I am so happy to share these ideas with
you guys is because I'm working every
single day on the same problems that you
guys offered me through the questions
that you said I'd like to say or it'd be
nice or perhaps others would appreciate
seeing me as someone sitting up on a
higher chair or a higher horse than the
rest of us but it's not the fact the
fact is that I'm probably lower than you
in many ways I'm behind you in many ways
and in that I'm always trying to catch
up so I'm neurotic I always talking
about you know breaking up neurotic
holding patterns and how have you come
neurotic the reason why I'm so obsessed
with that because i am neurotic I'm
always reading I'm always studying i'm
always experimenting i'm always
experiencing life so that i can figure
this thing out one of the things i
figured out is there's nothing to figure
out that's for another video so when I
come to you with my advice you guys look
and I love answering your questions
because I know that the majority of you
that I'm answering these questions for
are a few years younger than me so I'm
basically just stepping out of some of
the pits that you're in and not all of
our circumstances and situations are
exactly the same but there are
principles that's one of the things that
have discovered in my trying to catch up
trying to be good enough trying to live
life to the fullest potential allowed to
me growing to become the strongest
version of myself
and inviting you as I go along showing
you what I've discovered one of the
things I've realized that their
principles they're just a handful the
content of the questions that you guys
ask me the content of the answers that I
gave you are not nearly as important as
the context that means that the
container through which all of the
different flavors are dropped in is more
important than the flavor that's dropped
in were poured into the bowl and there
are only a handful of bowls or handful
of cups and those are the things that I
try to approach my conversation with you
through getting to the root issues
getting too why is it that we're having
these problems why is it that these
things keep showing up why is it that I
can't get over my soul low self-esteem
why is it they don't have the courage
why is it that I'm not strong enough why
is it that I'm not brave enough why is
it that i am not enough and there are a
handful of principles guiding principles
that won't answer that question you know
so sometimes people want to know why is
it that Elia feels that he can answer
questions about sex why is it the
Elliott thinks that he can answer
questions about psychology philosophy
religion because that those things are
just the flavor of the juice that's in a
container through which I am approaching
you it's the bigger picture if you will
understand so as we move forward as I
work tyrus tirelessly on myself and as I
work to support you in becoming the
strongest version of yourself I just
wanted to lay this short conversation
out so that we can move forward and I
feel confident in my not having to prove
anything I have nothing to prove I don't
want to be right I don't approve anybody
else wrong I don't to be a guru of sorts
I don't want to be anything beyond an
older brother perhaps a friend that you
can lean on in times where you're
confused there are times where I've
confused I don't know what's going on I
don't know who to talk to I go to
mentors I read books and hopefully i can
offer you that same type of metro
and that's it my friend I enjoy doing
this I appreciate your ears because
without your ears and your eyes nothing
that i offer the world means anything
there's no one to receive it and I'm
happy that you're here to receive it so
that's it I'm going to continue with the
next video I'm going to just start
banging them out right now answering
your questions but not necessarily
giving you an answer for giving you a
perspective some ideas perhaps a tool
that you can use as you move forward
please