all right this question comes from Mike
who's a football player and Oh soccer
because it met it's not American
football soccer but anyway the point is
that Mike goes practice and he does
really well he's an awesome athlete and
training and practice he's one of the
best but something happens when the game
comes and he loses his grounding that's
what I'm gonna call it he doesn't use
that term I'm going to say but basically
he starts throwing up he kind of loses
his edge and he screws it all up when he
gets in the game it's a mess and he
can't figure out why he's such a badass
in practice but he sucks ass in the
games so the very first thing is I'm
uploading a video to my other channel to
strength camp my strength camp channel
very similar to this one right and and
it's going to be called you'll you'll
see it either this week or next week
it's going to be called something like
tribal exercises tribal grounding
exercises or something like that but
anyway I'm going to offer you the same
answer that I did this ain't the kid
that asked me the question on my other
channel and and I can answer this on
both channels because it's kind of you
know it's it's mind it's character but
it's also body what you're experiencing
is the ungrounded of your energy so you
get nervous so what happens is all your
energy begins to rise that's why your
food rises up out of your body and you
say you're throwing up right
you're losing your legs you know boxers
say that you know he lost his legs you
know you don't want to lose your legs
that basically means you lose your
ground and you lose your Center you lose
your ability to stand firm and get done
what needs to get done here on earth see
there's a difference between someone
who's in the clouds and someone who's on
earth a grounded person knows how to get
shit done on earth but what happens is
circumstances create a situation in many
people where they start floating up in
the sky they lose their grounding
apparently that when you get nervous you
lose your grounding a lot of guys when
they go to talk to women they lose their
ground and give a notice I'm going to
say this because I used to be this way
when I was younger and I'd approach
women and I know I've watched a lot of
guys that I'm older and I'm married
I kind of watch guys at the bar and I'm
like all I know he's trying to pick her
up and all of a sudden he's like real
jittery he's moving all over the place
he's like you know he's like he's
giggling and shit I'm like oh so
unattractive dude you're not grounded
well that's kind of what you're
experiencing
there is a external stimulus you're
nervous so you lose your grounding
during our evolution as human beings on
earth there was a certain amount of
primal instinct and wisdom associated
with how men and women would go out and
proceed in the world if you take a look
at Native American culture even if you
watch like the old cowboy movies when
the Native Americans were getting ready
to do some damage what did they do uh
they would dance but not just any
fucking dance right they're not doing
Justin Bieber dances they're bouncing up
and down on their legs and slamming
their feet oh and making sounds uh to
summons the earth right whatever
spiritual language they want to use the
fact is they're grounding their energy
their breathing down into their balls
with that loud resonating sound and the
pounding on their feet right if you
watch some of the movies of the old
Roman soldiers right so this is not just
a new crazy Native American shit where
they dance around naked this is like you
know we our room you know the United
States is Rome in the contemporary sense
so people you know relate so if I say
Rome and it's very Western and penis
associated people get excited and think
that what I'm saying
is more valid than if I said it Native
Americans so if you watch some of the
old Roman soldiers as they're
approaching battle there's a lot of
heavy stomping going on right oh and
they would even even make sounds and
sing Oh any type of tree you know any
tribal society before the men are about
to go do damage what do they do
pound the ground make deep sounds it's
not a mistake it's not some weird shit
they decided to do it's not choreography
entertainment for the people that are
watching it's energetic it's an exercise
that they're using so that they can stay
grounded and get the job done this is
what I'm inviting you to do oh right
watch my bioenergetic warm-up routine
video if I remember which I never do
I'll link it up here but just you know
search Elliott Elliott Hulse
bioenergetic warm up and you'll find it
it's on my other channel my shunts
channel and that warm up if there's a
very strategic warm up by the way so
you're going to want to use this before
you do any work out but the workout ends
with this hands in the air
oh right so this you can ground your any
energy and you can perform and your
workout or your sport at a more
effective in a more effective way right
so that's it dude good luck Oh ground
yourself and kick ass next time Elliott
sick what
you