so got a great question from our buddy
will he's graduated in high school right
now he knows he wants to be a
firefighter paramedic
but he's receiving a lot of pressure
from everyone you know parents teachers
friends to go to college although he
really doesn't need a four-year degree
in order to do the thing he loves
apparently this is what what is moving
up in him this is the flowering that's
happening through him is to save
people's lives running into fire you
know fiery buildings and dragging people
out and bring them back to life pretty
noble shit dude like that's cool I can
see that being something that you could
dedicate your life towards but at the
same time perhaps you're sacrificing
some form of security because everyone
else keeps telling you you need a
four-year degree you could become a
firefighter today without a four-year
degree right according to the question
and begin living the life that is a full
expression of the Spirit through you
running into burning buildings and
saving people's lives
or you could delay that and spend four
years in college and all the things that
that's associated with you know it's
delaying your your gratification of that
desire as well as putting you into and
today slavery so degree and of course
I'm biased in many ways and that's
probably why you come to me with your
question so the very first there are
number of things that I want to share
with you the very first thing is it
doesn't matter whatever you choose
really doesn't matter and I've said this
once before that successful people don't
make the right decisions they make their
decisions right another way of putting
it is damned if you do damned if you
don't now what are you gonna do
understand so I can't give you an answer
I can't say you know what yes go into
your career as a firefighter and
paramedic now and ignore college because
it's the wrong thing to do and I can't
say you know you probably should have
this security which the security of a
four-year degree and be responsible and
then go into your career I'm not gonna
tell you either one that's for you to
figure out I can tell you what either
one you choose is the wrong fucking
decision this is wrong and that's
and guess what you can make this one
right and you can make that one right so
they're both right okay that out the way
number one you're going to have to be a
rebel you're going to have to in this
life and at the the spate at the rate at
which we are evolving as a race of human
beings the rapid expansion of our
consciousness our technology the world
around is just it's a beehive of
activity the only way that you're going
to contribute to the growth wherever
we're going and I don't have any grand
Kingdom ideas about what humankind is
doing but we're going somewhere right
and you can either contribute to helping
it go in a particular way that you like
plant trees because I like trees or you
can be a slave to it just let it take
you wherever it's going and you're just
kind of collateral damage you are you
paid your taxes while you were dead well
you're here now you're dead who cares or
you can you can impede you could resist
it right which never works can't was
this god you can't resist this this
thing that's happening but if you were
of the opinion that I am which is I'd
like to contribute I'd like to help this
the whole thing move forward in a way
that I see fit be the change that you
want to see in the world
Gandhi right then you're going to have
to go against everyone and everything
around you right because what's
happening is happening so quickly that
no one can safely say this is the right
choice because really within a year two
years five years whatever it is that
you've invested in could be completely
well that doesn't exist anymore right
think about all the people that invested
in real estate in the stock market up
until 2008 and then you mean you spent
the past 40 years investing in this one
fucking thing and that's how quickly
things go away think about people who
invested in different companies that
like remember those two-way phones right
who created those Motorola where the
fuck is Motorola anymore
right Apple came about Apple was like
fuck this we don't give a shit about
that Apple is one of those most one of
the most
Bela's companies in the world you know
whether you like them or not you got to
be like well that company just doesn't
give a shit and does whatever it wants
we're not going to use flash fuck you
we're gonna create a new our own way of
bringing video across our devices right
what do you mean
guess what they're a leader industry
leader I think the richest company on
earth right now right rebellious
rebelliousness is the only characters
trait that will allow you to create
something remarkable be magnificent and
add heavily to the evolution of
humankind you cannot stay stuck in
traditional ways of doing things you've
got to break the mold
it's not always easy breaking the mold
you might end up collateral damage this
is how I'm using this for breaking the
mold right there are some people that
are that paved the road in a particular
direction so that someone else can come
right john the baptist's pave the road
for Jesus right he basically came was
like you one fuck is gonna hate me they
killed him right but I need to prepare
shit for what's about to happen that
might be you but if this is happening in
your heart you've got to do it you know
and that's just an attitude obviously
has nothing to do with your your
paramedic miss but this is an attitude
that I want everyone to adopt realize
that if there is a flowering there's a
there's a happening inside you and it
looks completely contradictory to
everything else that you've been taught
and everything else want everyone else
is doing you sort of have a
responsibility to do it okay that's
number one and and again that's a
paradigm what I'm going to do now is I'm
going to give you practical ideas for
your particular situation and I boil it
down like this there are two realities
that you can play with now this is me
being poetic so you're not gonna find
this in a book or a philosophy channel
somewhere there are basically two things
that you're dealing with you're dealing
with the now which is really the only
thing that truly exists but in a way
you're also creating a legacy your
future right and when I say legacy what
you're doing now is going to contribute
to the world to evolution to your
children to your grandchildren even when
you're gone
so it's an interesting word legacy right
what you've got to do now and where we
are in this stage of social development
as a race of human beings is figure out
how can you play the socio-economic game
without losing yourself because you're
gonna need yourself for that second part
the legacy right and you've got to
understand the rules of the
socio-economic machinery see we've been
taught that we have to play this
particular game a certain way but you
don't all you really need to do is if
you're going to if you're going to live
in society understand that there are a
few things that need to happen number
one you have to serve other people
that's it I mean we just don't exist in
a vacuum
you want to save people's lives pretty
fucking cool right but again this is I'm
giving you rods sweeping ideas that will
allow you I give you guys tools do you
understand a lot of times I can't answer
your question but I give you places to
look and tools to carry with you as you
go in your drink because I don't have
the answer only you have the answer
carry this tool carry this understanding
that in order to succeed in the
socio-economic machine whatever it is
that you want to do right somebody
would've told me I wouldn't talk in
front of a fucking camera and
broadcasting it to 500,000 people when I
was in high school there I would have
been like yeah right that this fucking
is this it's going to evolve because
we're evolving service is paramount you
have to some way shape or form reach
people with depth and if you can breath
the more people you help and the deeper
you help them the greater your
contribution the greater your return
Genest and this is all a lot of my non
job philosophy you've got to find some
way to give yourself to the world be it
pulling people out of burning buildings
or writing poetry right there are
million in one different ways creating
an app that you can serve other people
and if you want to legally be a part of
this game not get thrown in a fucking
jail you got to pay taxes to things
that's it want to win the socio-economic
machine you want to win
now today you want to do your part you
want your parents every parent wants
their children to be respectable
which means worldly success does he live
in a nice neighborhood every mommy
Oh does my son live in a nice house does
he have a nice car could he find a nice
girlfriend can I have grandchildren this
is what you know this is what these are
the trappings these are the the winnings
of this particular machine if you
approach it the way that I'm telling you
right now you don't get lost in it and
you can get those things just with those
two fucking rules
you don't need college you don't need
you don't need anything all you need is
something that you can share with people
that enhances their lives in any
particular way there's so many different
ways gonna have people's lives the more
you help and the deeper you help them
the deeper the return you've got to set
it up so that it happens out and you got
to pay your fucking taxes right oh the
throw your ass in jail you got to pay
your fucking taxes it's just the way it
is you might not like like me what the
government does with your tax money
right but you gotta pay your fucking
taxes and that's it as long as you're
paying taxes and you're giving to the
world you have already gained a strong
foothold on the now cool that being said
it's a very limited way of looking at
life and approaching your life you also
have to pick your eyes up and consider
where the race is going and how you can
add significance how you can add
yourself to the movement of mankind how
you can support the evolution of mankind
and gain significance for the particular
70 years that you lived here those 70
years will be of great significance if
you consider your legacy you consider
the future you consider the next
generation what kind of gift
are you leaving behind right because
just serving people because you know
there are a lot of evil ways to serve
people you know you know a lot of nice
not nice things that could be going on
you know for example you know
the pharmaceutical industry serves a lot
of people in a pretty deep way but most
of that shit is fucking unnecessary
they're making us sick of they're making
us sick of all the pills that they shove
down our throat now are you going to
feel good about how you've contributed
to the evolution of mankind when you
know that you caused more pain than
goodness right and that's what you know
okay okay again that subjective Elliott
Hulse is opinionated in many ways maybe
the pharmaceutical companies right I'm
talking about like designer drugs about
talking about like shit that like cures
aids right cancer which apparently you
know there's not much money in that so
that's why we haven't heard about it yet
but hey that's just my opinion
choose anything you want a lot of you
guys get caught up in the details you
get caught up in the wrapping paper of
what I'm saying and totally missed the
point
you know the wrapping paper take the
gift hey might not like the fucking
wrapping paper might not like me but
there's a gift here but if you can get
over yourself you'll hear
so plant a tree my friend do the thing
that's happening right now in such a way
that you win the socio-economic game and
the way that you'd like to win for
everyone it's very different and plant a
tree while you're doing it and that's a
metaphor for consider the future
generations consider your children
consider your children's children see we
don't do that anymore
everything that we do is about how to
win the socio-economic machinery how can
I have more be more get more we you
could use the term greed because playing
the game is just playing the game you
know if you if you earn tens of millions
of dollars playing the game that doesn't
really mean that you're greedy you know
how to play the fucking game but if
you're personally identified with it and
you have a limited perspective ie you
don't consider future generations you
don't consider if you're hurting people
are actually helping them serving could
be serving like I said in a good way or
bad way
then you're greedy because you're
self-centered you're only thinking about
yourself planting a tree allows the work
that you put in today digging the dirt
and planting the seeds to afford shade
and fruit for a future generation and
bring significance to the short period
of time that you lived on this planet