so our buddy John here is 20 years old
and he only can see himself falling in
love with in being with a virgin so a
woman that hasn't had sex with another
man he talks to a lot of girls and they
get to know each other but the minute he
finds out that she's had sex with
someone else not during the relationship
but as they're getting to know each
other he finds out that oh so you've had
sex before her value in his eyes
immediately drops right and this it
irritates him in and he understands that
this is probably not very practical to
think and behave in this way because the
majority of the girls that he's talking
to and probably who he's going to come
in contact with are going to have had
sex already it's just you know it's a
part of the culture it's it's the way we
do things right we women we all become
very sexual at a very young age 14 years
old so so to expect someone to go into
sexual ripeness the age of 14 and then
move all the way through their 20s
without having sexs is rare it's just
something that's not going to happen
that easily or very often so what can
you do to get over this right you make
another very interesting point in your
question you say that the other thing
that I that really has to be there for
me is that I need to be able to speak
with this woman on an intimate level
very personally unless we can share very
personal intimate conversation I lose
interest you're an interesting dude it
and I I feel a sense of connection with
you because a lot of the things you're
saying I feel also the thing with what a
red light red flag that goes off for me
when you say that you can talk to women
or you need to have a verbal
communication relationship with them
you've got to be able to express
ourselves through talk means to me that
you're looking for a life partner you're
looking for someone who is on the same
energetic wavelength as
you're not just looking at obviously
you're not looking to just go and have
sex and you're not looking for somebody
to fill your ego gratification you're
looking for someone who you can share
your heart with and the thing is you're
also looking for someone you can share
your heart with who hasn't shared their
sexual energy with right so you want to
open up at the heart you want to open up
at the hall let the balls and you want
someone else that you can share that
with also this is very pure right and it
may seem narcissistic and crazy for you
to think I just want a virgin you're not
that type of guy you're not coming
across as like you know macho controller
type it's like you need to be pure for
me you're coming across to someone who's
willing to open your heart and you want
to share that openly with someone who
has not done so with someone else you
want your own and it's this selfishness
that's that's causing you this problem
it's thinking that when you share that
that heart and sexual energy with
another person that you own each other
what you got to realize is that everyone
is on their own journey regardless of
how much or who they love that woman
you're missing out on quite a few women
that might be perfect for you women who
have begun their journey and have shared
heart and sexual energy with love and
sexual energy with and you're missing
out big time because you're wanting to
own all of that person you will never
own all of anyone you might share heart
feelings with but you don't own that
person you don't own that love with that
who you only love but you don't own that
person you own the energy between each
other and the same thing with sexual
relations you don't own the vagina you
don't own her but I you'll never own her
vagina you own the sexual energy between
each other but that's her vagina and her
journey may take her on a path where
hope
china has been experienced before you've
got to get that through your head right
you've got to get it through your head
logically this is one of the times where
Elliot is saying get out of your heart
and balls and go back up to your head
all right this is it's usually the other
way around and and it's funny because I
not pro or con any of it they've all got
to be lined up father son Holy Spirit
they've all got to be lined up the head
the heart in the balls and right now
you're in your heart your balls you're
feeling and you're letting your even
scare you and you just you it's tearing
you apart get your head wrapped around a
lot of things with let us off to the
head it's just a matter of telling
ourselves right story do you get that
brainwash yourself tell yourself the
right story and the right story a very
resourceful story in a story that's
quite plausible is that she's her own
self she's her own person she will be on
her own journey to the day you die she
you can share sexual relation with ready
to share your heart and soul with her
but until the day you separate from the
physical realm you will not own her I
don't own my life she doesn't own me you
will never own the vagina understand and
and and there's a lot of under social
stories that she might be telling
yourself like it's unclean now because
there was another penis in there look
dude the vagina self-cleaning at least
most are don't worry about it you know
there's nobody his penis isn't still in
there it was an energetic exchange right
that happened to be physical for what
four minutes maybe get over it right you
just got to get over it dude right hope
that helped