the first thing I want to say is that I
believe that taking personal
responsibility is by far the most
powerful position that any human being
can take no matter what your external
circumstances may be it is your personal
responsibility to see and deal with
those circumstances as you wish and this
is never more important than in an
environment where you are choosing to
feel offended you see especially if that
offense because even that word is
subjective you're only being offended if
somebody comes at you in an offensive
way but if you're an environment where
words are being used or there are
symbols in your presence and you choose
to feel offended that is your doing if
you allow for example see I live in the
South right now and there are lots of
Confederate flags people fly them in
their homes they have bumper stickers on
their cars or on their t-shirts now
there are those who choose to feel
offended they choose to have a visceral
response they choose to allow their
physiology to be changed they become
stressed out when they see this symbol
and I've even been asked like Elliott
will aren't you offended when you see
this and that question is inherent with
their ignorance about the choice of
being or feeling offended or not you see
there are certain things like words for
example you know I say the word fucking
shit penis vagina these are words that
make people very uncomfortable or gives
them a visceral response you know they
feel their physiology changing either
the belly gets tight the asshole
tightens up they stop breathing deeply
they become very flustered and
uncomfortable right well you got to
recognize that those are just symbols
they're just words they're just sounds
vibrations in the air whether or not it
touches you deeply is based on your
ability to or your desire to choose to
allow that visceral response or not I
see a confederate flag
I have no visceral response I see it for
what it is it's a fucking flag now there
associations with it and I know but why
do i why shall I delve into the
associations with it especially if I
don't know the person who's wearing it
or the person who's using it right
because that's inherent with all types
of types of prejudice as well all right
to see a symbol or to hear a word coming
from another individual and then to tie
that individual to all the associations
with it is a form of prejudice I see a
man wearing a Christian cross it doesn't
mean that he was a participant in the
Crusades and believes that it was a good
idea
do you see just because he's has that
cross on his chest shall I associate him
with all of the the negativity that may
have been perpetrated on mankind because
of his chosen religion that would be
wrong that's that's pure prejudice
that's just as bad as seeing a black man
and saying oh he must be a rapist or a
or a murderer because every time I turn
on the television it seems like those
black people are always raping and
murdering prejudice you see something
that you may be confused about ask
questions if you become uncomfortable at
a visceral level that's your choice