welcome to the art of charm I'm Jordan
Harbinger the art of charm brings
together the best coaches in the
industry to teach you guys how to crush
it in life love and at work imagine
having a mix of experienced mentors
teaching you their expertise packing
decades of research testing and tough
lessons into a concise curriculum we've
created one of the premier men's
lifestyle programs available anywhere
and it's free this is the show we wish
we had a decade ago this show is about
you and we're here to help you become
the best man you can be in every area of
your life make sure to stay up to date
with everything going on here and get
some killer free ebooks as well as
drills and exercises that will help you
become more charismatic and confident by
signing up for the newsletter at the art
of charm com if you're new to the show
but you want to know more about what we
teach here at the art of charm listen to
the tool box at the art of charm
podcast.com slash tool box that's where
you'll get the fundamentals of dating
and attractions such as body language I
contact vocal tonality all that stuff
that's more important than you might
think we've got boot camps running every
single month here in California details
at the art of charm calm and I'm looking
forward to meeting all of you guys here
at the art of charm enjoy
today we're talking with super
charismatic physical trainer Elliott
hulls we're going to talk about why it's
important to become strong not just
physically but emotionally how do we
become the strongest version of
ourselves and how much of our
intelligence is actually found in our
bodies literally we're also going to
talk about finding our own path to
strength how your mind and body are
inseparable and actually kind of the
same thing how to breathe for real and
exercises to stretch out muscular
tension that we carry all the time that
impedes proper breathing we're also
going to discuss how the eastern mind
and Western mind differ not to Lulu they
don't worry and how we can absorb some
of the lessons that will make us
stronger emotionally last but not least
body psychology therapy mattress humping
for a healthy lifestyle and emotional
clarity enjoy you know you seem like a
well-mannered gentleman type but the
photograph that I got from your PR
people is kind of terrifying you
probably have the capacity to scare
small children it's kind of funny at
first I was like this guy looks like a
professional wrestler or something you
know cuz obviously you're built really
big but also you've got that natural
charisma talking right at somebody
you're like in their face in your videos
yeah i saw the your strength camp your
gym and I saw the beer kegs and I got
excited but I'm guessing they're not
full of beer so that kind of took the
wind out of my sails as well now sending
water sand and water yeah how much is
the sand filled keg way I mean that must
be whoa we just did a competition work
eight carries is one of the events and
we filled them up to about 175 pounds
each you can load them all the way up to
about 300 pounds you know wow I don't
know if I could move anything that heavy
yeah well you build up to it man that's
old point right yeah that's the point so
why do you have such a passion to become
stronger you know it's one of these
things where I've always had a natural
gift towards in a prepend enci towards
strength and power I kind of been that
way since I was a kid I was born that
way so I really embraced sports that
required strength power speed I
of course I trained that way in order to
get better at football to get better at
straw man all the wrestling all things i
did so i really enjoyed the training as
much as I enjoyed the sports so I
decided to become a coach yeah now tell
us when you got started because he got
started when you were really little well
my uncle was a at the beginning he was a
martial artist so when I was about four
years old he was heavily invested in
northern shaolin kung foo he was a black
belt he was an instructor and he come
over he lived with us for a little while
and he would do backflips and chop
bricks and who do all types of wild
stunts in front of me as a four-year-old
so I wanted to do it too like any four
year old would he saw a man doing
backflips in his in his living room so
at that point he just threw us on the
floor and started teaching us how to do
push-ups and sit-ups and climbing ropes
I mean I've been training ever since
that's amazing when did you figure out
you were stronger than all of your
friends kindergarten when I could do a
push-up with nobody else good right yeah
they just fall flat on their face pretty
much you know the whole sagging body
thing where you know the hips are on the
floor I I took it for granted because me
and my brothers got real strong real
fast at a young age and then when I went
to school and I actually remember this
because it was my first sense of being
empowered my first like self-esteem
boost it was like holy shit no these
kids can do anything I can do I was
faster i could do push-ups I could do
sit-ups and I guess that molded my
character yet as it would for anyone for
sure I remember when I was younger we
had a gym class and they were trying to
get us to do pull ups but we were all
too young I mean we were probably in
like first grade or something like that
so they just had us hanging on to the
pull-up bar and I didn't really get what
was going on so I hung on for a minute
and 30 seconds or something insane and
got bored and it turned out that I'd
like beaten the school record by like a
full you know 20-plus seconds or
something like that and it's funny
because I I'm definitely not that strong
right now I mean which is largely a
result of lifestyle and stuff like that
versus
genetics but it's kind of funny to see
that the genetics were there still are
there buried under as i like to say the
six-pack that i have is in the
refrigerator um but why is it so
important to you to become stronger both
mentally and physically I mean you have
what we call different levels of
strength and I definitely want to get
into that but why is it so important to
you to stay that way yeah you were
stronger when you were little so as I
why did you stay that way well the very
person yet understand is I've come to
use the word strength and the idea of
growing stronger as a metaphor for
self-actualization personal development
and because I came into my own and I
began presenting myself to the world if
you will through the medium of strength
that it has always been my calling card
I was a strength coach I was in strength
athlete and I own a gym and so on and so
forth but as I baval Dan my message has
evolved association with strength and
what it actually means when I say it has
evolved when I say grow stronger and
become a stronger version of yourself it
means on multiple different layers
multiple different levels not just your
normal scalar strength which I often
talk about and that has to do with
muscular balance and your structural
integrity and your your work capacity
your yourself as an athlete yourself as
a fully functional walking human being
and I often say and truly believe that
your body is your mind and if you are
sick decrepit broken down and weak
physically I don't think you'll be able
to reach your maximum capacity on a
cognitive mental spiritual level so I
begin there I begin with the body but it
goes far beyond that we're also
considering the physiological strength
of an individual or the physiological
health of an individual their organs or
hormones the nervous system and then
ultimately their psychology the way you
think the stories you tell yourself the
way you carry your body as a
manifestation of the psychological
character that you're carrying yourself
with someone who carries himself with
their head high and they're on their
toes is someone who looks like they're
going somewhere they feel good about
themselves they're moving forward
in the world and they're physically
moving forward because you know they're
on their toes and their head is held
high as opposed to someone who's kite
photic droop forward head hanging and
feet are flat looks like someone who
will physically they're not going very
far because you're kind of slopping a
lot of slopping along and if you take a
look at where that person is going where
they're coming from what they feel about
themselves in their day to day life be
it with relationships or career or
school there it's probably probably
plotting along also sure yeah one of the
core concepts here at the art of charm
is how you do anything is how you do
everything and that has to do with the
crossover between the emotional and
mental and the physical as well what I
do for a living and what I also train
people to do at the art of charm
especially when like intelligence agents
come in or Special Forces guys is how to
read people and one of the things that I
can show people how to look for is
mental characteristics or emotional
characteristics as a result of certain
types of body language and you just
touched on that issue as well when you
see somebody slumped over or certain
types of eye contact weak eye contact
week posture even the way they hold
their feet you can really learn to read
what someone's emotional state is and
what they think of their own
capabilities and things like that as
well and you can also see when people
are suspicious when they're hiding
things ask any cop right they look at
somebody and they get that gut feeling
it's not based on their sixth sense it's
based on nonverbal communication that
they can't articulate but that they can
see in process yeah people are doing
that all the time we're doing this when
it comes to dating two women are very
good at it there about 10 to 20 times
better at it than men are they just
don't know it necessarily and so that's
why guys who have their proverbial shit
together can do a lot better with the
opposite sex especially if their
physical component is there has nothing
to do with how big their biceps are and
has everything to do with how they carry
themselves yeah absolutely the way you
carry yourself will change the way you
think about yourself yes the button
that's why when I say the body is the
mind it's like you can change your mind
by changing the way you carry yourself
their exercise components to allowing
that to happen stretching the right
muscles breathing a particular way
walking a particular way reducing
muscular tension in certain
those developing strength and certain
muscles that are flaccid in week that
could potentially hold your posture up
you see ya class it's never an
attractive word right so absolute that's
impotent those are two that you don't
want to be characterized at exactly
exactly it's funny you should say that
the mind is the body because again a
principle of the art of trauma core
principle is that the body follows the
mind and the mind follows the body so
exactly what you're talking about before
with mirroring your emotional state and
it is very true i mean you've got
certain types of body movements or sort
of physiology that you can use to
improve mindset and of course we know
that mindset will improve physiology or
not improve physiology look at someone
who's depressed or look at somebody
who's in a great mood the way they carry
themselves it's very apparent they don't
have to come up and tell you that
they're depressed and they certainly
don't have to come up and tell you that
they are excited about life it has to do
with everything about what they're doing
and you don't have to understand a word
of their language you can tell if
somebody who speaks Mandarin Chinese is
excited or sad by the way that they
carry themselves you might have trouble
discerning between angry especially with
the cantonese people but i digress here
so your mission is to become the
strongest version of yourself that's
exactly in line with what we do at the
art of charm which is one of the reasons
why i decided to have you come on and
you inspire others on the same journey
and so you and I are very much in the
same role as mentors and role models for
people whether we like it or not and I
think this is important because
everybody as each individual raises his
own level of consciousness as you say he
automatically becomes a beacon of light
for others who may have been lost or who
might not know the value of their
existence what do you mean by that I
mean essentially this is the mentorship
role in itself well you said it best
before when you said you bring whatever
you are to everything that you do yes
got to work with who you are because
it's far more important than what you do
I can be totally intelligent verbally
and in the abstract about what is
required to get a particular type of
result for someone right I might be very
well-read I might
have all the degrees next to my name I
might have taken all the courses
necessary and in fact I happen to be
very eloquent in my ability to describe
everything that needs to happen but
Ralph Waldo Emerson once said what you
are speaks so loud that I can't hear a
word you're saying yes and and I live
that I live that because if I'm inviting
you to take action in a particular area
in your life or to improve in a
particular way because I want to see you
become self actualized I want you to be
the strongest version yourself that's
why I'm a coach I get a kick out of
watching people succeed i myself need to
embody that first yeah I agree a hundred
percent if you don't embody it really
it's about leading by example in a lot
of ways the difference here is that
we're leading all of those around us
whether or not we choose to or not and
you'd mentioning I think this is amazing
the most unselfish thing that we can do
is to become a stronger version of
ourselves because since we are always
leading by example again whether we
choose to or not we're either leading
people upwards or downwards so if we
become the strongest version of
ourselves we inspire others to do that
absolutely that sort of begs a question
what does it mean to become the
strongest version of yourself what do
you think about that I really believe is
a totally subjective experience and the
first place to begin is with the simple
question how's that working out for you
Yeah Yeah right because I can make all
my moral judgments that I could have all
my ideals lined up about what it should
look like for you but we're also unique
in our own individual ways and our
experiences our DNA all contribute to
who we are and for me to stand here and
say mine is the one and only way and all
other ways are doomed to failure doesn't
respect the human being in the way that
a human being should be respected and my
main sentiment to proceed from is with a
deep and profound level of respect for
the other human being the only thing I
ask is that we all be as objective as we
possibly can and honest with ourselves
be real
when the question is posed how is that
working out for you not what do you
think about these ideas and these morals
and these judgments and so on and so
forth and who told you and what book
says how's that working out for you for
example I had a conversation with a guy
just a few moments ago and we're talking
about the idea of vegetarianism now I
have nothing against being a vegetarian
absolutely not fact it seems as if of
course there are cultures that are
vegetarian cultures and they happen to
be very healthy and intelligent that
particular way but then you've got
people who have adopted this idea
vegetarianism because the book they read
or an experience that they had and it
clearly is not working out for them you
just look at your gray skin and they're
bloodshot eyes and yellow teeth and hair
falling out the weak frail disposition
that they carry themselves with and they
can explain all the reasons why
vegetarianism is right they can be very
adamant and convincing about
vegetarianism but one glance at the
individual and it's clear that shit
ain't working out for you yeah exactly
hey guys I want to take a quick break
for a second here you've heard me talk a
lot about taking you to the next level
in life at work and in your
relationships and you've also thought to
yourself yeah i do want to up my game i
want to become a better man a better
boyfriend or husband a better person in
general and my guess is that you've been
thinking about this for a long time am i
right well I'm here to tell you this
stop thinking your chance is now do you
really need more time more information
more plans for the future or do you want
to become that guy today because the
truth is this you can be the guy who
sits around and thinks about becoming
better or you can be the guy who decides
that today is the day that is going to
become awesome and take action in that
direction and I want that for you why
because you already got what it takes
the potential is there even if you don't
know it yet join me and thousands of
guys who take an action in their lives
at the art of charm calm all right let's
get back to the show it's funny we deal
with the same stuff here you know again
talking about guys and teaching charisma
and teaching guys how to be the best
version of themselves is not an easy
test and I'm sure you get this all the
time guys will go I'm really interested
in this this is great this is really
cool and I go all right
cool when are we taking things to the
next level when are you gonna put this
stuff into action well you know it's
cool but I don't really need it you know
cuz I've got this going for me and I've
got that going for me and like I don't
really need to go to strength camp la
you know cuz I'm pretty buff man I got a
six-pack you know I just ran a half
marathon you know I'm doing okay and
then you're thinking that's weird
because he just wrote in saying how all
this stuff is so inspiring and how all
this stuff is so life-changing but then
when I asked him to put his money where
his mouth is it's not quite happening
where's the disconnect and that's when I
bust out that question alright well
how's that working out for you and then
usually if you get that and you know
what i'm talking about Elliot when you
get that honest answer they're like well
it's not really where I want it to be
right now and I ran a marathon last year
and I'm in worse shape and this isn't
working I got some blood work back
that's not so positive and I got an
injury that I caused and I'm doing this
and and then you get to the bottom of
things when people are really honest
with themselves or honest with you about
how's that working out right you know I
use that term becoming the stronger
version of yourself with an emphasis on
becoming but i also want to shed light
on the fact that there is no final
destination except death and a lot of
people of course we want to be right you
know we sort of the way our education
system is conditioned us is you want to
be right and you want to avoid any
experience that might lend to failure at
all but life is not that black and white
and back like from my short experience
here on earth and the wisdom gathered
through many generations life is a
journey it's a dance it's something
we're doing and it would be in our best
interest in my opinion to be objective
about where we are what we've got how we
got here choosing where we'd like to be
what type of experiences we'd like to
have and proceeding in that direction
with full awareness that perhaps i'm
going to stumble i might scrape my knee
it might not work out but be willing to
get up and try again without being so
dogmatic and emotionally attached to the
particular ideals
associated with the journey or the
length of the journey that I started on
to say okay well time to put that away
and try something else sure yeah now it
makes a lot of sense and that sort of
leads to my follow up here which was
what everyone's thinking well great okay
guys got it how do I become the
strongest version of myself what does
this mean you know one guy over here
runs strengthcamp one guy over here runs
a charisma school what am I doing here
where do I start okay I'm going to take
a few steps back and I'm going to give
you a very broad answer that might not
seem like it makes much sense but bear
with me meditation when I say meditation
I don't necessarily mean there's any
fixed form of meditation that you need
to engage and I'm not saying you've
gotta sit cross-legged about saying you
have to do yoga but say you have to do
anything that looks anything like what
you've been told meditation is when i
use enter meditation I mean getting out
of your own way really that's what it is
shutting off the part of you that
happens to always get in the way and
that part of you that happens to always
get in the way has been labeled many
things including our ego and our ego is
is part of us that has been colored by
our experiences by our conditioning by
what other people have told us we are
other people told us we should do so on
and so forth it's the collective baggage
that has been laid upon us throughout
our lives probably since conception
there are people that look at it that
way sure but there's a time and there's
an opportunity available to all of us to
turn that off for a moment and get in
touch with another part of our
intelligence and I happen to believe
that this intelligence is found in our
bodies and when someone says listen to
your heart I don't think it's purely
metaphorical I don't think it's just a
metaphor to say this guy's got guts or
trust your gut or listen to your heart
what I truly believe is if we shut off
just ignore for a moment or temper the
chatter happening in our head brain and
consult with our hearts consult with our
guts develop the courage and the passion
associated with each then the answer for
what the strongest version of ourselves
or the journey towards the strongest
version of ourselves will look like will
be
revealed excellent so it's all about
essentially to sound so cliche by
accident and just totally unavoidably
it's all about getting in touch with
yourself but a lot of that has to do
with shutting off the noise from the
outside through say meditation and
getting out of your own ways that what
you mean by that absolutely one hundred
percent good sometimes it's hard to dig
through this stuff because a lot of guys
listen to you and I love what you say
that's why you're on the show but I
think a lot of guys listen and go dude I
have no idea what you're talking about
it sounds great but what do you even
mean and so it's important to sort of
cut through some of the chaff because
it's really easy for you guys like you
and I to get lost in years of study and
realize oh there's somebody listening
out there that's brand new right and is
going huh I think that one of the best
ways to describe meditation is getting
out of your own way fortunately any guy
who SAT there and tried to maintain
silence of thought 45 minutes knows
exactly what we're talking about you sit
down to go I'm just gonna focus on my
breathing and then suddenly you're like
why are pencils yellow whose idea was
that do I consider myself more of a
baller or a shot caller I wait a minute
oh crap no no thoughts no thoughts right
it's really hard um we're always doing
that and you just happen to notice that
layer of thought when you try to turn
off the conscious layer of thought that
means there's probably like a hundred
layers or more of thought that are
getting in our way and we're just
letting it happen because we've been
letting it happen our whole life but
once you dig through some of that we can
see what our bodies / heart truly wants
and then we can get that path that you
speak of right oh absolutely that's been
my experience it's not because I've read
a lot about it because I happen to like
the ideas I just happen to have use
these tools I've been lucky enough to
have people to share them with me and
I've grown for lack of better terms
addicted to them because without
meditation without exercise without deep
breathing it just doesn't work for me
life doesn't go as smoothly as it should
when I give up or take a break from
those practices so what about some of
the challenges that do impede us on the
journey I mean
you don't have time you don't know how
to do it we run out of ideas on how to
do it I mean there's a lot that gets
thrown in our way what are some common
challenges that you find guys walking
through your doors have I think the
biggest challenge is no of course I say
getting in your own way but what does
that exactly look like right number one
is everybody waits until the stars are
aligned before they take action now when
I say that metaphorically of course but
we want all the information with all the
ideas we want all the know-how before we
get started with something we want the
blueprint we want it all laid out we
want the perfect plan for action before
we do anything and we want security we
want safety and that's really what the
figment of our imagination that
stimulated when we have the plan laid
out the foolproof plan is providing for
us or giving us the illusion of another
Emerson quote because i love emerson so
damn much alright his words have just
been so instrumental in my life is this
do the thing and you will have the power
and that basically means don't wait
until you seemingly have the power
because no power is granted you without
experience go and do the thing you're
afraid to do go and do that thing wait a
second but I don't know doesn't matter
but wait what about this so on and so
forth at it really matter go do it put
one foot on the journey first and then
begin to feel your way down that road
and that requires like we discussed
earlier being in touch with yourself I
think that any goal that we set for
ourselves any journey that we decide to
go on is far less about what we attain
its follow us about the achieving the
goals follow us about getting to the end
of the journey and more about who we
become as we're moving along that path
and the reason why that happens is
because we've got to be very sensitive
about who we are and where we're going
and the choices we make and
self-reflection and objectivity it
brings up an excellent point because a
lot of people do this they don't start
until they're ready but the problem is
everybody who's successful that you will
ever talk to probably in your whole life
has always started
when they were ready it's something that
I find with all of the entrepreneurs
that come on the show all of the experts
that come on this show all of my
successful friends in my quote unquote
offline life if you will and I'm sure
you've seen this as well Elliot we
always start before we're ready did you
open a gym when you were a hundred
percent confident sure that it was going
to be a success and you knew that you
couldn't fail and you knew everything
about running a gym hell no you started
when you open the doors and you went
alright hopefully this doesn't drive me
into oblivion bankruptcy right let's see
what's going to happen and you learn in
the process at the end of the day sure
the journey might lead somewhere but at
the end of the day you take the lessons
and not the spoils that's the true gift
the true gift of the lessons you learn
along the way and the character that you
develop as you navigate the path and we
mentioned before a little bit about
breathing and one of the things that we
both share that this is actually one of
the comments that got my attention
because we say the same thing when we
teach vocal tonality at the art of charm
we teach breathing from your balls or
breathing into your balls you say the
same thing i think we probably mean the
same thing but i'll i'll have you
explain it if you don't mind because
guys don't really understand what it
means to breathe deeply they don't
really understand what it means to
breathe from your balls that idea was
first shared with me through alexander
Lowen who was a student of Wilhelm Reich
Wilhelm Reich was a student of Sigmund
Freud and Wilhelm Reich was an
interesting dude because as a student of
Freud's he studied psychoanalysis of
course and he was a psychoanalyst and he
began work by having his client lay on a
bed or couch and they would talk that's
how psychoanalysis began and that's how
many do it still today what this
interesting guy Wilhelm Reich who if you
google him you'll see all types of weird
and interesting things about him he's
kind of a crazy dude one of the crazy
things that he said that I fully
embraced is that you learn far more
about the psychological ills and pains
that your patient pass by watching him
breathe than listening to him talk and
that sort of points back to the original
idea that you are what you are speaks so
loudly I can't hear a word you say we
become so good at posturing that the
division of an individual can be clouded
by the amount of
words or the eloquence and their ability
to to speak we've convinced ourselves
and tricked ourselves to such a degree
that we can get other people to drink
our kool-aid as well but what Reich was
saying is I'm not interested in
listening to my patients speak in fact
just lay there and breathe and he began
just being very enrolled in watching
what he called the respiratory wave of
the individual and that means how the
softness of your torso allows the way
from your perineum down guys that we
call the tank yes we do because we're
classy like that right try to take your
balls and taint your asshole so it's
somewhere between there how's that how
that got coined even classier welcome
you know he's not watching their balls
but in Alexander Lowen who ended up
being a mentor of mine they would ask
their patients take their shirts off and
we're like you know bicycle shorts you
can literally watch from the pelvis or
all the way up into the face the facial
musculature across the eyes across the
jaw the neck the chest the belly the
pelvic floor he recognized that there
were certain bands of what he called
muscular armor bring across those
particular areas the eyes the jaw the
neck shoulders chest belly pelvic floor
and the therapy consisted of healing a
person psychological ills and trust we
all have psychological ills due to
trauma that we experience just by being
a part of civilization I mean it it were
caged animals in that way so where we've
all been traumatized it's not a matter
of were you abused or were you in an
accident or your war veteran it's a
matter of we live in civilization it's
truck is traumatizing to the physiology
of the human being the therapy consisted
of an Alexander Lowen took it a bit
further it consisted of helping the
individual reduce the muscular tension
in those bands of muscular armoring a
person who didn't have the tension
across the eyes because believe it or
not your eyes and your jaw play a
significant role in your bill
you to breathe deeply we might not think
so because we tend to think that it's
just the lungs but you're breathing from
your entire body from the tip your head
down to your your tailbone it's all
breathing you're you we're breathing
organism when there's no muscular
tension and the structural integrity is
integris you know you everything lined
up perfectly properly you breathe so
deeply and softly that your pelvic floor
expands there's a really interesting
book called embryonic breathing and
Qigong meditation and in that book I
think that's one of the reasons why I
started saying breathe into your balls
the technique was to begin breathing so
much that you could actually feel your
balls drop with your inhalation and the
reason why your balls are drop is
because you're so soft in your torso
that when your diaphragm expands when it
drops it pushes your stomach your colon
all your organs down into your pelvic
floor and your pelvic floor is so soft
that it allows those organs to sort of
push down on the perineum down into your
pelvic floor that is a person who is
soft from the tip of their head to their
tailbone and when they breathe they're
really accessing all of what's available
to us on multiple different levels
physiologically psychologically
neuromuscular Lee okay Wow this requires
some sort of work as well you can't just
start off doing it all right let's take
a quick timeout for a sec some people
think the art of Tron boot camps and
programs are just about picking up girls
and honestly there's some of that one
week with us and you'll be rocking out
in that department I promise but as a
guy I know how important it is to be
awesome and well-rounded and not just
awesome with girls awesome at work
awesome at home awesome with your
friends and family guys really need to
step it up everywhere and that's why we
call our company the art of charm that's
special something that gets you results
wherever you go and trust me the results
are real every day I get new emails and
calls from the guys who decided to take
our bootcamp and what i hear is simply
amazing just weeks after graduating they
land a promotion they form a new
Wolfpack start a new business or even
find a partner they have a new life and
it's not an accident find out why at the
art of charm calm all right let's get
back to the good stuff how do we start
to destroy the muscular tension that
blocks that type of breathing I mean
you've got some bioenergetics I don't
even know what that necessarily is but
there's got to be some stretching some
exercises that guys can do because I
know that it's not just as easy as crack
in the back and getting to work on that
stuff no and I tell you in my experience
it's an ongoing never-ending process of
adjusting to civilization adjusting to
life by using deep breathing stretching
exercising I there's one that I would
like to share with you one exercise in
particular it's called a bow and it
essentially requires that you stand on
your two feet there are several
variations of them but one which is like
the most aggressive is to raise your
hands straight up in the air spread your
fingers as wide as you can open your
mouth as wide as you can and that's the
toughest one for most people i mean just
stretch your jaw open and then begin
leaning backwards as far as you can and
breathing in that position you'll most
people if they have a high charge most
men with high charge will start
vibrating they'll either start choking
and having to figure out how to breathe
in this stress position or the whole
body starts vibrating and shaking
uncontrollably and most people freak out
but the idea is to allow that to happen
because it's essentially your desire to
breathe in that stressful position it's
fighting against the muscular tension in
your belly in your chest and your neck
and your face in your throat pelvic
floor and it's very uncomfortable yet
it's also very powerful and after a few
minutes of doing it you'll know that
you're breathing deeper simply because
your voice will get deeper because
there's no tension in your throat any
longer in your chest and in your belly
and you'll just feel very common and
grounded and relaxed and focused that's
one form of a bioenergetic yoga type
exercise that would support you in being
able to breathe into your balls you know
it seems like that would be something
that would be important for us to carry
in and practice
on the daily and not get frustrated with
as well but not all of us are patient
and I know you didn't start off being
patient as well let's back up a truck
way up and talk about how you got to the
point where you decided that physical
strength being inseparable from
emotional and mental strength was even
important in the first place because you
were doing strongman stuff you took a
lot of angles and advantages that ended
up biting you in the ass and bringing
you to the realization that this stuff
is crucial and is actually possibly as
important or more important than the
physical component itself right see the
body is the mind it is the physical
component your psychology your
psychological character the way you
carry yourself psychologically is it's a
chicken or an egg situation right your
body is going to dictate how you feel
about yourself and how you feel about
yourself is going to dictate how you
carry your body it's one of the same and
I've always been a body person like I
described earlier I've always been into
exercise I've always been into physical
fitness I've always been into sports I
but my focus has always been on the body
there was a point in which I became kind
of depressed I was probably about 23
years old and in my experience 23 years
on earth is one of those transition
periods in life where you're posed with
a lot of different options and ambiguity
about where to go what to do and we
start growing up but not sure for men
yet or all these different things that
kind of converge at the age of 23 that I
seen a lot of my clients and the
questions that come in and went through
a slight bout of depression but you know
not the type where I'm going to stay
there I'm never to type to stay anywhere
too long especially it doesn't feel good
and I started studying meditation i came
across the ideas of a man named Osho
also known as rajneesh and he's long
passed away now but his whole mission in
life was to bring meditation to the west
and he's done a tremendous job in doing
that but it wasn't so simple as well sit
down and meditate right he realized that
the Western mind body has far more
charge than the Easterns where a lot of
these ideas first came from and might be
easy to tell someone growing up in the
Indian culture you know typically of the
traditional Indian
well you meditate well of course yeah or
to tell someone from the traditional
Chinese culture well you've got to do
chi gong you gotta do Tai Chi well of
course I mean they do it every day it's
a part of the culture but to come to the
west where we're very are ye yang or
very aggressive we're very heady to say
well now you've got to sit down and
meditate I'm gonna show your brain off
didn't seem to work yeah yeah I think
it's kind of a difficult thing to tell
most Westerners especially Western men
American men well now go meditate
without seeming as if you're castrating
yourself right especially given the
religion of science in the west where we
essentially respect only that which can
be calculated or counted right she would
he decided or discovered and he was also
a big fan of Wilhelm Reich I think Reich
died before he did the guy was not just
a mystic but he was a university
professor and he taught psychology and
philosophy so he's well-read and he
understood quite a bit and he devised a
form of meditation very similar to
bioenergetics bioenergetics is the term
I used to describe a lot of this he
called it active meditation active
meditation if I could describe it
briefly is basically get all your
sillies out my children watch a show
called Yo Gabba Gabba where they teach
children you know there's one segment in
the shower and put on a song it says get
your sillies out shake your sillies out
and children basically shake their face
and end they jump around and they shake
their body and they they laugh or they
just they start throwing things around
like my kids will just like they'll roll
and do backflips and then it just go
nuts just go nuts for a little while
because there's so much tension and you
know this with children there's so much
tension in their bodies because they're
so active there's so much energy and
aliveness vitality that they just have
to get it out and if you don't as we get
older of course we get more conditioned
by society and we have more shame in our
body but the necessity for physical
release for catharsis if you will for
shaking your sillies out never goes away
you see so again I've got four children
so they're they're far more grounded
they're far more centered they're far
more available
after bouts of physical activity its
namely unstructured physical movement
like shaking your sillies out so anyway
active meditation dynamic meditation
appealed to me because I was my body
person and I saw that well there's this
meditation where you basically just
you've got 15 minutes to go nuts and do
whatever you want granted you're not
hurting another person in the room or
you know hurting yourself but you just
you shut off your brain and shake your
sillies out so I went to a class in New
York City and for 21 days you do this
form dynamic meditation at a significant
portion of it while shaking your sillies
out and called the catharsis and I got
involved in that way and it felt
tremendous it felt great I felt like a
new person that the whole sense of being
depressed had left me because I was
breathing deeper my body was softer I
just felt tremendous I felt good so I
started delving a little bit deeper and
I found that there are psychoanalysts
there are practitioners they're not
necessarily respected by the medical
community here for one reason for asthma
Selby's as medication so there's no need
to do studies no right there's no
empirical studies there's no clinical
trials there's no way to set it up it's
all anecdotal so yes it becomes
pseudoscience which does not mean that
it's complete bullshit and although
often it does I tend to be open in that
way and I got the benefits from the
dynamic meditation so I decided to
develop deeper I work with a
practitioner and here was my experience
and of course this is anecdotal I make
no claims about anything here this is my
caveat these things have helped me I'd
like to share it with you in hopes that
perhaps it may be resourceful and
helpful to you if not that's fine I'm
not trying to say I'm right I'm not
saying this is true and I'm not saying
everyone should believe me or do it
themselves I just happen to have gained
from it I got a big mouth so I have to
share the lady was a neo Rican
practitioner and I walk into her office
and the very first thing she does is she
puts me into a variation of the bow
which is an exercise I described earlier
and very stressful I've never done this
for my life I start by berating and
shaking and then she invites me to go
over to a mattress on the floor she
invites me to proceed in humping the
mattress she says just we have the top
the mattress and just start jamming it
with your hips like you're humping it
and she just continued to provoke me and
say just do it harder harder harder yeah
I'm like what the fuck's going on yeah
anyway you're looking for the video
camera like what is happening right now
uh and then I break into laughter I
break into this deep laughter the type
children do or you might experience when
you spoke to much marijuana or just
laughing and you belly hurts you just
can't stop tears are coming to your eyes
you're just it's such a pleasurable
feeling I'm hoping the mattress I start
laughing and I couldn't stop laughing I
didn't stop crying and I couldn't catch
my breath and I start apologizing to her
saying but I'm sorry I know that this is
a therapy session um I can't stop back
you know what's going on and she smiles
and says that's okay that's exactly
what's supposed to happen yeah after I
gather myself after several minutes of
laughing deeply from my belly she
explained she said now listen I wanna
know what happened here and she says to
me that at some point someone told you
that you're not a good boy if you feel
pleasurable feelings you're either told
you to sit down and shut up and to stop
playing you know having fun but we're
not supposed to have fun because you're
in church or in school whatever case may
be and the particular area of your body
your hips showed signs of muscular
rigidity due to an experience you may
have had now she said I can't tell you
exactly what that experience was at this
particular time but your body told me
that this is where you had tension and
all i did was i gave you an exercise to
help break up the muscular tension in
that particular area when the laughter
broke out it was a sign of emotional
release and a regaining of the character
associated with allowing pleasure to
happen in your body this is sort of the
way she explained it to me sure and I
felt really good and I figured well this
is awesome I I wonder that I did that
one session with already I never went
back but one of the long-lasting effects
that I experienced was that ever since
that it moment in that session I we have
sex with my wife and at the end I would
break down into laughter joyful laughter
my whole body we just vibrate with
laughter first my wife is like what the
hell yeah I was gonna say the first time
that happened probably not a good effect
on the wife's know she was I was this
and I explained there what happened the
day before and I knew that something had
changed in me deeply at that point now I
didn't have much time because I was busy
trying to get my life started and I
started a business and was moving and so
on and so forth so I didn't spend too
much time studying it years later
probably about three years ago I started
doing more research and i came across
the ideas of wilhelm reich alex and
alone i began working with one of low in
students my name Bob blasier who lives
in Florida and started a process of
therapy that he called bioenergetics
where there were X similar exercises he
would do certain things I put me into
stress positions where I be forced to
breathe even though it was uncomfortable
there would be some neuromuscular
trigger point therapy press on my chest
or press on my head or press deeply into
my belly like towards my belly button or
to the left and right of it and I would
experience this release of emotional
catharsis I would scream or yell or I
cry and it's been hours crying there so
my experience with the results of the
therapy was that I started making better
choices in my business my relationship
with my wife and children had improved
my athletic ability had improved I
actually began looking different in my
voice changed the physical change is
associated with the exercise also led to
all the character gems that I just
described my business exploded there
after that was about the same time that
my youtube channel went from about a
hundred thousand people to now almost
900,000 I had become a stronger version
of myself but I'd should be a lot of it
to these exercises that change not just
my body my ability
breathe but also my character who I see
myself to be excellent and that sort of
proves that emotional that physical and
spiritual component are always
inseparable they are the same thing
working on the tension that you had in
your body led to changes directly in
your mind that you can attribute
directly to changes in your body in
fitness there's a phrase that we like to
use and it's the same phrase that it is
repeated over and over again and
bioenergetic or body psychology therapy
circles but that is form equals function
and it's pretty likely everybody agrees
they shake their head well for me equals
function yes you know you can only
perform the way the structure is formed
even with regard to cars like you're not
going to get a Jeep Wrangler to run like
Moz rotten but also the way you carry
yourself that has a direct impact on
your psychology so the way that you
behave the way that your body's put
together will have a direct impact on
your psychology carry yourself with your
chest drop your storm dropped and your
head looking down for a day you're not
going to feel very energetic or happy
about yourself and people aren't going
to behave towards you in a way that's
respectful but put a spring in your step
you know sort of bounce on your toes
when you're walking keep your head up
high look at people in their eyes and
you're going to experience a totally
different psychological state excellent
it goes back to the mine fell in the
body and the body fall into mind a lot
of people think it's whoo whoo it's
really not it is based on science not
just easier in science but yes some
pseudo science in there but all people
need to do to figure that out is to
observe and to see how their own
physiology affects their emotional state
more from Elliot at pulse strength calm
and of course that's Huls a and that'll
be linked up in our show notes as well
Elliot thanks so much man there's a
reason you have nine hundred
thousand-plus YouTube followers will be
linking to your channel as well in the
show
note so that people can go and subscribe
there too oh man I appreciate it was a
fun show perhaps play a little game
called just the tip just for a second
just to see how it feels hey this is
jordan harbinger host of the art of
charm podcast the number one dating and
relationship advice podcast in itunes
i'm emily morris host of the sec to the
emily podcast the number one sex and
relationship podcast on itunes and it's
sex with Emily calm and this is just the
tip alright so you mentioned earlier
like 0 the brains the biggest erogenous
zone it's totally like a cliche thing
that everybody's heard but what are some
erogenous zones that guys might not ever
think about I know so glad you asked
that because really most mentally think
of like you know the breasts yeah down
and under 30 ever think about those are
my favorite erogenous exactly we all
know those your favorite artists on so
I'm here to tell you that a lot of women
have Roger stones that you had no idea
existed and you should make it your
life's work to find out what her other
erogenous zones are for example the
earlobes very sensitive some women just
you touch them kiss them gently bite the
earlobes since shivers down our spine
every woman I know jewelry in there
exactly or by our diamonds sottero
piercer ears um collarbone a lot of
men's like fine collarbones irresistible
why not touch it and kiss it I'm barner
shirt little touch that spot make
circles with your tongue give her love
bites yeah yeah thighs touch her thighs
before you go in for the treat okay
massage your thighs liquor tease her use
your tongue drag it on our thighs I
massage and then go in for it I'm
telling you it'll turn her on to be
begging you for it nice all right
anything else how much time do we have
we each give her faux massage every
woman dreams of foot massage you put
extra pressure on our toes and ankles a
side of her feet and she'll be putty in
your hands for whatever you want nice if
you guys want to learn more from the art
of charm about dating relationships and
even networking for business visit us at
the art of charm podcast.com or check us
out in itunes and follow me on twitter
at the art of charm and check out the
sector thelma podcast at sex with Emily
calm and iTunes if you want to have the
best sexier life that is also follow me
on twitter at sex with Emily alright
show feedback and guest suggestions we
rely on you guys to help keep our finger
on the paul
so if you know someone who's a good fit
for the show let us know at Jordan H at
the art of charm calm bootcamp details
for our live programs also at the art of
charm calm and that's where you're going
to find links to us on Twitter Facebook
and other social media as well if you're
listening to this but you're not
subscribed in itunes or stitcher or
something like that then that needs to
change getting our shows delivered free
to your phone or computer is the best
way to make sure you don't miss a thing
you can do that by going to itunes and
searching for the art of charm podcast
or by going to the art of charm calm /
itunes and clicking subscribe that's
really it and you guys can help us
subscribe in iTunes and give us a five
star rating write something nice and we
will love you forever just go to itunes
com / the art of charm and it'll take
you right there when you write us a
review it not only makes us feel proud
but it helps keep us up in the ranks so
that other people who can use this
information can find the show more
easily to get the credible advice that
they need it's also the best way to
support the show other than purchasing
products and training from us to tell
your friends because the greatest
compliment you can give us as a referral
to someone else either in person or
shared on the web now have a great week
go out there and get social and leave
everything better than you found it