all right we got a strange interesting
fun question here from one of our
buddies uh what's his name
Tahoe kid he calls himself anyway he's
19 years old and he was raised as a
Catholic he doesn't identify with with
the Catholic Church any longer he reads
some of Osho's books that I shared with
him so he he believes that love is God
not vice-versa so he's got a he's got a
particular standpoint with regard to God
philosophy theology yeah he sounds like
a pretty smart kid however and I don't
say he's smart because he's
quote/unquote atheist or or doesn't
believe in the you know the fatherly
patriarch type god that most people do
I'm singing smart kid because he pays
attention and he studies and he he
explores he ask questions people ask
questions are usually far more clever
than those who just do this anyway so he
says however the girl I love his
Christian Christ like hmm she believes
in God very much we've known each other
for three years never dated the reason
is because she says she can't date
outside her religion because Jesus
wouldn't like that you're being
condescending obviously even though she
says she really liked me once the date
maybe she can't she told me this when I
asked about two years ago and that day
on she's been in three relationships two
of the guys cheated on her I wonder if
they were Christian Christ like and uh
the other one just didn't work out we've
been talking so on and so forth she's
single now and he really just wants to
pour his heart out to her say look I
love you like guys are cheating on you
you're you're living you're living your
particular way cuz we all should but uh
I want to be with you and I know you
want to be with me - this is his
position he says that I know that she
loves me and I love her however I am Who
I am and I'm not going to become a
Christian just for her I'm not going to
convert just because if she did if he
did he'd be betraying herself and God
because in essence he'd be telling a lie
just to shack up with her probably what
the other dudes were doing you know yeah
I'm a Christian oh go Jesus and you know
they fuck her and then leave you know
most guys are douchebags in that way
you're not willing to do that although
your
Christian you're probably far more
christ-like than she's ever been so why
do I handle the situation blah blah blah
okay here's the thing
of course I sound very condescending in
the way that I described this answer
because I because the problem is she's
not a Christian never have I ever seen
and you know of course there are lot of
Christians that have attacked me here
but I don't think Jesus ever said don't
marry someone who isn't personally
identified with a religion that I didn't
even really create because I was a Jew
trying to tell the Jews how to do things
the way God really wanted them to do so
you got all these Christians out there
personally identifying with a religion
that really was not really created by
the teacher of it creating all types of
rules that aren't even in the book like
where in the Bible is to say don't marry
or don't don't be with someone who's a
Christian fucking Jesus would hang out
with anybody Jesus hung out with it with
the dregs of society the lowest of the
low he's hanging out kissing the feet of
bums and prostitutes and Christians are
so pious now so Christ like they can't
date outside their religion now I'm not
saying everybody but this particular
situation you know I like you said you
were you raised as a Catholic I like
this new pope I like this new pope yeah
I don't remember his name
the new pope this guy is like he's more
christ-like than than any quote/unquote
Christian I've ever seen and it's
incredible to see a pope you know behave
this way he saw a picture on the
internet the other day where he was like
caressing and kissing the face of a
severely deformed man like the type of
man that like back in the medieval days
like they would have they would have
shunned and killed him he would have to
live in a cave because he was so ugly
this man is like caressing him and
kissing him look if you if you're a
woman and this woman is really a
Christian she's really Christ like she's
really living by what would Jesus do she
would have
the sense of connection with God that
would have steered her out of the path
of those cheating Christians at screwed
ER and left and she could see the Christ
in you right and what's what's the
purpose of the Christ's love is to share
and invite others into the love of
Christ and if she really loved you so
I'm challenging really this videos to
challenge her her motives and kind of
wake you up to the type of person she is
I don't know what kind of love you have
for her but know that she's she's
manipulative and confused number one if
she really loved Christ she would see
the Christ in you and she shoot shoot of
Shor's health in the garbage that was
coming her way with those boys that were
so cool Christian that right away he
tells me she's not really a Christian
she's like one of these name-brand
Christians people who call themselves
things they're people like all over the
place they have these personal I have
indications with labels because it makes
them feel like they belong to something
right I belong to this I'm a part of
this I find stability in this particular
ideology which most of them they don't
even find stability in the ideology cuz
they don't even fucking understand the
ideology my people are parts of
particular religions they don't fuck
that's all about they just know that
that's what I am and you know these are
the rules my parents told me they we do
that's number one number two she really
loved you she really was a Christian and
she really loved you the Christ in her
heart would be so full spilling over
with such intensity that she couldn't
help but to hold you by your face kiss
you have compassion for you the same way
Christ had for his people bring you into
her heart with hopes that you could see
the Christ spirits in all not that she
wants to convert you into a particular
name brand or put you in a particular
category called Christian but she
would want to share her experience of
Christ's love with you most religious
people are full of shit she's up to her
eyeballs in it done