pretty soon I'm going to be a certified
personal trainer I just wanted to ask
you what I could do to be a good
personal trainers obviously I don't want
to do it just for money to have
something keep me occupied I want people
to know that I'm like we said I would
like to create masters I can just tell
you maggot I spent the fittest a bad I
spent a lot of time working with people
one-on-one time working in groups and it
does help and you look at the water
these actually a tremendous job changing
people's I believe that the physical
forms and manifestations of the
spiritual reality then these are these
are transform people activity they can
maintain it
but I found and that's why I end up
talking to where i talk i found that
physically transforming people is
powerful in and of itself and it's
rewarding for you to rewarding for them
what you will quickly realize that
you're more than anybody to train into
existence quickly realize that you're
more than just a training they'll come
in and it's like husband again before
you know they just no company to play my
boss complain about their problems their
mothers a bitch husband and their kids
coming and it's like all the ugliness
that you saw on their body when they
first came in doesn't go away even
though their body changed and when they
leave you what happened the other thing
that gotik walked into the restaurant
you look worse than when I first started
raining remember that guy you'll see him
in a couple years and like we talked
about before they're not different
people they come back five octaves oh
look at work then when they first walked
into my gym door and I just got
frustrated with that I realized that
personal trainers of waiting is emits a
funny position because you really want
to change your healing people's souls
touch people what their hearts they're
asking you to do it that's why they come
in they start talking to you about their
mothers and their husbands and I've
taken it in that direction now or I
don't see as many people but I try to
touch people with my words
then ideas and words might be
transformative answer but it was like
good luck people who have school this
shit on you see end up being a therapist
and really the talk