how many times a week do you fat well I
think what you mean by fat is jerk-off I
don't
yo Eliot would inspires you to take the
career and outlook on life that you have
well the career I decided to take
because I love strength training I love
sports so I decided why not do what I
love my outlook on life if I could trace
it back to a single experience its my
outlook comes from not knowing what I am
I was always asked what are you kid what
are you and and that set me on a path of
always asking what am i what am i what
am i and let me to all the philosophies
in psychology that I study now have you
ever popped a Molly I have no clue what
that means bro what's your opinion on
531 I like it anything that has to do
with lifting heavy I like why didn't you
go to Nebraska and play football well
then I would have never met you how fast
can you run a mile
since my light ran was right over seven
minutes like seven minutes and nine
seconds something like that how come
your legs are so big is it from
squatting or some Elliott Magic it's
definitely Elliott magic what is the
average amount of time that you sleep
when do you wake up and when you go to
bed in bed by 10:30 every night I like
to get up at 5:00 but that destroys me
for the next couple days so I usually
get up around 6:30 7:00 when did you
start this whole stronger version of
your self idea and goal well I've always
been neurotic and always been into
personal development the idea of a
stronger version of yourself comes from
a book by a guy named Matthew Kelly
where he consistently referred to the
best version of yourself and I really
like that but I thought stronger sound a
lot better so I took it and made it my
own Elliot what is the meaning of life
whatever meaning you give it Elliot
what's the best movie you've ever seen I
don't watch too many movies
to that I really like they're both Brad
Pitt movies the first one is Fight Club
and the other one is legends of the fall
yo Elliott why is my penis so small
genetics Pro Elliott why are you so
handsome
genetics babe have you ever dealt with
any injuries and what did you do to
overcome them yeah lots of them I told
my bicep a couple years ago and I made a
video series about it in my youtube
channel go check it out what race are
your parents my parents are from Belize
and please is a country that it was
inhabited by natives then invaded by
Europeans who brought along their
African slaves it was a big fucking orgy
that's why I look the way I look what
are your thoughts on CrossFit I think
CrossFit is cool it's fine I mean
anybody who has that much haters must be
doing a good job
what's your face you tell me bro are you
the hodgetwins brother or cousin hahaha
have you ever had an outer-body
experience yeah every time I orgasm when
will you come out as an anarchist you
talk about the principles that lead
people to that conclusion look I might
be an anarchist I might be an atheist I
might be a libertarian I might be a
Christian I might be all types of shit I
just don't know the names that you give
them I'm just Elliott Hulse and if you
want to put me in a box that's fine but
I'm not going to stay what is the most
helpful thing you ever learned or
realized that nothing is that serious or
nearly as serious as we think it is what
kind of car do you drive
I Drive a 1995 suburban Chevy Suburban
it's old beat-up blue and dirty how many
women have you been with not many
especially since I've been dating my
wife since I was four
why do you lift barefoot well ever since
I started doing yoga I've realized how
cramped my feet are so because a lot of
the yoga postures require that you
really spread your feet and open up your
toes I've realized that a lot of my
biomechanics have been destroyed by
wearing shoes so I just try not to wear
shoes that much at all anymore so
lifting is just one of those things that
happens to be what I do every day and I
don't wear shoes but usually what is the
root to the unique outlook you have on
life the root of it is as I described
earlier growing up not knowing who out
you what I am or Who I am and it does
that question embedded itself into my
consciousness and causes me to always
question everything were you good enough
to play in the NFL hell yeah
still makes me mad Eliot sick
[Music]