hey so we got this question form of our
friends who has a long hard stoic look
on his face and he says although he's a
happy-go-lucky guy I mean I feel pretty
good and I like people I want to make
friends but I just can't get the scowl
off my face and he says that people will
say to him boy why are you always so
upset why do you always look mean and
man you know what's with that what's
with that mean face dude don't you don't
you like us and he's like yeah I fucking
love you I really just want to have a
good time with you right now and I can't
understand why my face looks this way
right so he he's wondering Elliott how
do i how do i brighten up my look so
that are more approachable to people
that's really his question how could it
be more approachable because I've got
this hard face on and here's what
typically happens you know because at
first I was going to offer
dude just smile and this really was
thinking I read all I read a lot of
these questions I don't answer him isn't
Mike sometimes the question is so
fucking simple I'm like dude just smile
but then I began thinking about one of
the faces that I see on people's faith
in the world when I look at people that
I abhorred more than anything and that
is the fake fucking smile it is it's so
deplorable this one right it's like
because what people don't understand is
that your body is oh it's one thing and
it all tells the story and if you're
trying to paint on something with the
rest of it severed your you look like an
asshole face smiles look shitty they
look worse than a scowl keep your
fucking scowl dude it's don't do this oh
yeah women do this a lot middle-aged
women for some reason
because I need to see nice don't see
nice don't put on that that bullshit
face because we all see through it now
whether or not people are picking you
apart in their heads like I am or not
they sense it that's a fake fucking
smile and it looks horrible on you
here's what you got to do and it's gonna
require a little bit of exercise dude so
it depends on how important it is to you
to be approachable right any
approachable is one of these important
things in life because we kind of need
each other we live life through each
other right no man's an island here's
how you present with a genuine smile you
have to make yourself laugh laughter
doesn't happen here guy guy guy got like
Popeye right laughter doesn't happen in
the face uh Oh like spongebob hey but
he's got a square body laughter happens
in your belly and in your heart right it
looks like this you see how genuine my
smile is right now because I'm laughing
smiling is a fruit of belly laughter you
can't fake a smile or help what's better
way to put this you can't not smile if
you've got a laugh going on in your
belly you've got to make yourself laugh
I was in New York a couple weeks ago and
I did a UH I had a family reunion and I
and then I invited some of my fans to
come and hang out at this restaurant and
I'm taking pictures all fucking day all
day I'm taking pictures and I start
finding myself doing this but they smile
because they you know you want to be
approachable for the fucking camera
knowing how much I hate the fake smiles
like I ain't doing this shit so what we
started doing what I invited my my group
you know I had some old friends and
we're
we were taking pictures and shit I got
everyone to laugh just by fucking
laughing and I said this I said listen
guys we have to laugh so these pictures
look good so I started going this right
and if you're receptive of the people
that you're working with in that circuit
in that way or receptive because you
know you've got to have powerful energy
this is all it's about you know dude
being presentable and offering yourself
and receiving from other people it's
about how transparent your energy is how
permeable are you and how can you soften
other people up to be permeable for your
energy right I mean this is these are
sexual dynamics man how do you assert
yourself tenderly tender aggression
that's what I'm talking about you're
just too fucking aggressive aggressive
giggling is tender tender your body up
and it's going to make its way up into
your face done