so we got a little bit of a weird
question here my favorite kind says uh
our buddy says yo Elliott I notice a
month ago my back and chest started to
feel really tense I talk faster than
usual walk really fast it can't really
think clearly because I'm so hyper any
advice to be normal and get rid of this
tense muscle I feel in my tense muscle I
feel in my chest and back prior to that
a month ago I was high school and
weightlifting helped question mark so
this is a part of the reason why it
sounds strange but I'm against the
building up of a lot of thick rigid
muscle in the upper body
I personally have experienced that the
bigger my the muscles in my chest and my
mid-back especially up here the bigger
my chapped skin I naturally have just
big chaps but if I start doing shrugs or
up I rose or anything that causes the
muscles in this portion of my body right
because it's all it's all integrated by
fashio
right not just the nervous system but we
also have tissue that that links our
whole body together and then I end up
starting to have tension in my neck into
my jaw in my head because I'm doing a
lot of shrugs I'm doing a lot of like
hit like high volume this is really what
it is high volume part of the reason why
I like high-intensity low-volume is
because you don't get that tense feeling
in your muscular system that some guys
like and I'm not saying everybody should
do what I do or or a pre approach
training the way I approach it these are
my experiences and apparently our friend
is experiencing a lot of the same shit
that I do when I do high volume weight
lifting specifically for the upper body
and I'm talking about like from your
diaphragm up it all restricts my ability
to breathe softly and ground my energy
and if you're experiencing tension
across the chest and throughout the back
it's going to make you feel neurotic
like you're feeling right now and I know
what I'm ungrounded when I use this term
ungrounded I mean that your energy is
this place from your balls the ground of
your energy
existence is in your pelvic floor and as
you become muscular yes your your
muscular system becomes tense around
your belly and it starts moving up into
your diaphragm up into into your chest
and your neck in your face you sort of
lose the roots of your your existence
you lose your grounding and I don't know
how to describe it without being too
poetic and and what happens is you die
but you're noticing it right away
because first I'll begin speaking too
fast speaking ahead of myself and I like
you say I'm hyperactive you know they
gave me pills when I was a kid because I
was hyperactive this kid needs to sit
down and shut the fuck up well I
realized that a lot of it had to do with
the displacement the displacement of my
energy when I say energy it's nothing
mystical about it when I say that I mean
basically the how your nervous system is
focusing its attention if you will in
certain areas of the body and it would
read it would rise and my behavior is a
manifestation of this muscular tension
I've called it neurotic holding patterns
and my inability to breathe inability to
breathe is present this is why I
emphasize the use of doing exercise
doing bioenergetic exercises yoga
stretching stretching the body and deep
breathing these all contribute to
softening the muscular tension in the in
parts of the body that reduces your
ability to breathe deep because when you
begin slowing down and breathing deep
into your pelvic floor down allowing
your diaphragm the drop drop deeply into
the abdominal cavity your organs soften
your entire when I use that term viscera
the visceral system it not only includes
look this up the visceral system doesn't
simply include the organs I say organs
because the the autonomic nervous system
which integrates the organs is the is
the non-thinking intelligence of our
bodies it's the non conscious of
legends of our body it's the part of
your body that beats your heart without
you having to beat your heart you beat
your heart you say you remind yourself
heart you need to be or do you remind
your your stomach that it needs to
release certain enzymes in order to to
digest food you do to help peristalsis
with your colon you don't do any of that
when I say you I mean your conscious
mind you're not doing that that's what
makes you makes you mean so unique in
that way it's like we can focus on other
shit most animals but anyway there's
this there's this form of intelligence
in our body when I say viscera your
visceral system it is a portion of your
brain integrated with the organs and if
it becomes tense and it's rigid if the
organs are tense and rigid because the
the autonomic nervous system is tense
and imbalanced you're going to be
ungrounded you're going to be unhealthy
it's go it lead to all sorts of disease
and usually the disease stems from
actions and behaviors that we take if
you're if I'm ungrounded
I make ungrounded choices right I make
bad choices about my nutrition I think
veggie choices about how I speak to
people you know if I'm on ground and
I'll lash out because I'm hyperactive
because the entire visceral system and
muscular system is tense you've got to
reduce this tension this this nerve
these neurotic holding patterns in our
muscular system to allow ourselves to
relax into our strength and sexuality
it's why breathing into your balls I say
this often and it sounds like you know a
force I'm eccentric in that way but
there's there's a method to my madness
when I say breathing into your balls it
means that your organ system your
muscular system is soft in such a way
that you can breathe peacefully softly
have a nice what Wilhelm Reich called
your orgastic or respiratory wave you
won't have a respiratory wave you watch
a baby with the baby laying on its back
walls breathing there's this soft wave
of its entire core from its hips to the
of its head it almost looks like when
you're screwing no and you stroking with
your woman right a really good powerful
sexual stroke oneness it's going to
allow you to to muster up all the sexual
energy in your body and have a
tremendous sexual release orgasm and one
that your lady's going to like a lot is
when your entire core your entire body
is waving with the strokes see a lot of
us a lot of us are so muscularly tense
so tense in our belly and tense in our
chest we don't breathe and our body is
so segmented chopped up castrated that
one we're screwing it's just this right
it's like your body's one fucking unit
you're just jabbing with your dick
alright then allow for the four that
breathing orgastic wave Wilhelm Reich
one of the guys that I study that gives
me a lot of these wacky ideas calls it
your respiratory wave you'll see it in a
bit and a baby if you study ancient
forms of internal martial arts there's a
really good book called embryonic
breathing that describes this but right
not only likens it on to or not only
associated sit with your capacity to
breathe but also your orgastic capacity
or sexual capacity you would often
describe an assessment that he would
make about a person sexuality by their
ability to breathe because there's a
wave associated with breathing and
screwing dude I don't remember the
goddamn question what are we talking
about here honestly I forgot hang out
Hyper okay yeah hyperactive so through
bioenergetics of course I have a I work
with a professional my mentor Bob
glazier and I'm going through a multi
year six year course and he's got me
tied in because every few months I go
and I spend several days with him
studying bioenergetics the body mind and
psychology
you perform exercises that help you
reduce your it's a chicken and egg
situation you've got to consider that
the muscle the neuromuscular system and
the brain are linked so you can create
muscular tension in your body by with
bad thoughts just think scary shit a
really good book that I started reading
recently I'm ranting a lot lately is uh
my Peter Levine called trauma proofing
your children and he has a series of
exercises in that book there are stories
that you tell yourself and it's funny
because they go on these expansion and
contraction adventures so when you read
the story the idea is to notice the
sensations in your body and he'll talk
about a you're walking through it an
ice-filled
and all of a sudden a tiger jumps out
what do you feel so the idea of the
stories is to get in touch again with
our feelings the feelings of our body
and
boy I'm really ratchet today I need to
stop anyway you've got to learn to yes
okay
you got to understand the fluctuations
in your thought and recognize how
different thought patterns contribute to
muscular holding if you get scared
you've got to recognize that there are
certain muscles that are associated with
that fear so how does your body respond
or muscularly how does your muscular
system respond to thoughts of fear or
anger frustration right a lot of us hold
chronic anger for your frustration
from experiences that we had as children
you know if you've ever had road rage
like that's that's the straw that broke
the camel's back because you're carrying
around a lot of rage you're carrying
around a lot of muscular tension so it
could be the stories that we tell
ourselves based on the experiences that
we've had that need to be dealt with but
at the same time the muscular system
becomes chronically rigid in these but
in this particular way and needs to be
dealt with also through massage and
stretching it's why breathing yoga and
breathing exercises is so important and
bioenergetics because what bioenergetics
allows you to do when when you do a lot
of the crazy shit that you see me doing
yelling and screaming shaking your body
and going over the bow and allowing your
body to vibrate and doing all this shit
is you're releasing emotional baggage
that is causing your muscular tension
that doesn't allow you to breathe
doesn't allow you to stroke where you
should be stroking so that's it so I
hope that's helpful for you hopefully I
put you in touch with some resources
look my man if you happen to be
ungrounded in the way that you describe
because you've got muscular tension in
your chest and in your back watch a
video that I will either go up this week
or what up last week where I teach you
how to use the bow once again and build
a bioenergetics tool lay over the stool
that's going to allow you to open up
your thoracic cavity soften the muscles
on there on the back part of your body
and stretch the muscles so really you're
you're softening through with the foam
roller you're softening the muscular
system on the back and you're stretching
the muscular system in the front this
particular area is associated with
breathing and you want to soften it
through the exercises and structures
that I teach you
in that way don't