got a question from our buddy Braden
who's got a lot of pent-up emotion he
had a real rough childhood he says that
his dad tried to kill him a few times
and apparently he's still alive he's
still here he says he's lucky to be here
but he's got a lot of resentment a lot
of trapped anger and fear sadness
associated with that and also recently
what basically the straw that broke the
camel's back recently he lost two
friends and in an accident in a car
accident and he's tangled up on the
inside and he knows that there's emotion
that he's holding back it's trapped and
it is I'm telling you it is eating away
at you like a cancer every time we use a
muscular system because that's how we
hold emotion back use the muscular
system namely the extra respiratory
muscles you know I always talk about the
neurotic holding patterns associated
with the emotion that we're trying to
hold back through our face our jaw you
know the jaws associated with a lot of
anger but also sadness tears the chest
the belly in the pelvic floor right so
you've got muscular tension that's
holding this emotion in and you wants to
know how do I get it out well you know
I've made lots of videos about this but
I'm going to give you a little bit of a
different method here just because you
know these are all ideas that you've got
to play with we've got to use yourself
you got to see which one works for you
they're all a manifestation both forms
of bioenergetics I talked about what I
often what I would invite you to do is a
two step process my man because we all
have to do this we cannot keep emotion
trapped in our bodies because it will be
ungrounded we will be unhappy we will be
depressed we'll be frustrated we will
never become the strongest versions of
ourselves if we are holding in holding
back or holding on to notice they're all
holding patterns any Unruh source full
emotions you know they would say that
they're like demons
you've got demons in you you got to let
them out this is like exorcism it's
crazy but anyway the first thing I would
invite you to do is to open up your
respiratory pathway with exercises like
the bow I'll demonstrate it here quickly
for you but I've got other videos about
it you know to search the bow but anyway
we were to open up your chest
here and your belly and the best way to
do that is you can see me here too late
go back open your mouth and allow that
stretch to open up your belly your chest
your your pelvis and breathe open up
your mouth wide what that does is it
reduces some of the tension that you
just wrap in your jaw
you're literally stretching your jaw
muscles all the muscles in your jaw and
face that relax it and allows you to
breathe deep practice that you're going
to feel shaky you're going to shake your
that every day definitely gonna vibrate
that's basically you're fighting there's
like there's a resistance in your
muscular system against opening up to
breathe you're going to experience that
the next step because there are a lot of
different cathartic ways to get this out
you've seen lots of my videos I mean
I've got nuts on camera showing you a
catharsis looks like but one that may be
resourceful for you that may be easy to
begin with that a lot of people it's
very ancient very old
you know many religions use it is
speaking in tongues or just call it
gibberish right words are physical but
they're also abstract they're ideas but
they also because we verbalize them we
enunciate them they bring up and release
physical tension one of the words you
might want to begin with I'll start with
it with an actual word and an idea
associated with it but I'll show you
where I take it with regard to making it
pure gibberish which is speaking in
tongues yeah that's what they call it
all over the fuck you want but it's
basically what I'm going to show you now
one of the words that really evokes a
lot of the emotion is why get into the
why get it really emotional about the
why after you open up your body you're a
bit in a bit more resourceful place at
that point because you're stretched to
relax you breathe deep so you're charged
just look in the mirror and ask why why
why why why why why why why
why why you'll see as I acted out you
know I use my body I shake and I find
rating that and I I do physical actions
associated with why just do this why why
why why like a kid like a baby watch it
kid like watch a three-year-old live
children when they're upset ah why why
no no you see so children don't have the
radicals in matters because they do all
this weird shit that gets it out of
their bodies but as we get older and
more respectable and more neurotic we
clench up and we don't do anything you
know it's gonna be difficult first cuz
gonna be like why bye bye you'd like a
fucking robot most people walk around
like robots
how much more energetic I am after doing
this shit it does it works so you're
going to need to begin with that but
also let that turn into whatever
wherever will take you you'll find that
even though you're going to enunciate
words like I will do just in a moment
I'll show you how mine showing you guys
are fucking crazy I am enunciate words
that don't have any actual tangible
meaning they come from a visceral place
and then things that you're saying mean
far more than the then the definition of
the shit you're just saying if there's
emotion associated with the movement
blah blah devil the bumper dumper Zetas
but about that by that purpose
you see making myself crazy it so that's
what you got to do I the face crumbles
up for me quickly when I start doing
that because I'm getting into the
sadness that you need to express the
sadness that you need to to to go with
you know a lot of for a lot of us that's
the it's fear and sadness that's the
most superficial or actually I would say
the other way the deepest emotion
holding us tight if we can get rid of
the sadness by crying one of the easiest
ways to cries to use these methods I'm
teaching you right now make yourself cry
you've got to sob that's really it
becomes the it boils down to that it
boils down to me showing you a few
different exercises it's going to get
you emotionally charged so that you can
fucking cry because that's really what
you need to do you can't hold back those
tears holding back tears may seem cool
and you know you might not want to do it
in front of everybody all the time
but the fact is when you hold back those
tears you not only hold back the sadness
associated with it because physically
you know that's what it's going to be
all right here in the chest and in the
mouth but you're also holding back the
joy the pleasure the receiving of life
that you would experience if that was
not tense so you got to get rid of it if
you want to be happy again you got to
let these tears out dude
good luck