all right we have a really interesting
question from our friend Zoe she's a
female cross-country runner the the
actual problem that I'm going to share
with you is that she eats and eats and
eats and eats and it isn't necessarily
that she's junk food binging but she's
just filling her body with as much food
as possible multiple times a day
and it could be broccoli and chicken it
could be really healthy food but the
point is that she cannot stop putting
food in her body it gets to the point
where she's so full that she has to stop
and it's like it's a key and and then
she continues to do this over and over
again and it's almost like this is the
way she describes it a fog goes over my
mind and I become an animal who just
goes into the cabinet goes into the
refrigerator and just shelves my body
full of food and even to the point of
wanting to vomit I still do not feel
full so she wants to know what to do
prior to this so the history is that Zoe
has also suffered from a form of either
anorexia or bulimia she said that she
had a very restrictive diet up until
this point and she engages in the sport
of course country running okay that's
very significant and I want to approach
this first from your history of eating
disorders where you restricted your diet
right you mentioned restrictive you
didn't tell me exactly how but I took
that into account and the sport that you
engage in I'm going to use a term and
and bear with me for a moment as I
describe what it is I'd like to explain
to you they're both very schizoid
activities they're both activities where
the mind the head literally subjects the
body to its tyranny you punish your body
with your mind when you are bulimic or
you're anorexic you're essentially
putting yourself in a situation where
you're allowing your brain your head
brain to dictate the feelings lack of
feelings and motility
expression of the body so you just don't
eat you're using the will to punish your
body I'm just not going to eat like I'm
in control this is
control this part of your body this is
not in control none of us we're not in
control from the neck down you don't
decide how you're going to digest food
you don't decide what cells are going to
be regenerated you don't decide how your
hearts going to beat you don't decide
how your eyes are going to dilate and
contract you don't decide what your baby
is going to look like you don't decide
what do you see what I'm saying you
don't decide the things down here but
here there's a there's a sense that we
decide and you're punishing putting down
controlling that part of you that seems
out of control and it's a way to gain a
sense of control also cross-country
running nothing against the sport at all
there are functional and dysfunctional
expressions of every activity but a
dysfunctional form of activity or the
sport of cross-country running that
you've engaged in would be I'm using the
will to get my body to do what I want it
to do and what better way to deaden the
feelings in the body then through
repetitive movement movement so
cross-country running is just merely
this you use your head to lock your body
into a pattern and the body becomes like
a horse a slave the body feels something
I don't care the body wants to do
something else move in different ranges
MOCA does not matter you've locked it in
so you're using your head to decide what
your body gets and what your body does
right this is what would be classified
as dysfunctional behavior and you know
this this is the way you shared it with
me I'm just giving everybody competing
the picture for everyone but now it's
almost like your head shuts off and the
body says fuck you bitch and you're
never fulfilled that term is very
interesting I want to I want to dance
around that word right now fulfilled you
never feel full you never get enough you
eat eat till you know you're in pain and
you do this out of this almost a state
of unawareness guess what guess we took
over now the body took over
you're not even in control now you're
really pissed off it's like I'm not in
control of this it's almost like I
became hypnotized do you feel your body
with all this food and now it's causing
you all types of depression frustration
you're confused you don't know what to
do I used to be in control but I know it
was this functional now I've lost
control I'm gaining weight even though I
can choose the foods I can't help but to
fill my body in an unhealthy fashion and
even still there's a lack of fulfillment
so what have you done okay and I don't
say what have you done to judge you or
to like I say it let's take a look at
what happened it's a better way to
describe it you've turned your body into
the slave of your mind by deadening the
feeling in your body you can't be a
feeling body and starve yourself you
can't be a feeling body and subject
yourself to the pressures of
cross-country running in a dysfunctional
fashion like I said there are multiple
ways this could be done and you cannot
be a feeling body if you fill your body
with food but yet you can't tell if it's
full or not the mind is going well I
just ate a six-course meal an entire
chicken and you know whatever it is Jay
I'm still unfulfilled there's no feeling
in my body for whatever reason at some
point your life you chose that it would
be beneficial to you to reduce the
feeling in your body maybe there was a
sexual feeling towards someone that was
inappropriate at some time and you found
out that it was inappropriate and you
shut it down
perhaps there was something someone
wanted you to do move in a particular
direction that you really didn't want to
go but you had to so you shut down the
feeling in your body perhaps something
happened to you someone touched your
body in a particular way and you shut
down feeling to the body I don't want to
feel it whatever it is whatever happened
at some point perhaps you decided I
don't want to feel my body anymore
and now you're in a dysfunctional place
you're in a schizoid place where the
head has split itself from your body
what do you do now
well the short answer is you've got to
bring feeling back into your body easier
said than done
I'm just going to rattle off multiple
different ideas choose one or move in a
particular direction with any one of
them because I guarantee you that
somewhere you're going to knock on a
door and you're gonna pick oh I got
feeling back in my body when you got
feeling in your body a person who's
grounded in their body moves from a
grounded position they're actually more
in control than someone who shuts off
feelings to their body because if you
are all up in your head you can very
easily be carried away but if you are
grounded in your body you're adamant
you're a more practical you're a more
short footed individual and you will
make better choices and you will receive
the pleasure you'll feel good because of
the good choices that you make and you
will trust the bad feelings in you let's
say I shouldn't be doing this I
shouldn't be moving in this direction it
is truly earn avital system it all
happens down here that's why I say
listen to your heart listen to your
balls when I say balls of course you
don't have balls but listen to the Holy
Ghost listen to the instinct in your
body listen to that part of you that
beats your heart without you having to
think about it right your sexuality it's
all sexual energy you know people don't
like to hear that because I think that
Elliot's saying go and bone everybody
but what that means is that you know the
nervous system is a bunch of ons and
offs you know we have synapses that are
either turning on or off on and off on
or off this is the dichotomy this is the
male/female energy on off or on off and
it's happening to our entire body that's
what I mean when I say sexual energy is
that it's in male/female energy that's
happening in our bodies but if you're in
touch with that here in touch with your
heart you're in touch with your sexual
energy in touch with feelings in your
body then you make better decisions
right poor decisions made from a
hysterical place like I spoke about last
week with sexuality or not grounding
there's such thing as free but
ungrounded sexuality grounded free
sexuality
I understand what's happening here
you've got a we've got a foothold on the
situation so anyway in order to to
reinstate this place when you were like
a baby where you can actually feel your
body and you can respond appropriately
you're going to have to use a multiple
that you're going to have to try a few
different techniques the very first and
easiest one that I would invite you to
do is yoga and the only reason why I say
yoga is because there are two things in
yoga that are going to support you and
bringing feeling back in your body yoga
itself may or may not help you but the
opening up the range of motion in your
joints because yoga is going to require
that you stretch a lot and you're in
right now you're trapped in a very rigid
pattern of movement if you go to yoga
they're going to make you like pull your
frickin foot up to your head you're
gonna have like stretching and twist
that it's going to bring feeling back to
your body because it's opening up more
neural pathways and which is my opinion
the most important part of it it's going
to invite you to breathe deeply the
softness of your breath brings with it a
softness of the body okay now that may
be helpful to you might find that that
helps you right away right or you may
find that it's too superficial and
you're gonna have to go a little bit
deeper if you go a little bit deeper I
would invite you to get regular massage
we bring life to one another when we
touch either massage or form of Reiki or
some form of having another person put
their hands on you this may be difficult
especially if you were sexually abused
when you were younger and that's the
reason why or you were rejecting sexual
feelings that you had in your own body
that's really reason why we need to
bring that back we need to bring back
those sexual feelings those warm
feelings especially as they relate to
another human being back into your body
and that may look like massage okay
let's get someone to massage your body
all over your body massage your own body
feel your body there parts of your body
that you didn't association with put
your hands on it put your hands on your
heart breathe into your heart
feel your heart beating know that it's
there
give it your attention I have a heart
you know that's there feel the chills in
your body when you feel your heart okay
put your hand down below your belly
button right about a few inches below
your belly button and breathe into your
belly soften the muscles in your butt
soften the muscles in your pelvic floor
and breathe down into your pelvic floor
there's lots of sexual energy there that
often gets stagnant because we reject it
I'm not saying masturbate you know those
of you who mature enough to understand
the things that I say understand what
I'm saying is softened your sexual
energy
let go release it breathing into what
the Chinese would called your lower Dan
Tien about two inches below your belly
button put your hands there you can even
put your hands on your heart and you're
done Tien and breathe soften your jaw
let your mouth open right this might
work
breathing is often restricted by the
muscular systems holding back certain
emotions you might need some catharsis
I've made videos about this you might
need to take out the tennis racket find
a bed scream scream whatever comes up in
you if you find a place to do it fuck
you fuck you don't touch me don't touch
me get away from me
allow the energy to carry your
expression there might be things that
you need to express that are being held
back and that's not allowing you to even
breathe softly the breathing will work
but it might work better if you get rid
of the anger and very often the sobbing
the crying that you've been holding back
when you can grow when you can cry again
you will orgasm again and this is this
is just my assumption but I'm pretty
sure I'm spot on that your sex life
isn't that great you're using the
muscular system you're using the head
to withhold suppress energy in your body
you know an individual who has great
sexual feelings a woman who can orgasm
because she laughs with such a a deep
joyful laugh and she also cries the
softer your chest is your heart is this
is where we cry right here the softer
your heart is due to the allowance of
Tears and sobbing the easier will be to
share loving feelings towards someone
and orgasm is always best sexual
feelings are always more pleasurable
when they're done with someone that you
have a hard connection to you'll never
have a hard connection with anybody if
you're if your heart is closed and
finally the third thing I want to invite
you to do and this is very difficult
because it's so dynamic but find someone
you can share love with and physically
that may only that may be as simple as
someone who only hugs you it could be a
female friend doesn't mean you're a
lesbian
it could be a male friend it doesn't
mean that you have to have sex but bring
your heart close to another human being
let another person put their hands on
your body put their hands on your back
embrace you and let you breathe into
them rest your head on their shoulders
you see there's a longing for that type
of embrace that we used to receive from
our parents when we were babies and a
lot of our relationships are not mature
because people approach their love
relationships and not realizing that a
part of me just wants to be embraced and
it doesn't necessarily mean that I have
to own you or you you owe me anything
but participate in that embrace that
warm those warm heart feelings that you
open up to and allow another individual
to give you okay
you've got to bring warm feelings back
into your body start with your heart and
start with your pelvic floor down below
your belly button your sexual energy
stretch and breathe on your own touch
your body breathe into your body pay
people to touch you massage preferably
someone that you you feel good about and
invite someone else into your heart the
only way that's going to happen is if
you soften your body and when you soften
your body you'll bring feelings back
into it and when you bring feelings back
into your body you will not abuse it it
will feel fulfilled with nourishing food
in a functional fashion because you feel
what's happening in your body you will
never feel a dead body you will never
feel fulfilled until you can feel the
aliveness in your body I'm done