hey whats up guys Elliott Hulse here and
as you're probably well aware I've been
making YouTube videos since 2007 on
various aspects of becoming what I call
the strongest version yourself right and
of course that includes physical fitness
but it also includes mental fitness and
I love more than anything to talk about
these two various topics I enjoy making
these videos and I enjoy speaking with
you so don't get me wrong when I say
only so much can be said right you got
to actually do the thing in order to
have the power and growing stronger
becoming stronger version yourself it's
less of an idea or a philosophy or
something to talk about and it's more of
a way of being so I'm really glad to
introduce you to the grow stronger
experience where I'm going to be
traveling to various cities throughout
the US and Europe over the course of the
next few months not to give you another
talk because we've got enough of those
right where the teacher stands at the
front of the classroom and you sit tight
and take notes while he feels your head
with more information philosophy and
fancy phrases we don't need any more of
that this is going to be an experience
where we dig deeply into the
uncomfortable parts of who you are and
who you're being we're going to
experience and expose ourselves to the
shadow aspects of what keeps us small
you're also going to be exposed to the
Magnificent radiant light of yourself
you're fully embody itself and all that
you could be we're going to use music
dance and chanting they'll be laughter
some anger maybe some tears but we'll
use affirmation art and ecstasy in order
to get our hands dirty we're gonna get
sweaty
the gritty and dirty digging into the
depths of our being in order to discover
all that we are and all that we could be
I will see you there