so it's going to upload this video to my
non job YouTube channel simply because
there are a lot of people in there that
are being attacked by naysayers those
who say that the dream that our friends
have are not good enough and in fact
they're not good enough to achieve the
goals or the dreams that they have for
themselves and I want to relay a story
that I thought of when I started reading
those comments of those who are
naysayers when I was in middle school I
played football I played football when I
was in sixth grade the very first time I
played and I played in seventh eighth
grade which was in middle school in
middle school my math teacher also
happened to be the head football coach I
happen to be terrible at math when I was
in middle school so the teacher who also
happened to be my football coach
basically failed me in that class he
didn't he wasn't a man
angry man with me he was just like hey
look kid you're not very good at math
and he gave me a pretty bad grade and I
accepted that and that was fine but that
also left the seed in his head to
believe that I was a stupid kid so on
the football field shortly after the the
month that I failed his math class I
went out and I told them that I wanted
to be a running back I you know I felt
like I was fast I was fast I was faster
than all the other kids on the team I
wanted to be a running back that's
position when you grabbed a football and
you take it you run four touchdowns and
the coach told me that I was too dumb to
play running back right imagine this I'm
like 13 14 years old probably it's like
13 years old and someone who I look up
to by virtue of their age in position
you know he's much older than me and
he's my head football coach and my math
teacher and he tells me I'm too dumb to
stupid not bright enough kid to play
this position and I believed him he put
me to play a defensive line and I was a
very undersized defensive lineman but I
played that position with all of my
heart and I earned a football
scholarship to come
playing defensive line at five nine I'm
like five eight and a half five nine
playing defensive lineman I never waited
he more than two hundred and twenty-five
pounds very under sized but in high
school I was captain all-american MVP of
the all-star teams won a college
scholarship and was MVP Rookie of the
Year captain in college also at the
undersized position at an undersized
position at the wrong position for me
because I never pursued my dream of
becoming a running back for many years
because I believed with that one man
told me his name was mr. Crespi I hope
you watch this one day until one
opportunity came about when I was in my
junior year of football high school
college right playing college football
so this was many many years later maybe
ten years later all the running backs on
my college football team got injured in
my head coach at that time looked at me
and said hey Elliot I don't know why
you're not a running back but you're the
best defensive player we've got we need
your help
come and play running back for us so
you'll play both sides of the ball and I
plead running back for the very first
time led the team in touchdowns sacks
yards rushed and tackles behind the line
right if you know football you
understand what I'm saying that it took
many years for me to build up the
courage and for someone else to finally
see in me the ability to do something
that someone squashed in me when I was
in a very vulnerable place this is
what's happening to a lot of you guys in
many areas of your life and I think
namely of those who are in the non jobs
campaign in the revolution for non jobs
because I noticed that there are those
who are squashers of dreams now I don't
know why these people do this I don't
know why the naysayers or squashers do
this probably it's because they failed
in their lives
there's some shortcoming
that they experienced or someone else
squashed their dreams and in their
unconsciousness they go around squashing
other people's dreams and telling them
that they can't do it can't tell there's
a lot of resentment still in my heart
for that for the comments and the
squashing of my dream that that old man
shared with me it's not even the right
word he's vomited on me when I was 13
years old now that's not to say that I
am regretful for where I am today
because every experience that we have
leads us to who we are and where we
stand and that's always the right place
to be but there may have been a very
different outcome had that one negative
person not dropped his seed in my
consciousness and I personally let it
grow these people will drop seeds on you
don't let their fucking seeds grow it's
up to you to water and nourish that seed
when they drop it in you don't do it
ignore it completely you know what's in
your heart
the seed that's been planted in your
heart by God or the universe or Allah I
don't care what you call it the
animating force of the world has dropped
a seed in you of potentiality that far
exceeds even your imagination don't let
some asshole drop some shitty seed in
you and then you water it grow stronger
and then inspire others to become the
strongest version of themselves that's
how we evolve peace Elliott's it what