cut those questions one of our buddies
wants to know how to be more aggressive
as a male he notices that in a lot of my
videos I talk about being more yielding
and he says I kind of I already am
pretty yielding how they might be more
of an aggressive man and before I
started one of the reason why I often
talk about yielding is because I myself
I'm just like I'm just really aggressive
so I've had to cultivate the balance
associated with with stepping back a
little bit I call this tender aggression
and some of some of us are just way too
aggressive some of us are just way too
tender and and our question here today
is how can I be just a little bit more
aggressive I've got a couple videos
about this one of the more popular ones
on this channel which is uh I can't
remember the name of it but if you go to
popular videos it's the one where I'm
talking about how to assert yourself
with women this doesn't necessarily have
to be with regard to women but being
tender aggressive is a grounded place to
move from that allows you to navigate
the world with the type of aggression
that you need to take action in the
directions that need to be taken and
also to be sensitive enough to navigate
and receive the messages that your
environment is giving it tender
aggression is the ultimate place for a
strong man to come from now use that
term strong because it's just happens me
my word to describe well-rounded fully
self actualized tender aggressive man so
our yielding friend my super tender
friend wants to know how to become more
aggressive well I also made a video not
too long ago called about Heather called
how to become a lion amongst men I
believe and I spoke about Frederick
Nietzsche and thus Spoke Zarathustra I
always say it wrong
and the story of the camel going out and
slaying a dragon and then becoming a
lion and I often use that term or that
metaphor over and over again slaying
that dragon going out into the world and
slaying your dragon and you've got to
slay your dragon the thing is that there
are two tools that are very important to
being able to slay the dragon and that
could be anything it could be your boss
it could be your daddy it could be your
the fact that you'd like to speak to
women it could be I want to take that
plunge into starting my own business
whatever it is you need to slay this
fucking dragon and it requires
aggression and there are two separate
but equal
swords that you will carry with you
right who used to carry two swords
oh you pull out those swords the very
first one you keep it into your you keep
it to your right hand because it's the
one that you're going to use first right
it's called no and you carry that no
with you and every opportunity that you
have to assert you or no you do it
don't be a yes man be a no man and when
you are no man that means you don't
stand for anything that doesn't feel
right with your body regardless of what
anybody else tells you well you know you
should you know the right thing to do
you know you know you know you know you
know the whole fucking world and then
they make new promises you'll get a big
signing bonus for that ones chap but
your body's telling you know you pull
that fucking sword out and say no no no
no no no no no that is your first tool
for aggression and we learn it from the
time we're children when mommy's trying
to put strained Peas in your mouth and
you go right but mommy and daddy
sometimes teach you that you have to say
yes you need to be a yes man eat this or
there will be problems tyranny of our
parents you learn to say no once again
you you gain your no you use that don't
you exercise that no even when you don't
have to because all the practice helps
you might have said okay but you don't
say OK's in your life you say yes or no
100% either way practice that
I gotta say no to this phone call okay
you know the other one which requires a
little bit more sensitivity a little bit
more creativity and a little bit more
self-cultivation
but because you protected yourself with
your know thus far you'll know how to
pull out the other one which is called I
will now you begin exercising your will
in a particular direction that you are
firmly committed to and it could be
anything but the mere fact that you
practice your will means that you have a
virtue that you will carry with you in
all of your circumstances and challenges
in life so that I will might meet sound
like I'm going I will learn how to play
the electric guitar or the acoustic
guitar I like acoustic better I will
learn this I will I'll get it done
commitment and discipline are a big part
of my I will you commit to your thing
and you discipline yourself to get it
done and then it can be absolutely
anything you could be a model fucking
helicopter but you bought the box for
and the pieces are all over the place
will yourself to get it done say no to
your girlfriend wants you to hang out
and watch chick flicks with her and say
I will build this model helicopter you
see what I'm doing here it's not about
your girlfriend who okay maybe you've
got you would have gotten a blowjob or
something it's not about the fucking
helicopter like because who gives a shit
it's a model helicopter it's because
you're exercising the two most powerful
weapons of your aggression you're know
and you're I will ha go attack the world
done