okay so I want to respond to a number of
questions and enquiries I get on my
Facebook wall email so on and so forth
about this idea of suicide apparently a
lot of young dudes are thinking about
suicide at least considering it the very
first thing I want to offer you is
empathy I understand that the feeling is
real this idea that you want to just do
an end put an end to the entire game of
life so beyond my empathy and my care
for you my heart going out to you I want
to offer you this but there is a law
there's a law in nature which is that of
seasons right so let me give you an
example of how silly the it--if suicide
just might be for example in the
wintertime it's cold rain it's freezing
fucking cold in the wintertime
especially if you live in like the north
and it could be so cold that you're
miserable if a man was so cold and
miserable that he decided that perhaps I
should kill myself because this freezing
cold misery is not worth living in
someone might offer him the idea that or
remind him of the law that dude this is
like you've got maybe another six weeks
you got maybe another eight weeks and
then springs coming man it's just the
way it is things cycle through it's just
a season right now I understand it's
freezing fucking cold and you feel
horrible and you feel pretty bad about
the situation but hang in there because
the heats coming back it's cyclical it's
just like that and in the same way that
you acknowledge and appreciate respect
the law of nature of seasons which
dictates every winter will be followed
by a spring and summer realize that your
feelings are the same way I felt
depressed I felt miserable I felt at
times where it may be better to take my
life but with the wisdom that I gathered
and
thirty three short years of life I've
come to realize that it's just feeling
and in the same way that feeling cold is
diminished the misery of feeling cold
has diminished by the insight that
spring will come is the same feeling
that you should acknowledge the same law
that you should acknowledge that no
matter how miserable things are right
now it is just a season it's going to
pass the problem and see here here's
here is where the problem is here's
where you end up depressed and wanting
to kill yourself contemplating suicide
for more than just a few months is when
you become personally identified with
the feeling when you become so miserable
that you're attached to the cold that
when the heat comes when the Sun comes
back you're so focused on the cold that
you don't even realize that the sun's
coming up you're so focused on the
misery misery you're so personally
identified with the misery of depression
that when the season is naturally
changing you resist it you don't realize
things are getting better you don't
allow yourself to remove with the season
allow yourself to move the rhythm of
life because of your attachment to the
depression you've got to let go the best
place to be the most resourceful
position to take is that of a watcher
right now you're depressed that's real
right now you're contemplating the
suicide that's real watch it leave it
alone and watch it don't become
emotionally attached to don't play with
it
don't play with the idea watch it just
like you watch a cloud in the sky as it
passes by it's just a thought it's just
an idea see it for what it is and remain
detached it will pass bottom line is
this don't be like the man who kills
himself in the winter because it's so
cold not realizing that spring is right
around the corner Eliot's it what