got a question from our buddy moritz who
has been who's been dating a girl right
for the past couple months me about 10
months i think he says and recently he
discovered i guess they never discussed
it but recently he discovered that she
had sex with someone before their
current relationship elbow to that point
he thought he was the first one and and
she just revealed well you know actually
i had sex with a boyfriend prior to
being with you not a big deal he kind of
consciously understands you know you
realize it like this is normal you know
we're young and you know having sex but
now he can't get the vision out of his
head of her face squirming and squealing
with orgastic release in love with
another man he literally describes in
his email what her face looks like
during orgasm and then he places this
other dude on top of her and it drives
him nuts he wants to like rip them the
walls out of the house and just foot
tables he gets so heated and angry and
frustrated knowing that his woman had
this massive orgasm and the same face
that he loves to see on her right when
he's you know riding when he's doing his
thing and she's uh uh he envisions that
with another dude the other dude on top
the problem the problem is man that you
entertain that thought way too deeply
the fact that you have the graphic
description of what might have happened
yeah no fucking clue what happened when
they had sex you're making this shit up
in your mind I mean most of the fears
and problems of frustrations that we
have our it's made up shit in our own
head yeah she did have sex but you don't
know what her orgasm face looked like
when she was having sex with him you
don't know what that looked like at all
so you might be able to imagine is which
is what you're doing based on what it
looks like when you're having sex with
her but really you're making the shit up
okay and not only that you are putting
emotion into the thought you're you're
literally your entire physiology is
being affected by your mom
and by your thought by an idea by
something you made up right and you're
playing with it you're making love to
that idea you're entertaining it that's
what they mean when they say
entertaining an idea entertaining a
thought you're entertaining the shit out
of that thought so you're probably
sitting there visualizing so you know
how powerful visualization is
visualization can literally check it
does as your experience change your
physiology or neuromuscular system your
psychology you are literally creating
new neural pathways and secreting
hormones and neurotransmitters and all
types of amazing and macula shit shit
that changes who you are as a human
being when you visualize but you're
visualizing some real fucked up shit
stuff that you don't need to visualize
the fact is she had sex with another
dude but you are turning into a mental
movie that is quickly creating a
sympathetic response and fucking up your
brain you have to literally let the
thought come and go do not entertain it
and this goes with this is with regard
to anything that causes us bad feelings
any thought that causes you bad feelings
do not entertain the thought will come
they always come you know am I going to
go broke is uh is this girl going to
reject me is you know what is my
girlfriend space look like when she was
screwing someone else they come it's
normal it's normal for thoughts to come
what's not normal or resourceful it's
for you to take the thought and analyze
it you're like you're making love to the
thought remember it's abstract it's just
a fucking idea you made it up and now
you're entertaining it and now it's
fucking up your physiology and now it's
changing your psychology and now it's
damaging you from the inside with all
the stress associated with seeing your
girlfriend getting boned by another dude
ah you're doing it to yourself and
you've got to stop okay in the minute
that automatic negative thought comes
because it's going to come it's
automatic
got to immediately replace it with
another thought if they immediately see
it come and replace it with you boning
the shit out of your girlfriend and she
appreciating and loving and orgasming
the depth of her being with you right
you've got to really you can't entertain
that thought you can't continue to
replay that movie in your head because
you're just going to grow more
frustrated aggravated and more animosity
towards her that's your fault now you're
gonna start having bad attitudes toward
her you're gonna start like kind of
giving your cold shoulders you're gonna
start and it's gonna be all because of
sex she had over a year ago all of a
sudden you just you know what baby i
don't know i just am not happy with you
right now you just gonna you gonna have
a bad attitude with her and it has
nothing to do with her there's nothing
to do with anything in reality it all
has to do with this fucking idea that
you just keep entertaining and playing
with and making love to it's your fault
okay I knew you recognize that so I'm
trying to give you a technique a tool
automatic thought comes in replace it
immediately do not entertain it just
turn your turn your face to it you can
literally do that as a thought comes
turn your head I'm not looking at I'm
not looking at it I'm not looking at it
it's not that it isn't there you just
don't look at it and it'll go away it'll
go bother someone else but don't let
negative thoughts bother you that's your
choice negative thoughts come but it's
your choice choice to entertain it let
it go