we got a question from our buddy
anonymous he wants to remain anonymous
basically you got two problems the first
one ain't really a problem so adjusted
quickly the second one a big problem for
all of us so that's why I want to
address this first problem is his
girlfriend speaks Spanish apparently
he's black she's Puerto Rican or
something of the sort and uh six three
one you live in New York right that's a
Long Island area code I think anyway so
that's why I assume Porto Rican you're
black she's Puerto Rican and when you go
to her house they start you could be
anything they're gonna give me and you
don't stand for the word they say feels
like you know perhaps they're talking
about me and shit and you know gets a
little bit uncomfortable that they're
laughing and telling jokes you think it
might be about you get over it and I can
tell you that if things are to work out
with you that you first of all you'll
get over it but you'll also pick up the
language my brother married a Dominican
now we don't speak Spanish
we're from we're from Latin America
believes but we don't speak Spanish
because it was an English colony until
like the 1980s believe it or not so you
know the tendency towards Latin women is
there but the language isn't there my
brother they just they've been married
going on two three years I think and
their families of doing well or doing
well you know it's not a big deal you
can figure that out the other one is
you've got mail
urges like all of us your dick gets hard
and you see other women and you don't
want to cheat on your girl but you don't
know what to do that energetic pole that
sexual energy that pole of the penis is
very strong I totally understand that I
have mentioned that I married my high
school girlfriend I've been with my wife
since we were 14 years old and I
understand that when you give in your
heart to another woman it doesn't mean
that the dick ain't stiffening for other
women and you're kind of in it this
situation you're still young you're far
younger than I am I mean and granted
although I married my high school
girlfriend big no mistake
times of we're weaving in and out
throughout high school in college we
weren't a hundred percent the whole time
we decided to stay together and get
married but don't assume that she was
the only woman that I was ever with
right guys a lot of you guys would use
that argument like don't fucking listen
Elliot about sex and women he's been
with the same woman since he was 14 yeah
I married the woman that I was with when
I was 14 and we remained in love with
one another but you know we went through
high school and college together so it
doesn't mean that there was no other
experience there for either of us now
here's the situation
don't let the dick energy detract you
from that which is higher so if you
study Freud there is there these two
elements that guide us right and Elliott
Hulse talks about the heart in the head
Ford would have called it the the
pleasure principle there are two
principles the pleasure principle which
is guided by the it'd you know the the
enter the animal energy within the human
being the libido sexual and then there
is the principle of reality to reality
principle right and it's what makes what
makes human beings powerful is our
ability to use this reality principle
because of the concept of time that
we've created right we've literally
created the concept of time through this
principle that get makes unique make
makes human beings unique that allows us
to see how an action taken today will
affect the future right tremendously
powerful we can do this where most other
animals can that's what makes you me
being so freakin powerful the reality
principle that of which is the head
right so here you go here you go listen
an Eliot contradict himself once again
I'm telling you get out of your balls
get out of your heart get into your head
will guide you to do in this moment what
is right so that later on shit is not
fucked up so when you're in a situation
where the dick is just screaming I want
that and the reality principle is too
weak to overcome their pleasure
principle that's rising in your body
you're going to make an action that
going to regret later on it's going to
happen especially if you're very violent
you're very sexual right some I mean
some people just have really high sexual
charged sexually energy sexual energy
right you're looking at one
and that sexual energy will overpower
the ego it's just like I don't give a
fuck about anything right now what's up
right you just you just gonna go and
follow what the dick is gonna have you
do because that sexual charge is so
fucking strong here's what you do right
here's what all men do because here's
the thing cheating on your girl she ting
on your wife is gonna fuck up everything
for you that is probably that's going to
ruin your life in so many ways you don't
want to ruin the relationship that you
have with the person that is literally
your teammate in this journey of life I
mean that person is going to be there
when you die that person is there to to
deal with you on anything many many many
different fronts right that's and when
you share yourself with that person we
tend to think that like you know sex is
just penis and vagina but sex is more
than just penis and vagina is it's a lot
more than just this there is a hard
connection even if it's with a
prostitute
your heart has to warm towards that
individual in order to get it get an
erection so there is more than just
penis in vagina because if it was just
penis in vagina then it's like look
there every vagina is the fucking same
every penis is the same if penis and
fucking vagina what's the big deal but
really what makes strange right that's
the time that's my buddies used man I'm
gonna move for some strange basically
different vagina is not that the vagina
is different is that the energetic
processes in that person the energetic
pull the character the psychology the
emotion in that person is
different right so you've got a partake
of that person more than just the vagina
you're literally becoming one with an
individual when you have sex with them
right and if you are in a relationship
where the trust is such or she trusts
you and you trust her such that you're
not sharing your energy with someone
else because quite frankly our energy
reserves are are limited they're limited
especially sexual energy sexual energy
is very limited I think the Chinese call
it gene right there's a certain amount
of it that builds up in our body that's
why you want to be busted nuts every
like three four times a day every day
because you lose your sexual potency you
lose your sexual in it and if that's
neither here no there you don't want to
betray that heart connection that deeper
energetic connection that you have with
the woman that you love and that you've
chosen to move on with your life with
and you don't wanna betray that because
of because if your dick right I mean
really when it boils down to it busting
a nut it's really not a big deal
it's that sharing yourself that sharing
of your energy with another human being
so what do you do you're a young dude
right I mean you're 18 years old what do
you what do you do when you really love
this girl you want to spend the rest of
your life with her perhaps you know
maybe maybe not but right now you're
feeling like you know I want to do
everything that I can to support the
relationship I have with this girl don't
put yourself in situations where the
dick will overpower your mind you don't
the thing is we don't have to judge it
as right or wrong we don't have the
judgment as good or bad right that's
what this basically helps means when he
says that your feelings are right your
feelings are right if you get a boner
and you want to buck the shit out of
this chick that's sitting next to you in
a bar somewhere and it's like man it's
not bad it's not wrong this is what's
happening in your body what's wrong is
you and when I say wrong again it's just
you know some quotations is you letting
the sexual energy overpower the reality
principle right you realize if I fuck
this chick I'm fucking
my life right that's being weak as being
not a stronger version of yourself
because you're not allowing the reality
principle to play fourth goal setting
things of that nature or all a product
of the reality principle so what you do
is you don't put yourself in those
situations right Elliott Hulse is not
perfect right Elliott House will make
mistakes but what Elliott Hulse won't do
is put himself right in the face of a
mistake that could happen so if you find
that oh shit I think things are getting
real warm over here say you know what
I'm going over there you feel it right
away I mean the energetic pull the
sexual pull between polarities is strong
and you know it instantly especially if
you're sensitive and sexual you know
right away ooh
this energy is strong I'm gonna go over
here now right you don't smile and then
balance I'm telling you because it's not
worth it especially if you're in a
trusting relationship with another human
being so that's it folks just one more
time to reiterate starting to rant here
today to receive relationship and sexual
information or ideas really from me is
not that strange I've been in a
committed and beautiful relationship
with the love of my life for many many
years decades and I think that offers me
a perspective with regard to how to
navigate relationships how to deal with
women how sexuality works through
experience more so than someone who's
bounced around fucking people left and
right
I think that's an ungrounded way to deal
with sexual energy I would tend to
believe and think and invite you to
consider when I start speaking this way
that Elliott house is moving from a
grounded sexual position one where he is
balancing both the pleasure and the
reality principle in his life and his
behaviors and can offer you
ideas support advice that will support
you becoming stronger version yourself
so that's it dude
control your dick and enjoy your life
peace