so what a question from my name isn't
Liz and I'm assuming your name is some
other female name so you're a woman so
I'm going to say she and she says maybe
I think differently than most people I
don't see anyone around me who sees
things in the world the way I do I don't
feel like the people around me
understand me and that makes me feel
alone I have trouble keeping friends
because it's so hard for us to see
eye-to-eye I feel like I have no one to
talk to no one who understands me I
believe in the way I think and in my
ideas but it's so hard to be the one
person who has radical ideas I want so
badly to have someone who thinks like me
please help so the very first thing I'm
be a little rough I guess harsh on you
is you're not alone
I think a lot of people feel the way
that you feel in fact I feel that way
all the time
what I invite you to do is instead of
wallowing in your pain and suffering for
being alone in the limited sphere of
people that you engage with begin
producing art and when I say art I don't
necessarily mean it in the traditional
context what I say art I mean take the
things that are happening in you and
reproduce them in a way that you feel
comfortable reproducing them see I like
to talk so i reproduce my ideas that a
lot of people think are weird like I
will think I'm fucking nuts Elliott
Hulse you listen to that wacko but I
take those ideas I reproduce them in a
way that I'm naturally gifted in which
is being verbose and I produce art I
stay in front of a camera or I put our
workshops and I talk to people and guess
what even though lots of people in my
environment have thought I was strange
you know lots of friends would hear the
shit I say now like you're fucking nuts
hundreds of thousands of people that
I've shared it with think it's pretty
cool
now I might not be as weird as you I
don't know how weird you are but I
guarantee you you're not so weird that
you can't find an audience if you take
your gift because that's really what it
is we were all given you
any gifts you've got some ideas that are
unique to you and write poetry draw
paintings write essays write fiction
novels make videos if you'd like write a
journal online they call that a blog get
it out of you and put it somewhere for
other people to see I guarantee you in
the day and age that we live in
no one's alone that's the beautiful
thing about the day that we live in
today that no one is truly alone because
the Internet has allowed us to connect
in so many ways and there's so many
strange niches of people out there that
come together in their love for Kiwis or
I don't know just just just weird
obsessions we all just love the midget
tossing I don't know but you love some
particular form of ideal ideas thinking
philosophy whatever it is put it on
paper or text and put it out there for
other people to read if you are if you
just you're not reproducing it properly
or it's just it's not that interesting
right you think it's interesting but
people don't think you know you might
create a small tribe of people but I
guarantee you that you're not alone and
in fact there are probably hundreds of
thousands of people that will engage
with your ideas the thing is that you've
got to get courageous enough you got to
get over yourself and you've got to put
it out there anyone who feels as if
they're alone anyone who's feeling
lonely it's only because you're not
putting yourself out there to be
appreciated and there's more opportunity
put yourself out there today than there
has ever been in the history of mankind
turn on a camera start writing start
producing start sharing and people will
find you good luck