so if you watched part 1 of this video
you may be one of those people who are
very upset very touched in an
uncomfortable way about the things I
said that I spoke about in that video
right I want you to take a look at a
couple of things and this is the reason
why I'm making it part two here because
this is important look at your argument
for what it is you are literally
upholding the scaffolding of a story
that you've been told by people who
manipulate you I don't care if you are
into religion or you're into
quote/unquote science what you're
essentially doing is you're giving those
people power you're saying yes their
stories are true what they've told me is
right and I have to defend it because
I've become personally identified with
it I've become identified with the
scientific ideas I've been shared
manipulated or conditioned to believe
and the holy books right so you gotta
uphold that because you're personally
identified with it right you don't know
yourself without it so you've got to
save it you gotta protect it it's it's
it's a method it's a set of words
they're symbols they're things they're
objects your religion and your science
and look at what I'm trying to invite
you to do I'm asking you to set aside
that which has been given to you or
better yet forced upon you and trust
yourself go with your own experience the
language may be different in fact there
may be no language to describe your
experience until you create it and even
when you create that language to
describe your experience it will fall
short of your experience because they're
just symbols they're just words they
will never capture the essence of what's
happening in the inner in your reality
some of you will still be deaf to these
words they're so hard to absorb because
do you have no body
there's a body there or flesh but you
have no feeling you have no emotion
you've become so stone cold and rigid
because you've denied all the
spontaneous feelings all the spontaneous
movement inside the body you judge your
your erection you judge your body you're
guilty about your body you've been
taught not to trust it to look at look
at it as if it's something ugly and
nasty bad evil sinful or something that
is just merely uh an object a symbol to
be manipulated something fuck with it's
just pieces and just I'm just flesh
that's all I am that's all it is
dangerous because you because now you've
lost yourself you've given yourself away
my invitation is to get yourself back I
want you to experience yourself that's
my message that's my crusade that's why
I'm so fuckin nuts about this shit
cuz I want to invite you back to
yourself set aside the stories science
and religion set aside the symbols go in
its ugly stark it's dirty
cobwebs nastiness shit interactions but
it's yours it's the only thing you have
it's the only way you'll ever navigate
this world in this life in a resourceful
fashion
once you become addicted to yourself
drunk with your experience with yourself
set aside just for a moment you don't
have to reject you don't have to deny
you don't have to demonize but set aside
just for a moment your sciences and
religions