so we've got a fascinating question from
our buddy who calls himself the split
tongue actually signs off with the split
tongue well essentially he's begun
working out in his own garage jamb and
he starting to really exert himself not
only physically but emotionally through
his workouts he's really able to put his
raw emotion and aggression into these
workouts which is very different from
what he's been doing at traditional gyms
if you go to you know Planet Fitness so
for any of these commercial type gyms
you really can't let it all out and most
men most people in particular have a lot
of pent-up emotional baggage you know
with we really carry it around because
of the experiences that we have had and
the necessity to stuff it down for the
most part when you can go to your own
gym that's why I love having my own
garage gym you can let it all out as
you're exercising screaming throwing
just fully expressing all the aggression
that you have within you now our friend
the split tongue has phrased his
question how do I further develop this
warrior spirit he's taken into account
the idea that becoming the strongest
version yourself requires a deep
grounded sexuality and when he hears me
say breathe into your balls and when
those of you who hear me and have been
listening to me for quite some time
understand when I say breathe into your
balls
I mean ground your energy take full
control of your most vital and primal
sources of vitality
that's what breathing into your balls
does it's a it's an expression that
describes what you would experience if
you balanced what I'm going to call
tender aggression that's a very
important term that I'm going to be
talking a lot more about it's one that
I've developed and will continue to
develop in order to shed light on this
idea of what it is to be in our friends
terminology a warrior spirit you know
what this essentially means that in my
answer to your question is is to develop
this idea this concept that I'm sharing
with you of
aggression the idea of a really strong
man never comes across as very
hysterical and and wild and crazy but we
tend to think that an aggressive or a
warrior type person it's someone who's
just hysterically going about destroying
everything in his environment and
stepping on people and he's just her
right but if you watch even movies
because subconsciously we understand
this thing there's this stuff these
ideas that there is a grounded
aggression there's a tender aggression
that's not only more resourceful but
it's far more attractive you watch
movies like 300 you notice like king
leonidas right he's a big strong super
badass but he's also very calm cool
calculated and he takes his time he's
very soft as well as hard there is that
balance once again so how do we develop
this how do we continue to be stronger
men but also softer men at the same time
how do we become more aggressive but
also tender at the same time so that we
have this balance of our vital resources
and our ability to calculate and think
calmly right it's the again it's this
balance that I've described between
using the head and moving from your
heart right the heart is soft it's Yee
and it's female its passive the head
very aggressive direct formal
calculative there needs to be a balanced
well-being that my first positioning and
how I serve people essentially is
through the body the very first thing I
want to do is help you position your
body help mold a body that embodies
tender aggression the way that looks is
through a strong posture where the long
muscles of the back are firm are strong
are tense but also supple and the
musculature and that's where your
aggression comes from all the muscles in
the back are aggressive that's why when
you notice you're getting upset the
shoulders go when you're fearful the
shoulders go up even animals
they get their backup that's where that
term comes from don't get your backup
that means you're getting aggressive you
don't want to be too hysterical with
your aggression you want to balance it
with some calmness some grounding some
deep breathing so that also means that
the muscles in the front of your body
have to be soft and supple I've often
often talked about the neurotic holding
patterns across the front part of the
body that restrict your ability to
breathe deep
it's across the eyes across the jaw
across the neck throat and chest the
belly and the pelvic floor when those
muscles are soft when those muscles are
supple they allow you to breathe deeply
and you're moving now from a place of
uprightness right because when you have
strong thoracic extensors all the
muscles of your back are strong and you
can stand with good posture
you've got your chest up you are you
present a much more aggressive but also
confident individual and when you're
breathing calmly softly supple down into
your pelvic floor because the muscles in
the front of your body are soft you are
more grounded you can calculate you can
think you can take your time you can be
that much more grounded in your approach
to the aggression you could be that much
more tender in your aggressiveness
balanced one way or the other and in
balance one way or the other will
manifest itself as an imbalanced man
you're either too much of a pussy you're
just way too soft bro toughen the fuck
up or you're way too aggressive way too
yang you're way too hard dude those guys
who think they're big men because
they're really aggressive and hard are
usually the ones that have the hardest
time finding women and they find
themselves frustrated in business and in
life because they're just too fricking
hard they don't breathe they don't take
their time they don't think they don't
yield and receive the way a more tender
man would so the solution here and the
invitation for you to continue moving in
the direction that you are moving with
regard to being a peaceful warrior a
tender aggressor a grounded man
is to continue working out exercise
those you who even listen to my videos
that are not into fitness you need to
understand and of course I'm biased I
come from a position where I'm teaching
people how to be fit but you've got to
understand that you're energetic
strength your psychological emotional
power is exhibited through your physical
body we could think all we want about
what it would take me to philosophize
all we want about what it will take to
be a grounded individual someone with
real strength real power to navigate his
life or her life in a way that's
effective we didn't think and talk
theorize read and lecture all about it
but the fact is it's being exhibited
through your body what are you doing and
your body and everything that you do
right happens through your body happen
everything moves from a position of rest
that position of rest is your body what
that looks like in your body is strong
posture so my invitation is to
strengthen the posterior chain muscles
with exercises like deadlifts exercises
like bent over rows chin-ups done with
perfect form exercises like kettlebell
swings that bring into account the force
coupling of your hamstrings gluts low
back and thoracic extensors couple that
with that's all building up the
aggressive muscles in your body
couple that with softening the muscles
of your of your face you know how many
of us are we're just so tense in our
face world when we're thinking we're
doing this or doing this or grinding our
teeth right how many of us are holding
our breath shallow holding our bellies
in clenching up in the pelvic floor you
know they say when you're a tight ass
you literally are a tight ass you're
squeezing your anus up into your body
deep breathe and relax those muscles in
the front part of your body the best
exercise stretch for that are the bow
exercises that I teach taught you in
several videos as well as breathing on
the bioenergetic stool laying over the
bioenergetic stool I'll make more videos
like this and I am developing my
advanced energetic strength course as we
speak
in the meantime search this channel and
search my old channel my other channel
sorry my strength cap channel for videos
on deep breathing how to do the bow my
biogenetic warm-up routine bio energetic
warm-up routine and use those things use
those exercises particularly - deep
breathing video to soften the muscles of
the front of the body the belly the neck
the chest so that you can bring your
livewire energy down to a grounded place
where its power could be that much more
directed good luck