yo Eliot so let's begin I think the best
place to begin is by answering the
question that many of you are probably
asking which is Eliot where the hell
have you been for the past eight months
and what the heck have you been doing so
the best way for me to approach that
question is to use a metaphor for what
the past 10 years have been for me in my
life somebody asked me on my online
coaching program Eliot you know I do a
Q&A and they said Eliot can you describe
your mindset when you were first
beginning your work years ago during the
phases of success that you've attained
and where you are right now and the way
I answered this question was imagine
that in the beginning 10 years ago I was
running from the darkness I mean times
were dark and I think a lot of you can
probably relate to it that's why my
videos are so relatable to you because
you know what it's like to have darkness
surround you you know what it's like to
be hungry not to have but to be striving
that striving is usually out of fear so
there has been a process of running from
the fear of darkness early on in my work
early on in that 10 year period and then
as I think it works for anybody who just
keeps running there's a period where you
start to see that light at the end of
the tunnel right and the middle phase
fear started to disappear because I saw
that the light was just ahead I think
you could describe I think that time was
essentially between 2012 and 2014 early
2014 by by 2014 I had come so close to
the light that it began to absorb me and
blind me so if you could just take for a
moment
think of that spectrum of pure darkness
running towards the light getting
towards the light and then the light ah
scorching you because it's just so damn
bright
your pupils can't do doesn't know what
to do with it can't absorb it can't
deflect it you get burned up by it and I
think that's exactly what says hat what
has happened and what you've watched as
we watched my videos I mean go back to
2007 what I think I put up my very first
video you're watching a very fearful
young man right I'm gonna turn this off
you're watching a very fearful young man
trying to do the best that he can to get
where he wants to be one day because
he's got dogs chopping out his ass you
know I I was deeply in debt and I had a
family and I'm trying to start a
business I'm trying to do my work I'm
trying to fulfill my purpose even though
I don't even know what it is but I'm
just running a lot of you guys are like
that run you should run because you
shouldn't live in darkness but if you
keep on running you're gonna see that
light you're gonna see that that little
at the end of the tunnel just looks in
the beginning it just looks like a
little circle that's when things start
working out a little bit you start to
say hey I'm getting the hang of this I'm
getting some rewards from this and as
you keep going towards it what happens
to that little circle right it just gets
bigger and bigger and bigger and you
just keep running and you start to feel
the euphoria and the passion the
excitement associated with getting
closer and closer and closer until it
starts to absorb you
just imagine like like it's so bright
then you just become absorbed by it
blinded by it and completely disoriented
right because it's just too much light
if you've been in darkness just do it at
home if you've been in darkness and
you're in a dark closet and somebody
flashes the light on what happens right
you first wake up in the morning you got
it so if you're wondering where I've
been for the past eight months it's been
a matter of me trying to figure out how
to handle all this light right and
that's the metaphor that I'd like to use
today and describing five of the things
that I've learned during my time off in
trying to make sense of the light
process it deal with it responsibly
because a part of what happens with the
light is if you're not if your ego isn't
strong enough if you don't know how to
objectify it if you don't know how to
create separation between yourself and
the light you become inflated by it you
know this is a union term I've been
studying a lot of columns work and and
as I'll describe throughout these five
things that I've learned you know a part
of what happened was I became inflated
by the light and and that can be a
dangerous thing because it's so luminous
and so powerful that it will destroy you
if you don't create separation between
yourself and it you know and that way I
use the metaphor of light but it could
mean anything in the realm of success
anything in the realm of what you're
seeking to achieve you know so I've got
my phone here because I took some notes
I don't normally do this but I wanted to
make sure that I hit on these points for
you guys so that this could be an
informative yet educational or
entertaining video for you so the very
first thing that the very first mistake
or I don't want to call it a mistake but
um ignorance lack of understanding about
how to deal in this
new phase of my development my life and
again I just share these things with you
because I feel as if have I share my
stories they'll support you as you grow
stronger on your journey you know I
don't tell you these stories because I
want to brag or boast or I'm so
self-absorbed that all I want to do is
talk about myself I talk about these
things because my story is your story
it's our story you know and if you study
Joseph Campbell and this is why I talk
about the hero's journey and if you
watched my my video series on strenght
camp you know I did that whole hero's
journey thing right the call to
adventure the journey and then the
legacy it's because it's a recurring
motif it's something that shows up in
all mythology it shows up over and over
and over again and cross-cultural
studies it's the human story you know
and if I share this with you and as I
experience it as a contemporary man
living in the United States in this day
and age then perhaps you can glean some
some some bits of wisdom just by the
mistakes I've made you know it's not
that I'm any smarter I just got might
have some more experiences than many of
you so in dealing with the light the
mistake or the ill or this sin that I
carried was that rest is for the weak
this is a beautiful idea when you're in
warrior mode this is a beautiful idea
when you're in the darkness when you're
in the darkness rest is for the weak
it's a paradigm that supports you when
shit is going bad you can't fucking rest
when there's a dog chopping at your ass
right some of you guys are too restful
and then your life ends up being stale
so I tell you do things like throw away
you throw away your videogame machine or
move out of your parents house so that
the dog is chopping at your ass now you
can't rest you know what I'm saying but
um you know so the the paradigm
associated with that is rest is for the
weak what I actually learned is that you
should prepare for action while
minimizing activity in other words
manage your energy the way that looks
practically is if you look and you
notice behind me I'm not at the gym
anymore I literally had
remove myself from the environment from
which I developed myself being in the
gym and being amongst all the people in
the environment that was associated with
striving and and and uh and and and
grinding didn't allow me to space to
step back the objective meditate read
breathe relax so that I could manage
what is coming at me now you see so I
literally had to change my environment
and I think that's just a principle for
any of us who are who are going through
life changes who are going through an
evolution you can't be in the same space
you know it through in the initiation
process which all cultures are familiar
with in some way shape or form there's a
sacred space there is a container in
which you you go into order to grow or a
cocoon of sorts and the very first thing
in order to manage my energy in the
abandoned the luminous energy moving
through me you know you could call it
cosmic consciousness or God was that I
had to create separation in space so
that I could be literally humbled you
know I couldn't be Elliott Hulse in
order to allow the evolution to happen
and the fastest way does not be yourself
is to change environments right so many
of you are in high school then you go to
college and you're a different person
right you're not that same guy that you
were in high school because the
environment gave you an opportunity to
change your character I had to change my
environment in order to change my
character and it the environment has
allowed me now to relax and not
constantly have blasting rap and
hardcore music in my ears people coming
to the door all the time looking for me
it got a little crazy where you know
people show up and I you know I don't
blame you guys you want to come see
strength camp and meet Elliott
but um keeps me constantly on my toes
I'm constantly have to look out and and
see oh and do I have to prepare to
entertain you know constantly
entertaining I so there's a second one
had to stop making videos because I
can't constantly be entertaining I could
not constantly keep up the go-go-go-go
they're not too many other youtubers
that have more videos than me in our
niche the only other ones are probably
the hodgetwins because they make a lot
of videos and I took that same approach
they made a lot of videos but again
managing energy required that I stopped
so you might have to stop doing the
things that make you believe you are a B
or C you know the thing that the thing
that keeps you keeps you believing that
you're a certain the thing if you think
you're a baseball player you stop paying
playing baseball there's going to be a
challenge there because your ego
contract will have to be dissolved right
then I make videos I had to stop making
videos in order to manage my energy so
I'll continue I have a few other things
here including regular sleep patterns
you know making sure that I'm not
getting up at 4:30 in the morning to
work more I actually have to sleep go
figure right my human being I stop
weight training so if you're wondering
what I did for the past eight months it
wasn't working out it was doing yoga I
did yoga every single day for eight
months straight I put a hammock there's
a hammock in my office and I often talk
about the benefits of having a being
rocked and lulled into rest and I think
that every warrior and that tends to be
my my predominant energy is warrior fire
aggressive energy needs somewhere some
space some way of being cuddled coddled
soothed and rocked you see I rock myself
even if you notice in a lot of my videos
I rock myself because it's soothing but
laying in the hammock is it is one of
the ways that we can soothe ourselves
and rock ourselves out of aggression
number two
can't do it alone the the falsehood the
mists the sin was I can do it I don't
need you that's a purely a warrior's
attitude that's a purely running in the
darkness running
on the darkness attitude if you've got a
dog chasing at your ass chomping at you
you're not thinking about how anybody
else but your ass right and that was a
resourceful way of being during a
particular period of time but as the
light began to absorb me I realized shit
I can't handle this by myself
I need help I've been blessed enough
lucky enough and strategic enough to
have a wife that has been my partner my
best friend migrated she's my biggest
fan she's my biggest supporter she is
100% Elliott Hulse as much as Elliott
Hulse is 100% Elliott house there is no
me you don't know me without that woman
and she's been this way for with me
since the time we were children we've
been together we dated throughout high
school in college you know and I'm the
man who I am today because of her but I
realized that I needed to invite more
people into my life in an intimate way
and as you probably realized through
strength cam videos that there I'm
survived surrounded by lots of very
fascinating people now I'm surrounded by
a lot of huge support staff you know if
my mission is to be bigger than me then
I have to give it away and share it and
allow up create opportunities for other
people to bring the mission into
fruition you see and and that's what I
learned that's one of the things I
learned during his time
of course you know the more people that
you support the more people will support
you it's kind of you know playing that
that give-and-take games you know I'm
really happy to be able to bring these
people into my life and bless them with
opportunities at the same time they
support the mission and help grow
strength camp number three talk less and
listen more see this is tough for me
because you know what I did for eight
months I stopped talking right and we're
already going
fifteen minutes of this video and it's
challenging for me because I really
became personally identified with what
got me where I am which is I answer
questions and I began being yo Eliot in
my daily life and it didn't work real
well you know it didn't work it doesn't
work at home doesn't work with friends
when you got an answer for fucking
everything you know it's a little
difficult right now because I'm gonna
begin answering questions right now and
you know what I don't feel like I have
very many answers anymore I watched all
my old videos and I laugh and I'm like
why does this motherfucker I have an
answer for everything my parents used to
say that to me - Elliot you got an
answer for everything as that light
blinded me you know what it also did
humbled me it humbled the Elliott Hulse
construct the ego configuration that ran
towards it it just it mobile iterated it
I'm still trying to pick up the pieces
and figure out how to manage this thing
because I love wisdom I love sharing I
love Fitness I love making these videos
but quite frankly guys I don't have an
answer for as much as many of the things
as you've been asking me right you know
I I listen to myself asking the
questions in the videos that I used to
make and then giving an answer and I'm
like why the fuck that I answer that
because I'm just I'm just talking for
the sake of talking and maybe that's
what I do
maybe I just talk for the sake of
talking and stuff just comes out of my
mouth so is it right I don't know
is it wrong I don't know but one thing
for sure is I don't know
and that's that's been a process has it
been a part of the infantile grandiosity
the inflation of believing that I was
the ego constructive Elliot host you
know that was a tool and I kind of
understood it too I've made videos where
I said I'm not le Atos because I
understood I knew at a primordial level
that fuck I'm developing and growing
into an ego construct that will have to
destruct it will have to be fragmented
at some point in order for me to grow
and to beat for me to become the next
evolution of whatever it is that cosmic
consciousness or God is moving through
me right
God is dynamic the universe is dynamic
constantly moving your physical body is
dynamic you're not who you were
yesterday physiologically either all of
your cells are constantly in motion
they're caught slim flux if we get
attached at any point to one version of
ourselves
we're defying God we're not going with
the DAO if you will you know so it's a
matter of letting go and not believing
that you are what you think you are
today I am NOT yo Elliot number four
create and commit to life building daily
rituals so the false idea was do big
things you do big things and I think
this is a cultural are our young people
think that you can get success by doing
big things I'm gonna do big shit right
now I'm telling you right now that it's
not a matter of doing big things it's a
matter of doing the little things in a
right way every single day I again you
know I share these things not because I
know I share these things because I've
experienced and I can tell you right now
that doing big things burns you the fuck
out it's unsustainable have a grand
vision have a big idea but do little
things every single day in a very
long-term manner so some of the things
that I've had to commit to is uh again
yoga you know Yoga isn't doing big
because weight training is doing big
things lifting a 400-pound log over your
head is doing big things doing downward
dog and Sun Salutations is not doing big
things it's doing little things and I
did it every single day as a ritual I
think that's really the magic word here
also with nutrition you know I got to be
completely honest you know I even said
to you in the past
don't take too much nutrition advice
from Elliott Hulse because I am a Binger
I'll do a binge diet and get the results
I want then I if watch my videos again
it only takes the proof is in the
pudding
just watch somebody you know what's
going on you know I got videos where I'm
I look like this
I got videos where I look like this
what's going on with that guy right
because I binge I get huge and I get
skinny and and over the course of past
eight months I've been working with a
nutrition coach specifically to get
myself on a diet that's long-term and
sustainable I hired him for six months
and I'll probably work with him for
another six months because I just like
I've even said it's the long term take a
year you know I'm cutting again but in
the past when I was cutting it was a
matter of I'm gonna cut this shit out
right now boom doing big things not
doing big things anymore I'm doing a
little bit of the right thing every
single day number five finally right is
gonna be a 20-minute video Elliott Hulse
comes back with a 20 minute video do the
difficult thing it works out in the end
and I know it sounds like redundant
because Elliott always talks about
knowing the difficult thing well it was
a difficult thing for me to stop and I
resisted it I didn't take my own advice
I lacked integrity for for quite a few
months for about eight months I think
was eight months of of fighting the
river and then eight months of yielding
into the river I was trying to swim
upstream since January 2014
Terry 2014 I started a sense God was
telling me
the consciousness was moving through me
the universe had planned but I Ito said
not like that and I started swimming
upstream I use this metaphor for
somebody the other day imagine that you
get into the river and allow it to carry
you at some point you know that's that's
really what's happening we think that
we're creating our lives but really we
are allowing our lives you know we set
visions and we have ideas for where we
want to go and of course that influences
things but we don't really make things
happen so much as we allow them to
happen a lot of times just getting out
of the way so imagine you know you're
going down this river and and as you're
going down the river you know just
imagine if it was you know the when I
use that light metaphor imagine now it's
a river
here first in that river and you're in
that boat has crickets and scary things
and you know it's a negative environment
you're scared as fuck you get down the
river and you start to see oh you hear
music playing and you start seeing what
it looks like there's a city down there
you start seeing beautiful women coming
and you smell food mmm and you get you
keep going down that river and you get
to it you get to that place now you
don't get off your boat because life is
always moving but the people are coming
out and they're giving you some food get
some beautiful women come over and give
you a kiss yeah all the good things
alright to give you a drink smoke some
ganja alright so you're you're in that
beautiful part words like man things are
going really well until that River
continues to go and you start looking
back at whoa whoa whoa whoa I liked it
in that village I liked when I was
flowing through that but life doesn't
work that way life is dynamic life is
constantly moving and you say I can't
leave it and you start trying to pay you
take that paddle you start going
upstream right you start paddling back
upstream what are you doing you're going
against the current not knowing that
life has something else for you I've had
something else for me you know I I
I saw the light you know I saw the light
I was absorbed by the light inflated
blinded you know what does it mean to be
blinded you don't see and I and I was
lacking my ability to see reality and
when I decided to quit making YouTube
videos it's kind of like I put that
paddle down and I said you know what I
gotta trust this river
when it took me and I can tell you that
all of our pain comes from trying to
paddle uphill all of our pain comes from
attaching ourselves to the things that
to them to the to the character that we
think we are and to the things that we
think we own when the reality is that
life is found in yielding to the river
and allowing it to take you on the
adventure that it wants you to have when
you were born into this world you were
born into this river I was born into
this river I'm grateful for the river
that I was born into and if you're
watching this video I dare you to pray a
prayer of gratitude for being born into
the river that you're born in today
because in this day and age it's a
beautiful thing all of our per of our
problems you know they say
firstworldproblems because you could
have been born in a different place you
know there are parts of the world right
now that are steeped in darkness and
that was the river those people were
born into I'm pretty sure that there was
a time see I sort of believe in
reincarnation I believe there was a time
when I was born into darkness you know
there and there was a time like if you
look if you and if you know the history
of Africa Africa is steeped in darkness
right now I mean conflict after conflict
and the Empire's raping it of its
resources but there the time when Africa
was the land of kings and queens right
it's just a different time in a
different place be grateful to be born
in the time and place to partake of the
technology that allows you to gain
wisdom through the internet you see I
don't know I'm starting to rant now as
if this whole video was in a rant but
you know
I'm grateful for you grateful for this
opportunity grateful to be doing the
work that I'm doing I'm grateful for the
time and day that I'm born into and I
trust that all the experiences that I
have no experience that you have are for
the collective good and if you're in
pain right now today if you're in
darkness or if your whole life is
steeped in darkness keep going there's
always a light at the end of the tunnel
and if you're absorbed with light and if
things are good be grateful because the
light always dins at some point done yo
Eliot
you