a lot of people think they're making
their own decisions when they gather
facts and information and opinions of
other people they think that with more
information they'll have more tools to
use that are at their disposal in order
to make a decision right you've got more
to think about people enjoy thinking
it's very gratifying to the ego and with
all this information all these facts and
all these studies and statistics they've
got something now that they can use to
go and make a decision not once
consulting with the only thing that
really matters that's yourself now just
because you calculated and you shift it
around all these different ideas that
were given to you doesn't mean that the
decision is yours because all of that
information is somebody else's there's
somebody else's ideas somebody else's
opinion somebody else's book somebody
else's study they brew it you bring it
all in and you sift and you try to
calculate your decision so you really
your decisions not your decision your
decision is the best choice that you've
decided to take based on the information
you've been given and a lot of times you
don't realize but the choice that you
made after all that mental masturbation
has nothing to do with the facts why not
go straight to the source why not go
straight to your intelligence before you
start seeking advice and information to
calculate your decision the reason why
you don't do that is because you've been
taught very early on that your body is
not nearly as important as your head
brain our bodies have become so
desensitized to the information input
and the trust that we should have for
its output that we completely ignore our
heart you know it's no wonder that the
language is wrought with phrases like
your heart calling your heart is warm
your hearts feelings this person has a
cold heart or a warm heart because
there's an intelligence in your body
it's not the bundle of brains like the
bundle of cells like the neocortex
trapped in your chest but there's a
sense
there listen to your gut you've got a
gut feeling every time I ignored my gut
I've made the biggest mistakes it
doesn't matter what I think I know
because it's all based on dead
information information is always dead
the only that's alive is this moment and
the only thing that's happening in this
moment that you can experience is your
subjective reality what's happening in
your body you've got to trust your gut
don't look for information to support
your choices because there are other
people's based on their experiences but
you don't know what's going to happen
now we did none of us know what's going
to happen now but if we trust ourselves
we're going to create something brand
new one of the problems is it doesn't
always look like the way other people's
experiences have been but wouldn't that
be boring why do you want other people's
experiences see they'll give you the
right path to follow in order to have
their experience but don't you want your
own it might not look so neat and clean
and down the well-trodden path as
everyone else's it might be messy and
dirty and you might be hungry but it's
yours it's what your guts telling you to
do it's what your hearts telling you to
do there is a magnificent intelligence
in the body of the subconscious mind
lies in the peripheral nervous system
it's a part of your mind that beats your
heart and digest your food without you
thinking about it this brain doesn't do
all that and you know when they say that
you only use about 5% of your brain it's
because you're just using this one start
to feel your body if you haven't been
that deadened so far that you can't most
of us have been and that's why I tell
you should do things like massage and
bioenergetics tapping is very helpful
breathe breathe deeply into your body
relax all the muscular holding patterns
all the all the tenseness in your body
recognize it and start releasing it
basically what you're doing is releasing
the intelligence in your body when you
do this that subconscious mind that 95%
of the brain that we're not using it's
not in here it's way down here the brain
doesn't stop in the neck
it shoots way down into our body via the
spinal cord and spreads out all into our
organs our viscera our muscular system
there is an intelligence that you're
ignoring because that you've been told
to ignore it you've been you not been
told how to use it when you go to school
it's all book information it's all sit
down and bring it in through your eyes
and ears there's no feeling
there's no get in touch with your
feelings experience and creativity mean
nothing and it's very easy to manipulate
people when all you give them as
information but when you teach people to
start trusting their bodies they become
dangerous be dangerous