so today we got a question from our very
ambitious young friend he is on his way
to becoming a amateur bodybuilder he's
studying for his personal trainer
certification he's studying consistently
for business he wants to own his own
business where he helps people with
disabilities through exercise very
admirable he also happens to be from a
family that is somewhat struggling
especially financially and he says over
the past six years he's moved five times
because his family can't afford to pay
the rent and now he's in a place where
he's is branching out in his own way to
become a man becoming a man by making
decisions about what he wants to become
and how he's going to do it and as he's
making his tippy-toes in that direction
and having some experiences in that
direction
he's stricken with fear now he doesn't
say this I say that the way he describes
it is that he has sleepless nights he's
constantly battling with that he's going
to see doctors because he just can't
seem to put a rest to this restlessness
and he knows that if he's ever going to
help other people and he's going to
become the strongest version of himself
he had I better get some sleep and he
had better figure out how to deal with
this anxiety that's associated with all
of the history of insecurity as well as
the ambition of moving forward that's
really the deep question here that many
of us may be able rate or relate to how
do I work my way towards what I'm
ambitious about when I have quicksand
under my feet I have no stability you
have no you seemingly have no stability
many of us you know we're deep in debt
how am I ever going to do what I want to
do achieve the goals I seek to achieve
when I've got all this debt how am I
gonna make this happen when I don't have
how am I going to move forward when I
have a history that has conditioned me
through fear because it is a fearful
situation especially for your parents
and parents our energy moves towards the
children whether we speak it or not they
feel what's happening and if you have
parents who had to move five times in
six years because they can't pay their
rent those are fearful people they're
probably fearful and that's why they got
in the situation and the situation your
circumstances always just play back your
sentiment so if you're fearful you're
going to get fearful shit so you're
coming from a cesspool of fear my friend
and you have great strong ambitions how
do you go about it well first I'll give
you some abstract ideas some things that
you can chew on for a little while that
you might want to consider and if they
help you today great if they don't maybe
one day you can come back and use it and
then I'll give you some practical
application some practical things that
you can do to make your way out of this
because I've been there I know what it's
like to be deeply in debt have a
mortgage you can't pay a wife and two
children at the time but you can't put
food on the table for have a truck that
has no window on it and it rains on you
and there's no you don't have gasoline
to put in it and you have to push it to
the gas station and leave it there
because there's no money on your car to
put gas in there and you've got a myriad
of other things going on that make you
fearful and sick and you feel like
you're standing on quicksand I've been
there I just described my story and I'm
here I'm in a pretty good place and I
want to show you how the very first idea
the abstract part that I want you to get
through your head is that you will
always be taken care of as long as
you're true to yourself and you're true
to your values as well as your ambition
isn't
your gratification but heart fulfillment
you will be taken care of when your
ambition is shiny objects you're going
to have a difficult time because shiny
objects don't come till much later shiny
objects don't come till you've began
actually serving people and it takes
time to create the infrastructure where
you actually serve people so your whole
business idea through strength training
and body building for those with
disabilities is going to take some time
you get the shiny objects after you
serve those people that's how people get
shiny objects unless they use credit
cards like most of our society does look
a lot of a lot of the people who have
nice shit they don't have nice shit they
got dead oh that's a great car a nice
Escalade you got there mrs. Jones
Miss Jones own own shit the bank owns
her but if your ambition is to fulfill
your heart's calling see this is where
the sentiment from which you perceive
matters more
you'll always be cared for you will
always be taken care of your needs not
your wants your needs will always be met
when you're following your heart's
calling I have a deep and profound
compassion for those with disabilities
and I sacrifice myself in a direction by
which I can serve them it's a very
different thing then I want to own shiny
objects and lots of shiny objects and I
want to control people and have power
over them those are things that are
byproducts of doing the right thing by
serving people and now I'm talking about
the shiny objects power over people is
something that is uh I should make a
whole nother video about that it's one
that there's a lot of associations with
that people that don't understand power
have
and doing a lot of digressing today so
I'm just going to come back so my friend
make sure your heart is in the right
place when you head out on that journey
and it's a righteous journey you will be
cared for your needs will be met in
other words you'll have food in your
belly and a shirt on your back roof over
your head and that's it don't expect
anything else everything else besides
that if you can answer those questions
because now we start getting into the
practical practicality of this if you
can answer those questions did I eat a
meal today do I have shoes on my feet
and a shirt on my back a roof over my
head and just enough means by which I
can fulfill my heart's desire fulfill my
heart's purpose you see the type of
business I have I was lucky enough to
come up right when in 2007 YouTube came
out in 2007 I started making videos
serendipitous I didn't make that happen
or did I serendipity happened whereby I
don't have advertising money but I got a
cheap-ass camera I still have a
cheap-ass camera and I make videos you
see so the means will always be there
and even if you don't have the the
finances the technology or the the good
kind of heartedness of other people
somehow you're gonna get what you need
if it's in pursuit of your hearts
calling boom that's it
the only thing you should expect
anything that surrounds that
circumstance that creates bad feelings
meaning I have a roof over my head Eliot
but I don't have next month's rent I
have food Eliot but it's not the food
that I really want anything that comes
from a place of fear anything in those
circumstances that puts fear or bad
feelings in your body you have to ignore
completely I don't I didn't say do you
have six months rent in your bank
account I said is there a roof over your
head
yes I'm late on my bills this month but
do you have a roof over your head yes
don't worry about it your landlord will
perhaps figure something out to help you
you got to set aside the things that
make you feel bad about your
circumstances ignore them completely and
I say ignore not so that you may live in
ignorance I say ignore because they're
not resourceful things to consider when
you're a man moving forward in his
calling towards his heart's calling you
can't be tangled up with the ideas of
I'm $90,000 in credit card debt
see I was $90,000 a credit card debt I
stopped thinking about it you know what
I did I got myself on a payment plan and
I kept working and I worked and I worked
and I worked had nothing and I paid off
all my hunch almost a hundred thousand
was a little over ninety almost six
figures worth of debt I paid off because
I stopped thinking about the debt and I
started working to serve people I did
that all to my old ass Jim on the south
side of st. Pete with crackheads and
prostitutes
that's how I made that money and an
e-book I created with a friend called
lean hybrid muscle I paid off debt with
that I got myself out of the quicksand
with that see now I have shiny things
I'm standing on firm ground because I
did what I'm about to tell you the next
thing you need to do my man is to
remember that you are to live in this
world because you chose to be here we
all chose to be here but be not of it
meaning don't let the tumult and the the
anxiety the craziness the tornado that's
why I'm doing this you know I talk with
my body
don't let the tornado carry you away
don't let the tornado of life turn you
upside down and knock you over the head
with a bunch of shit that's in the
tornado also debt is one of the things
that's shit how much shit do you want in
there - it's another question when
you're getting tossed around you don't
want too much shit in there
you don't want women problems that's
what I'll tell you when you get tossed
around because you're following your
heart know
get tangled up with a woman that doesn't
understand you I watch too many guys
they lose it all because and once they
lose it all I mean they lose their heart
and soul because of a woman vice versa
as well
so what you need to do what I'm telling
you to do is to meditate that's one of
the very few principles that I put my
foot down on and say you must do you
must meditate you must find a way every
single day to take yourself out of the
storm and go into the eye of the storm
I've used this metaphor before don't
step out of the storm see most people
they think that doing drugs and drinking
alcohol partying with their friends or
watching television right that's one
over that many of us get trapped in
watching TV or watching YouTube videos
all day long stop watching my fucking
videos and go do some or any form of
entertainment or distraction is relaxing
for them no that's called escape
that means I'm stepping outside of the
tornado now you've checked out of life
you've checked out of everything that
you're you you believe in all your
values and where you're going I say move
to the eye of the storm where you're
fully engaged with the storm because
it's going around you but you're at
peace because you're in the eye of it at
the center you're at the center of
yourself come home to your Center
meditation is medicine just like prozac
and alcohol except it doesn't leave you
with a hangover or addiction it leaves
you it leads you to a stronger version
of yourself because you carry meditation
with you if I didn't meditate I wouldn't
be here because the world would have
carried me away you my friend must make
use of meditation and there are many
different forms of it and I don't sit
here and and and claim to have a patent
on any of them I happen to like yoga and
bioenergetics these are forms of body
and body psychology body meditation Osho
has many dynamic meditations again
they're all body meditations I'm a body
guy I'm a body builder I'm in the body I
feel all my power comes from my body so
I do body type meditations there are
sitting meditations where you just sit
then you breathe just focus on your
breath whatever works for you but
explore many different forms of
meditation and don't let anybody give
you their patented meditation tell you
that's the only one the only requirement
of meditation is that you become closer
to your truth you can become closer to
your Center you become closer to who you
are many people jog that's their
meditation they run and I've experienced
that one too it's a good one exercise
you've got to meditate the second thing
is very likened unto what I told you
before about ignoring the circumstances
and focusing on where you're going and
that is to automatically dissociate from
negative thoughts I've made videos about
this about how to how to deal with
negative thoughts or something in that
fashion search my channel you've got to
detach yourself from negative thoughts a
lot of people you know some of you are
so clever well what does that mean
Elliott do I just ignore reality no
motherfucker you create
reality by taking your eyes off of what
you have and put it up or what you don't
want and put it on what you do want cuz
you create your reality I create my
reality I knew what I didn't want and I
turn my eyes away from it put it what I
wanted and you need to do the same thing
and those either who too clever to
figure that shit out too clever to try
that shit out or you want science to
prove it fuck you keep living miserably
you want something amazing on a mystical
life trust this one idea give it a try
mystery the mystery of these things
that's all I want to do is point you in
the direction the mystery I have no
answers the mystery of creating your
life because no one who's created in
life can tell you exactly how they did
it but there are certain ways of being
that they were and that's the most
important thing to consider be
meditative and be focused on what you do
want and I'll stop there because this is
probably about a twenty minute video so
that's it my friend listen I'm going to
finish this way
for you to become a success out of the
depths of dysfunction that you're coming
from will not only be a gift for
yourself but a gift for seven
generations forward you rid yourself of
the sins of your parents your children
grandchildren and great-grandchildren
and so forth
will receive the gift of your
transcendence beyond their sins and I've
also heard it put this way that by you
overcoming the sins that your parents
laid upon you when I say sins I'm not
judging your parents as bad people I'm
saying they gave you fear you grew up in
fear you free them from their sins and
you free seven generations before you of
that sin you grow stronger not for
yourself in this mere moment you spend
on earth you grow stronger for your
legacy and for those who might not never
know your name because they need you and
we need you as you spread the seeds of
your light while you walk this planet
keep growing stronger done