okay so we got a great question from one
of our friends who wants to know how
Elliott Hulse changed his voice so
apparently he's been watching some of my
videos from several years ago where my
voice was at a much higher pitch and he
notices that it's much deeper now and
what I'm going to call more grounded so
the long story short is that since I
discovered bioenergetics and how the
body is a manifestation of the
psychological character of an individual
and that we can create what I call
neurotic holding patterns where the
external world stimulus from the outside
causes a particular response you know we
respond to fear by tightening up we we
respond to anger in a particular way our
body takes on the character of the
predominant psychology of the individual
so the situation that I was in who I was
prior to breaking up the neurotic
holding patterns with some of the
exercises I'll show you and the one
there's ones that you've seen me do on
this video including my you know some of
the crazier ones the person that I was
was a uptight rigid individual my energy
was way too high and that's why I use
the term grounded just now what I've
been able to do is through bioenergetics
break up the muscular armoring
throughout all of my extra respiratory
muscles and allow my energy to drive
much deeper often I talk about breathing
into your balls well before I was
breathing in a castrated fashion
I had a castrated voice my energy never
went lower than my chest right because I
had muscular armoring across the belly
across the hips and my legs were not
grounded so long story short again my
ability to breathe deeper and to bring
my energy down into a lower region of my
body has allowed me to speak from a more
grounded place ie with a deeper voice my
voice resonates within my body that
more so the very first thing is to open
up your capacity to breathe deep I've
done videos on this before I'll link it
up but there's the bioenergetics tool
this thing that I and I stretch on and I
breathe deep with an open mouth on in
order to bring my to open up my ability
to breathe the other thing that's very
helpful is to make deep resonating
sounds and help your body vibrate in
order to break up some of the neurotic
holding patterns and especially in the
hips and in the belly I hold most of my
tension even today in my belly so I've
got to do different things including the
ball massage that I show you in the
other video in my deep breathing video
but I also do a lot of grounding
exercises I call this the ground bounce
and it's a part of my bioenergetic
warm-up routine I'll put another link if
I remember to that that's on my other
channel but it goes something like this
I wear no shoes and often times when I
make these videos I take my shoes off
because it helps bring my energy down
energy is you know people get kind of
confused and they think when you use the
term energy you're talking about like
some hocus pocus magic force field
that's I don't know they get all
confused it basically is where your
attention is it's where you're directing
your intention and attention okay so by
having my shoes off I'm able to direct
my intention and attention down into my
feet right I also massage my feet with a
foam roller then I just bounce on my
heels and as you heard me just started
to do I start to make a deep resonating
sound that comes from my belly now this
may be difficult to do at first if you
have tension in your belly like I often
do so you might have to massage it or
stretch on the on the biogenic energetic
stool you're also going to want to hold
your mouth open while you're doing that
and it that's that was a bit confusing
to me at first but basically by holding
your mouth open you relaxed a lot of the
muscles that are in your
throat right I didn't understand at
first but my experience tells me that
it's true this is what my mentor dr.
glazier has taught me so you hold your
mouth open and as you hold your mouth
open and balance on your toes you make a
sound that that resonates within your
body it looks like this Oh
[Laughter]
and you notice that my pitch is by
moving my pitch around because I'm
trying to find that really deep spot
right I feel great right now I'm trying
to find a good deep spot right below my
belly button right and as I'm doing it
I'm just focusing on those different
restricted areas namely my belly right
because if the belly's tight the
diaphragm can't drop right can't drop
low and you can't Center your Center
your energy so there's just making those
deep resonating sounds you will be
astonished just like don't found it when
you begin to open up particularly the
throat through the deep breathing
exercises and the the ground bouncing
like I just showed you so that's it
didn't want to make this video too long
so I'm going to cut it short right now
I'll continue to share more information
about this with you guys but um it's
been a byproduct of my use and study of
bioenergetics so good luck with that
buddy Elliott what
[Music]