so let's create some context for that if
you want I know you spoke a little bit
about it but about I'd like to talk
about how how do we get like this hey
what's up man
good to see you how do we get like this
our muscular system is our is our
self-made prison and where it's our self
perpetrated prison meaning that the
muscles and especially in the front part
of your body because this is where our
softness is if you're if you look at a
dog
alright we're an animal it gets angry
what happens their back goes up right
all the aggressive muscles in the in the
back the long muscles of the back tense
up especially the neck and shoulders but
when they're happy when they're open
when they're available that's the first
thing they do they lay on the floor and
they they give themselves to you so what
happens is we become tense in our
shoulders and we close ourselves off to
the world right well a dog that is more
is going to be receiving love as a dog
that gives love right you just fucking
love the dog he's looking at me you show
up in it he just rolls and does this to
you cuz he's soft here he's soft in his
neck and jaw right down to his balls ah
right I mean when you relax what you do
it's this right here so it's a lot of
attention that we hold in the front
burner of our body from perineum up into
the jaw really across the face here
these are our lover muscles right you
kiss you hug and you fuck it's all right
here but if you're tense in any one of
those areas it's going to show up in
first while your posture obviously
because we can look at you and see this
but how you're breathing so right now
I'm trying to find my energy I'm trying
to find my ground right now because I
just stood up here and you know I had
this firecracker that all the noise and
I could like figure out where I'm at but
the idea is to bring softness to the
muscles that allow you to breathe that
allow you to
communicate be open smoothly have this
wave thing going on here
right it's all these muscles here so
this is a really simple exercise I know
you probably see me do like you see he
do shit like that
I'm not gonna ask you guys do it yeah
I'm open that way this little you know
Owen same thing you know he comes up
here
he's non-stop it's just his energy is
expensive and he's gotten out the way
we're all this way we're all very
expansive but we get out we have to get
out the way to allow these vibes to
reach the people we're trying to
communicate with the women you see so I
try to be like I like wash me shit try
to be loose like that well you know I
I'm a slave to I'm a mind slave also so
I'm constantly having to practice you
know you described this also you're
naturally troll all right
I'm naturally dysfunctional also so mind
I always come up with pre video
techniques and what I've been doing
recently is listening to binaural beats
frequencies but at the same time I'm
doing this so I'd like to actually take
someone first and I'm gonna choose
someone you yeah this you look actually
pretty yeah okay you two also yeah okay
so what we want to be able to do is
loosen the muscles in the front part of
our body that is like the dog that's
getting tickled you want to be dog is
gets tickled right that's what does he
do that's a good place to be isn't it
I am so take your shoes off take your
shirts off yeah cool cool cool cool cool
and so our face our faces are how we
meet and receive the world we meet each
other we were with each other through
our faces first so a lot of our most of
our attention is here really you know
you think about breathing muscles and
you think your lungs but it begins here
really is in your eyes and all your all
throughout this particular area first
thing would ask you guys to do is to
open your eyes and mouth as wide as you
can
awkwardly wide good good get and keep it
that way you're going to be there for a
while so everything that I asked you to
do hang out there take your hands and
spread your fingers as wide as you can
bend your knees slightly bring your toes
straight shoulder-width good bend your
knees good I don't want you to begin
leaning backwards wide mouth wide mouth
and breathe and I want you guys to watch
them yes you started choking you started
choking there's a lot of tension in here
for you I want you to stay stop for a
moment I want you to try something
before you can because the choking is a
sign that that's where your your clogged
up that always happens to me I've done
your exercise before okay let's try to
let's try to get some of the tension out
of your throat there's gonna be weird I
want you to I want you to gag a little
bit right right like anything we're
doing here is sort of adorable
now now we get to the weird part I want
you to I want you to put your fingers
down your throat and you wins last time
you ate applause yeah you're good
I want you to get the gag reflex going
what you do try just try that I just did
it so you're cool I might get this thing
dirty all right
face face that way let's try the gag
reflex do you feel your throat opening
up good and that was a sponte you didn't
make your throat open up you just gave
it a stimulus and all of a sudden the
muscles relaxed right did you feel it
like do it one more time and then we'll
go back into the bow just do it one more
time ended okay cool cool open your
mouth wide wide wide wide wide wide get
back into the bow good you too you're
okay yeah you're different so what I'm
doing is I have to you know I got to see
where the tension is and that was a sign
breathe now I wouldn't hear you breathe
look how red his neck is because that
means that's where all his tension is
good good I want you to bend your knees
bend your knees bend your knees get out
what you lean back even further and I
want you to breathe ah
good very good continue forget him right
now watch this guy breathe you see that
vibration here good continue breathe
hang out there and keep going breathe
breathe good yes don't be afraid of the
vibration allow the vibration to happen
breathe good you're going to be there
for a while so figure it out
bend your knees bend your knees
bring your feet closer yeah you're
cheating bring your feet closer even
more and more and more and more and more
and more and more and more good and hang
out there good breathe bend your knees
good you see how that was vibrating a
little bit more there's more of this
going on what you're experiencing while
you watch them try to breathe in this
stress position and he's having a hard
time here also yeah do this it's to come
on back up I don't listen with two guys
at the same time when analyzing both so
I'm pointing at different things let me
stop let me go with him for a moment
here vibration breaks things right I
mean if there's an earthquake buildings
are collapsing it breaks shit up
this is muscular tension that is keeping
him from being the strongest expression
of himself expression happens here right
so you can think all these techniques
all you want and you can repeat all
these techniques all you want and you
can speak them well but it happens here
life happens here you have intelligence
and memory here the intelligence that's
happening here is so magnificent that if
he had a vagina a person can grow in
here and he didn't have to do nothing
about it except get fucked right right
you know what's the funniest thing when
somebody says kind of gradual ations
when you get pregnant like Oh
congratulations what she did this
okay gracias what you did this
congratulations
they were fuckin and that happens
it's like anyway so your heart beats or
food digests there's intelligence
there's power but there's also an
implicit memory that stores all of your
experiences in your body and it
manifests physically in muscular tension
that doesn't allow you to be soft enough
to breathe and breathing is flow and
flow is what you want to get into when
you're trying to talk to chicks right
cuz that's what you guys are into that's
your thing here
I say become the strongest version
yourself for whatever the fuck you want
to do but I want you to get into that
flow if his throat is so closed and
tight and there's so much energy trapped
in this in the first part of the inner
tube that allows him to inhale such that
there's redness in the area you're a
redneck I'm Hispanic Asian well so that
you're a redneck and I'm sure you carry
that redneck with you a lot yeah you
know he's if you could just imagine that
if he was a vessel for the expression of
all the magnificence that he is and
someone took a belt and wrapped around
his neck and did this it was like God
buddy go talk to chicks you see so we
have to find ways to reduce the muscular
tension that doesn't allow him to
breathe in a simple position you're just
whatever you
I'm practicing for a long time because
I'm all fucked up so how long will it
take you to get rid of this if I did it
you'll be working this for the rest of
your life because the implicit memory
yeah sorry
I've never seen her make it fixed but
what you do is you manage your fucked up
miss that's the way I see it you know
we've got this magical idea of the
strongest version of ourselves you know
I sell that idea but the short version
yourself is you're figuring the shit out
as you go along you got some cool tools
to make you a little bit better than
yesterday you see so I just imparted a
piece of information on you from an
objective viewpoint that you now can say
if I'm having a hard time approaching
women it's because I have a fucking belt
wrapped around my neck right well he was
he saw audience you're not as obvious
and you might not have had as much
trauma as he's had and I don't know and
I say trauma because it's a matter of
having Unruh source full experiences at
some time in our life when we were
vulnerable that gets trapped in the body
memory that creates muscular tension
that doesn't allow you to breathe or
flow so at some point and I'm just
completely I'm making this shit up and
that's how I make my videos at some
point someone told you shut the fuck up
and you you did and you kept it do you
see see so this particular area a lot of
the stuff sounds like bullshit crap but
the metaphor seems pretty fucking
literal to me in the chakra system of
understanding our physiology this area
is associated with verbal communication
that's not that strange that was it and
if you have a trauma associated with
verbal communication meaning shut the
fuck up and sit down
and you have a mechanism by which
implicit memory gets trapped in your
body this is not this is science you
then walk around with a redneck and you
can't talk to chicks I've always had a
problem for jected my voice always and
you get a nice voice thanks you know you
you've got a deep grounded voice you
haven't lost much down here you could
probably make magnificent gains by doing
this every day opening this particular
area you know gag the gag reflex is an
amazing thing that we have that allows
our inner tube our esophagus to open up
when we need to release something we not
only release food from this particular
area but we release our expression to
this area so we need to like never saw
hit meet someone and it's like this guy
just fucking threw up on me or a chick
yeah it's like something you want to
talk to chicks but sometimes it's like
she won't stop talking to me she's got
too much here you have not enough so we
need to open that particular area up and
they're mechanisms by which we can do it
exercises all right it seems strange but
hey you practice the gag reflex every
morning and then you periodically
through the day throughout the day you
just are aware of your neck and throat
and do this you will start to be a
different person because you you're
freeing that particular area of your
body that's also associated with a
character ability to be open so that you
can get more of this right more tickling
you're not as obvious just yet
you know I haven't watch you that much
he's just like glaring
but when you stop when he starts
vibrating did you notice he he opened up
and we got him to a point and he hasn't
let go just fully yet what what's
required is that you
let go into the vibration let the
vibration happen let's do this keep your
feet straight a little bit wider just
with shoulder-width no good bend your
knees good I like the position you were
in before hands here but it was very
aggressive let's do hands behind the
head first I'll give you a little bit
lesser open your mouth as wide as you
can real wide good now begin to fall
back keeping your knees bent good bend
your knees
good and breathe lean back
good allow the movement to happen good
see where it takes you
flat feet thank you
good continue but raise your hands out
good spread your fingers as wide as you
can
good now I want you to do this and now
lean back continue leaning good there it
is that's the spot allow that to happen
breathe good yes yes
allow it yeah laughs if you want to
laughter is a good vibration yeah good
wide mouth wide mouth yeah
good that's life
bursting out of his body right now it's
this dissonance against the muscular
tension holding all that he is behind it
he wants to get out he wants to burst
out so vibration breaks that up but it's
also a sign that there's tension there
open your mouth and go ha ha ha good do
it again ha ha ha uh-huh yes go that's
it good
breathe
breathe I want to hear you breathe good
really uncomfortable come on back up
there's a lot of resistance you're
resisting it but that's cool because
you've got a we'd have to work a little
bit longer so what you're he's built
like what we would call a phallic
narcissist he's he's got a good healthy
strong build with evenly distributed
energy not so much like you your
Energy's trapped in one particular area
his and he's like a tube and all the
energy is evenly distributed but it's
trapped the felt narcissus is built and
there's a lot of this Freud shit so kill
me if you will
the phallic narcissus is built his the
muscular restriction is built from a
trauma associated with holding back
joyful feelings joyful feelings are
sexual feelings his first slip excuse me
I just slipped all over your fucking
case so embarrassing here I'm checking
him out as he's doing shit but his first
slip his first inclination when he began
experiencing the vibration the breaking
up of the muscular tension that's
holding back who he is
was laughter laughter I mean I'm
checking you out of you guys here but
he's like uh-huh and I'm like go ahead
go with it but you know there's
cognitive dissonance there's there's the
you that wants to laugh which is in your
body because your body laughs with your
body you don't laugh with your mouth
laughing is a is a body vibration when
you laugh like you have a laugh so
fucking hard that your belly hurts but
you think you're laughing with your
mouth you laugh won't your belly so
you're holding back your laughter the
laughter wants to come out associated
with joyful feelings that have been
repressed in you and you're confused
about it and that's why there's
resisting
against letting it happen you were
getting very I know you're getting very
uncomfortable then and amen round of
applause for both these guys yeah for
hanging out there I mean you're hanging
out there for quite a while and what
happens also too is in that stress
position you you become sort becoming
defensive and in order to maintain
yourself because you've probably felt
like was going to snap so there's too
much resistance for it all happened it
would take process it would take time
for that to come out but I would love to
see you breathing into your belly and
you need a big joyful laugh like tears
ones last time you laugh to like tears
came across I don't remember yeah yeah
yeah that here's a funny fucking thing
here I go again right like all the shit
isn't fucking funny and weird you got to
put your shirts back on - I don't you
know I know you're standing up there
exposing yourself ah you if you release
that trapped vibe which is a joyful vibe
I use that word by because it's a
abbreviation for vibration you know it's
not in some hippy shit
vibration we're all fucking vibrations
you release that you give yourself the
opportunity to allow that to explode out
of the muscular tension holding it back
you're going to be such a cool fucking
dude you're not going to know what to do
with yourself
because you have now pierced the armor
holding back a part of you that it's
that is joyful and a joyful person
spilling joy out wherever they go from
the front of their body is attractive
now you guys dig Gila I'm saying here
cool so you have a seat then could you
guys tell me what is it for me his is
joy - yours is just expression it's very
high you probably and this is I'm
pulling this shit out of my ass right
now
I bet there's a lot of anger because
this particular area is also associated
with this is our first form of
aggression biting so it's a in order to
reduce attention now this is one way
with a the throat right but another way
is to is to break up a lot of the
tension in here through screaming so
show your teeth like this like I can
angry doubt it and I want you to growl
I'm gonna press on your neck it's gonna
feel painful but I want you to growl
with it ah go with it not necessarily
not necessarily ladder this is this is a
he's in a very compromised position here
with all you guys staring at him you
know much less if it was just he and I
the most resourceful thing would be if
you were laying down and you were could
be in the moment and it's a difficult
thing that's why I hesitated before I
was like what you need it's a bit
different you know there's a bit there's
and I would say there's some anger and
there you need to make it some fucking
noise
you need to yell you need to a lot of
it's probably in here try that
yeah yeah I do it now
this is massages besides it like rub on
it like this
because we have that in us because we
have that in us because it's in here and
when this comes out everything comes
back easy or embarrassed we've been made
ashamed of just how fucking powerful we
are
I'm done