hey what's up guys yesterday we spoke a
little bit about breaking down old
character right old versions of
ourselves old Unruh source for ways of
beings rituals habits and behavior so
that we can build up into a stronger
version of ourselves with new habits so
basically we talked about what new
things are you going to do daily to add
to the construction of a stronger
version of yourself so today in my blog
post on Elliott Hulse calm I talked a
little bit about eating elephants so
today in this video we're going to talk
about three different elements that
y'all might want to eat right like they
say about elephants the only way to eat
it one bite at a time
right so this means we've got a
gargantuan task ahead of us and we've
got to take daily steps towards getting
the shit done eating elephants so the
three elephants that we're going to
devour today are related to fitness
career or vocation and addiction all
right we'll begin like this I'm going to
share a few ideas about how to chew away
at the giant task ahead of you with
regard to weight loss or muscle gain or
performance as well as in your career
and as well as the slightly different
tasks it requires a little bit of a
different approach to eat the elephant
of addiction so let's begin with regard
to Fitness right I'm going to assume
that we're dealing with a person that
wants to lose weight right because most
of us the majority of us can stand to
lose a little bit of body fat we do live
in a cozy culture all right so if you're
gonna go ahead and say lose 50 pounds
right now that might not be the hundred
pounds that some of us are after but 50
pounds so we're sort of in the middle
there what can we do every single day
whether we feel like it or not in order
to chop away or chew away at that
elephant right this is going to require
that we not that we avoid
trying to make grand plans and
statements right going from nothing from
go from zero to a hundred is what a lot
of people like to do I can tell you from
my own experience and as a coach shit
don't work you can't go from zero of 0
to 100 you're not going to lose 50
pounds by by killing it by crushing it
like a beast right that's the that's the
language we use this describe when balls
to the wall well that works to a certain
degree but what really gets you the
long-term results would really choose
that elephant to pieces down to its
brittle bones
sure LF it doesn't have brittle bones is
what you're going to do every single day
little by little bite by bite to get you
where you want to be these are by far
the most resourceful rituals and habits
to engage in it may seem like you know
you're just tippy-toeing but a tippy-toe
er is gonna get there a lot faster than
a sprinter who burns out and scrapes his
knees and doesn't get back up because
his feelings are hurt right let's
tippy-toe tippy-toe our way to success
fitness what do you do
I've often spoken about taking a walk
every day I think it happens to be the
simplest and most refreshing ritual that
anybody can engage in on a daily basis
edit killed multiple birds with one
stone
you're not just going to lose weight
because you're exercising you get out
there especially I live in Florida it's
hot you're gonna be sweating but it's
also a time to either meditate clear
your mind listen to the birds early in
the morning I like to walk by the water
so sort of a meditation also you can use
it as a time for education walk and
listen right it really happens to be one
of my favorite habits for life in
general than I think most people who
were kind of struggling should try
nutrition is also mine and you know a
lot of times we go from eating Big Macs
Pizza Hut Twizzlers tab and soda and uh
and pop you know who are not in the
United States or those of you in the
Midwest called pop right there sugar
bowl beverages people like to drink I
say a very simple
Oh applicable daily activity that you
can engage and that's going to get you
tremendous results physiologically
energetically your mind will change
because you don't have so much
stimulating caffeine and sugar in you
and your body will changes you simply
replace shitty sugary drinks with water
simple might not be easy for me so some
of you who are addicted right and we'll
talk about that a moment but simple
that's really what we want we want we
don't attack this with simple steps tell
you it's the way to go you know it's
been my experience that life is life is
long we got to take a long-term approach
at this thing and the best way to do
that is to integrate the daily rituals
that you that will last a lifetime
you could drink water and walk for a
lifetime you'll be 80 and still in good
shape just by doing so finally let's
let's talk about addiction you know I
mentioned it could be obviously a sugar
addiction a lot of us are are addicted
to our our junk food and we're addicted
to various uh you know what would be
considered health foods but are loaded
in chemicals and whatnot you know what
we call health food usually isn't health
food
but then there's the obvious one of you
know say porn addiction that seems to be
one that I keep hearing a lot about
pornography addiction I can't help
myself but to watch people on my iPhone
screwing while I beat myself up I just
can't stop doing it no matter what I
can't seem to shake this habit right
there's that there's obviously drug
addiction alcohol addiction all these
various addictions require here's this
really important and different about
addictions the light the Sun is coming
up see that here's one of the things
that's really interesting about
addictions are important to know about
addiction addiction is there because
it's filling a hole right what do I mean
by that I mean that there's an emptiness
within us
there's something that we're not willing
to explore or we're ignoring or is too
hurtful to dissect so we mask it we fill
it with alcohol drugs sugar jerking off
alright jerking off it actually isn't
filling a hole having sex will be
filling a hole so basically you're just
skating into thin air right but the
point is that it's it's fulfilling
something in you so what we need to do
instead of just getting rid of it so
getting rid of that thing that you can't
stop doing you replace it with something
that is somehow reminiscent of and a
good substitute for the addiction so for
example if you smoke right you smoke
cigarettes right can't stop train
smoking these motherfuckers then what
you might want to do is switch to a
vaporizer now I'm not saying that
vaporizers are healthy for you and the
you know who got pens people use not
saying that that's a great habit to get
into
but it's far better than incinerating
all that paper and trash with the
chemicals and the cigarettes right it
might be a good way to destroy one a way
of being by implanting a new one and you
could of course progressed from there
right you can go from smoking your
vaporizer your hookah pen to um you know
lessening me you could progressively
lessen the nicotine my point here is
that you got to take baby steps you got
to take you gotta take elephant bites
baby elephant bites what's another one
um porn right so pornography and and the
addition to ejaculation really is not
even attack you the ejaculation it's
kind of like the UH when we orgasm the
French call it the petite where the tiny
death orgasm is a is a is a way of
transcendence it's a way of kind of
getting away from it all and while
you're beating it off and you're getting
ready to let it take you to heaven
you're all your problems go away
right ain't got no problems when your
eyes are rolling back so what we got to
do recognizing that it is a physical
addiction
and physically are being affected
replace it with a nother activity that
releases euphoric hormones makes you
feel good about yourself right get your
body buzzing go run sprints marry time
you're thinking about beating it off you
go outside and you beat the pavement go
for a sprint go do sets of Sprint's I
guarantee you your mind will get off of
it completely right and you're going to
be huffing and puffing and be completely
centered and grounded in the exercise of
sprinting you can also try which would
I've been doing most recently I don't
have porn addiction but just to create
resourceful rhythms in my life is
breathing exercises or Qigong Taichi
bioenergetic breathing all right there
are plenty of books are plenty of videos
out there on how to take just a few
minutes a day here and say it would take
you 20 minutes to watch a watch a video
and rub one out and instead you do a
simple Tai Chi breathing movement the
idea here is that we replace the Unruh
social habit with something new so
that's it here folks hey if you guys
have any ideas about how you might what
were one of our friends down below in
the comment area might be able to eat an
elephant what are some baby steps that
we can take towards our success since
this is a long-term project please share
it with us down below I'll talk to you
guys tomorrow