okay so we got this great interesting
strange sad question from our friend who
says Elliot greetings from a dude living
in South Korea among people who hold the
suicide record for developed countries
congratulations
since basically my question is I've been
living this country for two years now I
feel like a collective depression has
gotten to me like I am sinking down to
normal levels of happy which is you know
kind of like the stick happy in this
country but in this country that's
barely above depression this question is
do you ever feel that you have to do
things like bioenergetics meditation
yoga just to stay afloat says like if
you don't do it every single day would
you not be alive or would you only be a
shell of the man that you are now he's
asking me I know any form of physical
expression like in your video so on and
so forth he wants to know Elliott did am
I going to have to always do some form
of meditation be it body meditation
through yoga or bioenergetics or sitting
meditation Transcendental Meditation you
whole thing all the things I talk about
when you're living in an environment
that's oppressing you that's pressing in
on you to such a degree that you
yourself feel as if you're falling apart
yes and that's exactly how I live my
life you know I for whatever reason I
don't live in the suicide capital of the
world in fact it's always bright and
sunny here and I'm really not around too
many people you know I've got my family
then who love me and I love them I've
got my really good friends and
co-workers partners a great life I don't
watch TV but for whatever whatever
reason I I'm very sensitive to the
collective malady the collective
sickness that that we live in we live in
a stew of sickness and even though I I
put up walls against it like I said you
know I don't subject myself to many of
the things that make people ultimately
sick I feel its effects on a daily basis
I can't explain to you why I'm so
sensitive to this but I am and if I
don't meditate if I don't do some form
of body meditation or mind meditation
those things that I've shared with you
in these videos I grow ill and my wife
will say it too she be like you need to
meditate to say or you need if she'll
giggle and tease me about going to dr.
glazier so you need to cry on dr.
Glaser's couch oh you know because
that's what I do I go and I have to I
fill it out these emotional releases I
have to find all different sorts of of
cathartic method methods to rid myself
of the pain associated with living in
this world I know that sounds horrible
right like I'm saying that this world is
horrible Eliot and you're having to self
medicate although it's not medication
most people drink
most people will drink they'll go to
drinking or have every use of drugs or
or pharmaceuticals me I just dance
around act like a maniac you meditate
but we all have to medicate somehow I
just happen to do it with the means by
which our ancestors have done it you
know they're very old methods may sound
my boy Eliot that's a pretty dismal way
to look at the world well you know what
it's just the way it is and I'm not a
pessimist I'm more optimistic than most
people you'll ever meet I just happen to
think everything's going to be all right
if I take care of my mind I take care of
my body it's just like training you know
you wouldn't you wouldn't try out for an
NFL football team if you didn't train
for it life is like it is like you're
stepping into the arena you're a
gladiator you know of course you might
work for ups or you might work in a
corporate office or you might really be
an NFL athlete but the fact is that we
go out into this world and it bombards
us with all types of challenges and
stresses and things that we don't even
want emotional baggage through poor
energy and vibration from other people
that just they just vomited on us you
know you go to certain environments and
it's just like the people there they
just they throw all their shit on you
and this is why I have to stay away from
most people you know I'm coming to
realize this about myself I seem very
extroverted through these videos but if
you meet me I'm kind of an introvert but
some people will probably say that who
have met me this weekend last weekend my
boy I expected you to be a little bit
more laughs really I'm
kind of closed in it's just it's the way
I am but it's also why I've been
vigilant in my discovery of all these
methods by which I can fully express
myself and experience joy and pleasure
in life because I believe that life is
good so you my friend living in an
environment living in a soup of illness
so much so that more people kill
themselves in your country than than
anywhere else and I don't know the
reason why I couldn't tell you you know
could be everything from the political
situation to the to the to the actual
physical environment you know monsoons
or lots of rain I don't know the fact is
this is where you are for the rest of
your life my friend you will have to
meditate you have to go to your body you
have to breathe into your balls you'll
have to stretch you'll have to shake and
vibrate you have to do yoga this is
something you will do for the rest of
your life till the day you die at least
that's what I've accepted I will be 90
years old and I'll probably be doing
Qigong or tai chi or yoga or something
something something to yoke my mind to
my body and bring me into alignment so
that I can be a resourceful being on
this planet as opposed to one of those
who vomited on other people and make us
sick so my friend get used to the idea
you will be meditating until your spirit
leaves this flesh done