good morning guys Elliott Hulse here and
today I'm going to pick up very quickly
where I left off yesterday yesterday we
were talking about the development of
new habits and rituals to support you in
becoming a stronger version yourself I
was to mention three different things
and and various habits that supports you
in these three different areas of
becoming a stronger you it was helping
fitness career and addition you know
eradicate addiction and filling the hole
with something more resourceful but as I
read it on yesterday I forgot to mention
career or vocation so today we'll pick
up very quickly before I get into
today's main message by talking about
three different habits that would
support you in the development of your
career vocation or job if you have one
so I'll actually split it up that way
those who are in your own business or in
sales if you're an entrepreneur or if
you're in sales the three things that
you know right whether you're building
your own business or you're selling
titanium screws like a friend of mine
does he sells titanium screws in the
medical industry knee kills it so if I
didn't personally if I didn't own my own
business what I would do is I probably
go into sales if I you know if I were to
get a job because it requires a little
bit of a courageousness bravery and you
know it's either a sink-or-swim
situation when you work for yourself or
in sales and the three things that
matter most when you're developing your
clientele is to get leads do one thing
every single day to get leads that means
people in your funnel or people that you
attract them to you your message or
product through a various activities so
I make these videos I write blog post
the thousands of videos that I've made
on my youtube channel and the thousands
of signs I put up a whole from my city
when I was first starting strength camp
all brought leads into me they either
clicked and went to when website or they
called me so if you gotta do something
every day together leave number two
to follow up you gotta follow up your
leads which it's no good to have leads
if you don't follow up right that's like
if I made a really good youtube video i
made one and it got like 70 million
views and then never made another one or
didn't have an opportunity for people to
contact me if they really liked my video
my message my offer or for you your
pamphlet or your sign you got to give
them a way to follow up right you got to
follow up with them one thing every day
following up with your with your leads
either sending an email sending a card
making a phone call and then finally the
habit of closing baby you're not in
business and you're not making sales if
you don't close the deal the whole the
whole objective here is to get the thing
rolling by getting people to invest in
your product service or idea so every
day you should close at least one sale
if you're in sales or entrepreneurship
now if you have a job or career where
you're working for someone else this is
very important because as I learn more
about working with people I'm
discovering that those who come and
either internet strengthcamp or I hire
them for certain things I want to create
opportunities for the go-getters the
guys that make their boss look good
always move up the ladder and there's
always opportunities for them in fact
guys that make me look good by creating
my websites better Danny who does these
videos the better he helps me edit these
videos the more opportunities I want to
create for him so a habit of doing one
thing every day to make your boss or
your company look better is going to
open up doors for you there's no two
ways about it it's been my experience
you know of course you could be in an
environment that doesn't allow that but
get yourself if you're an advancing man
if this is the your pursuit is in career
invocation not all of us are and there's
no judgment about that but if it is and
get into a place where you can work your
way up the ladder by making your company
in your boss so good so that's it I want
to wrap that up as I forgot to mention
that yesterday on to today's message
down below you'll find a link to my blog
post from earlier this morning where I
talk about
getting very clear on our true root the
real reason why we pursue the things we
pursue so in my blog post I talked about
when I was pursuing strong man accolades
right between the eight between 2006 and
2010 I was heavily involved in strongman
competitions I was winning and I was
getting trophies I have lots of trophies
dozens of trophies and plaques the thing
is with all those trophies and plaques
is that they're in a box somewhere in
storage what because I have come to
realize you know it's taken some time
really a lot of these things aren't
judgments and we don't choose them
there's self observations and one of my
self observations has been that I really
could care less for trophies and gifts
and prizes what I really thrive on again
it's not a judgment it's just an
observation our words of affirmation man
every time I want a straw man show and
my coach or my or my dad or my wife or
my friends put their hand on my back
gave me a hug so you did a great job I'm
proud of you Elliott that just rose in
me but my heart swelled and I was
overjoyed by simply having those words
of affirmations a pat on the back of hug
my wife looks into my eyes and says I'm
proud of you well that does it for me
more than anything so that's me being
very clear on what I'm pursuing in a way
you could say that's in a way you can
say but that Elliott version of myself
and percept perhaps you when we start
getting clear on why we pursue you know
the real things that we pursue you find
that you know there's out there there
may be a lack of love that we're trying
to fulfill we're trying to raise our own
selves self-esteem is right when someone
would I make these videos or what I used
to you know an older version of myself
when I say older I mean younger a pass
to version of Elliot I'd sit around
waiting for people to tell me how good
of a job I did Elliot the video
right Elliot wonderful job and I in sit
there and I just I glow right so that's
me being self observant and realizing
that you know a lot of the things that I
i slaved after I went after you know
even sometimes with the attitude of I
don't care what anybody says I don't
care what anybody's thing really was for
words of affirmation praise and
acknowledgment by other people so my
question to you today my friends are and
really I want you to think about this
one a little bit I want you to take your
time really meditate on this why are you
doing the thing that you're doing I know
a lot of us are are busting our asses
slaving away grinding beast mode you
know sometimes it's for survival right I
gotta do this thing cuz I need money to
feed my kids that was part of it for me
but you know what is it for you is it
because you know it takes some objective
self-observation am i doing it because I
really just wanted my dad to say that
he's proud of me right that may be one
of them am i doing it because of won't
say I have a list here belonging you
know what are you really seeking after
right what do you really want what what
hole in you what missing part of you
what's sore spot in you is healed by the
pursuit of your goals what are you
really after so that's my question for
you today it might take a little while
you might have to sleep on that one I'm
not gonna I'm not looking forward to you
know a lot of very quick answers here
take some time observe yourself look at
how you receive various forms of praise
and how you kind of ignore others I
could give two shits about trophies but
a hug and a kind word is like a million
dollars in my bank so that's it guys I
hope that's helpful share your answer
down below talk to you next time