yo Elliot hey whats up guys today we got
a question from our strength camp online
member vincent de santiago Vincent's
problem is he can't keep a fucking job
he says every new job that he gets about
nine months in he starts getting bored
and he just wants to quit there have
even been circumstances by which he's
gotten pay raises and he's like more
money I don't care and he just wants to
quit so he his question basically is
Elliot although i love my industry i
love the work that i do i can't seem to
get past this board feeling after nine
months so one approach this from a
slightly different perspective you know
because in the past I've said things
like motivation and love gets you going
but commitment keeps it rolling right
and that would make sense if you made a
particular commitment to a mission or a
greater purpose but when you've got a
job oftentimes it's like you just
getting a paycheck right i mean how many
of you guys out there you get a job and
the first thing you're looking at is how
much you're gonna make when you get
vacation how many hours you got to work
it's all about the mechanics of the
circumstance well recently I watched the
video not recently it's an old video
that was it brought it spoke about a
study that was done by the Federal
Reserve Bank you know where all the
money comes from and they want to know
what made people motivated enough to
work more work harder or to get jobs and
they did this study and they found out
that people really weren't motivated by
more money they also offered people more
vacation time interestingly enough I saw
commercial the other day I think where
most people don't use their paid
vacation time in other words like at the
end of the year when you've got like
you've got 14 days a vacation you could
use and do whatever the fuck you want
with most people a lot of people don't
do anything they just don't go on
vacation so apparently that doesn't
motivate people you know time off
imagine might be something that is
alluring to a particular profession or
or career but I you know apparently
people they just don't give crap they
don't want more money they don't more
time off but what they do want is a
sense of purpose I want a mission people
want to feel like the work they're doing
mean something more than the mechanics
of time on time off in dollars and I
totally get it so when you sign up for
these jobs and you enjoy the type of
work you do you should always you should
also find out what the company mission
is I guarantee you that behind that door
behind that particular job that you're
going to day in and day out there is a
single man who started that corporation
or woman and started that corporation
and that person probably had a vision a
mission a worldwide vision that's what
entrepreneurs do we've got great big
ideas about how we can affect the world
and I guarantee you that that person is
infectious enough that if you get next
to them they will infect you with that
sense of mission now when you get into a
job you get into a brand new company
chances are you know you're kind of low
on the totem pole you might not be going
to the quarterly and annual meetings you
might not be rubbing elbows with the the
people at the top or the people who are
you know really pulling the strings of
the corporation but I would invite you
you know this would really be a step in
the right direction not only for your
own self esteem your own sense of
purpose but also for the mission of the
company that you're working for to ask
if you can go to the quarterly meeting
ask if you could talk to the owner right
the CEO I'd like to meet this man I want
to know what he what really drives and
motivates that man why did you start
this company and if he is a righteous
dude which hopefully he is you know I
think more and more of the the new
startup companies that were seeing in
this next generation of business and an
economy are headed by really passionate
people who have world transforming
missions and visions and
you get next to that guy you just say
look bit I just want to take you out for
for dinner you know I want to do
something nice for you and sit with them
you will probably get infected with the
passion that sparked the entire
organization that you're a part of now
if you go on this meeting and the guy is
a complete douchebag he cares about
nothing but the bottom line and you know
people using too much toilet paper well
then you know you're probably in the
wrong company you know so when you're
looking for a job even look for a place
that's headed by people and run in such
a way that mission and vision is the
biggest driver not finance you need
money sure as hell do super important
should be looked at can't have a company
without money nothing happens without a
sale but if you want to be infused with
the passion and the fire to keep going
get on that mission train brother done
Elliot's it what
[Music]