tough tough question from our buddy
Craig in fact it took me a few minutes
to sit down and figure out how to
support you in dealing negate in the
situation
Craig is 20 years old he's a college
student he lives at home his 23 year old
brother is a autistic savant apparently
he's a genius
but he's a wild mess and he creates
havoc at home verbally and mentally
abuses his parents his parents kick him
out every once in a while his older
brother and but ultimately bring him
back and this is creating a very
frustrating cycle of dysfunction that is
eating away at Craig because he feels as
if his parents his father in particular
who's ill with Parkins disease
Parkinson's disease is growing sick and
decrepit due to the stress associated
with their wild and crazy'
oldest autistic son and he goes on to
say that he feels powerless he's got an
idea about taking decisive action he
doesn't give us any idea about what that
decisive action is but you know he
sounds frustrated so that decisive
action probably is something that's real
harsh relatively speaking but he's
powerless because his dad keeps saying
to obviously this is not choice it's not
his choice he can't kick his older
brother out of the house but his dad
keeps on saying something that sounds
very Elliott Hulse esque this is a
challenge for our family that's going to
help us grow stronger it's through these
challenges that we'll become stronger
versions of ourselves and that we've got
to put up we've got a tolerate we've got
to deal with this and it will only help
us in the long run God doesn't give you
challenges that he doesn't believe you
can overcome the things of this nature
which is very poetic and I often spout
the same advice but um what Craig is
like something needs to be done
his ultimate question actually is and
this is really that this is really the
root of it this is a great question
challenges do make us stronger yes but
at what point is it time to take
decisive
action and put an end to the madness
okay so the thing is you can't make the
size fashion you'd like to make decisive
action but you don't have the power to
make decisive action it's your parents
responsibility to do what needs to be
done in this situation all you can do is
sit back now there is power also in non
action so you're you're very
forward-thinking you're wanting to
attack with decisive action in order to
deal with this situation but you're
powerless to do so one of the things
that's happening in your home is a is
called in what's that term I'm sorry
enabling that's it there's a lot of
enabling going on with your brother and
I'm sure it has a lot to do with guilt
associated with his illness and whatnot
so your parents are constantly yielding
to him and that's neither here nor there
it's not our place the judge is not my
place to judge but you do not have to
support the situation you don't have to
actively do something but non-violent
resistance speaks just as loud as
physical aggressive decisive like you
say resistance and you merely have to
look at the likes of Gandhi and Martin
Luther King to realize just how powerful
not putting up with the Enabling is
going to support you so my invitation
would be to first speak with your
parents about what you are about to do
explain that you see what's going on and
I'm sure you have before that you don't
approve of what's going on and this is
not my judgment this is your so you
don't approve of it
in other words Elliott Hulse I'm just
giving you a perspective that might
support you from where you're at you
don't approve of it you're not going to
resist it but you will not support it
and that means it could show up in the
form of when they ask you to do
something for your brother Oh your
brother needs you to pick him up from
the hotel that he's got you just
kicked out of or whatever case maybe you
just don't I'm sorry I'm not
participating now doesn't mean that you
actively kicked him out
you're just not participating in the
enablement of his activity of his
behavior of what's going on in the house
you do not support it but you're not
fighting against it and a lot of times
there's far more power in our nonviolent
resistance as we've seen throughout
history then actively decisively
attacking that which is causing us
problems it requires a bit of yielding
but it's a far more intelligent and
agile way of dealing with the situation
you will use less energy also you'll be
able to reserve your energy so that you
can do better in school besides it my
friend I hope that helps you give that a
try good luck