hey whats up guys so yesterday I decided
to open up and share a personal
experience a story with you about how I
was able to spontaneously manifest a
towel when in great need now the towel
story might seem completely random to
most people right there were several
comments down below that reflected the
idea that perhaps Elliot you're just
being superstitious and there's
absolutely no meaning to you being
completely lined mind body and desire
with the spontaneous receiving of a gift
at the right time by the right person in
the right format wait right when I
needed it right but I want you to
understand that when I answer your
questions about your mommy and daddy not
understanding your desire to do
something besides go to college when I
answer your questions about your
girlfriend breaking up with you or
cheating with your best friend on you
when I answer those questions and when
you watch those videos and when you feel
relief that perhaps there's hope in your
dire circumstances understand that I'm
doing the exact same thing I am choosing
to find significance in the complete
randomness and meaninglessness of your
life that's what I do i find
significance in order to allow myself to
bud and blossom and move forward towards
everything i want in life and i offer
you the same advice rather than looking
at circumstances and experiences as
random maybe they are random maybe there
is absolutely no meaning to anything on
earth to anything in your life to you to
the food you eat to the women you have
sex with to your parents but
significance is something that a human
being chooses to place on something else
i love words and i love that word
significance because it seems like it
comes from the root word sign to put
your authenticity or your authorship
your name on the friggin thing so when i
put my name on the experience
of the towel coming to me when I needed
it it basically means that it offers a
profound spiritual signifier of how the
universe works in fact that's how my
life has been up until this point
everything that I have everything that I
experience everything that I feel is
because of the significance that I
personally put on it you can choose to
put significance on absolutely anything
that you want the only question I ask is
how is that working out for you so for
example the Christian cross is
meaningless it's too frigging sticks
that dissect each other some people
think it means salvation that's the
significance they give it and if they
receive the feeling of salvation every
time they pray to the cross then it's
real some people say that it's
completely random and meaningless well
that's fine you can completely ignore
the symbol and offer it no significance
by not putting your signature on it I
happen to take the ancient approach that
the symbol represents the crossroads or
the axis between the spiritual dimension
and the physical dimension that just
happens to work for me it's easily be
easily placed into my philosophy and
experience for life so I use it but it's
completely meaningless so I just wanted
to offer that to you with regard to how
you choose to think about things in your
life and how you choose to receive it
when Elliot health's uses it for himself
just one more thing I wanted to share or
get off my chest before i go into
today's message the motivational
inspirational enlightening insightful
information that I've shared with you
guys through these videos over the
course of the separate last several
years comes out of my desire to support
you in becoming a stronger version
yourself with the tools that I
personally use for myself so when you
see Elliott Hulse taking a break from
YouTube when you see Elliott Hulse
wearing significant stones around his
neck when you see Elliott how
seemingly being superstitious about
random events in his life understand
that you're probably watching this
channel because I did the same thing for
you so if you ever find yourself
uncomfortable with the way Elliot frames
his life or frames or circumstances or
frames the people and relationship in
his life understand that it is this very
tool that I've used in order to support
you and many of you write this Elliot
you've been very helpful to me over the
past several years there are several
videos that you've made that save my
life even but now Elliot I'm very
confused and upset with you because it
seems that you're doing things that
don't well that simply just don't jive
with your ignorance that's really what
it is it's okay to receive a gift but
when the individual uses as a gift to
support himself it doesn't feel so good
does it and that's what happens to a lot
of people watching my video so if I
sound frustrated because not angry I'm
not upset but I'm I'm struggling to
educate you on how our relationship was
built and what my transparent
communication with you through these
videos over the past several weeks and
moving forward will look like it will
look like Elliott Hulse on his journey
using his own advice in order to grow
himself stronger because without a
strong Elliott Hulse there is no room or
opportunity for me to fulfill my
obligation or my mission in life to
empower others now if you're ready for
some more Elliott Hulse hippie shit
listen closely last night there was a
full moon in the minds of several people
including myself a full moon could
represent the reflection of various
parts or aspects of our character and
during a full moon oftentimes we get
reflected back shadow issues or parts of
ourselves that we would rather patch up
clean up we oftentimes get exposed parts
of ourselves that we didn't realize
we're brilli
int the moon reflects the Sun showing
its radiance to all who become a part of
its presence whereas in its presence so
a full moon is a good time to reflect
and in doing so I honor our relationship
my relationship with those of you who
watch my videos and I want to do it by
extending an invitation for you to help
me better understand you now horse you
watch these videos and you have somewhat
of an idea of an aspect of what Elliott
Hulse is and so our relationship
continues but in the same way I'd like
to get to know a little bit more about
you so that perhaps I could serve you
better perhaps our conversations could
be more appropriate to where you are and
of course we can strengthen whichever
bonds we currently have so I need your
help in order to support our
relationship please click the link down
below there's a link and it takes you to
a survey right there are no tricks there
no gimmicks are not going to be up sold
or sell anything it's simply a survey
for me to get a better idea of where you
are on your journey of growing stronger
now if it isn't enough that the survey
would support our relationships and
hopefully you value our relationship I
sure do I'm also offering a gift those
of you who fill out the survey down
below will be entered into a draft a
drawing where we will choose I think
three to five depending on how many we
get three to five people who will be the
winners of a new strength camp camo tank
top that we've come out with its the
desert camouflage Jersey so that's my
little rant that's me getting something
off my chest today and that's me opening
an invitation for you and I to have a
deeper more meaningful and significant
relationship Donna