the word depression is an interesting
one because it's very descriptive of
what happens to the biological processes
to the physiology of a person who's
depressed basically what happens is the
mind that the head brain becomes so
overly active with a particular thought
usually a thought that's Unruh source
for or a set of thinking or way of
thinking that's Unruh source code that
it depresses the biological processes in
the body it literally shuts down the
body so when someone becomes depressed
their energy retreats in so that's why
they start feeling or you and I when we
become depressed start feeling like weak
we feel limp our breathing shuts down
becomes very shallow we've become very
sensitive to light because we are our
skin in our eyes start to constrict and
everything loud sounds become very
irritating to us because everything is
depressing and moving inward the exact
opposite of depression is expression
right the way most of us try to get out
of depression is by talking and thinking
more about ways to get out of our slump
out of our depression but that's
attacking the problem from the same
level at which it was created
in the head and since we know that the
opposite of depression is expression
we've got to recognize that expression
happens in the body we don't express
with our brains we don't express through
thinking we express with our bodies
we've had a tendency to neglect the
power and the
the intelligence that resides within our
bodies we forget that we can use our
bodies to affect our minds the mind has
become overactive it's not your friend
anymore it's depressed your body but we
can take our body back and express it
and allow it to help the brain recover
from its neurotic pattern of thinking
that's depressing the body now I'm not a
psychologist I read a lot I think a lot
mice actually consult with some
psychologists on a regular basis I have
a great interest in it so I'm going to
share an idea that might be resourceful
for you the next time you find yourself
in depression the next time you have a
friend or someone that you know is
depressed
what I'm going to ask you to try is the
exact opposite of your depression which
is expression I'm going to share with
you a meditation it's called dynamic
meditation it was created by a brilliant
man that no longer lives with us they
used to call Rajneesh osho or Osho
Rajneesh and I'll provide some resources
down below for you to look at dynamic
meditation but what I'm going to share
with you is a condensed form modified
form of Osho Rajneesh dynamic meditation
there are five stages I'm going to
describe them now and then I'll show
them to you in a moment
they're all about expression the very
first phase is going to be charging the
body you've heard me talk about this
with my bioenergetic ideas and exercises
this is an entire vital energetic
meditation charging the body with
chaotic breathing the way we're going to
do that is by Bri pushing out the
out-breath right you'll see me do it a
moment but you're going to do it in a
chaotic fashion the brain likes to lock
on to patterns of behavior or activity
so you've got to move your body in many
different ways
completely erratically spontaneously
while you're doing the first part of
this you're charging the breath
see me do it the second part is
catharsis this is really the essence of
your expression this is where you
totally let go and express whatever
comes up laughing crying stopping
throwing a temper tantrum
yelling beating your chest whatever you
your body is is bringing up go with it
during the second phase which is called
catharsis the third stage is called
grounding this is very important because
when we're way up in our heads we're
kind of airy right we've lost our roots
we've lost our ground we're going to
show you next or for the third phase is
a grounding exercise in fact you've done
it before if you've used my bioenergetic
daily warmup this is where we raise our
hands in the air
hook hook hook and we land flat-footed
on the ground we let our body shake and
vibrate while allowing a hoop sound to
resonate within our bodies and come out
of our mouths the fourth stage is
tranquility just drop to the floor or
stand where you are do not move a muscle
just lay tranquil like someone shot with
a tranquilizer gun lay tranquil and then
the fifth stage is to put on some nice
music or listen to some music in your
head peaceful calming music and just
dance just flow with it really rejoicing
fake it until it you make it is one of
the phrases people would say but you
want to pretend that you're rejoicing
I guarantee you'll feel like rejoicing
after going through this meditation each
phase is going to last you start with
two minutes two minutes is probably
going to burn you out it's going to be
very difficult but what I like it to see
you do is build up to ten minutes of
this Metta each phase for this
meditation so the whole thing will take
an hour you might might take it several
weeks to build up to that but start with
two minutes one minute if you really
make it through two minutes I'm going to
go through each of the five stages for
you right now so you can see what it
looks like and then I'm going to invite
you to try it okay hopefully you can see
me very first stage is chaotic breathing
looks like this
first name second stage third stage
crowning oh four stage right Lily
this stage peaceful music
so as you can see just in my small
demonstration here how expressive and
that meditation is you're not sitting
and thinking you're expressing you're
doing the exact opposite of where you
are and you're depressing do this give
yourself permission to do this try it
once I promise you something will happen
something will change in you but you got
to build up the courage to do this you
can't find a place to do it words you're
in a safe environment where it's quiet
where you can really let loose do it
without the sounds close your door do
everything I showed you without the
noise but if you can find a place where
you can let loose and express you'll
find that little by little your
depression it's going to let way for
your expression to take hold good luck
and I love you see you next time
Eliot sit