so our buddy tom is getting hired or has
been hired for his first full-time job
starts in a few days now he's really
concerned because tom has no skills he
really is at the bottom of the barrel
when you know can with regard to
seniority and his new company and he's
little freaked out because he believes
it in this economy he can be laid off at
any moment so he's wondering if he
should rest all of his energy on
pursuing and developing this career path
knowing that he's so vulnerable
especially since he doesn't have any
real skills according to him so what
should he do well here's a situation
dude regardless of the title you're
given regardless of the degrees that you
have your greatest asset is your ability
to find out what your company needs what
your company values and how you can best
support their managers and the president
and owner of that business in achieving
their goals your number one objective
even beyond the work description that
you've been given is to do everything in
your power to support the owner of that
company in fulfilling his goals because
when you've given yourself in that
particular way now I don't know what
kind of business this is or what
industry it is so you know of course
it's different from industry to industry
and business to business but when you've
given yourself over in that way to a
business that you work for a company
that you work for you then very quickly
become indispensable you're the other
type of person that they won't get rid
of when it's time to slash people
because of budget cuts you know whatever
whatever the situation is where they got
to start getting rid of people it does
not matter how long you've been there it
doesn't matter what your title is if you
are seen as a valuable asset someone who
is contributing to the bottom not align
not just there for a job see a lot of
people are looking to get a job give me
a job they say if you go about with the
attitude of how can I serve you you will
be somebody who
this of hot who is of high perceived
value the question you've got to ask
yourself and the one that you've got
opposed to you know the owner or the
managers of your company is how can I
best serve you and the purposes of this
organization it is an attitude more than
it is a skill set good luck