so got a question from our buddy we'll
call him Dave here he's 24 years old not
too long ago we broke up with a girl to
use living with and then he set out on a
journey to find the perfect woman and in
doing so he decided to write a
description of what he would like to see
what he would like to have keeping hold
in his new woman he goes on to describe
it here as an attractive woman mature
and well-educated lady with good values
someone who wouldn't cheat on me a lady
that like to cook and work hard a lady
that didn't like to party and has moved
on from her teenage years and has turned
to a mature adult someone who like me
lives a healthy lifestyle a lady who has
an attractive body big breasts a bit
shorter than me long black hair very
specific he knows what he wants and he
set out to go find that in what do you
know he found someone that came really
damn close so I think it was at a gym he
met a woman was in very good physical
shape started daily in fact couldn't
date her right away because she wasn't
interested in him and he pursued for
multiple months about three months until
eventually she caved in and said yes you
know what I'll give you a chance and it
was a match made in heaven they did
really well together until a few months
into it and I'm not exactly sure how
long he started to find flaws in her the
very first flaw is one that uh that he
describes as poor nutritional habits so
she would eat foods and drink a lot of
sugary beverages and just didn't really
take care of her nutrition the way he
would have liked her to and as a result
she he noticed that like her her breath
began to stink he was like you know
she's toxic
and um and a vagina stinks that's what
he says he says you know it wasn't the
case in the beginning but as her her
dietary habits got worse she began to
stink and it was like look I just can't
fucking handle this and uh and although
she was the match made in heaven some of
the choices she made pushed him away and
he broke up with her and now he is uh he
gets text messages and phone calls from
her she's like you know please take me
back like whatever I have to do and he's
like he now he's
conflict you know my heart I gave my
heart to this woman but we're little
idiosyncrasies and nastiness in other
words Julia drove me away from her and
you know I I didn't find her sexually
attractive anymore anymore and now I
want to pursue other women but my heart
is still tethered to this lady okay
let's get past the nastiness part first
because yes you know what a an unhealthy
individual is an attractive unattractive
individual and if she tends to be
naturally attractive but she's making
choices that make her stinky then I
could see why you would you be turned
off right these are choices that she's
making so what I'd like to do with this
video is not necessarily approach it
from the perspective of your specific
concern because those are habits that
she could possibly change the thing is
that now although she could possibly
change that and not smell so bad anymore
and you do have an opportunity to take
her back and try over again and you know
obviously it's twofold you know for her
own good it would be better if she
didn't eat nasty food and have a stinky
vagina and also for you because it's
like boy now I can enjoy being around
you once again because I really do love
you my heart is still tethered to you
instead of being approaching this from
that specific situation what I want to
do is I want to broaden it just a bit
and talk about loving someone and all of
their weirdnesses all the nastiness
quote-unquote all the things that don't
necessarily fit into the box of what
society has taught us is acceptable and
that we adopt as our own parameter by
which we will deal with another
individual it's one of these strange
things where again and he makes allusion
to this and his question where he's like
my heart is drawn in particular to this
particular woman why a head is like nah
fuck that how do you deal with that that
conflict it doesn't matter if it's like
I said if it's something that it's a
choice that a person is making that
perhaps they could change or it's you
know she's got like one eye bigger than
the other or or one breasts bigger than
the other or
got like a weird mole on her face or you
know the the little imperfections that
make humans human will start to irritate
you if you're if you don't adopt the
perspective that I'm going to share with
you in a moment someone who you have
easily fall in love with who have fallen
in love with you could just as easily be
grossed out by because of the weirdest
littlest things like if you've ever
watched Seinfeld that he's so like what
like to watch Seinfeld on television
it's a sitcom comedy and Seinfeld could
never find the right woman and he it
would always be the weirdest things two
of the weirdest things that I think that
he broke up with women for in this show
was one was man hands I don't remember
this episode but this woman was
beautiful in every single way except her
hands were like literally like big thick
muscley man hands and every time he saw
her hands like it was funny like she
would wipe something off his face and
he'd be like grossed out because her her
nasty man hand was touching him or she's
like open a beer bottle with her hand I
mean like grossed out and another one
that I can remember specifically was uh
was a woman who well there's so many so
many of them but this was a an additive
behavior that the woman adopted where
she would eat peas one by one so he
loves this fucking woman everything's
doing great but then he notices she eats
peas one by one and he's like grossed
out he's like ah that's it I can't do it
and this is I mean there are multiple
different examples of this throughout
throughout the show anyway so what
happens when you love someone and
they're weirdnesses begin to argue what
I found is that the more we come to love
ourselves what I'm asking you to do now
assume is to come inside come back to
yourself it's usually my invitation in
all these videos come back to yourself
explore yourself look at look at how you
feel about yourself and your
idiosyncrasies or weirdnesses right
there are things about you that you may
not necessarily like and don't fit up
fit fit the mold that you feel you
should be falling into we all have this
and I'm not doing this to point fingers
at you because I have this I've had so
many insecurities especially as a kid
where I would spend
hours literally looking in the mirror
wondering do I fit up Who am I what am i
I remember this I thought about it
recently like I would spend a lot of
time looking in the mirror when I was a
kid and it wasn't because I was
self-centered and loved what I saw it
was because of this ambiguity that that
arose from the question that I was
constantly posed Elliott what are you
and I was never satisfied with the way I
looked I never fit in I never measured
up to the expectations that I even had
for myself and none of us do very rarely
will you find an individual and if you
do it's always tainted with a sort of
like psychopathy they're a little weird
if they love every single big piece of
themselves as is so what I'm asking you
to do is is to do an assessment on
yourself of those things that you don't
love about yourself but then come to
peace with them come to peace with
yourself in the areas through by which
you don't measure up and I found just in
my own experience and in my own self
discovery that the more I accept myself
the way the ways I look the way I carry
myself the things I think though you
know I never measured up in in cognitive
ability I was I was labeled as
attention-deficit learning disability
there are ways that I think which are
very different than that which the
school would would deem praiseworthy
you know I don't get very good grades so
very easily I get you could become to
hate yourself I'm just not good enough
I'm not smart enough I don't look good
enough I'm not right but through my own
self exploration the more that I've come
in touch with those things that the
world has told me is not right and I've
looked at with a objective eye with an
objective eye and come to appreciate in
myself and realize that these are
actually my gifts they're actually the
things that make me unique they're
actually the things that allow me to be
Elliott Hulse and you to be Dave and
each one of us to be our unique selves
and that is magnificent in and of itself
the fact that you have but your
you are a individual weighted portion of
God the universe Allah you know that I
use these words interchangeably but that
which we don't understand but from which
we come the more you become to realize
just how magnificent that is and from
that place I've begun to look at other
people who perhaps in the past I would
have been disgusted by distrustful of or
just turned off and actually come to
appreciate love respect and uphold the
weirdnesses that they have in fact you
know I think about it I want to I don't
want to call anybody out specifically
but I think about many of the piece of
people closest to me the people that I
love the most in my life and it's just
the very things that they're insecure
about that I love deeply I love these
things about these people the very
things that they look at themselves or
question themselves about and wonder why
they're so inferior in this particular
way I embrace I kiss I love i caress not
just respect but adore these things in
the individuals that I love and it's not
because I should right you should love
everyone regardless you should not be
prejudiced towards individuals you
should not these showers and shalt nots
it's not about that at all and it's not
about guilt it's not about uh you know
feelings of guilt about why you should
again it's all these sugars it's because
I love myself I love my weirdnesses and
through that I've come to love the
weirdnesses I use that term lightly
weirdnesses they the uniqueness of
individuals in my life so look my friend
of course this chick is making some bad
choices and you know what you might even
want to help her explore the roots of
her consciousness why why do you make
such poor choices about your health
help her explore that it's easier to
help someone explore that about
themselves when you take
the time to explore why you make the
choices you make
I'm always exploring the choices why I
make the choices I make we go about life
almost on an automatic autopilot but
every once in a while you got to step
back and I look at ourselves and say why
the hell do I do that why do I feel that
way why do I keep making these choices
and when you can do that with yourself
and you can be objective with yourself
and you could be honest and loving with
yourself in that regard it's that much
easier to help other people go on that
journey with themselves it's part of
reason why I make these videos it's like
I give you permission
I invite you look at the weirdnesses
that you have and embrace them and then
question why is it that I make the
choices that I make it this is the whole
point of this channel so I'm not saying
you need to go back to her I'm not
saying that you need to love her because
she's got stinky pussy I'm saying that
an evolved version of yourself a
stronger version of yourself will come
to appreciate who you are as you grow
stronger and will support other people
in their journey to becoming the
strongest version of themselves and
because of the love for yourself and
your expanding love for all human beings
you will not only embrace them but you
will adore them in all their nastiness
done