hey what's up guys been away for a few
days haven't made a video on this
channel and I'm back and I'm excited to
be back I'm happy to to be looking at
these questions and supporting you guys
the best I can I begin today question
from a 14-year old friend in fact he's
14 but he's 6 foot 3 and he's got a
voice deeper than most grown men so he
tells us but anyway he's really
passionate about music he's really
passionate about film and he also
happens to be a very talented student
he's in advanced classes he says that he
was reading at a college level back when
he was in 2nd grade and he does what he
has to do to get by in that regard but
at the same time he doesn't love school
he doesn't love the fact that he has to
subject himself to daily rigor in a
direction that he could care less for
what he really wants to do is play his
music and when he's away from playing
his music he becomes depressed so he
goes to school he doesn't want to become
an engineer he's very clear about that
he doesn't to be a physicist basically
anything that the school system invites
us to aspire to he's like fuck that I
have no interest in that I want to play
my music and the fact that I have to
take time away from that thing that I
love that music letting the spirit move
through me through my mouth through my
fingers through my hands in order to
produce beautiful music I've got to go
and sit in a fucking classroom study
memorize shit even though I'm good at it
fucking it's making me sick so here's
the thing you're 14 years old you're
still fairly young and not even high
school yet so I'm happy to be able to
give you this piece of advice because
you're gonna have to carry it with you
for quite a while
you got you got quite a ways left ahead
of you one of the things you're gonna
have to understand is that no matter
what road you take in life there are
always going to be things you have to do
that you just don't want to fuckin do
right and mind you is always a choice
but in order to live the way that you
see fit for yourself there are always
going to be things that you have to do
that you don't want to fuckin do so you
could drop out of school you totally
could but that's a whole nother set of
problems with your with your parents
perhaps and
you know you'd have to resolve that and
that becomes something you have to do
that you don't want to do also if you
decide to become a musician I promise
you they're going to be things that you
have to do that you don't want to
fucking do you're gonna have to really
if you become a musician you're gonna
have to build a business infrastructure
you're gonna have to do weird shit like
accounting and in promotions and
marketing and sales and you're going to
need a management team there's a whole
lot of shit there that you don't want to
do but if you want to be a musician you
want to do the thing that you love
you're going to have to do right you
want a family everybody wants not
everybody but you know if you want a
family you know especially when you're
young dad I get so many young dads
sending emails and they've got their
their newborn baby right all this
build-up to this new experience with a
baby guess what it's so cute you snuggle
it you smell it then you think about all
the things that this child is going to
become all the dreams and aspirations
you have for it and if you're like me
you read all these books and you've got
all these grand ideas and plans about
how it's gonna be and then guess what
you're changing nasty fucking diapers
six times a day
you smell like vomit all the time you
can't sleep they're fucking annoying
it's 50% love 50% Archer 50% work it's
always going to be that way I don't care
how much you invest in your particular
line of love your line of work
so 14 years old look it hours a day is
quite a fucking bit plus they give you
homework and you've got to study and you
got to pass tests you do it but don't
personally invest in it you do it
because you know that this is a part of
this is 50% of the big picture right so
a part of the big picture is I want to
fulfill my parents expectations for me
right and I'm the first one to tell you
don't live your life based on other
people's expectations but then again
you've got issues when you do that also
because now you've got it
to fight that you're gonna be a fighter
right and sometimes fighting is it's
totally not worth it it depends on the
situation I fight for a lot of fucking
shit and when I later on I realize boy I
could have just chill the fuck out and
got the same result so go to school but
don't be personally identified with the
result do it because you're supposed to
do it and it only lasts a little while
trust me I'm 34 years old right now and
school seems like that was totally a
different life like a different person I
have absolutely I have no memory of it
it's so god it's so back there right I
live my life on my terms
I'm building a family right now you
think I want to go home to for whining
fucking children some days some things I
walk through the door it's like I love
my kids but it's going to suck for the
next three hours while they're fighting
and whining with each other and they
want things that I don't have to give
them and then I got to give them baths
and shit but you don't become personally
identified with it with the down part
you remember the good part or you or you
really invest your heart and soul into
the good part when I'm sitting there
reading stories to them or I'm kissing
them and snuggling a move for bed that's
the beautiful part when you go and play
your music you'll be able to appreciate
those times much better the insistence
through which you can produce your music
are going to be given that much more
value because of the time you spend
doing the shit you don't want to do so
that's it I guess that was kind of a
long way to say you're always gonna have
to do shit that you don't want to do
don't let it distract you or or depress
you in such a way that you can't fulfill
the love obligation that you have within
you do it gracefully do it happily don't
personally identify with it
let's just see it for what it is it's
the night time that allows you to
appreciate the day it's the winter time
that allows you to enjoy the summer it
is the other side of the coin and it
will always be there what that helps