so one of the things that I'm probably
known least for is having short concise
answers you probably followed my channel
simply because you enjoy my long poetic
rants on simple questions well some of
your questions are really just one word
questions so I've decided to make this
video where I answer all of your
one-word questions as quickly as
possible the biggest challenge for me is
to refrain from ranting so here we go
Elliot how tall are you 5 9 Elliot how
much is your body fat percentage think
it's about 12 to 13 percent I don't know
you tell me
Elliot are your eyes different colours
yep Elliot what did you study in college
I studied Healthcare Administration in
undergrad and then I went to grad school
and studied exercise science yo Elliot
do you smoke weed vapor isn't
technically smoke Elliot what are your
maxes I don't really keep track of my
Max's but the heaviest sigh dead lifted
was around 700 a little over 700
heaviest benchpress was around 455 heavy
is squat I want to say six change Elliot
how old are you 33 Elliot what is your
current workout like right now my
current workout is like really focused
on movement and the nervous system so I
everyday I do most days I do yoga in the
morning and then when I come here and
train it's just it's functional
movements and heavy lifting
yo Elliot why your teeth so nice I was
born that way except for those amalgam
fillings back there maybe that's why I'm
so retarded
yo Eliot what's that tattoo you mean
that one well if you look closely it
used to be a Christian cross it's
actually a cover-up tattoo and the
reason why I covered it up is because I
no longer wanted to identify with any
religion so I got the cross when I was
in high school I guess and then I
covered it up with this which is
symbolic of the Native American Sundance
that my younger brother participates in
yo Elliott where can I get Elliott swag
if you mean swag by clothing t-shirts
and stuff wristbands wristbands you
can't get but if you're watching this
before April 2013 I'm going to be giving
away five hundred these on my birthday
which is uh April tenth there abouts
t-shirts you could always find there's a
link on the right side of my youtube
homepage and links in my description so
check it out there yo Elliott are you
aware we're what yo Elliott what are
your next fitness goals right now is to
continue to reduce body fat reduce body
weight but also to maintain as much
strength as I can while doing so
yo Elliott also do you drink often and
no probably less than once a week now
maybe twice a month
yo Elliott what do you love most about
your job I really like the fact that I
can talk about the things that I enjoy
most which are strengths and philosophy
and earn a living doing so so my
interactions with you guys helped me
earn money doing what I love most
what is the entrance music to the ask
Elliott vids that is a custom beat that
was created for me by a guy named Nick
balls that's not his real name but if
you google and I see be alz you will
find his youtube channel and his
soundcloud he makes really awesome beats
he made that one for me a couple of
years ago that's where it came from
you know Elliott what is your religion
and why I don't have a religion
I like religion I just don't identify
with any of them
yo Elliott what motivates you I'm not
sure it motivates me but I'm inspired to
do the
things that I do when I hear the results
and the success stories that you guys
send me Elliot do you take a pre-workout
no I drink black coffee though
yo Elliot what's the size of your BBC no
homo you mean big black cock I don't
have one it's brown yo Elliot would you
take me into your home and teach me the
ways of life if I move down to Florida
please ah you don't want to live in my
own I've got four children under the age
of eight and they will drive you nuts
yo Elliot how much do you eat on a
regular basis I'm finding that I don't
need to eat very much at all because
while I'm doing intermittent fasting and
paleo style diets my calories are fairly
low but my strength stays pretty hot yo
Elliot what do you find most annoying in
life the smell of exhaust driving behind
a car it has lots of fucking exhaust
that blows into my face ah
Elliot sit
you