got this question from Austin he's doing
with a lot of anxiety fear of failing he
says that even though he's a physically
strong and capable person
he's just fearful that he's not strong
enough
this is wreaking havoc and hit the
relationships that he has you know with
women and in his life he's just he's
afraid to do anything because he's
afraid of failure and and it's probably
self-perpetuating so what I'm going to
offer you that here is an idea right
because that's all this is this is all
Elliott can offer you is just ideas or
perspectives ways of looking at your
situation that you may not have looked
at before that might be resourceful for
you
so the whole idea of failure was one
that I had to wrap my mind around when
my life was pretty unstable you know
starting a business starting a family
all the things that uh that can make
someone fearful you know for you it
might be situations in school or with
women or the case may be you've got to
embrace failure because failure is the
soil that brings forth the plants of
success in other words with every
failure is the seed for success you
cannot succeed without failure in the
same way that a tree cannot grow if you
don't bury the seed in the soil right so
be okay with it say yes I'm gonna fail
yes this is not going to work out yes
this is going to be a complete failure
you know I deal with this all the time I
put these videos sometimes and I'm like
oh that video sucked it's a failure
people aren't gonna like it right but I
do it anyway because I'm gonna make
another one when I make another one I'm
gonna make another one I'm gonna make
another one and one of them is bound to
be good so make more mistakes make more
failures keep going the idea is to just
shut your brain off because that's what
the thing the thing is you're neurotic
you're thinking too much shut your brain
off and just do it anyway screw it up
big time I tell this to people all the
time if you're going up to a girl that
you like to speak to and you've never
done this before
be prepared to fuck the whole thing up
be prepared to do it completely wrong
but be prepared to do it
because you're gonna learn something
from that failure you're gonna go and
talk to her and she
gonna say just get away from me you
loser right and you're gonna say ah next
time I should probably pick my eyes up
when I talk to her right you'll pick up
a tip then you do it again you'll pick
up another tip pick up another tip the
idea is that failure is your tool
failure is is the evolution towards
being a stronger version of yourself
you've got to fail embrace failure love
failure fail as many times as you
possibly can so that you can get one
step closer to having the thing happen
fail II was so afraid of failure we've
been taught to be so afraid of failure
that nothing ever gets done we get
paralysis by analysis we just kind of
were we have no ability to move forward
we're just stuck because we don't want
to fail right and this is a bad idea
there's nothing gets done if you don't
fail so that's it my friend I truly feel
for you I know you this is a deep
repressed situation you're dealing with
you said severe anxiety I know that it's
not as easy as an idea but what you got
to do is you've got to put yourself out
on that limb that you're so scared of
because 9 times out of 10 that limb that
we're scared of is not nearly as scary
as we thought it was we get out there
and we're like oh well this shit might
crack and I might fall but the ground is
only 4 feet away no big deal but when
we're up down looking at it we're like
oh my god it's so scary I can't do it
put yourself out on the limb do the
thing you're afraid of and the fear of
it will go away do the thing you fear
most and the death of fear is certain
Emerson you've got to go do it so all
the things you're afraid of run
full-speed Adam embrace hug and kiss him
deal with it and then move on you'll
grow stronger with each failure buddy
good luck Eliot sick what
[Music]