so our buddy max calls himself in eighth
so he says he's not so good-looking and
he's not so popular but there's a girl
in his high school who's really
good-looking a ten and really popular
hangs out with all the cool kids and
even he rolls his eyes when he uses that
term because it denotes or points to
this idea of hierarchy or caste system
that we put ourselves into or we tend to
fall into that begins at about the about
high school but he's ready to break out
of his level in the caste system and
make a stab at a woman who's in the
higher echelon what does he do how does
he go about that why is it there are
some kids that are popular and it's easy
for them to be with one another right he
talked to all the good-looking popular
kids right and good-looking isn't always
synonymous with popular but all the kids
in the cool category seem to get along
real well and the guys that are that are
cool talk to her and he's kind of not so
recognizable how does it go about
breaking the chains of bondage in his
caste system and move into the category
that would allow him to pursue this type
of woman this whole idea of caste system
is interesting and I tend to think that
it comes less from our abilities as
human beings or even our our god-given
gifts like strength or or the way we
look and more of the either conscious or
unconscious holding on to and developing
a concept that was produced by a guy
named Carl Jung of archetypical
individuals okay so a lot of the ideas
I'm going to share with you right now
come from a book that I shared with you
a few weeks ago called King warrior
magician lover where basically for a
fully developed man to proceed in the
world he's got to recognize where his
predominant strength is within each one
of those archetypes and archetypes are
idealized version of of individuals so
for example in in Greek Greek mythology
you've got the idealized King found in
like Apollo right you've got the
idealized warrior found
in Aries or an Achilles you've got the
idealized lover in a Dionysus and the
idealized magician in perhaps Poseidon
or somebody who can rule over nature
each one of those archetypes has a
particular set of character traits
strengths and virtues that allows the
individual who embodies it to be highly
praised and looked upon and oftentimes
those in our culture who we deem as
celebrities and cool people are
idealized versions of these archetypical
ideas they follow so there are two
pieces to being able to to really
develop yourself and then promote
yourself into recognition so that you
can bone checks that are tens and in the
high society right so this is of course
this is all just mental masturbation
it's games but they're ideas that will
support you so what I want to put this
what I want to share with you so the
very first thing that I would invite you
to do the most practical piece of
information is to know thyself right I
think Shakespeare said know thyself and
that's cannot be false with any man it's
basically the most important thing is to
come to know yourself the second piece
of this puzzle is to promote yourself
we'll talk about each individually to
know thyself is to recognize where your
strengths within the concept of
masculine archetypes lie mankind loves a
king and the king is though are those
individuals who whether good for good or
evil
have a capacity to command attention
just with their presence they seem to be
those that attract followers so a lot of
your a lot of your popular kids they
could be cool they could be good or bad
it really doesn't matter but the fact is
that wherever they go their ability to
attract followers people who are of
different archetypal strengths but are
yielding to the archetype of King in
this individual
makes him pleasing to others right he
might be a complete dickhead
but he's pleasing because he represents
the archetypical king then you also have
your archetypical warrior usually in
high school this is going to be your
athlete like your your wrestler that
that's won the state championships or
the quarterback of the football team
someone who's used physical strength and
vigor to get their way in the world you
know so you're going to find that those
are those are kids that are gifted in
and develop their warrior archetype
you've got the magician types who I
remember when I was in high school they
were the kids that would soup up their
cars right they've got the strange
technical ability to do something right
so it might be some of those kids who
now perhaps are like really good with
developing websites or doing something
with computers or it might still be I
think there are still lots of kids that
uh that once they get their cars they
would super mop I remember in college
there was this group of Chinese kids
that would buy a little Honda's and they
would like they put new engines in it
they would put all types of gadgets and
lights and they'd turn these things into
a magnificent little machines and it
began it came from the magician within
there was a magical ship to be able to
do some of the things that I've seen
these kids do with their cars
so is that present in you recognize them
as I move down this line is that present
in you do you have a tendency towards
could you develop the magician in you
and the lover and lover the lover is
kind of like the poet also the singer
the musician the artist is there some
ability in you to produce a subjective
piece of art a piece of your heart if
you will and produce it for the world
you know it's in our world generally
speaking the lover is not so much
respected as the others if you look at
the teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles you
also get the four you get Leonardo who's
the king you've got Raphael who is the
warrior
you've got Donatello who is the magician
just look at their characters you know
I'm
I kicked my son is into teenage Mutant
Ninja Turtles then he got Michelangelo
right he's the lover he's the one who
eats pizza and always drops stuff and
like makes a mess and maybe but
everybody loves him but that person is
always the life of the party there's
someone who's enjoyable to be around
because of that capacity so when I say
know thyself what I invite you to do is
explore yourself in each one of those
realms and find out which one do you
have a tendency towards and which ones
might you need to develop just a little
bit more the reason being once again is
that mankind humankind women tend to
love archetypes tend to love people who
embody a ideal when it comes to
character and you'll find that each one
of those individuals are highly
respected or appreciated by other men
and by women know thyself and develop
thyself become the strongest version of
yourself that's the first step and I
just use this one idea of the the
archetypes to give you some perspective
as to how you might do that
systematically study this idea of
archetypes particularly the four male
archetypes do some research by the book
by Robert Moore I believe his aim is
very fascinating perspective on
developing your your character and then
finally the second half of this whole
thing is that you've got to have the
courage to promote yourself don't
promote yourself if you have nothing to
offer meaning that you don't embody and
in one of those magnificent archetypes
right and this might come off as harsh
it's one of the harsh things my dad used
to say a lot of times you know I spit
out language to you guys it sounds like
man alias just being a rough dickhead I
have I probably have the most compassion
for you then than any other blogger or
youtuber because I move through these
challenges myself and then I share with
you what I've learned so when I'm harsh
it's not because I'm trying to be a dick
or I don't love you because sometimes
some shit is just harsh and one of the
harsh things my dad used to say that
really meant something to me I was upset
when he said it when I was a kid but I
understand it now as I've moved through
life and face certain challenges is
don't be useless
my daddy used to say that I don't care
what you do just don't be useless and
useless would mean what are you
producing which one of those four male
archetypes are you embodying or are you
just blah are you just I don't know I
don't do anything I don't like anything
I have no hobbies I have no interests I
have no talents faculties or skills well
then guess what you're fucking useless
and it's a waste of oxygen and a waste
of food it's a waste of fucking human
flesh if you if you're useless make
something of yourself
I've given you a framework that might
support you delve into it it's a
powerful idea that I've made a part of
my own I've remixed it into my own
that's why I share it here with you so
that you can remix it into your own but
as that's developed you also need to
have the courage to make known your
powers make known your ability to embody
that archetype and serve others when I
say serve others I don't mean in a soup
kitchen
I mean serve others in that let them
recognize how you contribute to the
clique to the club to the environment
with your abilities as a king warrior
magician or lover what makes you unique
back to trying to date this woman when
she sees that this man is up to
something
he has value to him he's very a very
powerful leader right
he's an incredible athlete he's got this
incredible technical skill and or he's
just fun to be around he makes everybody
happy Michelangelo then she's going to
be attracted to you don't develop your
skills in private don't develop your
skills and and I think there's in the
Bible I think st. Paul once says nobody
likes a candle and puts it under the
table you light a candle so that you can
illuminate
the room light your candle develop
yourself and make known your powers make
known your powers don't be afraid to
promote yourself see I make these videos
a lot of people get upset with me
because we're like Oh Ellen so damn
arrogant and he makes these videos and
he thinks he's so fucking cool well yeah
a little bit but a part of it also is
that I make known my ability and I've
got some strange abilities here that I
that I developed and blend together so I
can serve other people and it makes me
attractive own it that way be confident
in that way and then from that place of
strength you can approach anyone and
they will come to appreciate respects
and even love you done