no I was just telling Austin awesome
wants to train this is why exercise is
like medicine because depending on what
you want to have happen in what your
current condition is you've got to
choose the right type of exercises and a
guy like this whose life is invested in
what's your high school stuff he spent a
lot of time playing your instrument he
doesn't want to take a medicine that's
going to ruin his ability to continue
playing his instrument huh right yeah
right because we just spend a lot of
time doing chin-ups and button and uh
tire flips they're all muscles that are
going to learn in balance
he's already imbalanced because of doing
this don't get me wrong but I know
you're somewhere like this he's already
in balance right meaning that his
shoulders and his bicep are really tight
in the flexion position so if he goes to
the gym let's say it's a personal
trainer because he was get in shape his
personal trainer has him doing incline
bench presses and curls he's further
facilitating the imbalance that's been
created by his particular sport I'm
gonna call it a sport because you're
using your body to create something so
Austin says he wants exercise you went
to the gym a couple of times but um but
he also experienced some sort of
tendinitis right you're getting it in
your throughout here in your hands bicep
and if he's doing exercises that crude
that literally create that particular
type of pain then he's going to end up
hurting himself and saying excess weight
lifting lifting wings is a bad idea it's
stupid
well that's because he took the better
oral medicine so what I'm going to do is
we're going to get him to do what he
needs to be doing for his activity the
right type of medicine for what he needs
so we already assessed the fact that
he's that tight PEC minor he's got tight
tight biceps they need to be stretched
also both of the both of those muscles
contribute to medial rotation of the
upper arm which is coupled with thoracic
kyphosis so really our body needs to go
from here I'm exaggerating but you're
definitely a balance in this particular
way to here and this is why I like
extension movement extension stretches
especially coupled with breathing like
the bow have you ever seen videos were
bow-bow and which is a lot easier and
more direct to the point but also you
lose some benefit but that's not the
point of this video
laying over the bioenergetic stool so
we're just going to get our buddy into a
really easy stretch to open up his
thoracic right because if we just focus
again here's the thing the body's your
unit if we just focus on this and this
it right down here right we just focus
on his arms here that's good
that's going to benefit him greatly
because it will reduce any type of pain
especially even here he needs to stretch
all this if we stretch this that's okay
but we need to also couple it with
stretching the thoracic stretching a
spine so that the core from which all
movement emanates supports what we want
to have happen there does all that make
sense yeah am I just talking in circles
so what we're going to do is I'm going
to let you do a really a really gentle
stretch first so let's move this this
way back about the way I'm going to show
it to you first just get down here get
this right below your shoulder blades I
didn't want you to just reach your hands
behind you and lay you can spread your
fingers let your hands be very heavy
reach over your head and just stay here
when you're here now right what I want
you to do is going to sound strange but
I want you to open your mouth real wide
and just breathe
that might be enough of the structure
that you go and start with
keep your hips down widen your feet a
little bit over your mouth just let your
jaw relax and breathe
your fingers as wide as you can
by fingers why fingers
good you're gonna probably feel a
stretch through here if you do this
portion of your spine feel it up here
too wow that's really tight feel it's
right here
biceps arms I'm going to make it just a
little bit more so you can control you
control the depth of the stretch stay
there I'm going to break this so that
you can wrap your fingers under it like
try your best and that's going to help
you support you in stretching just a
little bit more feel the difference that
you're not relaxed your job only stay
there as long as you want to I just
wanted you to feel that so you guys who
are watching and just stay there try to
relax keep your mouth open relax you
guys can see what's happening here we're
mobilizing the thoracic portion of the
spine also if you if you had a chance to
feel what's happening here a lot of
tension in his upper abdominals
that's probably associated with the way
he holds himself when he's on the cello
when he was laying over there you can
see that the tightness in his biceps
causes them to flex them the fingers and
actually want to curl your neck probably
feels like hell right now too right yeah
there's a lot of tension there so
coupled with corrective stretching which
is always still good to do the one I
would recommend is head against the wall
you've done this before yes because I
had to PT or a while yeah that every
every day every single day multiple
times a day you should do that if you
want to be the best cellist right that's
how you say it
that's cellist around without damaging
your body you would have stretched that
stretche both of those but that also in
organic or more of an organic stretch
more like yoga is organic meaning that
it it brings together it's holistic it
brings together not just the individual
muscles that you need to stretch but
also the spine the core the bow will do
it actually both you eligible to do it
you start here by opening up your hips
but ultimately for you what we want to
have happen is for you to get really
comfortable in this position
and this recession that why do we try
this one good ok bend your knees
slightly open up your mouth spread your
elbows Danny when come around this way
come around this way it's really
important good just to see how much
tension there is there open up your
mouth and watch how much he vibrates
good you see how his body shakes there
that's the resistance between the full
extension that it would be necessary
hoping about just do keep doing it I
it's so uncomfortable keep doing it yeah
that's weird right people if you want to
also it'll help open your mouth and
breathe yes
okay relax for a moment good that's
crazy yeah it is it's opening you up
energetically also you might feel that
in my hand is it a little bit more more
nice like cool dude good cooler do don't
you yeah haha try this one it's much
more aggressive but um be gentle just
definitely lose every day to try that
think about reaching your hands out with
wide fingers and leaning back wide mouth
wide mouth instantly begins vibrating
look at that good wide mouth yeah stay
there for a while tell you when to stop
though wide your mouth wide or not
awkwardly wide like stretch your jaw
good see all that vibration that's the
life in it wanting to explode out of
this muscular system but if there's a
ton of tension right here
a lot of locked up tension right there I
mean almost look like a hole when he
goes back I don't know if you can see
that you go back and almost collapses
here so I would do a lot of work opening
here on that and this good try to work
up to if you can try to work up to like
two minutes with this one and then two
minutes with that one I mean if you get
two minutes a day begin by trying to get
two minutes with this and then stop and
then slowly work up to two minutes that
would be a different man could reach
your hands overhead try that one he's
not his body isn't nearly as I'm gonna
use this term lightly deformed as yours
because of he's sprinter he does more
you're a lot of what you do is here so
his body hasn't taken that shape the
same shape as yours
white mouth I want you to do this right
now look forward though foot forward
look forward yeah well he's got some
vibration going on there too good
attention the shoulders cool relaxed
yeah it's like the feeling we're always
inspired by like the military and
being just part of that but it may kind
of like do this do that kind of thing
but I almost kind of like that yeah
sometimes oh yeah yeah totally I will
you have to you have to do more of the
basics all over it in today so your
aspiration is to be in the military that
or music or vibe I know I'm going to
regret it if I don't if you don't go
into the Mo's all right you know I think
there's so much value to it and it's not
I when I say this I have no political
agenda with regard to it or I'm not
trying to feed into any grand ideology
except for becoming the strongest
version yourself and for young men to
access the warrior within them I spoke
about that before and if you're
interested there's a really good book
I've been reading and/or I've read and
I'm like I'm told I'm about to get
tattoos of this fucking thing King
warrior magician lover which are the
four major if you will angels that are
talking to each man they come from Carl
Jung and he calls them archetypes
they're different archetypes that
struggle for prominence within
developing masculine and I really
believe that this idea of the warrior in
many ways has been suppressed depressed
look down upon to our detriment because
a kid like Ito guy like you for you to
want to go into military means that you
wanted you want to be able to say let it
all out have someone be controlled you
want to be controlled by the mind you
want somebody telling what you do you
want to be dragged through rigors and
experience pain and and discipline
because there's a warrior inside you
that up until this particular point
perhaps you have an experience or hasn't
been invoked but you go to boot camp
you'd better be a fucking warrior and
that might be the hunger that you have
within you so I would say yes yes with
again without any regard to the
political implications of it for you to
become the strongest version yourself
and for you to be feeling this desire to
go to the military you have to when
you're right if you don't you'll
probably be upset with yourself