it's a really good question one that uh
that a lot of people ask in roundabout
ways some more facetiously than others
but our friend wants to know if becoming
the strongest version of yourself
requires that you hurt someone else
either physically or not is that okay
what should you do that
if becoming the strongest version of me
means that I'm listening to my heart
like Eliot house always says right Haley
said at least I listen to your heart
listen to your feelings listen to your
balls go and do shit if it requires that
you're hurting someone else is that okay
is it okay that just because I feel like
raping someone I go and do it I'm just
doing what I feel like doing right Eliot
here's the problem and this is why my
advice is dangerous because we live in a
schizophrenic fucking world that
question is just an expression of how
schizophrenic we fucking are when I say
schizophrenic I literally mean the term
to the Schism the schizoid situation
where our head has dominated our body
there's a split from our head which has
become the ruler of mankind from our
body which is really the life producer
of mankind the brilliance of humanity is
found in the heart and balls and it
doesn't mean that the mind isn't a
valuable tool because it is it's what
brings us a lot of the beautiful things
that extraordinary technology that we
have is a product of our deductive
reasoning our ability to calculate but
who's beating your heart right now who's
producing your hormones right now who's
digesting your food right now who's
growing a baby inside your wife's belly
right now not this guy so we have been
conditioned through schools through
education through culture and media to
honor the head and dishonor the body the
body's gross it's nasty it's if farts
and it shits and it smells and it gets
boners and it there's all types of weird
stuff happening down there you cut it
open and like things are beating and
pulsing and it's like
Oh what is that we hate our fucking
bodies no matter how much which we love
pornography we fucking hate sexuality we
hate our bodies we've been taught this
and the reason why I know this is
because you're so out of touch with the
reality that's happening in your body
that you might think that a stronger
version of you would be produced out of
hurting another person feelings are real
when you are grounded and in touch with
them and human being any creature on
earth especially that which can produce
compassion cannot freely willingly and
joyfully with pleasure in its body hurt
someone else it will happen we will hurt
other people there will be Wars there
will be destruction there will be murder
they're all a product of bigger better
more expansion expansion the mind right
the killing off of the entire race of
natives that lived on this continent
that I'm standing on right now is a
product of bigger more take you over
take over take over take a look now to
judge it good or bad neither here nor
there that's not my objective but to use
your hands to pull the heart and soul I
don't know that human being is not
something that someone who is
compassionate someone who is in their
body someone who's in touch with their
feelings and deep rooted true humanistic
emotions is going to do it's fucking
neurotic right so for you to ask this
question that I understand I'm totally
empathetic dude I get it I know why
you're asking this question because we
live in a schizophrenic world and it
might seem like a a stronger version of
me might just need to fuck you up when
in reality that's not becoming a
stronger version of yourself
that's proceeding in the same with the
same attitude and in the same fashion in
the same direction that all the wars
that we develop come from
right all the religious wars I fucking
love religion because at its core it's
all about getting in touch with nature
God the universe our bodies why do you
think Jesus always why do you think
Jesus doing this shit his heart why do
these always our fucking heart here it's
all about getting in your body the Son
the Holy Ghost is all down in the body
we do this right but we become so
neurotic that we take that and we use it
to kill people take that fucking cross
turn it upside down and turn into a
sword
Constantine right it's an erotic it's
fucked up it doesn't make any sense I'm
not judging it because it is what it is
is what human beings do but don't for a
minute believe that the higher evolved
version of yourself that which is the
greatest expression of your personal
evolution self-actualization is in any
way shape or form a product of hurting
other people it's Chuck you cannot
justify it in no way shape or form can
you give me a logical explanation as to
how an individual will grow will evolve
will become self actualized as a product
of killing or hurting another person
that was not to say that you you know
you could be someone that's murdered you
could and still become strong as version
of yourself right that's what the whole
idea behind Redemption is right that's
the whole idea between behind repentance
is look yeah you killed a lot of my
fuckers you were bad it is a bad shit
but you can be born again today you can
still become strong version yourself
after doing horrible things to other
people things that that someone who has
a heart would never do right I love all
these people
again you know I'm a Christian but yet I
want to kill people you know Jesus with
the heart you know you're not no you're
not you're using that as a tool to
further fulfill the neurotic obligation
that you've created for yourself where
the world has taught you
obviously I'm ranting right now so I'm
kind of lost my place oh but you will
not become the strongest version
yourself as a product in spite of yes
but not because of your hurting another
individual that's it