so I got a question from a 44 year old
Brazilian mother single mother of three
children ages 10 and I guess some twins
at the age of seven not the typical
question asker and it's not that I don't
recognize realize appreciate or want to
serve anyone outside the demographic of
young men between ages of like 15 and 35
it just so happens that the way I
approached this practice of making
videos the way I made my self on the
scene was just through answering
questions for young kids who wanted to
guys we wanted to build some muscle but
I realized that because of the the depth
and complexity and sensitive nature of a
lot of the questions that I answer on
this channel that there are people of a
far broader demographic and I am
grateful for your viewership and I am
even more grateful to support you and
Gracie was one of our friends who just
made mention on my facebook wall grace
that she would love some support and and
that there are a lot of older women that
that are in dire straits situations that
are very grievous that they would be
grateful to get gain a little
perspective on from you know the unique
ideas that I tend to afford through
these videos now grace is her situation
is not unique it's quite typical she's
middle-aged she's a single mother two
children that are approaching
teenagehood
and she feels lost depressed there's no
joy in her life there's no satisfaction
in the jobs that she used to once enjoy
there's no love in her life she used to
be creative and dreamed big and had all
these aspirations and life has just
weighed heavily on her and she's in a
place where there is debt destitute and
depression there's not much good going
on in her life and she's overweight
she's sick sad depressed and doesn't
know how to regain that spark that
vitality for what life has to offer
again and it seems as if when you have
to pay bills and you got children
yelling in your ear and you don't have
the support of someone to help you and
you've got work to do and there's no
room for yourself there's no time for
yourself there's no time - for
creativity much less time - for personal
development
so before I offer you a bit of a
solution or ideas that might support you
I want to go back to a high school thing
I was in tenth grade 10th grade biology
a lesson that I learned about cellular
cellular division if you look at the
world around us the biological world
around us I'm talking mainly plants and
animals we are all a product an
expression of cellular division watch
the way a baby grows in the womb watch
the way a seed tiny seed is inserted
into the earth develops into a mighty
oak it's this process of single cells
enduring the pressures of the
environment either intrinsically or
extrinsically and then evolving into
more complex organisms organ systems and
organisms right you would also call this
over the long stretch of humanity or or
life on Earth you call this evolution
but each individual organism an organ
system goes through its own evolution
like I said it's most obvious if you
look at the development of a child in
utero it starts out as a two cells that
come together and then there are they
start to develop into bundles of cells
and then into cell systems and organ
organ systems and then the organism it
grows boom boom boom boom boom pop pop
pop pop pop if you remember the stages
of cellular development when you were in
biology it started the way I remembered
was it Maps we started with interphase
prophase metaphase anaphase telophase I
believe that's what was and that's
basically where you got one cell right
this is how all of life this is why it's
so important what I'm about to share
with you this is how all of life as we
know it evolves in a in a microcosm each
one of us we evolved this way start out
with a single cell and then within that
cell there is a period of catharsis
right there's a time when the cell is
just it's cool it's fine it's by itself
it's one fucking cell who cares but it's
cool but eventually it's going to it's
going to respond to the intrinsic which
is inside and extrinsic forces of life
happening through it that's very
important to consider that life is
happening through us life is happening
through these cells such that it created
creates a disruption within the organ
within within a cell all ourselves or
individual life's that lives that are
going through this at all the time right
the way that looks if you like you if
you pull up on YouTube a video of
cellular division you'll notice that
there is a constriction or a depression
of the of the Kroll chromosomes and
chromatic row Matins all the different
weird names
elements within the within a nucleus
there's a depression or or tightening up
of it right and then there's this period
of catharsis where it's it starts to
shake and then it starts to it starts to
divide into two separate parts of itself
so basically all of the all of the DNA
for a lack of really better
understanding starts to separate and you
get two equal halves within the same
organs within the same cell and then
those two Pete bits of DNA begin to tear
literally tear apart within from inside
such a tear apart the cell until it
becomes
boom two cells right so basically the
intrinsic and extrinsic pressures that
are going on create so much stress
within the organism that it has to
it breaks down and reorganizes at a
higher level now there are two right
there sister cells they call them now
door to two can handle the stress better
than one and then it happens again and
then there are four and then there are
eight and then there are sixteen and
then as it continues to expand it grows
into like a heart and it grows into a
stomach or it grows into the branch of a
tree a bud into a branch right and this
shit is just going on boom boom boom
boom boom the whole world is constantly
doing this pop pop pop pop growing
growing growing growing growing growing
growing we are a product of tiny little
cells within each one of our organs
organ systems and the organism this is
happening in us and it's happening
through us see a lot of times you'd like
to think that life is happening to us
right and that's that type of resistance
because it's merely a story that we tell
ourselves that type of resistance that
is associated with life is happening to
me and I've got to fight against it
doesn't allow the peaceful evolution of
the human being or the allowance of
becoming a stronger version of yourself
and that's where stress comes from our
stress doesn't come from the extrinsic
or at least the depressive type of
stress that distress doesn't come from
life happening through us it comes from
our resistance to life happening through
us it comes from the resistance of the
extrinsic circumstances it comes through
the resistance of not allowing what's
happening around us to happen through us
so that we can evolve so that we can
reorganize at a higher level this is a
situation where becoming the strongest
version to yourself is not something you
do it's something you will laugh easier
said than done and I totally get this I
understand that basically it sounds like
Elliot's saying well my children are
disrespecting me I have bills to pay I
have jobs that need to get done I want
to be creative I had big dreams they
cannot have
any longer because the circumstances are
such that my time is limited what the
fuck are you talking about Elliot why
are you telling me about cellular
division and allowing life to happen
through me the reason why I'm saying
that is because one of the biggest forms
of resistance against cellular division
evolution personal evolution personal
growth becoming the strongest version
yourself is letting go of the version of
yourself
that is on its way out we're constantly
changing the world around us is
constantly changing this tree that I'm
looking at outside is is growing it's
constantly changing it's never the same
from season to season and you are not
the same from season to season the thing
is that the environment is changing
right God the universe nature is
changing the people around you are
changing and you got to keep up with the
demands of the the new environment your
children are older now your husband has
left you you have more bills to pay but
you are just not strong enough yet to
handle all of that the ability to handle
all that stuff is there there's an
ability that you totally have the
ability to do it but the resistance
against the growth that's associated
with reorganizing at a higher level in
order to handle all that shit is not
being allowed to happen right again
easier said than done what do i do
Elliot it's so fascinating that when we
get out of our own way how miraculous
life is how magical all the things that
seemed like it was like going fucking
nuts right imagine inside the cell all
the things that seemed like they were
going nuts when we let go imagine the
cell as the the chromatins
were doing this was like oh I don't like
the way this feels there's too much
pressure from the environment and
there's too much turmoil on the inside
and the cell resisted breaking
sometimes feels like you're breaking
apart doesn't it breaking apart and
reorganizing at a higher level the cell
just lets it happen and it becomes a
heart we resist it and we become fucked
up and depressed and stressed to the
grave we've got to allow it to happen
we've got to become a higher version of
ourselves our stronger version of
ourselves we have to reorganize at a
higher level when the environment is
asking us to that means letting go of
the grace that got you to where grace is
right now whatever grace got you into
the certain situation that you're in
right now was great because that's where
you belong now you still have a whole
lot of ideas you know you talk about the
big dreams you once had and that you
know some of the things you used to do
the old grease the old grades had these
things have these aspirations feel felt
this way was participating this the old
grace always always is dead in fact the
old grace is making you really anxious
right now the old grace needs to die
those old aspirations no matter how
great they were they were creative they
were full of life they were full of
vitality I was a dreamer okay good
that's fine that grace got you to where
you are right now neither good nor bad
but the environment the circumstances
intrinsically and externally is
requiring not that grace goodbye
you've got a literally step back I'm
gonna give you I'm gonna give you
practical pragmatic means for doing what
I'm talking about here right because
again easier said than done you
literally have to step back from the
situation you've got to be able to
become completely subjective objective
about what's happening and watch it from
afar and let the pieces fall in place
they will fall in place if you get out
of the way how do you get out of the way
because it's not getting in the way so
much that it is what I'm doing with my
hands it's how I'm proceeding
psychologically
how can I just let it be right like
here's the Jesus quote for you that I'm
gonna get all messed up but he talks
about why worry about why worry about
tomorrow when all the birds in the field
and all of all the birds in the trees in
order that feels that the flowers in the
field they either spin nor toil and
they're taken care of the father takes
care of him God takes care of them the
universe takes care of them nature takes
care of them right this is basic what
Jesus is saying like the fucking birds
are okay
the flowers are okay you are ten times
more important according to the story in
our first of course you look at you you
really think that nature is gonna take
care of the fucking birdie you're not
gonna get what you need relax
take it easy back off be a part of the
kingdom he calls it which basically
means detachment from all the shit
that's going on you've got to meditate
that's the answer that is the answer I
say breathe into your balls I say
shaking vibrate I say bioenergetics I
say yellow scream catharsis really
they're all means to relaxing the
muscular tension in the body so that you
can let go
you'll know you let go when the muscular
tension is gone and when you can
literally sit back and proceed or watch
from a place of peaceful observance as
the world is happening around you and
because you're not so emotionally
entangled with everything that's going
on your negative energy will not be
influencing those around you nearly as
much you mentioned your daughter giving
you a lot of beef a lot of problems
she is a energetic expression of what's
happening inside you you're of a higher
being per se again these are all just
metaphors and ideas but you're you're
the mother you know she came from you
you're the ruler of the environment
you're the manipulator of the
environment she is reacting to the
stress that you have within you when you
chill out she'll chill out I don't say
this out of poetic flourless flower enos
in fragrance I say this out of personal
fucking experience I know that when
things aren't well in my home I know
that when my daughters are going nuts I
know that my wife is stressed out I
realized immediately I know what am i
doing how am I thinking how am i
behaving in this environment because I'm
the I'm the energetic strength in my
home everybody knows who happens to be
the end of the real who's gonna control
the environment and it's not so much
like I control the environment but if if
that it shows up and daddy's pissed off
and tired and aggravated guess what the
house is like pissed off aggravated and
tired mommy's gonna be pissed off
aggravated and tired because daddy's
being a dick and the children are all
going nuts because daddy's nuts so
you've got to relax you got to meditate
I would invite you to begin and I know
your time is limited but it's so funny
how when we meditate it's almost like
time expands one of the strangest things
that's ever happened to me when I began
meditating is I started getting more
quality
done and time with my family even though
I was using a significant portion of
that time to meditate so it's almost
like how do you take a piece of your
time and gain more time Hey look I'm not
gonna tell you how because I don't
fucking understand but I can tell you
what I experienced meditate and you will
gain the perspective associated with
allowing evolution to happen through you
you will become a stronger version of
grace that will have all the tools
associated with fulfilling your current
job you're doing the things and allowing
the things and enhancing the world
around you if those cells don't shake up
and divide they never become a heart if
they resist that that that that growth
they resist the cellular division
because they're so attached to the cells
that they actually are they never get to
beat blood they never get to do the
thing they're supposed to do you never
get to be the strongest version of grace
you never get to be what you're designed
to do so that's it your circumstances
aren't unique none of our circumstances
are unique we think we're so stressed
out we think we've got it so bad we
think we've got a heavier load to carry
than someone else
we've all got heavy loads to carry even
the 14 year old kid who's dealing with
strict stress from school stress from a
girlfriend that hates him
zits on his face his parents aren't
happy with his grades and he broke his
foot and can't play in the football game
that's a lot of fucking stress but it's
all perspective right because we can be
adults like ah you're so lucky you're
just a kid it's all Bubba no dude that
it's doesn't work that way it's all very
subjective we all experience stress
we're all carrying a heavy load the
biggest difference is how you carry that
load are you gonna carry it on your face
and let it weigh you down
or do you grow stronger so that you can
carry it and then pick up bigger loads
and continue to serve other people along
the way good luck