talked a lot about how someone take
inspiration like online right to get a
situation you have this feeling you get
tons of information but how do we
translate that to a sustainable life
skill or habits people to actually take
what's available and try to hit you
something so how would you approach that
how do you get someone call your
information after inspiration
skill on like a half yeah taking on
years of bringing them into reality
right because you are a person who wants
help actually help people change your
life it's not good enough to just give
them information give them tools you
want to see it manifest another Bible
story not Christian but I mean this one
it's not good shit man I am at a phrase
it properly but basically the story goes
where the farmer had seeds and he goes
and he spreads the CD to go down and
spreads disease because he needs to
needs to manifest something see there's
an idea right like your idea what
manifests is the crime and the flower
and the plant the fruit right but he
goes have the bomber know who's that as
he goes out and express the seeds that
some of them will fall on rocky ground
some of them will fall almost two weeks
right rocky ground means there was no
potential there to begin with you spread
your seed but there's no potentials
there beginning this rocky ground spread
about sea weeds things that look there's
potential there but the person is
stifled and surrounded by too much
negative
write a web address some of it falls
upon hold the birds take it so when you
spread it before when fertile ground but
the bird comes and takes it basically
that person was distracted right
everything you did was right to put it
from soil but no verb to me right the
point is that the farmer still gets up
and spreads its seeds and you got
recognized it as a as a sprinter like
demons you're doing the thing you're
fulfilling your job as the farmer does
but without lamenting on the rocky
ground the weeds and the birds and
focusing solely on the fertile ground
that's followed that it's falling on not
everyone's going to get your thing is
that helpful do it anyway you can't
worry about you can't worry about
everybody you know there was a time
especially if you know you a personal
trainer also so you actually work with
people you want all your clients to have
great results right it hurts your
feeling that is that it like if bill
moving three months in your
matter what am i doing wrong hey I know
that feeling well rocky ground amongst
the weeds maybe there was never any
potential there anyway and they're just
you know drinking right there nice
person but it's like a reduced up
attention of England they're full of
them seaweeds they will be the negative
situation at home our husband is
constantly you know browbeating here to
make you feel bad about herself because
disrespect her she's not gonna lose
weight that's how she comforts yourself
or you know thought what's the birds you
know it's like hey you show up here but
you go when you drink on the weekend
it's like you really you're not focused
and it's just a part of the situation
every one of us has our own story we
only were always so subjective right how
many know my story I don't need a wife
feelings I don't know what's going on
but there's an objectivity to the entire
thing you do it and you don't know
what's happening when you do it what you
do it because you have to do it and
you'll be shot there are times where
like I have clients that I thought okay
attention like you know you never got
any results with me you show up ladies
in time I smelled alcohol on your breath
and then you see on my three years later
like you know what you do to change my
life you really changed my life there's
this one something you said one day we
worked out and i went home and i change
this
and I'm like how do you what's your name
again you know it's just I'm dead
serious Michelle would you change my
life I'm like I don't remember you
that's how dysfunctional you were when I
want to bet you just do your thing they
meet my question was specifically about
my question is that not app allows
people interacted me a workout progress
and the links and Facebook right so they
have this huge transformation astoria
it's like to their friends or any season
right
they always ask to do it look at the
profile you can see anything been found
let me go as a how to be so I could get
people inspired with the right
information to help you is there that
then do you get people to build habits
and life skills that you know give them
to you
you talk about like lazy earlier it's
about my system like how do you get
people to talk about me like that do I
gotta take this on but is it the heart
eat that you use like two names and
constantly borrow those who think as
effectively
process that encourage people to take it
from ATP you do have seen a photograph
you just tell them you tell them what to
do when you offer the amount of
encouragement that that's a bit you can
muster but that's it I know what you're
saying like you want to give them here's
the thing information and methods are
only as good as the people that receive
them right it was all about information
I mean we've got libraries if I'm life
if you've got the internet there's never
been a generation that doesn't have the
internet and they're still stupid people
you mean you don't know this you know
you only do use this thing called google
and you can learn all about that like
that's how you think it's coming up
information and methods are only as good
as the people and for a true revolution
or personal evolution would take course
this is why I talk about these names you
got to get anything that you've got to
tell people like and get again you're
only offering look watch you try
meditation because you got all these
fucked up thoughts that are like screw
it up the whole things like and that's
why I try to keep things simple like the
heartbeat because people are busy so
much going on there so distracted but if
you just give them look don't think
about anything you don't here's what
happens to be so I think it's right or
wrong because
something i read an article I read it
that's all video I saw Aaron ignore laps
do these two things and it has a
professional don't be wrapped up and
whether or not those two things are the
right things what you're doing is not
helping them through the method but
through the habit you're helping them
and still it's like it doesn't matter Oh
should I drink this kind of water that
water district a CO and okay it's your
boy don't get wrapped up simple you know
but again we can't take responsibility
you offer you keep offer like I created
the non jobs thick and I didn't create
it because first of all I'm created
because i want to change me Bob and
create because I want to see you guys be
great ok because i watch it feels good
for me to do this thing and if somebody
makes something of it oh damn fantastic
we've talked about this chris and i like
there's a lot of kids that come come
through my gym you know and and as i was
developing my business online he's come
to only see what i'm doing like and they
were those that pain and more interested
and i say this is what i'm doing it's
pretty cool you know you create workouts
and then you sell it to people they'll
be to put workouts and they're like
cool could you teach me how and I'd sit
down for an hour maybe more multiple
times this house done is how to set this
up that you do this yet not and get to
again okay the Lord on but this which
got here and it's like I just give you a
crash course that I can charge the house
down and your later I see anyone like
what are you doing and we're gonna
double doughnuts right then I can have
one kid show up Haley for you doing ah
this right now making something every
workouts and I want to make some people
over yeah so you sell them about here I
brought it's all right now and then a
year later I talked to like bro what are
you doing oh yeah I'm pulling like 10
grand love from the decibel workouts
that I said sell people online when were
you told me that time but to do is like
a I wanted I got a book if you mention
it that way you don't know you just do
your day oh I hope that's helpful
you just do your thing without thinking
about what's going to happen I think we
we live in this insurance day and age
where we want and assurance guarantee
everyone wants a guarantee I get out of
college of guaranteed a job I do this
thing I want to guarantee I wanted for
see what's going to happen what I do
this how many of our clients say that
what am I going to lose 20 pounds like
what is that way like 30 de genève sick
days from now we will this guarantee and
we base all of our pro CD and our
activity on what is over there nobody
knows the bus and a half nowhere which
is you today