yo Elliott hey whats up guys today we
got a question from our shred camp
online member Joshua Dickinson he says
that I'm currently attempting a career
in law enforcement at some level whether
that be federal state or local policing
anyway to move along in the process he
needs to be able to pass physical
fitness test and he trains his ass off
he says that uh you know he can do
push-ups around 30 to 40 in a minute sit
ups 35 to 45 in a minute he can run the
one and a half mile run he doesnt sit
and reach body weight he does really
well in his training he practices and he
can pass all the tests when he's at home
or in his gym but the problem is when it
comes time to do the actual test for
whatever he's attempting to potentially
be a part of d falls short in other
words you choked buddy right so there
you are spending all of your time energy
and effort to build up your strength and
your ability in these particular tests
and then when the ten you do well
practice right you're a winner in
practice but then when game time comes
you choked up right so uh you know
language the way somebody says something
tells you a lot about their state of
mind and as I'm reading your question
and you begin with you're currently
attempting to start a career it in law
enforcement at some level it essentially
it says to me that you're really not
committed to anything you want to
attempt you see hurry what you're really
committed to is attempting right and
that's what you do it like when you show
up for the test you've committed to
attempting and now you're attempting
you're not committed to winning right
you're not committed to passing the test
you're committed to trying it out and it
kind of reminds me of when I was
competing in straw man and what some of
the guys I would train with were a lot
stronger than me
and in practice they really would whoop
my ass I mean they're lifting stones and
flipping tires and doing weights that I
could not even touch but when it came
competition time i won I always want in
the competitions but they always kick my
ass in practice why is that because when
they went into the show they were
attempting to win when I went into the
show I was committed to winning what you
need to understand is that language that
you're using is a manifestation of the
way you're thinking about yourself in
the circumstance I don't attempt to win
I go to win understand so what that
means is and what it requires is that
you spend some time really visualizing
and feeling and knowing that you're
going to pass the test it's a no-brainer
when you walk into that test knowing
especially that you've done well in
practice you are going to pass see it
feel it know it be cocky about it right
because even if I'm getting my ass
whooped in practice because hey you guys
are stronger than me that's fine but
guess what I'm a winner you ain't gonna
beat me well all the numbers say no
matter it's the attitude man so you got
to go into this thing not attempting and
and you know you mentioned at some level
no no no exactly what you're going into
exit at exactly what level right I mean
spell it out for yourself visualize it
right up until the end I'm going into
this branch of the Armed Forces or a
policeman force at this level and I'm
going to pass the test on this day and
it's as good as done done Elliot's it
what
[Music]