okay our buddy Vince here is uh he was
involved in martial arts right and
really really talented so much so that
he would beat the shit out of his
training partners without even thinking
about it he was really getting close to
hurting people really really bad and it
was a combination of his natural
aggression he's just freaking aggressive
guys got a lot of energy not an angry
person not someone who's trying to hurt
others but he's strong he's aggressive
and really really skilled what happened
was he was kicking the shit out of
people so badly so easily so often that
the martial arts instructor and his
father basically everybody like tell him
you got it back off you got to stop you
got to stop
and this weighed heavily on his self
esteem because now he feels like a bad
person right you're beating the shit out
of people meanwhile it's like you know
that's the sport you're supposed to
fucking heart people but anyway I
understand you know you walk into a
martial arts class like nobody expects
to get their arm broken and you're
supposed to back off just a little bit
but our buddy Vince you can't you don't
even know he's doing it and in the
advice essentially is to temper your
talent and that that's really what he's
got he's got a talent for hurting people
really bad right then that's not a
talent that uh that works well in our
society because you know we've got to
get along with one another and we've got
to make sure that we're not killing
people and hurting people and this is
all you know so that we can all get
along and live life without fear of
going to martial arts class and having
our arm broken so I so I understand I
understand why your father and why the
teacher told you what to do but the
problem is that and your concern now
because he what he decided to do is to
quit martial arts altogether
because he just he couldn't handle it
the instinct was there to hurt and if he
puts himself in the environment to hurt
he's going to do it so he decided not to
he's now doing bodybuilding and he hates
bodybuilding a just he doesn't like who
he's becoming with regard to
bodybuilding either because it's not
bodybuilding in itself that's bad but he
realizes man I've got a lot of talent I
had this urge I want to go
do this how do I go about my life in a
resourceful fashion when I when I have
this skill and desire to hurt people
number one would be the sport of what
you're in the right sport
I mean mixed martial arts is about
hurting people you probably need to find
a new instructor and you need to find an
environment where you can let out all
the aggression that you that you have in
a resourceful way you might just need
better training partners someone who
will beat the shit out of you so that
you can build up your skill and that
person can handle it that's the most
practical thing I mean else it's almost
like duh right I can't believe that you
know you're forced to quit find
somewhere where you can exert this this
gift use this gift you can probably end
up becoming one of the best fighters
around right you know that you can beat
the shit out anyway the other thing and
the reason why I decided to choose
chooses your question and to answer this
through the video is because I've
experienced a lot of what you're dealing
with and there comes a time when you
graduate from your activity that you've
always been talented and I've always
been talented in football and there was
a time when it was football is done for
me that's it you know I had to realize
that it was done and you will realize at
one point that what your whatever
endeavor you're it you're participating
in is going to be done I don't think
martial arts has done yet for you right
so it was really my answer go back to
that but this is going to happen in
people who are watching this might uh
this might be resourceful for them there
was a time there was a period of
depression for me because I had this
will desire and I have created it the
the character associated with being a
captain on a football team and leading
people to victory and smashing the shit
out of people and working hard towards a
goal and when I went out into the real
world and I realized that what most
people this shit doesn't even like
people didn't makes you feel
uncomfortable when you have big goals
and when you're like you you're
committed and you're working hard I know
most people are just trying to get by
you know
don't sweep you are like bureaucrats you
know do as little as they can to get by
notice this in graduate school and I
noticed this in my in the first stint of
my career like people are fucking lazy
there's no sense of teamwork and there's
no commitment and I grew a bit depressed
because the things that were strong in
me found no place
in the workplace and you're experiencing
that to your your natural aggression is
not finding any place in the world so
what you've got to do is you've got to
find a way to channel that strength that
natural strength that you have that
aggression that you have into a
something that's valued in the economic
system and I use that term economic
system because no matter what we think
we're doing we're really a cog in an
economic system it's a game that we're
all playing we're all subjected to the
game right you just decide how to play
this frickin game okay you're going to
want to play this game really really
well and you're going to play the game
really well because you're aggressive so
you're going to be a cutthroat
entrepreneur CEO executive whatever it
is that you do because you have the
discipline you have the commitment and
you have the aggression and that's a big
one that most people don't have a lot of
people it'll have any aggression you
don't like limp noodles I don't know how
they go about their lives yeah some like
what they want what they're doing and
like they're just flounders that's not
going to happen for you so you're going
to be able to take those virtues those
god-given talents virtues and you're
going to be able to channel them use
them towards building great things for
yourself where it is highly praised in
this machine that we live in good luck
bro