so I got this question here from one of
our buddies who recently lost a parent
six months ago and wasn't get a grip on
his emotions and I think that's probably
the problem he says that his life was
falling apart and you know he doesn't
trust anybody anymore surprise don't
accept him not that they were checked
him but he's kind of like a downer I
mean come on your mom or dad who was
recently died six months ago
and and you're asking me how can I get a
grip of my emotions so that I can go
about my life and be happy again
the problem is that you're thinking
about having a grip on something that
needs to be let go
we're taught at a very young age to to
suck in and hold down hold back shut
down shut up and suppress the emotional
responses that our natural impulses
within the body because they're they
make other people uncomfortable
you know after certain age when the kid
cries everybody gets uncomfortable watch
a grown man cry you get uncomfortable
right because we're all comfortable with
ourselves and we've been taught that and
so then it's just kind of this this
thing where we all make ourselves and
each other slaves too neurotic ideas
like you shouldn't cry even laughter
have you ever been somewhere and you
know some like an adult is really like
laughing unless you are open enough to
receive that energy and start laughing
yourself because that's you know that
laughter is contagious also you
everybody else are looking at each other
like what is this person crazy what's
wrong with them why is he not fucking
neurotic like us tears is a big one and
you're a man you're a boy you've lost
your parent and I can I put money on it
that you have not mourn the way you
should mourn you have not cried you have
not released that emotion that is a
natural response to losing your earth
you come out of your mother the tree
doesn't exist without its roots without
its without the ground through which it
was birthed in for you to lose your
mother and at a young age I'm assuming
you're not any much older than I am
means that your groups have been clipped
it's very traumatic and you need to
experience it in its fullness because if
you don't you're going to experience
what you're experiencing now the sadness
is going to color all of your
interactions with other people for the
rest of your days all of the activities
that you engage in we'll all be colored
with this subtle sadness that has not
been expressed you're carrying it with
you it's like they say some people have
a great cloud over their head you ever
know these people you know they come
around and it's like she's here and
everybody feels a particular way either
down sad angry frustrated you know you
know people like this there are also
other people that when they're around
it's like hey she's here he's in there
it's great because those people carry
sunshine with them because they've let
go of the clouds we all have clouds
you've got a tough one right now but we
all experience things that give us an
opportunity to hold on to a cloud those
clouds will just follow us we hold on to
them and bring them with us and you're
bringing in a cloud with you because you
have not let go of its content yet so
I've shared different exercises and ways
and means by which you can get back in
touch with your feelings the very first
one that I think is probably the most
superficial the one that's holding back
the tears that you have is probably
anger and or why why did you have to die
why did you have to go why why is such
an info Cravero ssin why why I know you
got a Y in you go somewhere where you
can scream and ask why why why you get
all the anger that's holding back that
which is underneath and that is
tears sobbing sadness because once you
get that that edge off what's underneath
is a softer emotion we usually use the
harder emotion to hold back the softer
motion and once that softness that
sadness has been expressed your body
will feel very limp you will no longer
be tense our muscular system carries our
tension with us that's why school
tension and through our muscular system
we approach the world so if your body
takes on a particular form because of
muscular tension you behave out of that
character generous and your body your
physical body becomes a costume that is
synonymous with a role you're going to
play so you've got to release the
muscular tension it begins with letting
go of the emotion emotion is movement
that you have trapped so that's it my
friend I mean the only way that you we
can deal with this is on an energetic
experience or level talking about it
thinking about it going to a
psychologist like you mentioned is not
going to happen
it's not going to work unless they're
you know bioenergetic an Al's the
analyst or therapist it's not going to
work because it's not in here we've
become so abstract in our dealings with
the world in our own lives that we think
we can do everything through this and
we've forgotten our bodies we rebelled
against our bodies we hurt our bodies
with this you got to go in it's press go
and get it out take a baseball bat to up
to a punching bag take a tennis racket
to a to a mattress get it out and then
you'll be free my friend not from the
loss of your mother that's a fact but
you'll be free from the emotional
holding due to your your lack of
expression good luck buddy