so their question for my buddy Blake
here who today is his very first day of
college and he's dreading it he says
that he's got a college scholarship
worth basically it's all paid for his
dad's really excited about him studying
biology you have to be good at biology
but Blake really doesn't give a shit
he's not excited he actually would
rather do screenwriting or play writing
he says that's his his passion but his
dad is like come on man you gotta love
this you're going to college for free
you're gonna study biology biology I
love biology hey make me proud son and
on Blake's like fuck this but he's going
he's biting his lip he's dragging his
feet and he's going he wants to know
what should I do
should I should i disappoint my father
should I throw away this college
scholarship because I love screenwriting
this is the first day of school
what am I going to do for the next four
years let me share my experience with
you because I think it might help you I
studied Healthcare fucking
Administration in college health care
administration that means that I should
be managing a hospital you think I went
to college because I wanted to study
fucking Healthcare Administration yeah I
went there because I wanted to manage
hospitals I'm going to shit on hospitals
I don't remember any of my classes
I graduated I went because I had a
scholarship I went because I didn't have
to pay for the shit I went because I
played football okay so now that now
that's a little different but here's the
thing today I do exactly what I want to
do my life is fucking awesome I own a
gym just like I wanted to when I was in
high school I trained people just like I
wanted to wanted to do in life in high
school like I did all my life I workout
I talk to people I make videos I enjoy
doing this if you have if you ever hang
out with me this is what I do all day
long
my friends like hanging out with me cuz
I just come up with weird answers to
their questions shit to make something
so I'm doing everything that I want to
do but those four years of college I do
not see as a waste first of all if
you're going into debt for it then I'd
say reconsider but you're not you'll
have to pay for this shit four years is
a drop in the bucket the big scheme
things quite frankly I mean I look back
and you may think I'm old you know
thirty four years old but I can tell you
right now that it's really it's gonna go
by so fast it's a drop in the bucket
it's not a big deal plus who knows man
there's all type of experiences that she
might have in there there's so much more
to college than what you're actually
learning in the classroom you know
especially if you're not going in order
to fulfill obligations for a particular
career you're just going because you
know you're supposed to your dad wants
you to go biology is not that bad
big deal now never let your schooling
get in the way of educating your
education while you're there why not
keep screenwriting what the fuck I mean
school is like a few hours a day do your
playwriting do your screenwriting then
want you to study Hey look just pass
your classes you know you don't have to
bust your brain and get all A's because
you have no passion for or intention of
doing anything with biology so don't
worry so much about it but spend the
rest of your time doing the thing that
you love growing the thing that is
rooted in your heart get through these
four years I promise you you'll be like
huh good thing I did that shit peace