yo Elliot what's up guys today's
question comes from strengthcamp online
member David Evan Flores he goes on ask
how do I go from being a gymnast so
essentially he says he's a 56 125 pound
former gymnast who wants to develop his
ability to do the Iron Cross and those
you who know anything about gymnastics
the iron crosses where they take the two
rings and grab them they can hold their
bodies out like this right so imagine
how difficult that must be to hold your
hold your entire body weight out with
your arms extended this way with the
Rings quite an athletic feat you want to
be able to either maintain or retain the
ability to do this but at the same time
he also plays basketball and he wants to
be able to dunk a basketball so he's
asking can I have contradictory goals if
I want to be able to maintain or develop
my Iron Cross I really can't have big
heavy bulky legs that would be
associated with somebody that can jump
and dunk a basketball and again those of
you if you've ever watched in nastics
these guys they got huge upper bodies
and then and then it just looks like
this they just come down to a pin right
they look like a triangle and it's
partly because you don't want to have
big legs when you're on that Iron Horse
and you're whipping your legs around
when you're trying to do iron crosses
and whatnot so it's it's it's really not
sports specific it's not advantageous to
the sport to have quads and glutes and
big giant hamstrings and calves right so
our buddy wants to know how can I go
about developing my jumping skills and
maintaining my gymnastic prowess well it
reminds me of a seminar I once went to
or I watched their own VHS was while
back early in my career that was
presented by coach Kim Gauss right and
he tells this story about how he was
training a
an ice skater a figure skater right and
you can imagine it was a woman there
there long slender but they're powerful
right i mean these chicks they got nice
lean legs nice slim bodies and then they
jump up in the air and do this boom then
keep going right just imagine so uh
you've got to have some pretty powerful
freaking legs to be able to jump up in
the air come down do all the the liaison
whatever the hell they do all that crazy
stuff I don't know if they actually jump
up in the air and do that right I think
they just spin but either way they need
really incredibly powerful legs so uh he
he go he takes her into the strength
conditioning room I guess it's really at
a university takes her into the southern
conditioning room amongst the football
players and that you can imagine of
course football players are huge there
Jack they're squatting they're dead
lifting their massive their beasts and
here comes this petite little chick who
plays on ice and he loads up the barb
the barbell in the rack one plate two
plates when I say two plates I mean to
25 three plates 315 four plates by the
time he gets to the fourth plate all the
football players like what the fuck is
this guy doing and here's this pretty
girl that he's he's supposedly gonna
coach and she gets underneath the bar
right and then he sets up a box in front
of her and she proceeds to do a step up
she does a single leg step up with like
405 on the ball in the bar
now she doesn't do it for refs she does
singles and the point that he was trying
to make in this seminar was that it
doesn't require a lot of muscular bulk
in order to grow strength and power in
the legs this thin young lady who is
performing a sport that requires a
tremendous amount of power wasn't
getting any bulkier and she wasn't
getting bulky like the football players
because she was simply training the
nervous system to respond in such a way
that it could overcome overcome the
resistance of the weight when you jump
it's kind of the same thing you know
jumping is overcoming the resistance of
your body weight against the floor and
in a very powerful or time intensive way
so the difference between like strength
and powers that time is one of the
parameters within the equation has to be
done quickly right but you need to be
really strong in order to perform the
movement quickly so anyway my point here
is my friend there is no need to gain
massive amounts of bulk in your legs in
order to jump really high in fact you
can get really really strong using low
repetitions with high weights followed
by jumping I mean that's you get get
better jump in by jumping right so there
you have it man so there it is you can
gain both things you can have your cake
and eat it too you can be an iron
crosser and a dunker done Elliott's it
what
you