got a fascinating question from our
friend Andrea here she says that in our
environment there are people lots of
them in fact who are getting cancer this
must be family members friends and so
forth and she feels number one that a
lot of them are making themselves sick
through the stories that they're telling
themselves and that they're unable to
overcome these physical challenges
because of again the stories that we
tell ourselves now this is her assertion
not mine so you know those of you who
want to challenge that look I'm just
giving you her story she also feels as
if those people and their stories being
so saturated in her environment are also
causing her to take on the character
characteristics behavior and thoughts
that are going to ultimately make her
sick as well and she says now every time
I get a cold or I've got like a little
feeling in my body that that I don't
understand I feel like I'm gonna get
cancer and she is aware of this idea
that perhaps if she's amongst these
people were all sick getting sick
telling themselves sick things and she
herself she herself is now susceptible
to to this to this plague that perhaps
she's going to make herself sick totally
understandable I mean our environment
we're so permeable in that way that's
why I often say be very careful about
what TV shows you watch what music you
listen to I think a lot of you
especially if you're younger and you're
involved in pop culture don't realize
just how permeable you are when I say
that I mean how susceptible to brain
washing your nervous system is if you
don't protect it it's very susceptible
to manipulation and impression sickness
is no different again I'm not saying
that these people are giving themselves
cancer per se but you can make yourself
second if you're around sick people they
can help you make yourself sick too
because you start taking on these
stories as if they're your own
so and Rooney's wants to know what to do
she can't leave
obviously these are her family and
friends she's not a situation where she
can just pick up and leave or go
somewhere else
she's probably she probably loves these
people how to proceed me give you a sh
what so some of you may seem to be a
strange invitation my invitation to you
is to begin using prayers of empowerment
to support those in your environment who
are disempowered and who are a victim
they're creating circumstances that are
a byproduct of their disempowerment do
you see prayers are a strange thing
because they seem like they're so linked
to superstition and religion when in
reality it's another conversation right
because the same way that you would say
to yourself I am so happy and grateful
now that my friends in our environment
see the power within them to overcome
their physical challenges to grow
stronger and support others Thank You
universe thank you lord thank you God
thank you whatever you want to call it
for making this a reality when you say
that it is just the flip side of the
coin that sounds like oh I'm so sick and
sad and I can't believe that I got this
illness and why me God or why me
universe why do I always have to be a
victim of this why can't I just have a
nice life why your things so horrible
bad and and malicious in my life do you
see what I just did there they're both
prayers people when you complain and
when you condemn and when you feel sorry
for yourself and whether verbally or
mentally you tell yourself stories that
support that circumstance
it's a fucking prayer
you're always praying whether you know
it or not right I think Jesus even says
this right those who who who can
appreciate the words of many of our
masters make your prey not I think he
said something like don't pray in your
corner go pray in the closet
but make your life a prayer recognize
your life is a fucking prayer everything
that's being embedded in your
consciousness is a form of prayer and
when I use that term pray prayer it is
literally using the conscious mind to
embed ideas on the unconscious and the
unconscious doesn't just reside in our
body but there's a collective
unconscious there is a universal
unconscious there's an intelligence in
your body and in the world that is
united the only separation between who
we think we are us you and me and the
rest of our environment is the stories
that our conscious attention tells
itself that it enrolls in that it
believes that it warships
it's the conscious mind that creates
separation but you can use the conscious
mind to embed in powerful ideas on the
unconscious to raise the consciousness
of the entire world must let you must
let your own body think not evil
thoughts think not sick thoughts but
instead impress powerful positive
message upon yourself and those in your
environment by praying for others you're
praying for yourself because you're
focused and concentrated on the
intention of good health empowerment
strength stability and power praying for
others is a prayer for yourself and as a
powerful means for self growth and
raising the vibration power goodness and
resourcefulness that we see in the world
around us done