Elliot said what someone asked if a
man's home is representative of his
penis in the same way that the home is
representative of old woman's vagina the
answer is no the woman goes inside the
woman brings things in and nourishes
nurtures the man goes out I mean it's
all represented by the phallic symbol in
the vagina we go out women go in what
you see is the is what's happening in
the world is a manifestation of the
tools that men use in their hands which
are an extension of the penis so if you
see war and destruction it's because we
hold guns in our hands if you see
technology and creativity it is an
expression of or it's an extension of
our penis which would be the paintbrush
or the the keyboard on the computer
something that creates technology so the
world is more of an example of what is
being manifest by penis madness or
creativity Elliot said what