hey what's up dudes before we get
started today I just want you to know
that I've been fasting so no food no
water and no caffeine today so my energy
might be a little bit different but hey
bear with me I'm gonna do my best to
offer you entertaining informative ways
to be the strongest version of yourself
right and we begin with our buddy Samir
Samir says that he happens to be a
handsome looking dude he also has the
gift of gab he knows how to plant a joke
to open a woman up and open
relationships and although he can engage
with beautiful women and sustain a month
two months three months of a
relationship he can't seem to find a way
to stay in lobby says he falls out of
love you can't figure it out all these
women are great but each time I engage
with them a few months later I'm waiting
I'm counting down because the feelings
gonna go away and what was once a
roaring flame becomes a smoldering ember
and uh any wonders how he will ever make
it in a long-term relationship because
he would like to have one just to know
how to make this thing happen so good
hey I'm happy that you came to me right
because I've been having sex at the same
woman since I was 14 years old right I
still old man yesterday was crazy
yesterday we uh we dropped off the kids
at camp and usually she goes and she
does her work and I'll go I'll come to
the gym but we have a little date we met
back at the house I was like a little
sneaky little thing we turned on some
music
we had a damn good time II my lady right
palden after 20 21 years so I'll tell
you how we keep that flame roaring
because it's rip-roaring man I can't
keep my hands off her ass it's because
when you first fall in love and this is
interesting I've said this before that
analogy of falling into love head over
heels meaning your head is no longer
over your center of gravity your summit
when you're when your head is over your
base of support your center of gravity
right center gravity over the base of
support that means you've got your
wherewithal you've got your cognition
your your analytical your logistic you
are aware in this linear sense but right
but when you are head over heels meaning
your
tipping back you're getting swept off
your feet and when you get sucked off
your feet what happens you fly and float
up into the air until I mean you can
only float for so long what goes up must
come down
see it slipped off your feet and bang
you hit the floor and then you wake up
and you have to dust yourself off won't
get up and the same things happen in her
now you get a look at each other you
look each other up now you're like damn
now I got to deal with you right because
you weren't in love with that person at
the time you were in love with the
feeling of being in love you're in you
were in love with the feeling of falling
in love because when you fall it's so
euphoric because there is just a you
float into the ecstasy of life right
there's no grounding there grounding is
so boring here you're floating
you're in the clouds you know when they
say someone's in love it's like they're
in the clouds you're floating that's a
good feeling right I mean that's the
feeling of orgasm that's why we like sex
so much cuz after you're as you're
orgasming there's this floating feeling
you you let go of your grounding right
then you get up and guys we know this
one right you get up you put your
clothes on you're like uh what did I do
oh shit right once that all passes
that's the acute version of it right
you're talking two three four five month
version of it this is going to sound
strange and I hope you can follow I hope
you understand the wisdom of what I'm
about to share with you clearly it works
in my life and I'm I'm going to put my
foot down and say that it's a principle
because it damn right is a principle
because you can apply this to your
business you could apply this to school
you could apply this to your artwork you
can apply this to absolutely everything
that you become excited about in the
beginning but solely starts to fade take
notice of the things you do when you're
excited see there's a science to this
right because you're completely
spontaneous when you get kicked off your
feet you're swept off your feet and you
don't know what's going on man you got
feelings in your belly
feelings in your legs sometimes the feel
I've had this happen the feelings near
you your legs actually buckle women know
this like you just you can't even stand
on your legs oh you're so in love your
heart all this spontaneous shit is
happening right you do things you touch
her in certain ways you smile at her in
certain ways you hold her hand
you call her you think about her you
text her you look at her pictures on
Facebook and Instagram you're doing all
these fucking things but you're not
having to think about doing the bitter
spontaneous right there you've been
swept away and the spot the brilliant
spontaneity of your body or your
intuition your passion and compassion of
the heart carries you to enact these
particular behaviors be mindful to
keeping journal when you fall in love
next time keep a journal what you do
today
start being scientific about it Jack
that shit down right
today got up in the morning and I
thought about her and then I started
rubbing my lower belly and grabbing my
balls and then I called her and then I
looked at a picture of her haha I got
her but I brushed my teeth and then um I
heard a song and this song was the first
song we listened super when we met it
was in my car all that dumb shit write
it down motherfucker take note because
when it no longer happened spontaneously
and it won't happen spontaneously
forever you will now have to do those
things to maintain the feeling maintain
the fire it's the kindling of the fire
see right now when you fall the fire
just goes Bouchet right it's like
someone threw gasoline on it it's
roaring out of control you're out of
fucking control when you're when you
fall in love right that's what it's been
said don't trust a man who's falling in
love don't trust someone when they're in
love they're fucking they're out of
their minds but now that the fire is
cooled go back to that Journal all the
things you did because to do the thing
also creates the power I often say this
this is a Ralph Waldo Emerson do the
thing to have the power you do falling
in love to keep falling in love
I keep touching my wife's ass because
that's what people in love do and the
more I do it the more I like it and the
more we fall in love and the more I want
to be in love and the more I want to
touch her ass I can't keep my hands off
of her it's one of those things we do we
also send nasty text messages about what
I'm gonna do to you when I get home
right that's what we do that you were
well I'm a bit older right so texts met
we sext I think you guys probably do it
through like I don't know the private
Instagram messengers and send pictures
and shit whatever it is that you do
whatever nasty little fucking thing you
do do it again and do the N see three
months when the fire has dwindled you
got to throw a flog on the flame you got
to throw some logs on it so you start
you go back to your journal and you do
the things that you did when it was
spontaneous but now you have the
discipline to do it you can't be lazy
about love love is discipline also you
do the things that keep recreating the
fire that keep the kids you keep the
keep the wood on the fire you got to put
wood on that motherfucking fire the fire
is gonna go out and there are those of
you who are completely fooled your trick
tube TV and movies have lied you Disney
has tricked you into this one that it
should be easy to fall like fall in love
should just remain easy you fall and
should stay falling you're going to get
back up you're gonna dust yourself off
and look at her and you you have to face
this person you don't stay falling in
love nobody stays falling that's the
food most foolish thing in the world to
think that you know we fell in love 40
years ago and I and it has never ceased
it never cease because you still keep
doing the shit that people fall in love
do that's how you maintain the fire
right it's it's a deliberate spontaneity
you're deliberately doing the things
that are spontaneous and that
spontaneity and and and it's that
spontaneity and deliberateness have to
go together you deliberately do things
that keep you spontaneously in love like
I say I deliberately grab my wife's ass
so I can spontaneously get an erection
you got to do the things don't wait for
your for the energy to carry you right
for love to carry you anymore once
you've gotten back on your feet you're
going to get back on your feet
don't wait look for love to carry your
hands back to harass don't wait for your
fingers that care of you back to text
messaging sexy photos and messages
don't don't don't wait for yourself to
be carried into thinking about how
beautiful she is I dream about my wife
two nights ago had a dream about my wife
huh I don't know I embarrassed the shit
out of her through these idiots I don't
have embarrassment before we work
innocence we get freaky in our dreams
and the woman is laying right next to me
I can roll over and do what I'm thinking
about in my dream with her spontaneity
you see the dreams are spontaneous
because I deliberately grab her ass when
we're walking we stand up I like to grab
her ass mostly when I'm standing up when
we lay down and it's like well now we're
doing spontaneous shit when I'm being
deliberate Hannah right on her booty so
that's it man you know of course I'm
ranting I'm going on and on because I'm
Spacey right now fasting and stuff and
I'm enjoying this conversation but look
if you're falling out of love that's
fine but it's your it's your job to
rekindle that fire we all fall out of
love but do you want to stay out of love
or do you enjoy we enjoy the feeling of
being in love it's a joyful feeling it's
a great feeling you want to maintain
this don't be lazy about love
throw some logs on the fire grab her ass
send her a sex message and you'll be
fucking there 40 years from now like you
did today
done