Elliot says what so today I decide to
post one of my real controversial ideas
with regard to sexuality on my facebook
wall and it turned into a train wreck
and if you go there now you'll see that
the dust is still settling I also wrote
a blog post clarifying my idea on what
sexuality actually means and offering a
counter to what popular culture and
media calls sexy by posting a picture of
a woman who clearly was photoshopped but
nonetheless represents what the modern
mind thinks of as sexy so you can go and
take a look at that as the dust has been
settling people are asking me questions
about what I think is is a way for us to
access what I'm calling true sexuality
in this blog post if I can explain it
all here to you now I'm going to have
you read the blog post but I'm gonna
offer a idea cuz that's all this is to
your folks that's all this is is
Elliot's ideas take it or leave it if
it's interesting and resourceful to you
use it if it makes you uncomfortable
then just turn it off that being said I
you know the train wreck created such a
turmoil that people were name-calling
here for the tenth time look I enjoy
debate I enjoy sharing ideas with you I
enjoy if you challenge my ideas because
it keeps me sharp well when you resort
to name-calling it's an automatic lose
and you're banned sorry I just won't put
up with name-calling ok it's just my
rule so anyway the question that keep
getting ass is Elliot how do we access
our sexuality get to the point and the
way we do that is through deep breathing
accessing our body through deep
breathing the problem is that we've
become so tense there's so much muscular
armor in our neck in our chest or
stomach and our pelvic wall pelvic Basin
that we can't breathe deep there's the
ability to bring in the nourishing life
force through the air that we breathe in
order stimulate our body for activity
sexuality feelings has been greatly
reduced you know this is true you know
that your body dedenne's its its
feelings through lack of breathing when
you stop breathing it's not breathing I
mean your body it becomes no correct but
when you increase your breathing when
you deepen your breath especially after
breaking up the rigidity the muscular
armor in the neck chest stomach and
pelvic floor you access a part of your
parasympathetic nervous system explain
all this on the blog post where you are
now stimulating sexual hormones the way
we break up the muscular armoring is
with some of the exercises that I've
taught you some of the emotional ones
where I'm telling you say fuck you and
get all the tension out of your
shoulders but namely the breathing
exercises I said it before you've got to
breathe deep into your balls the only
way you can do that is by stretching the
neck jaw chest stomach and pelvic floor
I've showed you how to do the bow in
other videos it's the one where you put
your hands in your back here Lee open up
your mouth as wide as you can and
breathe through the open mouth when you
do this you're essentially a long gating
and stretching out all those extra
respiratory muscles you're opening your
mouth which relaxes the muscles that
would cause tension in your breathing
through your mouth and jaw you're
spreading your chest by pulling your
elbows back you're lengthening your
abdominals by leaning back and by
bending your knees and leaning back here
you're grounding yourself you know so
this all sounds weird and hokey and
stuff but it will make perfect sense
when you read the blog post down below
but to answer your question guys the way
we access our animality our humanity our
sexuality is by honoring and bringing
life back into the body getting in touch
with our emotions getting in touch with
our feelings getting in touch with our
sexuality and it begins with accessing
it through the breath breathing
breathing breathing deep breathing into
your balls or regards women down into
your sexual Center okay hope that's
helpful I'll expand more on this later
kind of burnt out today from all the
comment monitoring talk to you guys
later Elliot's it