hey what's up guys in today's post you
can read down below I spoke about
honoring your biological rhythms as a
means to achieving success I got
thinking about biological rhythms and
honoring your physiology especially as
it relates to sleep wake cycles our
circadian rhythm when asked a question
by a young man a few weeks ago at my nod
jobs summit he stands up and begins to
explain how he started on his journey of
becoming a stronger version of himself
in many regards but through the advice
of one of our favorite YouTube Instagram
motivational celebrities many of you
probably know who it is but I won't
reveal the name here ah to go to sleep
later at night you know midnight stay up
late and crush it grind it be a warrior
no go to sleep and and waking up earlier
than 5 o'clock so our friend stood up
and said man for the past year I've been
sleeping less than five hours a night
and I'm dying here he explains he
started to explain all of the symptoms
that he began to have since cutting back
on his sleep because he took the advice
of a motivational Mushmouth who told him
not to sleep at night because successful
people don't sleep you gotta want it so
bad that you don't sleep at night this
is the type of advice that you get from
Mickey Mouse motivators on Instagram on
YouTube so he stands up and offers his
uh his question what do I do
how do I crush it how do I become
successful while making good where I've
destroyed my physiology was essentially
what it is a year of not getting enough
sleep will destroy you and if you want
to be successful in any realm of life be
it like I mentioned in this the title of
this video sex or success you must begin
with self-love you've got to practice
the principles of self-love first and
when I say that it sounds real hippie
like Oh Elliott waiting
we're a flower in your ear and those
round dark sunglasses for now on the
point here is to be completely fucking
scientific about becoming successful and
it's scientifically unsound to accept
your body to produce vital resources
energy bodily energy mental energy
if you ain't fucking sleeping at night
it goes against nature do you understand
how of course there are many people who
written books and they're many ideas
about cyclical uh you know intermittent
sleeping and shit like that hey look
that's cool you can you can play a body
hacking mind hack all you want but
walking with God or walking with the Dow
walking with true nature means paying
attention to biological and daily
seasonal and epic rhythms you can't
disobey laws and expect to to always win
you know it's a shortcut you know you
don't sleep for her for a couple days or
a week look you might be able to cram a
little bit like these kids do in college
in order to study for their tests but
it's going to catch up on you it's gonna
catch up very quickly and the symptoms
my friend will not be of your liking
you'll begin to wonder why you're
catching colds you're beginning to
wonder why your muscles don't recover
you'll begin to wonder why although your
girlfriend is beautiful and seductive
why your hammer stays limp there's an so
today I'm going to talk about six
principles of self-love that improve
sexual energy because you need to
understand that the vital resource that
keeps us grinding that keeps us going
that keeps us energized it keeps us
joyful comes from our belly our sexual
energy the Chinese or in Taoist medicine
and martial arts and whatnot they call
that position down between your perineum
and your bellybutton the lower done Tien
we can refer to it as the bio battery
because scientifically it
dueces a tremendous amount of lively
hormones hormones that repair right all
your anabolic your your sex hormones
right that help repair your body and
help you um you know really feel your
oats come from your sexual gland so of
course taking good care of your body
supports the production of sexual energy
which supports the vitality of your body
which will support your ability to think
clearly sharply and succeed on any
playing field
beginning with principle number one I
spoke yesterday about reframing your
problems but essentially what I was
referring to yesterday is the principle
of keeping your stress low stress mental
stress your thoughts that's really the
first principle because if you can't
have a good conversation with yourself
then how do you expect to ever have a
good enough conversation to close a deal
with someone else
how do you expect to have a good enough
conversation to say hello and seduce a
partner into sexual relations how can
you keep good relationships with the
people that you love if you're not
having good conversations with yourself
right your career will advance your sex
life will advance and your relationships
will suffer if you harbor negative
thoughts I won't go any further because
the majority of the videos on this
channel revolve around that topic and
you can simply click back to yesterday's
video about reframing problems in order
to get on the right path for for that
principle principle number two is going
to be diet now I'm not going to go too
deep and diet because diets one of these
things like religion people get real
uncomfortable with you know any
criticism of their diet philosophy or
religion and it happens to be one of
those things that we become personally
invested in because we've got to do it
all day long so my only question to you
with regard to diet is how is that
working out for you have you chosen to
be a vegan
well great that might be just fine for
you how's it working out
for you do you have more energy or less
energy
are you sleeping better or you're
sleeping more are you hungry all the
time you have headaches what do you feel
vibrant and vital is your sex drive
improved or have you lost your libido
these are all questions to ask yourself
in order to gauge whether or not your
chosen diet choice is of any value to
you
it's just one of these strange things
where we got to get out of our own heads
and actually listen to our bodies
regardless of the religion that you've
adopted you got to ask yourself is this
thing helping us or is it hurting us
okay so with diet
be mindful I will say that it is a
principle to eat Whole Foods so do your
best the next one would be hydration it
astonishes me how many people don't even
drink water I've ranted about this in
many videos I've made several videos
about drinking water you can watch some
of those but at the same time we still
have people who think that Gatorade and
coffee and sugary bubbly drinks are
going to support them on their journey
by offering some sort of magical
hydration electrolyte mixture or the
promise of more energy and friendship
like have a Coke and a smile right again
all up in the head one of the ways to
gauge whether or not your diet and your
hydration your food and drink is
supporting you is your digestive health
are you constipated right because if
you're constipated it means you haven't
taken a shit yet today and we haven't
taken a shit for a couple of days you
start a pile up with shit and then when
someone says you're full of shit they'd
be completely accurate drinking enough
water to make sure that the food passes
through is eating enough Whole Foods to
have the fiber associated with healthy
digestion again I'm not giving you any
bullet points to follow I'm saying pay
attention to your body the next one
would be exercise and exercises the same
damn thing you've got kettle bell nazis
and you got people who'll do nothing but
bodybuilding and call everything else
hippy workouts
well look how's that working out for you
we could use the same gauge is your
workout supporting your mechanics is
your workout supporting your body fat
percentage or your ratio of muscle to
body nobody fat is your exercise program
supporting your energy or do your
workouts train you and you can't recover
for three days right
you could be crushing it in the gym like
I used to you know by the way of all of
my advice my ideas in these videos
typically come from me making mistakes
in the past me learning things along the
way me finding tips and tricks that
helped me as I was struggling on this
journey one thing for sure I know how to
abuse myself with barbells and stones
and tires but it's dawned on me it's
been my experience that the less I abuse
myself in the gym the more successful I
have in other areas of my life I'm more
available to have loving relations with
my wife I'm more available energy wise
and mental wise for my children in my my
friends and my co-workers I have more
energy to make these videos I have more
energy for my creative work by daily
writing so the exercise program that I
engage in today has to support those
things I value in my life and beating
the fuck out of myself with heavy
barbells doesn't support the strongest
version of one becoming so my exercise
is like medicine is I believe yours
should be if you're a football player in
high school well then by golly you ought
to do some heavy squats on the other
hand the type of work that I do requires
that I have an adequate amount of energy
and the capacity to breathe fully that's
the other thing you better consider with
regard to biological rhythms as well as
your physical ourselves skeletal system
you know are you are you free enough to
breathe deeply can you breathe into your
balls is it is it mechanically possible
for you a lot of people it isn't one of
my friends I work with one of the
interns at the gym and
but the other day I asked him to do some
deep belly breathing and he had a
complete reverse breathing pattern he
couldn't breathe into his balls it just
took a simple reframing of the breathing
mechanism showing him that you know we
want to inhale first with the belly
about 1/3 of the way then begin or one
third of the way I believe and then you
begin to expand your upper body 2/3 you
know we begin with our belly and then
the ribcage begins to expand most people
breathe up here and suck their belly in
all right so the mechanics are off so
that brings us to so we did exercise the
next would be rhythms and rhythms are
heavily discussed in my blog post down
below as it relates to sleep and rest
we've got body biological rhythms like
how do your heart health
you know we can consider the rhythm of
your heart an indicator of good health
if you have high blood pressure that
means your rhythms are a little bit off
the rhythm of your digestion again I
mentioned constipation but there should
be a rhythm of foody and food out but if
you're going to food in food in food in
food in and nothing out your rhythms are
a little screwed up we don't take it
into great consideration but annual
rhythm set play a tremendous part in how
we feel in our success in the world if
you realize that you know during
summertime you have a tendency to change
which is normal because even the nature
changes around us or as fall comes
around and winter time comes about if
your energy seems to recede you feel
like you're going in a little bit some
people call it depression which is an
accurate way of describing the energy
receding but be aware of it know that
every year around this time I start to
head into a sort of depression head it
off at the past by recognizing boy it
might mean that you know during this
time of the year I should change my diet
a little bit maybe more hearty healthy
foods as opposed to you know fruits and
light foods that I would eat during the
year this is
I'm telling you what to do during the
summer most all you want to do I'm just
telling you know there's are things you
might want to pay attention to the the
clock changes this time' here are you
sure you've got your sleep setup so that
you're getting adequate amounts of it
right are you taking the right
supplements from what I understand by
taking fish oil supplements in darker
times of the year supports our brain
health because we're not getting the
vitamin D from the sunshine just take
notice and of course I'll throw in the
hippie idea of epochs or epochs right
the epoch me pop you know or or
generations I don't even have to go that
far
generations there's rhythms in history
human history we can look at our history
books and recognize where we are you
know many people rekha relate to the
rise and fall of the Roman Empire as it
relates to where we find ourselves and
the American Empire right now you know
there are some parallels to when Rome
would as it was at its height and when
it was starting to see its decline this
is normally natural everything that
rises Falls the US has been up on an
incline for many years but there are
those that believe that the signposts
are shining that perhaps were at a
plateau or descend then you know of
course that's a lot of opinion and there
are experts that are better suited to
them to advise you on that but just
recognize that there are rhythms empires
rise and fall so on and so forth and
finally brilliant breathing as a common
thread throughout all your breathing
will be affected by your mental stress
but your ability to breathe will handle
your mental stress you'll be better at
dealing mental stress your diet affects
your breathing I mean just take a notice
take notice of how you breathe when you
drink caffeine hydration again there's a
sympathetic response to deep being
dehydrated which will affect your
breathing exercise of course we know
that because we breathe while we
exercise either be a cardiovascularly or
with the valsalva maneuver our moving
heavy weights
rhythms obviously because there's an
inhalation and an exhalation all day
long do you recognize your breathing
rhythm or you know Gordon's with healthy
breathing rhythms that's it so those are
the six principles for sex money and
self-love you want to be a success in
Aird any area of your life you've got to
begin with your health you've got to
begin with becoming a stronger version
of yourself first you might think of
yourself as a warrior by abusing your
body but that's just called masochism a
true warrior is devoted to his body he's
disciplined about the foods he eats the
water he drinks and the rhythms in his
life and he's very decisive about what
it is he wants in life and all the
commitments associated with getting it
done