that interesting question from our buddy
programmer guy 88 because it was he
wants to know how is it that he can't
finish books he wants to learn you know
there are a couple books that he's
really interested in he says that he's
interested in he starts reading it and
he just like he can't get through it
he's got a list of books that are
half-finished or whatever the case may
be how is it that Elliott perhaps can
get through books well the fact is
Elliott does not get through every
single book that he reads what you've
got to do is you've got to approach your
education right because that's really
what it is the way I see it
see I don't read for pleasure and like
my wife my wife I'm funny because we
will sit and read in the evening time
and I'm reading like stuff about
neuroplasticity and she's reading like
Fifty Shades of Grey
right so she gets through books quickly
and I'm like scratching my head while
I'm reading because I read with a
purpose when I'm reading a book I have
to feel as if there is something I can
extract from this book I'm not reading
it just because it in fact I'm a slow
reader I'm not a good reader but I'm
reading with a purpose I am an innocent
in such a state when I'm reading these
books that the words are literally
becoming a part of my physiology I'm
absorbing them and some books the way
they're written by some authors are more
easily absorbed by my consciousness than
other books and I will know within a
matter of chapters if this book is being
absorbed into my consciousness or not
and it has to do with a lot of different
factors one being the way the author
presents the ideas okay so you can't
blame yourself
when the books he wants to read is the
Communist Manifesto right so I've never
read that by Karl Marx but I'm assuming
that it is like a deep philosophical
discourse that's probably like like rats
your brain as you're reading it and it
may not be pleasurable learning has to
be done in the state of pleasure that
you should yet write that shit down
learning needs to be done in a state of
pleasure because pleasure softens the
body it softens the mind and it allows
allows in right right learning is like
oh is a hidden behavior
vagina behavior you've got to soften
just like the vagina so that you can
receive the potency of the books that
you're reading or what you're learning
you've got a soften you've got to
breathe so that you can literally absorb
the words into your consciousness if you
have to attack the reading and that such
that it causes you to grow tired or
uncomfortable that means it's just you
shouldn't be reading that it's just the
way we and we're all very different so I
can read Ralph Waldo Emerson right most
people read Ralph Waldo Emerson and
they're like what the fuck is this guy
saying because he talks in circles and
there's like so much going on and it's
written like old old old American
English like nobody talks like that
anymore but for some reason I can soften
to his words I think because they're so
dense that I literally have to go into a
meditative state in Hawaii in order to
read it I can't read Emerson when I'm
like anxious I have to read Emerson when
I'm soft when it's like I'm kicking back
I'm relaxing and I'm just like right I
like reading
Alexander Lowen a lot of people can't
stand out it's old its end alone because
he's a scientist
I mean the guy was a medical doctor at
so many medical doctor degrees and he
was a he was a genius but he writes like
a poem like a poet right so it's like
it's all the scientific shit but he
writes it's so poetically and I love it
because I enjoy poetry if you can figure
it out so when I read it I can lay back
and absorb some people are just
different like they they like very
direct words like I can't read too many
books that are just very like if I see
numbers on a page like if there are
statistics no fucking page I'm like like
my eyes just like glaze oh or I just
can't read it
some people they really delve into it
they're more I guess they're more active
learners they really delve into it they
see numbers and they're like calculating
shit and it's like all happening inside
them we're all very different it's not
right or wrong so my invitation is to
first discover figure out what kind of
learner are you right what kind of what
kind of authors can you learn from if
you're reading Marx and you can't finish
the book then don't read Marx
but guess what there are tens of
thousands of other authors that may have
read marks and then represented his
words in such a way that you can absorb
it don't feel guilty don't feel see a
lot of times when we when we're trying
to learn when we're studying we're
reading books we're doing it in a very
narcissistic way you know we want to
prove prove that I can read this prove
that I read this fuck that you can't be
narcissistic about learning learning
again has to be a softening of the mind
even if you're an active learner like a
number person you have to actually open
up there's a part of you that needs to
open up to allow that stuff in and that
way you can actually instead of just
being engaged in the activity of reading
you are actually learning you know a lot
of people want to know how is it that I
learned so much well it's not because I
read them I do be a lot but it's not
because I read a lot
suppose I absorb a lot and that you want
to get yourself into that state of mind
I think a really good course for you to
study would be accelerated learning
techniques by Brian Tracy and he talks a
lot about this all about the psychology
of learning right I haven't listened to
that in what in years but I think
there's a lot of good stuff in it so
that's it dude it's how do you approach
your studies and it's finding the right
teachers who present the material in a
way that's resourceful to you good luck