what's up gentlemen today we have a
question for one of our buddies here who
asked about becoming the strongest
version of himself and wonders how do
you balance that concept with the idea
of wanting to be perfect so he seeks
perfection and everything he does to
such a degree that he becomes obsessed
with it and he knows that it's not
healthy but he's looking for some
perspective on it perhaps something to
allow him to feel as if his journey
towards becoming the strongest version
of himself can be colored with
imperfections it's okay to be imperfect
and the reason why I took this question
is because one of the most powerful
quotes that I complete I often repeat to
myself that was taught to me by a man
named Dan Kennedy when I was studying
business and marketing was this that
success is cooked up in a dirty kitchen
what that means is and the way I
perceive that is is that as long as
there's momentum as long as you're
getting up every single day and moving
towards your particular ideal you're
worthy ideal you are winning it is
success it's not necessarily having all
the eggs lined up having everything
perfect and clean having everything set
properly in the and making sure that the
stars are aligned its momentum are you
doing something today and the metaphor
of a dirty kitchen makes perfect sense
because a dirty kitchen is a kitchen
where there's a lot of activity going on
am i saying dirty like there's
cockroaches and rats shit I'm saying
dirty meaning like you know things are
left about and you know it looks like
someone's cooking in here looks like
someone's doing something it's an active
circumstance that's being perceived from
the outside and there it is my friend
that is that is really the secret to
becoming the strongest version yourself
and when I say that term becoming it is
literal you don't become you don't land
on you don't achieve the stronger
version of yourself you're constantly in
a state of becoming doing momentum
activity my father used to say I believe
this to this day he still says it he
says son as long as you get up every
single day and work you will be a
success you'll have nothing to worry
about
you'll always be taken care of but you
must maintain the momentum of working
every single day and that is my advice
to you young friend it is not to achieve
a particular ideal that you set for
yourself and the castle's of yours in
your sky in your mind but it is to work
every single day in the same way that
Earl Nightingale says success is the
progressive realisation of a worthy
ideal it's the progression the
progressive realization of what might be
perfect but you never ever ever ever
attain to perfection
besides the fact that perfection is
completely subjective you're just gonna
make yourself neurotic trying to achieve
it you'll never be perfect it will never
be perfect but you do it every single
day done