so we've got a question here about how
to be good at being bad and basically
the question is how do I accept it when
someone beats me or someone's better
than me at something I'm a very
competitive person but I can't get over
this deep-seated feeling of resentment
and anger towards someone who's better
than me right we live in a world where
everyone's a winner and you should pack
the winner on the back if you happen to
be a loser feel good for him right feel
good for the guy that's done better than
you the guy who's achieving greater
goals than you beating you winning and
you're not right we should all feel good
for each other we should all accept
everybody as a winner right if you're
anything like me which apparently are
you are you've got this you know the
perpetual phallic narcissist ideal that
I should always win I'm always striving
and I don't want anybody to beat me as
much as I stand up here and I offer you
guys all these philosophical ideas on
becoming the strongest version yourself
I cannot lie and say that I don't become
hateful towards people who are crushing
it where I'm not right this is I think
this is normal and natural for most
people but we've suppressed that you
know and the way I deal with it is to do
as I typically recommend and that is to
turn the attention back to yourself so
if you're projecting outwards and you're
you're literally spilling your energy in
you're throwing it out and being upset
angry or jealous because really that's a
big part of it we've got to admit you
know it is this is a form of jealousy
towards someone who's beaten you damn
that guy got me he beat me or he's
winning and you're not then you know in
business in relationships and sports in
life whatever it is and you feel
animosity towards that person the very
first thing you've got to do is
recognize that the part of the reason
why you feel that way towards that
person is because you know you can do
that to you see so I get very upset not
so much with that person I think I am
and you think you are it's not that
you're hateful towards them you just are
eating up on the inside because you
realize
I can beat him I can do that that is
something in me that's being reflected
in another human being and it's
uncomfortable I totally get it the
reality is the real feeling is coming
from a sense that there is more
available to you yet you haven't
produced it yet so you've got to get
busy quickly turn your attention back to
yourself get busy doing the things you
need to do to get where he's going right
so take your attention off of him don't
worry so much about him winning see it I
that guy got me and then you turn your
energy back to or two what can I do next
that should always be your your next
step what can I do next what am I going
to do about this not how can I take him
down why he's a douche bag and I'm not
why he doesn't deserve that and I do all
of that serves no one and it's stupid
quite frankly would you go to do is turn
the attention back to yourself and say
okay boom he's got me I can see a place
where he's a bit better than me how can
I build that in me so if for example you
see that that guy you know let's say
it's sports and you see boy he's a
little bit faster than me alright cool
got it got it gotcha you go back and you
start focusing one hundred percent of
your effort on building up that weaker
skill in you now you're doing what i
call becoming a stronger version of
yourself you become a stronger version
of yourself and that is going to afford
you the capacity to supersede anybody
else who's outwardly focused so that's
it man i don't want to make this too
long i tend to rant don't worry so much
about the perseid you're going to feel
it don't suppress it that's one of our
biggest problems we tend to suppress our
feelings your feelings are right
feelings are always right what is
happening in your body is a function of
the autonomic nervous system it is free
from your conscious thought you are
feeling this feelings happen except
appreciate realize what it is but then
don't tie negative associations to it
and honestly recognize it for what it is
it is a perception that you are not
living up to the magnificence that's in
you and then turn your energy towards
yourself and focus on becoming stronger
version of yourself that was a long
video to make a simple point good luck