so we got a great question from our 18
year old friend who wants to overcome
what he calls built-in fears so
specifically this is the fear of
speaking up or speaking out when he
feels he has something important to say
and it is a manifestation of the
experiences that he had as a child where
his father was an adult you know we all
experiences are sort of oppressive
towards the expression of a child so a
lot of the shut up sit down what you
have to say is it important I don't care
what you have to say zip it that type of
attitude that authoritative stronger
bigger bigger figures in our lives
have have pushed on us so you end up in
a situation where you want to speak up
you want to object in some particular
way but you're quickly shut down and
made to believe that what you have to
say isn't important now you don't carry
this consciously with you as you go
about your life as an adult or in school
but it's there there's this feeling that
was injected in you there was a seed
dropped in you that basically says what
you have to say is not that important
please sit down shut up wait your turn
because what happens is we then go to
school where we have to get along with
the rest of school mates and raise our
hands if there's something that we want
to say and perhaps what we have to say
is looked upon as enlightening and
interesting or just rejected by the
other students and by the teachers a lot
of kids a lot of people they just
they're not willing to do this they
don't want to speak up because of that
fear of rejection which is a left over
manifestation the experiences that they
had when they were told to sit down and
shut up
as children so everybody everybody ends
up I say everybody but not everyone and
not you for any longer because I'm going
to teach you something goes about their
lives not wanting to ask their boss
arrey for a raise or making some
suggestion in the workplace their wife
they might want to speak to their wife
or to someone a friend they might want
to speak up and say something and in
school and they just bite their tongue
they sit down they shut up and they just
kind of Fester you know what happens
because this is what you're experiencing
that held back expression that you feel
is needs to be let out grows like a
cancer inside you because you literally
have to use the muscular system you know
they say bite your tongue because you're
literally punching your jaw you use your
muscular system to reduce the energy in
your body that would allow you to BA
speak up I have something to say
speaking expressing is physical so
you've got to use your body to depress
that thing and it leads to different
forms of depression anxiety frustration
as you're experiencing because now there
are things that you want to say to
people but you just can't you won't and
it's eating you alive so two things I
want to share with you the very first
one is a very broad suggestion for fear
Emerson once said move in the direction
of your fears and fear will essentially
move out the way something of that
nature you know do the thing you fear
most and the death of fear is certain
that's exactly how it goes actually so a
lot of times we're fearful and and you
do exactly what you're doing you start
to rationalize well maybe I should ask
la host what should I do about this fear
maybe there's a book about how to speak
up in public maybe there's a book about
communication maybe there is a teacher
or a course or a mentor that I could go
to about how to express myself verbally
when all these things are just natural
within you but you're looking for
permission you're looking for
information you're trying to attack the
situation from the conscious level when
expression really happens in the body
then happen in the head although we'd
like to think that you know I'm very
smart so I'm bringing forth what it is
that's happening in me expression
happens here in your bodies you've got
to speak it up you got to do it so you
actually have to stop thinking about
getting over the fear of whatever it is
that you're afraid of you know I know a
lot of different people are watching
this with multiple different fears and
do the fucking thing you're scared of
you've got to do it you can't think
about it you can't talk about it you
have to actually move towards it no
matter how scary it is and I'm of the
opinion that the scarier the fucking
thing is the more you have to do it I
often speak to young people and I say
okay well you're not sure about what you
want to do in your life you've got three
options right and then they'll spell out
the three options and I'm watching I'm
watching the body language because
I know the expression happens in the
body happens in your eyes it happens in
your facial expression it happens to the
way you breathe and then they'll go well
option number one bubble bubble bubble
blah okay cool
option number two okay well very good
option number three that's what they'll
do and when I see that I don't even want
to know the option is that's it that's
the one that's what you have to do but
Elliot I didn't tell you what I have to
do yet I saw the fear in your expression
that is the thing you have to do because
if you don't there are a number of
things that are going to happen number
one you're not going to evolve in the
way that God of the universe or Allah
what the fuck you want to call it you
guys get upset with me when I say God
it's part of these might say it wants to
see you evolve the world is evolving
earth is evolving humanity is evolving
the spirit is evolving this thing is
going somewhere and we're all called to
do a particular work and it's usually
something that is outside the bounds of
the conventional way of doing things
because evolution doesn't abide by
conventional rules okay so you're so by
not moving forward in the in the
direction of your dreams not moving
forward into the thing that you fear
most you're doing a big disservice not
just to yourself it's a whole fucking
world because we're evolving here and
you're a goddamn anchor you got to do
that thing no matter how crazy it looks
but Elliott that's it you know everyone
says this is nuts everyone says I
shouldn't do it
everyone buh buh buh blah fuck everyone
you I saw it right away you're scared of
it because it's happening in you and
there's resistance if it's happening
into you stop resisting it and allow it
to happen
imagine if jesus christs or Gandhi or
Martin Luther King
we're like uh-uh I can't do it
everyone's gonna hate me no one's gonna
like me Madge Annette betcha Martin
Luther King who the white folks is just
gonna kill me well they always kill you
whenever you have something important to
say you're bound to get killed I mean
think about those dudes they were all
killed right people that got important
shit to say never have an easy road
ahead of
but this brings me to my second point
which I'm kind of already alluding to do
the thing that you fear in the death of
fear is certain but remove yourself from
the expression of the the thing that you
want to say we like to think well
Elliott Hulse has something to say I've
got something to say Bob I'm Bob Jones
and I've got something to say if you
take that attitude you it's a lot more
difficult than if you approach it from
an attitude of selflessness so just
think about those magnificent men that I
spoke about think about where Luther
King right if he was like Martin Luther
King has something to say Martin Luther
King is a genius and y'all better listen
to him then it would have been very
difficult to put himself in a situation
where he is now sacrificing himself he
was crucified right we crucify these
guys with big fucking mouths so what you
got to do is speak from a place of
service in stem saying I have something
to say think to yourself there is
something very important that needs to
be said okay
there is something there's something
very important that needs to be
expressed over here it's happening over
here and it needs to come out see a lot
of times that's how I approach these
videos that's how I approach my answers
it's not how can I look smarter how can
Elliott Hulse be more revered for his
brilliant ideas about how to navigate
life because a lot of times I could just
in heat for the shit that I say I say
what I have to say not because Elliott
Hulse needs to express himself and gain
notoriety but because this is just we
need to be fucking said and that's a
dangerous place to be because some
people just aren't going to like you but
the people's lives that you do enhance
because of your speaking up verbally
getting over your fears and expressing
that which is happening in you
regardless are going to love you that
much more you are holding back a
tremendous service to the world by not
speaking up if there's something
happening in you there's a flowering in
you
it is your responsibility to offer that
flower to the world and it nine times
out of ten if it's very potent it's
going to be rejected severely but it
will also be embraced severely
so let's come full circle because
obviously there are a lot of points that
I I felt needed to be made with regard
to fear and your expression one of the
things you need to get over my friend is
that what you have to say is either
right or wrong because if you're
constantly searching and surfing for
that thing which will be embraced by the
majority you will never say anything
important because everyone will just say
oh yeah oh sure of course
and then they'll look you they'll kind
of look elsewhere because you're not
saying anything and for you to actually
want to speak up and be holding it back
and be battling the demons associated
with fear
of expressing yourself means that
there's probably something pretty
important and guess what you're gonna
piss some people off
don't be so attached to the things that
you say either there was a time when
artists poets speakers and people who
basically presented themselves to others
in any way shape or form because it
could simply be when you're speaking to
your family
we're given free license to allow the
Meuse they would call it the muse or I
think another term was the daemon to
speak through them so there was afforded
a sort of detachment between the person
who's actually saying something and the
thing that's being said and that person
would never take personal responsibility
for the thing that's being said because
it was always it was oh he was always
granted the fact that well this is what
their Muse is doing through me this is
what my Daymond is speaking through me
and the public the world cuz if you
search this stuff it says oh this is all
basically how a lot of like the Greek
philosophers went about things and poets
and artists you know this is a Western
idea also the people that heard what
they had to say very often wouldn't
attach them to the thing that's being
said they would say boy the daemon is
doing something real strange through
that guy or boy the spirits are really
with him his muse is really with him
right now
or boy I wonder what the muse is doing
through him because he's going it seems
like he's going nuts there was a sort of
detachment from the speaker and the
thing that's being said so if you get a
tap if you could adopt that sort of
paradigm when you're going ahead and you
know you want to raise your hand you
want to speak do not be personally
identified with it comes out because
Pete if people attack the thing that's
being said you can step back and say
well that's what was said and not feel
as if you're being personally attacked
these are all techniques and tools that
are going to support your self-esteem as
you go about life these are things that
I do you know and again I'm saying this
I guarantee you there's a lot of people
el8 your fucking nut that doesn't make
any fucking sense you're an asshole why
would you say that
of course you're personally responsible
for the things that you say well guess
what
when those people say that
I don't really care because I'm detached
from the thing so I'm already immune
from the abuse you see so speak up my
friend speak up because your personal
evolution is intrinsically linked to
your overcoming fears and speak up
because what you have to say will
contribute to human evolution in
whatever way it shows up I'm done