you know today we got a question that's
a really good follow-up to our
conversation yesterday about sex
relationships and women and today we're
going to talk about your mission your
purpose and whether or not your partner
is supporting you or an anchor on your
Purpose Driven lifestyle so we got a
question here from screen name we've got
hi all right he goes on a said Elliot
say Elliot I'm a huge fan of your work
especially your philosophy and outlook
on life I've been inspired by what you
said in your videos about giving advice
on choosing your own path in life I'm in
a dilemma that has torn me for sometime
and I would like your advice I've been
going out with my girlfriend for about a
year and I love her very much she's an
amazing woman and I'd like to spend my
life with her
the problem is I'm passionate about
music specifically creating music and
I'm in a band I'm barely starting to
pursue my love for creating music but my
girlfriend wants me to get a degree in
something to have a back-up plan
because it's hard to have stable income
with music I want to make her happy but
at the same time I don't want to get in
debt for a degree I don't really care
about whatever it may be I don't want to
get a degree in music because it can
cost a lot of money and many times is
useless
I want to create music and sell my music
and tour with my band but she wants me
to have a stable job in career I want to
have both her and music but if I'm not
going to get a degree she may end up
breaking up with me because she doesn't
want to struggle financially and be with
someone who is unstable any advice man
well quite a bit and that little piece
there brother man and I read your
question and I decided boy since there
are so many different ways to start
let's choose one and the first place I'd
like to begin with you is by sharing my
experience I mean really that's all I
can ever do is share my experience
because any
that comes from a book or comes from
someone else or comes from some
celestial idea doesn't have the
grounding of this is what works for me
and when I first started dating Colleen
when we were in high school I was
already very clear about my purpose my
Okhla head-injured introduced me to
strength training I had been playing
football and I knew I was going to
either be a professional athlete or a
coach well I ended up being both but I
also had a girlfriend and very early on
we started having conversations about
what it would be like to live a life
together and I warned her she she might
even talk about this I think she spoke
about this in a interview we did once I
warned her I said look I'm going hard
I've got a mission it's going to be a
bumpy road I'm on there going to be
challenges I'm ready for that struggle
but I'm never going to stop until I get
where I'm going I love you and I would
like to have you come along with me this
is where I'm going and you can either
come with me or not I said that to her
when I was probably about 17 or 18 years
old and you can see the result I'm well
on my path dominating it reaching my
mission clarifying my purpose and my
wife is the perfect partner teammate
while I attack the world and get things
done that need to be done through me
which is to become a stronger version of
myself and empower others I'm very clear
about my purpose very clear about my
mission and I design my relationships
around making sure that I'm everything
that I should be here's the thing we
need to understand about masculine and
feminine energy it's not a right thing
or a wrong thing masculine feminine
energy are like the yin-yang symbol we
need it for completeness and when I say
masculine and feminine I'm not talking
just about penis and vagina I'm not
speaking specifically about men and
women I'm
about the predominant energy that men
typically carry in varying degrees and
the predominant energy that women carry
in Portman varying degrees the
particular mimic the energy that men
carry is masculine right and masculine
energies energy is very purpose-driven
it's very single-minded it's very
mission oriented going in a particular
direction right men's concentration or
the masculine concentration the
masculine trait associated with focus
can also be a detriment right I've got
children I've got three girls and a boy
what I call for the girls whether
they're did on their iPads they're
reading something or watching TV when I
call for the girls there's an immediate
yes daddy and they come they relates to
me when I call Benjamin maybe because
he's the youngest and he's a brat he's
not a brat he's a boy when I call
Benjamin he might not hear me because
he's focused in on the thing that he's
doing whatever it is that he's doing I
can get upset but I got to realize the
dudes focused Benjamin no call Benjamin
I go to find out what he's doing he's
playing with some Legos and I say dude
did you hear me calling you
no daddy and he starts to explain what
he's doing with the thing that he's
doing if I went up to one of my
daughters and they were playing a game
and I said did you hear what I was doing
they probably invite me to join
that's why I've worn tiaras and and
dresses and makeup and shit like that
tea parties right I'm a dad to girls
the masculine mind is focused right know
them and again it's just a generality
doesn't mean that we all have masculine
and feminine energy traits you study
Jungian psychology Carl Jung refers it
to the anima animus psychological
aspects that we all carry but the
feminine energy is much more associated
with relating right relating
relationship nurturing and in order for
that to happen you need a certain level
or women need a certain level of
stability this is why women nest when
they're nursing women and that's why
even if you look at female cats right
like if they're if they're going to
build their life which means make more
people which is associated with
relationship this is what the feminine
does and there are hormones associated
with it like oxytocin they like they
need to find a stable little cozy area
when I say stable I mean just like out
of the knot and don't you don't have
wind and rain on you right stability is
very everything in life is very
subjective it's the law of relativity
right relative stability could mean well
I've got a roof over my head versus I've
got $10,000 or $50,000 in the bank
completely relative the cat is safe the
female cat will allow herself to swim in
all her femininity and share her love
with her young ones in an alley on the
road under under a dumpster I'm not
saying that that's what needs to happen
what I'm saying is that you've got to
realize the contrast between the
masculine and feminine energy and you've
got to learn how to play with each other
by recognizing honoring respecting the
natural Ink inclinations in one another
I recognise the feminine in my wife and
I do my best great environment and a
life so that she can blossom fully but
she also very early on gave me
permission gave me room but not only
that but encouraged me on my purpose on
my mission dominating and she has reaped
the gifts
for supporting me in that way you know a
lot of the ideas in the Bible may seem
outdated but you know there are various
Maxim's that are are steeped in wisdom
and one of them which oftentimes gets
misunderstood or bastardize and even
used as a weapon both by men and women
is this statement that women should
respect their men men love your woman
well of your wife but if you understand
masculine Fenna net feminine energy and
how to get along with one another you'll
start to realize you begin to realize
that yes it that word respect makes
sense meaning that a man is on his path
and you got to let him be on his path
you can't nag him off his path this is
what a lot of women try to do is what a
lot of men allow themselves to be done
to like yourself you're about to get in
that trap dude you love her I get it you
love her but mission is number one for
men hard pill to swallow
can it be done can you have a wonderful
relationship admission well all I can do
is share my experience the next one is
financial stability is a myth now this
could be a totally other second video
and I kind of already started relating
to you this idea of relativity but one
of the things that we've got to come to
grips ourselves so that we can relate it
to other people especially those that
don't understand our mission money comes
after mission mission is first also
comes before women comes before money
mission is number one and when it comes
to mission you've got to realize that
when you're on your path you're actually
building up internal resources it's who
you're becoming that matters another one
from Jesus is don't build up your
material wealth in this world he said
something to the effect of like don't
build up your wealth here in this world
build up your world your wealth in my
kingdom the kingdom within right
the kingdom here inside crossroads right
in my heart right in your heart you got
to understand that that's where you're
gaining wealth because currency can be
devalued which it is there is inflation
the dollar could at any moment because
we do live in a tumultuous world the
dollar or whatever currency you're using
you can talk to the Germans you can talk
to the to the to the Greeks
you can talk to various nations who've
had their currency collapse and what you
think is $10,000 in your bank account is
actually worth shit as the Russians
I've heard stories about them using
their currency in order to stoke fires
because it was worth nothing now you
spent your entire world building up
these material wealth and it dissolves
into nothing and you are empty because
you're a man on no mission but you've
got your girlfriend weak finally dude
I'll leave you with one more if you read
my newsletter today I did not post it on
my blog because well it's a special
message that is intended just for those
who on the VIP newsletter if you read my
message today you got the bit of wisdom
from one of our fellow kings about not
giving up and he refers to dying before
he gives up on his path that is the type
of commitment I'm talking about
yesterday when I made the video about
commitment devotion discipline it means
you dominate your path till you die my
friend so even if you go and start your
music company you begin with your band
things don't work out your girlfriend
leaves you you find yourself in a very
compromised and even depressive place
understand that those challenges those
heartbreaks those things falling apart
are merely opportunities for you to grow
stronger my friend
embrace them fully and finally when you
embrace your mission fully when you go
full-bore in your path and you decide
that you're not going to give up until
you die you offer the world your gift
that's what this is all about guys when
I say become the strongest version of
yourself it is the only one half of the
equation we offer our gifts to the world
when we're living our passion when we're
living our purpose and your partner your
woman your man whoever it is who you're
deciding to build your life with side by
side can either be an anchor or a
booster someone who supports you someone
who helps you and if your woman's vision
is too small if you can't enroll her in
the purpose the mission the vision the
dominance by which you want to take this
world and give it your energy and make a
love to everything that you do then
maybe you need a new woman
done
Hey