so we got a question from another one of
our buddies who's ended up in the
dreaded friend zone right and this is
where a woman tells you that she loves
you like a brother because she doesn't
respect you like a man you end up there
because you didn't take action when the
arc of attraction offered itself at the
right time you know the attraction of a
man and a woman the attraction of
opposites yin and yang if you will come
together through the arc of sexual
attraction regardless of if you call
each other friends or not the fact is
that you're drawn to each other
because of sexual attraction in its many
forms what happens with that
relationship is contingent upon how the
people either get out of the way and
allow it to happen or step in either
because of poor self-esteem which is
usually what it is or perhaps you know
you're already in a relationship the arc
of attraction is going to happen even
when you're in other relationships so if
you're married or you already have a
girlfriend and you recognize the arc of
attraction with someone then they're you
suppress it
well not necessary suppress it but you
you transmutate it I've spoken about
this before you don't act upon it yeah
it's like hey I'd like to fuck you but
this is just not going to work in the
long term me having sex with you is just
not going to be a good decision so you
know you take that energy and you you
directed elsewhere the fact is that it
always that's that's what's bringing
people together we you know might not be
politically correct but men and women
don't just become friends all right it
they they're attracted to each other and
then they decide what they're going to
do about that even we're going to have
sex or we're just going to say hey I'd
love to but no or one of the people the
guy that ends up in the friendzone is
gets cold feet doesn't know how to
proceed gets in his own way and doesn't
take action when all opportunities have
opened themselves up so here's the
situation now they're friends you know
they go shopping for shoes together they
laugh and giggle and then she goes and
talks to another guy and you're left
there with blue balls feeling like you
know I'm dying for your hair
and you just left me or every time you
get together you want to do girly stuff
like shop for shoes and pocketbooks and
you know and talk about the boys that
she has a crush on right your friend so
what do you do dude you cannot be
friends with her any longer you're not
friends you're never friends to begin
with you were two people who were
attracted to each other right wanted to
have sex because that's what brings
people together and you didn't take
action now there's this uncomfortable
awkward relationship where you're
giggling but really you want to put it
on her and and you're suppressing all
this shit and she's walking all over you
she's treating you like the bitch right
now because she's carrying you around
like a you know like a boy on a on a
leash and treating you like crap and
every once in a while she kind of like
flirts with you this morning what he
said sports with you and kind of like
you know tosses the cheek and it is like
it too bad because she knows that you're
not aggressive she knows that you're not
going to take it so you got a limb
innate the relationship that you're
having with this girl right now it's
just not going to work because you're
making yourself sick and she's playing
with you so without being rude you
literally have to just straight hey I'm
going somewhere else
now this is your opportunity once you've
broken the bondage of that friendship
that so-called evil friendship
friendzone when you broken the bonds of
that you've got to assert yourself you
got to you've got to make up for the
damage do you understand you've gotta
you gotta prove yourself again and that
means go and be with another woman this
time fix up fix what you screwed up last
time you screwed up last time and she's
still draining you she's still screwing
you up you gotta cut that shit off she's
draining your energy like a fucking
leech and you've already hesitated so
you've died you got to cut that off stop
letting her suck your energy and go and
find a new opportunity where you can
take aggressive action the arc of
attraction is there move forward you're
it's a lot you're allowed to make
mistakes we've all done this before I've
been in the friendzone before I made
mistakes before we've all made mistakes
before but you can't like by staying
friends with her you're remade
that mistake and you're letting that
mistake drag on right I know you love
her you have warm feelings towards her
but the only way this is going to work
is if you cut that shit off and then
make right with another girl now you're
just going to happen when you make right
with another with another girl number
one cuz is not you know it's always
about me
self-centered Elliott when I say me I
mean always think about yourself what's
happening to you is you're getting
stronger where you were once week you
were weakened your aggressive action
towards the sexual yielding of a woman
but now you're exercising that shit so
you're growing stronger right boom
you've got the opportunity again you
exercise it hey what is exercising do
makes you stronger so you're growing
stronger and your ability to assert
yourself sexually with a woman number
two hey you get another chance like you
know you might find another woman it
turns out like - I'm so happy I met her
she's the one she will always be the one
and you end up living happily ever after
and number three she's going to see you
acting like a man and she's gonna say oh
shit he's got balls I wonder why he
didn't move his balls towards me she's
gonna second-guess herself and she's
gonna come crawling right back to you
dude she's gonna want to know what
happened you know you never tried that
with me so you win on multiple fronts
but I got to tell you you got it you got
to take that leech off she's a leech on
you right now don't me she's a bad woman
she's a bad person but you know you
didn't take the opportunity to get what
she wanted now she's taking the
opportunity to get what she wants and
that's to carry around like a little
bitch making you do you know friendly
things and never giving it up to you
so that's it dude good luck with that
one you know once you do it once you do
it twice it starts becoming pattern
starts becoming habit you get stronger
and then you'll never end up in a friend
zone again when you find that you're a
friend with a woman you either cut it
off or you're mutually greet agreeing
that boy I'd like to take you and she's
like yeah I'd like to take you but it's
not appropriate you know you're gonna
have relationships like that you can end
up working in an office and they're
going to be attractive girls and you're
attractive
her and like you're both gonna look at
each other like drooling but you're
married and she's in a book she has a
boyfriend it's just like look boy I'd
like to I'd love to but it's just not
responsible in the big you know the
reality principle in effect it's not
responsible for us to do this so you
giggle and you move on but you're not
friends
I understand so that's it good luck