it's got a question from our buddy
Ostreicher 31 he goes on to say that he
feels as if he's too passive his
attitude is too passive and it makes him
an agreeable person you know he never
really asserts himself or says no or
denies anyone so a lot of people like
him because of this but he is coming to
see how this creates a lack of respect
for himself personally and from other
people he ties some of his creative
abilities to this idea that he's more
passive or what he calls passive
feminine and he's wondering if he should
how he should go about asserting himself
better building better self-esteem and
also wondering if that's going to you
know detract from his ability to be
creative so I want to attack that one
first no it's not going to detract from
your ability to be creative at all in
fact I think you are going to be more
creative when you give yourself
permission to do and to be all that is
happening inside you and that only
happens the only way that you'll have
the time to even allow yourself once
given that permission is by learning to
say no no is the very first ego
assertion that a human being develops
from the time they're a child oftentimes
it's the very first word that babies
begin uttering which is no no no no
don't know when you assert no you're not
only just putting up a clear boundary
between yourself the violation of
yourself and the expectations are other
people set up on you but you're also
seeing yes to a far greater and bigger
reality which is that which is happening
inside you so when you have retained
your yes you'll have more energy you'll
have more conviction you'll have more
time available to you to develop your
creativity you will be a stronger
version of yourself by not letting
people take advantage of you the way
this happens because right now you're
personally identified with being a
spineless doormat you know people like
me hmm they like me because they can
push me around that's really why they
like you they're not going to like when
you start saying no you're probably
going to have to create a entire new
group of friends the people who are used
to the doormat don't like it when the
doormat gets up and brushes itself off
and says stop stepping on me because now
they can't wipe their feet on it
right well good if it is a doormat that
it starts itself you're a doormat for a
lot of these people they don't like you
they're using you and it might not
necessarily be in a utilitarian fashion
you know squeezing the juice out of you
but they know they can push you around
they know that you're not an obstacle
and in that same way that you don't
create barriers and they can push you
around
and you do end up doing things that you
don't want to do or yielding to demands
or just taking shit that you shouldn't
have to take you are saying no to the
greater essence that's within you as a
creative individual you know exactly
what I'm talking about you've got to
practice this because it doesn't come
naturally to you right now so there's
going to be some cognitive dissonance
but you will need to have to practice
saying no and you could start small when
you're walking through the street and
someone has one of these uh you know
they want you to sign I figure out what
they call it but basically um I don't
know people are always asking you for
shit in the street you know sign this so
that like kitties will could have homes
or sign this so that I know that the
mayor can stop taking all most people
off the street well the case may be
forget what they call those petitions
all right that's just a simple one
anyway say no no I mean you could be it
could be completely logical
ah you know there's no route why
wouldn't you want to sign this I don't
want to and it's because now you're at
your your your developing your
strengthening your ability to assert
your groundedness
your about your your saying yes to
yourself every time
you say no to someone else it can be
very simple it's simply as simple as
signing a petition but start to practice
it in other areas of your life someone
asks you hey can you give me a ride
downtown for blah blah blah blah no I'm
sorry I can you don't even owe an
explanation we don't know anybody an
explainer for anything no I'm sorry I
can maybe next time
right and you could rationalize because
you probably have through years and
years of being stepped on why you should
probably say yes what's the big deal
it's only going to take five minutes who
cares it's not about the thing it's
about you practicing your ability to say
no you've got to practice this because
you will go through your life and you
will have relationships and you will be
in jobs and you will deal with people to
the day you die that are not going to
respect you they're going to step on you
they're going to wipe their feet on you
and you are going to feel like shit you
will never be the strongest version of
yourself if you don't create boundaries
through which people shouldn't pass good
luck