what's up guys today we got a question
from my buddy Jeremy who says that he's
doing pretty damn well he calls himself
financially independent and he says he's
got to secure jobs as a personal trainer
in two different gyms
he just likes meeting new people but the
problem is he says is for as long as I
can remember I seem to have have a
inferiority complex feels inferior
specifically in the face of people who
he seems to feel are more successful
than him even those his age he says he
acts less confident he feels inferior in
front of them he's a big dude he's six
feet tall 180 pounds you can pull almost
450 pounds he presents himself well
likes to shake hands dress well so on
and so forth but there is a feeling
associated with inferiority and low
confidence when he is around people who
either carry a large light with them
they've got a large expansive energy or
and you got to be mindful of this
because or you've built them up in your
own mind to be somehow more illuminating
than you okay we are we're always
affected by the energies of people in
our environment we're always affected by
energies but a big part of how we're
personally affected by the energy of
someone else is how we receive their
energy right so and oftentimes we're not
even familiar with the language of our
own body to know how we're receiving
someone else's energy we don't even know
we don't know if we're happy excited sad
or or anything we're really not in touch
with our feelings it's funny a lot of
times when I'll meet a young man will
come to the gym to meet me shake my hand
or come to open gym they're shaking and
I know they're happy because it's this
first time that get to meet someone that
they've seen in YouTube and it just
helped them in some way and I know that
there's a lot of excitement going on in
their bodies and their bodies almost
shaking it you know although I know
they're happy because they're saying oh
my god oh my god I'm so happy the face
is like this oh my god oh my god oh my
god because of an inability to process
the
bombardment of energies going on in the
in the environment in the circumstance
me and him now I hang out with my
friends and I hang out with Chris who's
my partner I hang out with my wife and I
hang out my children I all people all
day long I go to the grocery store and I
check things out nobody has that they
don't have this when they see me all
right I didn't see me as I olds up dude
right I just met a guy a little while
ago he had to bring me something you
delivered a package and for the first
time we met he's like I would sup - very
cool
take care of sign-off was it so you got
understand that uh
which I think you do that although there
are those that carry it we all carry
energy and some people have more potent
and energy that that that I want to say
can it infuse itself into others you
know these are expansive people you can
feel them when they walk into the room
how you receive and how you manage the
energetic response in your body has more
to do with it than the actual the other
person and what's happening is for
whatever reason your when you feel the
presence of these people you're
unfamiliar I don't want to say you that
confidence and that you feel inferior I
think you're confused about what you're
feeling and I think it would be very
important to come into contact with what
you're actually feeling very oftentimes
it's ah and it's okay to feel ah at the
success of another man in fact if you
really own that all you really own that
admiration admiration is another one I
really admire what comes with admiration
also is inspiration I'm inspired by that
person Brian Tracy once said that you
most secretly admire the things that you
are becoming and when these men make
themselves known to you and you're
bombarded with an energy that has a lot
to do with the stories you've told
yourself about them and their actual
energy and you freaked out
you're not inferior you may be in awe or
admiration all in a beret
when honored grow into inspiration why I
want to be more like you and that's a
very healthy place to be as an advancing
man is to be in the presence of someone
that you are in awe of and know that
you're becoming that person now that
that person exactly but that which you
are in awe of in that person a part of
that person that really is attractive to
you is what's growing in you my man so
you see these men and they are mirrors
reflections of the awesomeness that you
actually are you get it so what are you
doing okay great Eliot that's nice to
know what do you do or I tell you man
I'm starting to sound like a broken
record I will keep saying this shit over
and over and over again those of you who
think you know me right because if
you're watching up on my video someone
who'd sent me an email a little while
ago and they commented on one of my
videos and how might the energy was
wrong I shouldn't be giving that advice
I have almost 400 maybe 500 videos on
this channel alone watch them all it's a
story it's a story you can't take my
take can't take me for one video we're
gonna watch lots of we got understand
how these pieces come together I'm not
writing a book on making videos you got
it so without sounding like a broken
record man you got to go to your body
you've got to go to these people because
again you said I feel inferior well what
does inferior actually feel like see
that's important what does now when you
are feeling inferior it's not in your
head feelings aren't in your head it's
in your body check out your go from the
ground up I'd like to start the belly
personally I start at my belly and I say
boy am i holding my belly tight because
right now I don't feel very good about
myself and that's gonna force you to
take a look at your breath how am i
breathing in the presence of this man
have I stopped breathing right and if
you stop breathing there's often a
posture associated with holding your
breath
so my shoulder my hiking my shoulders up
my cleansing my jaw my cleansing my feet
clenching my hands am I am I am i
tucking my tail under and cowering you
know almost like a dog with his tail
tucked under because he's scared
what are you doing physically to give
yourself the feeling
of inferiority scan your body and feel
where inferiority is showing up get
intimately involved with the workings of
your unconscious your and your
unconscious work through your body your
body is the language your body speaks
the language over your unconscious all
the time okay take a look at how your
breathing be aware of it awareness is
transformative in and of itself it's
good that you can see see it don't judge
it now I'm going to go back to your head
and you create more neurosis don't judge
it and if you feel that it's available
to you at that moment let go try
something different if you find that
every time you're in the presence of
these men your shoulders go up and you
continue in your jaw is tight do this do
that - try that just try changing your
body try doing the opposite of what you
typically do when you're in these
circumstances it happens this way in all
relationships even with women those you
guys now of course I'm not a pickup
artist you know and don't compare me to
my buddy Tyler Durden because we're not
we're not playing the same game but we
both understand the same principles and
if you're talking to women now I'm not
going to give you the step-by-step
blueprint for getting them all dazzled
and juicy for you not tell you this you
had better be breathing into your balls
your muscular system had better be
relaxed you had better be grounded you
had better be in touch with your
unconscious in your body if every time
you're around a woman you find yourself
you know tapping your foot and like
chewing your lip you know that's really
you know for lack of a deserves it's
really beta you're way up in your head
now your body is is showing your
twitches and how you fight fix that let
go or the fucking blip biting and stop
moving your foot
it's going to force you to ground your
energy so that's it hey you're doing a
great job keep up the good work
you admire those people because they
should be admired and aspire to be more
like them you'll only be available to
that sort of resourceful ideal if you
relax your body in their presence
done