I made some choices that put me in a
place where I had no choice basically
quitting jobs and and you're starting
your own business and having the
responsibility of a family I'm not all
put me in a place where was like swim or
you drown motherfucker it wasn't my kind
of in-between that's why I always talk
to where I talk about like taking risks
in your life
don't take calculated fucking risks
that's the most biggest bullshit lie
I've ever heard you take the type of
risk that makes you fucking succeed so I
was in a situation where it wasn't like
I had a I had a business plan or some
sort of financial aid from a joint
capitalist or or anything of that sort
it was just like okay you want to teach
people how to get stronger and you need
money go figure that shit out I had no
equipment no gym nothing no clients so
luckily I came across a website zakat
finishes website where he was shown keep
you know showing uh making videos about
how he was training kids with like tires
and sandbags and stuff that he made at
home and he would train them in his
backyard and he was just doing like
backyard fitness he had like backyard
workouts I was like I could do that I
don't have a gym I can't afford to pay a
gym for me to train my clients there we
don't have any clients but I got this
big-ass van and I could make sandbags I
remember spending like an entire weekend
just filling sandbags and and fine and
driving around the city looking for
tires to train people with literally
garbage and that's how I started my
business cuz I had all that crap in the
back of my van and I would I would show
up at parks and give people free
workouts and then slowly but surely that
from that that seedling
training people with trash in their
parts I mean what you see are the fruits
you know today it strange as it may
sound of course it's like it's not that
simple
but what you see literally is the fruits
of those seeds that were planted when I
literally had just garbage yeah and I
mean I only only pay for the bare
minimum things that I needed so for
example I had the gym but you remember
some of the equipment I had I had like
logs that remember that day I was like
yo guys there's some logs out there go
pick that go pick that up like we
trained with just whatever was heavy if
it was heavy even if it was garbage was
logs they were throwing them away he's
like Oh get it this is what we're
working out with you know part of it was
necessity and then a part of it was like
hey this is actually pretty damn cool
cuz when you first came training at the
gym with me it was like I've never seen
this before like who does this so it was
a unique selling proposition and having
to learn marketing out of necessity I
realized that if I position it as hey
this is the way we train not sorry this
is all I've got
then it's going to conviction is going
to fuel the fire that's what it was I
had conviction that's really what
mattered more than anything
that I'm gonna win no matter what cut my
legs off I'm still gonna find a way to
go you have if you have an attitude that
says you're a winner
doesn't matter if your circumstances
look like they're losing you're gonna
win attitude is fuckin everything in an
attitude of conviction always wins