we've got a question from our 16 year
old anonymous friend who titled this
question my life is fucked Elliot what
do I do and after reading your question
I wouldn't argue against that you got it
pretty rough you're sixteen years old
so everybody has a perspective on what's
going on his dad's got cancer right on
top of the fact that he thinks that his
dad's using heroin alright so that's a
drug addict and as cancer his mom's
working two jobs in order to pay for the
chemotherapy and to help them live their
lives bills are piling up either his
parents speak English so our friend has
to deal with the bill collectors and and
so on and so forth that are like you
know knocking on the door because they
want their money but they're broke sick
on drugs
his sister used to be there and was a
very supportive character but she left
and now he's all alone he's way too
young I'm telling you you're way too
young to be carrying the burden of your
parents sins and I don't use that term
sins in the religious Association I say
where they're missing out that term sin
is from an artery is an artery term to
me which means to miss to not get it
basically they've missed the mark and
you got to pick up the slack it seems
for where your parents are missing the
mark particularly your dad who's sick in
on on on heroin it's not fair and your
sister checked out and this is not going
to be popular advice there are people
that are probably going to argue with me
on this but the very first and most
important thing for you at this point
regardless of how much you love and need
your parents is self-preservation it's
not fair what they did to you okay and
doesn't mean that you need to grow
resentful or hateful towards them what
it means is no one's going to protect
you except for yourself
right now you're at a very vulnerable
age where the adults in your house
should be and perhaps they are to the
best of their ability but it's not
working out doing everything that they
can to make you the strongest version of
your
self or help you develop the foundation
to grow stronger there's one thing my
dad my dad has a lot of awesome sayings
one of the things he used to like but if
you think I'm intense he's to just beat
into our heads is your how did you got
to be better than me you're gonna be
better than me you got to be better than
me
it is everything that he said and
everything that he did was with the
premise of my children who will be
better than me you're going to do better
than me I think that's I think a lot of
parents perceive from that sentiment
they perceived from that place I want my
children to do better I want better for
my children your parents regardless of
the circumstances and how it how what
would be a pure intent is being
manifested the way it's being manifested
which is not pretty they're true the
core underneath all of the dysfunction
is this want for their children and you
to do better than they're doing because
they know it's this facing our mortality
thing we all know we're gonna die your
dad is on his deathbed apparently and
then your mom is she you said she's sick
because she's working so hard that
arthritis on Alexa shit they're on their
way out dude
that's something we've got to face
they've got a face and you got to mix
they're on their way out you're on your
way in
what's it what's more important for that
thing that it's on its way out to fizzle
out without distracting that which is
coming up right or for that thing on its
way out to suck the life out of the
thing that's coming up right out put the
old in with the new but the new is going
to carry a lot of dysfunction and
disturbance if it cannot separate itself
from that which it came through your
parents they brought you into this world
be grateful for them but you've got to
get out just like your sister got out
your sister saving herself you mentioned
that you're going to college you're
supposed to be going to university next
year but you don't want to I understand
the feeling is not there right now
you're due
rest you're anxious you've got a lot to
carry right now this is the time when
Elliott Hulse says going to college is
going to be the best thing you do with
your life I mean I don't care if you
have to go into a hundred thousand
dollars to get right I'm usually so
against that go into the day you got to
get out then that's going to be your
escape you've got to get out of your
parents house as fast as possible and
I'm not saying don't look bad or don't
have any empathy towards them or don't
want to help them but you got ahead in
energetically and physically remove
yourself from their presence because
they are destroying you like I said this
is not going to be popular advice but
this is what I sense by reading your
your question and your concern here I
might give different advice to someone
someone else but right now what I see
from you is you are sinking down with
them you're 16 years old you shouldn't
be depressed you shouldn't be carrying
the weight of the world on your
shoulders
you shouldn't have to see your parents
go through what they're going through
and you cannot save them that you need
to understand you can't save them it's
not your job to save anyone it's none of
our jobs to save anyone anyway our only
jobs is to become the strongest version
of ourselves and inspire other people
the word inspired means to
breathe in to write what Xfire means
breath has left right expired
die breathe in to give life you can only
breathe life into that which is growing
into that which wants to become alive
that's why that word inspires so much
more powerful and potent than motivation
inspire so your job is to then use the
strength that you've gathered by
becoming a stronger version of yourself
which it can only happen when you remove
yourself from the expiring situation the
dying situation and then in their honor
inspire breathe life into other people
make that your life's mission make that
the focus of your attention from this
day forward you get out of there go to
college go get out of there
grow stronger and that's going to be a
journey in and of itself there gonna be
ups and downs there gonna be challenges
they're gonna be heartbreaks they're
going to be pains associated with but
you're on a journey and you stay on that
journey and while you're on that journey
and you can look back to others that are
a few steps behind you a few years
behind you on that journey
like I do because I know most of you
guys are younger than water than me that
watch these videos you breathe life into
them you bring them up you can't save
your parents but you can save or breathe
life into better learn breathe life into
inspire those that are coming up behind
you because like I said earlier things
everything is dynamic some people are
moving out and some people are moving
into this thing right right like my
camera my hands moving out but as one
hands moving out one's moving in your
parents are moving out you move in but
guess what where are you going to you're
moving out so as you move out make sure
that you're doing the exact opposite of
your parent don't be an anchor be an
inspiration and bring up that crop
behind you that's it dude that is the
most important thing that any human
being can do on this planet and it's
subjective it looks like the DNA in
every individual
it will be unique it'll be your unique
expression good luck