got a question here for my buddy Phil
who has a friend that's been living with
him for the past several months his
friend he says has a good heart he
happens to be pretty accomplished he's
31 years old he's he's got a college
degree he's had great careers he's got a
pretty good foundation he's no slacker
in the way of getting shit done in his
life but he's reached a tough point
where now he's got some responsibilities
that he seems to be avoiding and and and
now that he's living with our buddy Phil
Phil has discovered that when his friend
doesn't have the stability and structure
of an institution or a goal driving him
he turns it to a lazy bastard so he
stays at Phil's house for free right now
because he's getting back on his feet
which is fair and plays video games all
day long use the internet eats food and
Lee's dishes all over the place he's a
sloppy fuck but the thing is Phil knows
that he's better than that he just
doesn't understand why he's falling into
this trap of laziness phil has
conversations with him every once in a
while that Rob what revolve around hey
dude you're better than this you can do
better than this why don't you pick
yourself up and get something done and
his friend says I know I know I know but
doesn't doesn't really do anything so
Phil is wondering how do i how do I
support my friend who I dearly love and
he even says I don't mind him living
with me he could live with me for
several more months I love him doing but
how do I support him in becoming the
strongest version of himself when he
just won't get off his ass and get
something done
especially this hurts so much especially
because he's capable he's able he's done
magnificent things in his life up until
this point so I think you given me the
answer already Phil and he filled allude
to the fact that when he's when he's on
a job he's usually the best worker when
he's he was in the military he happened
to be exempt blurry
he was good whatever he decides to do
he's really good at his motive
it Phil what what he doesn't have in
himself and that you need to become for
him and help him establish in himself is
this archetype of the king okay I'm
gonna invite you to read a book that
I've loved and I've read multiple more
books by the same author Robert Moore
called King warrior magician lover I've
talked about this in other videos and
the fully self actualized man is a man
who has developed the archetype the
characters associated with a king a
warrior right a magician and a lover and
your friend may very well be a great
warrior when told what to do right
that's a lot of guys go into the
military they don't necessarily have a
very strong King component to them but
they're very warrior like so as long as
the commander is telling them what to do
they're gonna get shit done and they're
gonna be the best one at it because
they're very warrior your friend might
have that he might also be very much a
magician
meaning that he he's technically able
he's skilled the magician is is that
that able person the person who can like
learn things he can learn he could
figure things out he can he's he's
intelligent in that way and the lover
who is someone who like you have alluded
to is friendly has a good heart
clearly your friend has three of the
four major male archetypes running his
life for him in absence of a king and
the king is the is the ruler of the
other three the other three will run
your life into the ground in a very
imbalanced way if they're if they're not
all if not all for a presence especially
if there's no K read that book and then
also there's a there's a spin-off book
that's all about developing the King
archetype sharing these ideas or
supportive reading and thinking and and
that's why I make these videos I don't
make these videos to fix anybody nor to
save anybody make them to give you some
shit to think about so the books are
gonna help him think they'll help you
think but ultimately something has to be
done right and I'm placing the
responsibility on you because he
in need of someone to give him orders
now you're a friend you're helping him
out but you're also enabling him this is
the time when you create very loving
ultimatums your friend needs to hear
something that sounds a little like this
you've got five weeks to find a job or
you're out of here I love you with all
my heart but you're going to end up on
the street and I have no problem putting
you out on the street because look if
you put him on the street
he'll have the king up right so you're
helping him but you're still enabling a
little bit give a little bit more room
you're enabling a little bit but you
know what if he's out in fucking Street
he'd have to develop that King because
he'd have to strategize and he'd have to
you have to build the discipline King is
the disciplinarian in many ways he'd
have to build him discipline to get some
shit done otherwise he's gonna find
someone else to lean on he's gonna find
another nipple to suck on someone else
who's going to enable him and he's just
going to he's gonna spend his life that
way looking for enablers right now
you're being the enabler you've done
your job to support him in the best way
possible when you kick his ass out if he
doesn't find a job you've done the best
thing that anyone has ever done for him
so feel just in your actions when you
kick his ass out feel just in the fact
that you're supporting him better than
anyone at this particular stage in his
life has ever supported him sometimes
you gotta let people fuck themselves up
that's the best way to learn in fact I
believe I really believe that a lot of
times you just gotta you just gotta get
fucked up right you ever hear somebody
say like you just need to get punched in
the fucking face ha well the depending
on who says that cuz some people are
just idiots but where that comes from
means you need to learn a lesson you
need to hit rock bottom you need to have
a painful experience a lot of people
need crisis in order to rise they need
to hit the bottom the bounce back up but
if they've got someone coddling them the
whole time there's no crisis and in that
there will be no hitting the rock bottom
and no bouncing back up
and thirdly you're doing righteous by
the universe you're doing a service to
God by kicking his ass out because he's
an able man who's not contributing to
the world with gifts that were given to
him now for us all to collectively
evolve and grow as a race of human
beings on this planet we need as many
hands as possible and your friends hands
are stuck on these fucking video game
handles you're doing a service to
humanity by kicking him out and getting
more fucking video games and on the
streets where he will have to bounce
back up and that's it and you mentioned
that he likes watching my videos and
perhaps he'll know that this is about
him if you can sack up and kick yourself
out if you don't find a job in 3 4 or 5
weeks
it's amazing how resourceful we we come
we become when we're about to drown
somebody throws you in a lake you had
better learn how to swim or you die you
become really resourceful at flailing
your fucking arms until you get to shore
so you might even kick yourself out this
thing you have to but understand that
that's that's the next logical step if
you can't muster up the motivation to
get shit done sometimes you just got to
throw yourself off the cliff and learn
that to fly on the way down and I'm done