so it's been said that a man's life is a
product of the activities that he most
often repeats basically you become which
are habits dictate your habits act as a
scaffolding on which you build your life
ever since I was 14 years old I've
always lifted barbells I thought about
this this morning and my life is a
metaphor for barbell strength I used
strength as a metaphor for every area of
life and if you've watched my videos for
a while you know this during the good
times the barbell was always a habit
during the bad times the barbell was
always there strength training and
lifting barbells is the habit that acts
as the glue that holds my life together
so my question today is what habit are
you instilling and allowing to guide you
down the path to which you will end up
in your life