what all things like you're saying like
we manifest very weak screen in our
heads right we came together as a
community or whatever and we created
economy like what is economy right it's
it's not a thing that you know girls
under the ground is full of the might
yeah yeah yeah it's just the illusion
yeah it's a game but we become I
personally identified with it and that's
when it sickens us I think it's cool to
play economy it's cool to play
civilization as long as we're a person
identified with it and which is
difficult from one for a difficult one
for us now of course being personally
identified with it which is is the
individual sickness but the collective
sickness is a manifestation of defying
the second important rule which is cause
no harm and we cause harm to each other
recourse harm to the planet and that's
our that's our demise play economy play
society play nations play languages play
religions play all these things because
they're beautiful they're their
manifestations of a brilliant
consciousness but don't be personally
identified and cause no harm and would
be much happier
let's get talking to you guys what do
you think that each other right now yeah
did you think you care I don't want to
it's just I always it's always weird
playing right after exercise but I'll go
you got a good point even shot but it is
your chance yeah come on I'm gonna shine
on strength billions of people
apparently not at this moment right ha
ha be nervous yeah yeah I'll be right
back okay all right cool yeah you know
what I'm fascinated with is uh this is
going to sound ignorant but only because
of my perspective but being able to have
conversations with like this with high
school junior yeah and you're what 16
yeah that is incredible because when I
was 16 it was how can I get a 40 ounce
and get laid or how can I go beat
somebody up there on the football field
and I don't know if this wasn't
available to me but I didn't know
anybody else that was that April would
have been able to have a conversation
like this when I was growing up in my
high school in Long Island it's not to
say that the people there were stupid
but we didn't have the Internet exactly
and the internet I mean I don't know if
maybe this is just innate knowledge or
your parents are really smart people to
share these ideas with you or you got
lots of books in your house but the
Internet has created an explosion of
consciousness that allows young bright
absorbent minds to dig into ideas that
adults just a generation before I've
never even heard of hazing it's all
right okay we find we can finally see
everything
you know it's we're not just confined in
our area so to speak right like you know
we're nestled in high school we don't
have internet or anything like that no
books well only perspective you has you
have this like around you right whenever
you teachers are telling you figure with
it TV yeah exactly whatever if you're
telling you that's all it is right you
want to news and like this is what
telling anything you got terrorists or
whatever over there dural terrorist
stuff alright another yeah exactly it's
your food should be scared right hit but
like how we're gonna know that if he
can't actually see it right we just love
me right we just believe what we see
what it would be here and I think so
part of it is fear and part of it is
also just I guess ignorance that's
exactly the word you look yeah like it's
you just don't know yeah so we want to
go eat the right clearly one class love
you know what I think would be the
coolest thing i would have it's been
done already like a documentary right
we're like straight cracker redneck from
Middle America somewhere goes and has a
conversation obviously they have to
speak the same language with a man of
the same age with let's say they both
have three children and they're both
socioeconomically about the same in
their current cultures from Afghanistan
you know who lives either in a cave or
however they decide I don't know because
of my ignorance but this guy lives in
trailer he carries a shotgun that guy
lives and his cave yeah and they got
together over I don't know some beers or
some hookah or something and they just
sat down look each other in the eyes and
started talking you know what I really
believe that the end of the conversation
they'd be like this you know what man
you're okay you're okay too yeah because
they're just human beings doing the best
they can what they have in the place
they've come from without all the
political garbage and wars that you know
are monetarily based economically based
hey just this guy just wants to take
care of his kids and teach him right
thing especially singer of his kids
teach him the right thing if they
actually got together without any pre
prejudices yeah I think I think it would
be beautiful