what's up gentlemen today we will
question for one of our buddies who's
going to be participating in an exchange
student program he's going to live with
another family in another country and he
wants to make a good impression upon
them he says normally I'm a very
diplomatic young man and I do fairly
well in social engagement with adults
but I know that I'm going to be living
with this family and that means you know
potentially 12 hours maybe 24 hours a
day at some point and he wants to extend
himself in an outwardly way a
respectable way but at the same time he
knows that sometimes he just he just
doesn't want to talk he just wants to be
by himself he wants to be introverted he
wants to not engage how do I go about
making a good impression upon these
people but yet retain my own desire to
withdraw times because it's not
necessarily that he doesn't want to
engage but there are times when quite
frankly my friend
you shouldn't have to engage you know I
mean what the nature of energy is to
expand and contract if you expand expand
expand expand expand expand you're going
to pop that's just like if it was day 24
hours a day 365 right the earth would
explode we couldn't handle that much
heat you need expansion and contraction
so know that this is normal I know that
you grew up in your own home so you can
go to your bedroom and you know your
parents want to engage or not you know
and of course these are strangers so you
want to make a good impression and a
part of the reason why I took this
question I know it sounds like it might
be arbitrary is because I think that
this is one of these things where all
young man at some point all of us we're
going to have to go into the world of
adulthood we're going to have to go and
we're going to have to seek the
validation of adults it's just the way
it is you know unless you become just a
complete rebel and join a gang or I
don't know but at some point even then
you've got to show you even then join a
gang anytime there's a hierarchy you're
going to have to impress yourself upon
those who are of higher status than you
of course status is
is subjective but you get my point
so I began thinking since this is
something that we will all have to do
what are two easy ways to I I also like
to choose to whenever I'm giving advice
or or giving an invitation because this
idea that there that the world is just a
composite of two ends of a spectrum
expand contract right like we spoke
about before heart beat cyst all
diastole it keeps us alive it keeps us
alive the two things that are going to
keep you alive with regard to impressing
yourself as a respectable young man in
the adult world are decisiveness and
gratitude I tell you based on my
experience when I meet the young man and
he is decisive meaning he can stand on
his own two feet he introduces himself
with a firm look in his eye he makes a
decisive choice to extend his hand and
has a firm grip not because he's trying
to prove that he's stronger than me or
some sort of a tough guy you know those
guys that like shake your hand it's like
what the fuck is this like a strength
contest no a firm handshake and look in
the eye means I am grounded in myself I
trust myself I come from a strong place
and I respect you enough to offer myself
to you that's what decisiveness is all
about and the first instance where
you're given an opportunity to display
your decisiveness smile also because
when you smile it's a decision that's
where decisiveness comes from the
decision
you know how to make decisions is the
decision that I appreciate you gratitude
I appreciate you as a person just smile
at people just the look on your face
either says I'm open to our relationship
I'm open to receiving you and I'm also
available to give myself to you you now
have what's really the foundation for a
powerful relationship with that person
also as things progress you will be
offered opportunities to be decisive now
I'm not saying be
a tyrant make things have to be my way
but when offered a question offered
different opportunities where adults
will say would you like to do this or
this
choose one don't say it doesn't matter
to me I'm okay but if I kind of like
didn't start doing this because now
you're you're flying away right you just
look at the body language you do this
oh don't never do this shit say yes I
would like a bob would you like a or b I
would like B thank you do you see this
Sai Cygnus make a choice if there's if
you're in a circumstance where
everyone's trying to be diplomatic or
democratic those are too dangerous where
it's oftentimes being diplomatic and a
democratic means that nobody makes a
fucking decision there's nothing there's
nothing worse than being amongst a group
of men and no one can decide what we're
going to do next because they want to be
diplomatic and democratic I'm not saying
be a tyrant and say this is where we're
going this is what we're doing I'm
taking charge and you stand tall and
walk you know walk away from people what
I'm saying is you offer your opinion and
stand on it guys where are we going to
go for lunch what are we gonna do uh
order and he end up with one of these
situations where nobody knows the fuck
to do nothing it gets going here's how
you assert yourself here's how you be
decisive you say gentlemen I propose
that we go have chicken io Pizza Pizza
Pizza piece of our on our hamburgers
gentlemen it's my proposition and
oftentimes because they're so wavering
and weak and they're all kind of like
ungrounded in what they're going to
choose to do in life because they walk
their whole lives this way they're just
gonna go with you anyway right and
that's there's a little manipulative
tactic but always propose something
there's you know that whenever you're in
a situation we even with adults
propose hey you know what guys I'd
really like to do B be decisive okay so
that's it
and the second one like I alluded to
before have gratitude let me extend some
gratitude for a moment for the garbage
man because without the lovely garbage
man there would be trash everywhere and
of course we live in a world that
creates lots and lots of fuckin
unnecessary trash what was I doing this
weekend where there was fucking trash
for no reason I don't know I I ordered
something I think it came in the mail I
can't remember exactly but it was like
this big and it was enveloped in a big
fucking shell of trash and we had all
this trash I did throw away for this
little fucking thing of course I wasn't
very grateful at that moment realizing
that we lived in such a wasteful world
why all the trash but I'm gonna extend
some gratitude for the trash man because
I wouldn't want that trash lingering
about my feet you understand but he
makes a lot of fucking noise when I make
these videos back to my point always use
the magic word Thank You magic phrase
thank you thank you thank you thank you
you can't say thank you enough every
opportunity that you have to extend your
gratitude even use the word gratitude
you say I am very grateful yes I am very
grateful to be here
I'd like to here's here's a really good
one for presenting yourself here's a
very assertive way to extend gratitude
you say to the people in your life to
the adults you say I'd like a moment to
extend some gratitude that's a powerful
statement you know what everybody does
when you say hey guys can you give me a
moment I'd like to extend some gratitude
or I'd like to share some gratitude
everybody quiets down and goes like this
because everybody loves to hear thank
you
they say so but that's one way to to
create create the environment to temper
the environment for what you're about to
say you say I'd like to extend some
gratitude
oh really thank you we're all ears you
get a lot of respect when you use that
word so that's it my friend carry those
two tools with you bees
be decisive and extend your gratitude
done