hey what's up guys Elliott Hulse here on
another Sunday but obviously today I'm
not Jim you won't see barbells behind
him but you might see boats right cuz uh
I'm an Amsterdam I'll be an Amsterdam
this week Colleen and I flew out here
today we just got here so I might look a
little jet lag as I am and I'm also
going to be speaking at a friend's event
and we are also doing a one-day
grounding camp while I'm here so the
next few days we'll be exploring the
city and then getting ready to meet some
of you guys at the one-day grounding
camp but I figure while I'm still here
why not maintain my Sunday ritual by
answering one of your questions now
the question that comes to us is very
timely especially given that I imminence
in the city known as the most liberal
city in the world when we use that term
liberal here in Amsterdam it's a bit
different than you know the political
scene in the u.s. it really stands for
liberty freedom Amsterdam is one of the
first places to have religious freedom
or the expression of religious freedom
it's also one of the places that had the
first books printed this place is known
for its tolerance and in freedom so we
have a question today related to freedom
of in a way as it relates to love one of
our friends who his question is inside
this phone but because I'm using the
phone to make a video you I can't read
it
he has a question related to a
relationship yeah he and his girlfriend
were dating for a long time he's very
much in love they were doing really well
together and he betrayed her this is
what he tells us he says that he was
dishonest and she left him and it has
been heartbreaking it has been hard over
the past several months he's been
mending his broken heart and it seems as
if time has mended that wound he's gone
on to be a stronger version of himself
and now that he is a bit more mature and
has moved on to a degree he wants to
know if he should try to get her back
and here's his plan he wants to write a
letter he says I'd like to write a
letter to express my remorse and also
share the love that I still have in my
heart for her and share it with her
now our friend being on the journey of
being a stronger version of himself is
very objective and I and I commend you
for recognizing that when you do share
that letter he says when they do share
that letter I'm going to probably want
to have her respond in a way that she
may not respond right and that's always
the case when dealing with other people
right we may say something or share
something or divulge something hoping
that the other person will respond in a
particular way but we can't dictate how
they're going to respond right by
holding them up to a particular hoping
them hoping for them to respond in a
particular way or even oftentimes we
hold them to a particular standard we're
putting that person into shackles of
sorts
you know we're enslaving that person by
our imagination and that's not fair and
I know you know that's not fair so just
like when you're dealing with your
friends right a good example of this
hopefulness with regard to a response we
often see when we've got a joke that we
want to tell right or a friend comes to
the crew he's got a joke something funny
just happening he wants to tell
everybody about it and he gets everybody
all ready for the for the response for
the laughter and he tells the joke and
then there are crickets and nobody
laughs now if our friend goes ahead and
tries to explain himself he is just
digging himself into a deeper ditch
because he's not allowing the process to
be natural right if you tell the joke
and nobody laughs and you walk away but
you still hold that giggle in your heart
well then that's normal and natural and
you're completely detached from other
people's responses you're detached from
the outcome and if you attach to it and
you try to make it happen try to force
it to happen or
try to get people to see your way see
through your lens when especially they
don't spontaneously do it then you
further entangle yourself with all kinds
of weird karma right you know I it just
gets old it gets beat up and it just
turns into something yeah unruhe source
well not not only is an explained joke
not funny it's kind of annoying it's
like dude alright get out of here
so you can expect the same sort of
situation when it comes to love right
you can tell someone you love them and
if you're setting yourself up for an
imaginary response that they're supposed
to give you're gonna find yourself
backpedaling you might find yourself
trying to explain yourself you might
find yourself further entangling
yourself in the situation which you know
if you're trying to heal the wound that
could potentially pour some salt into
that wound my friend so here is an
invitation from me I thought it was a
great idea for you to write that letter
you mentioned writing the letter in
order to get all the burden off of your
heart I think that's great man of course
I am all for full self-expression I
think it's not only going to relieve
your mind but it's also cathartic for
the body right when we have heart we use
the term heartbreak very figuratively
but anybody who has any sense of
sensation in their body will feel the
sting in their chest when they have that
heartbreak right the solar plexus
tightens up in the heart literally feels
like it was stabbed those you guys who
are sensitive you feel emotion in your
body right that's what emotion is right
let's what feelings are you feel it all
right do you have your feelings here you
don't conceptualize feeling so there's
going to be there's going to be a the
processing of feelings by getting it out
by writing it down on paper I say you
write the letter but you write it for
you you write it 100% so that you can
get what's in your heart
expressed and it's very helpful to you
now the other thing is the other
invitations I mean I might share with
you I'd like to share with you and it's
complete
be up to you to decide to try it or not
is if you really want to put yourself to
the test right I'm a strength coach so
I'm always about testing your strength
testing your character if you really
want to go ahead and do that right and
and you write that letter and you share
it with her but have complete detachment
from the outcome meaning I'm sharing
this with you because I am move to share
it with you not because I need you or I
need something from you or I'm going to
wait into intense in anticipation right
like the friend waiting for the jokes
waiting for the last but there's no
laughs you wait there for anticipation
you're setting yourself up I'm sharing
this with you because it is just an
outpouring of my heart and you remain
detached you remain unmoved and stoic
you allow the emotion to rise in your
body right because if she doesn't
respond the way you want her to you're
going to feel something allow that
emotion to rise in your body breathe
into it notice right if she responds in
a way that's not she drew drops
everything opens her arms and comes
running back to you right oh I love you
and tears coming down her face she
stands there looks at you or calls you a
name or something you've got to practice
I invite you to practice breathing into
the emotion that rises when that
situation occurs right you're gonna feel
a pain in your body breathe through the
pain
breathing through that physical pain
breathing through emotional pain
breathing through feelings allows it to
be processed we don't want to stuff it
down right cuz here's here's what's
going here what could potentially happen
what could potentially happen is you go
from being detached right to having
disdain and I don't want that to happen
I don't want that to be the case for you
at it a lot of people they act as if
they're detached but they're not really
detached they're actually disdainful we
call that sour grapes right it's like
you can't have the thing so fucking so
you start thinking she's yeah I don't
fuck that bitch she's nasty anyway right
you know I see a lot of guys do that
well it's very strange it's like you
love her and you're hoping for a
particular response but now that you're
not getting the response that you want
sour
fucking graves real and mature so
recognize the difference between
detachment being with the emotion
breathing through it allow it to process
because through that experience you're
going to become a stronger version
yourself right and you know contrast
between that and disdain be very clear
about that brother and I wish you the
best man look maybe she will drop
everything and come running back to your
arms right maybe that happens that we
wonderful that'd be great but if she
doesn't look at it as an experience and
opportunity for you to to grow stronger
look at it as an opportunity to become a
stronger version of yourself hold her in
high regard hold yourself in a
self-respecting place do not allow
yourself to make her a slave to your
imagination and do not get caught up
with your own vein Imaging's I will see
you next time
maybe an answer them again or maybe back
home
done
so I also wanted to share this with you
if you notice my chest normally I have
on a pendant it's actually iron it's
Tiger iron that I've been wearing for
about a year and then I really like and
love a lot and I had it about two three
hours ago here in Amsterdam and I lost
it I must have dropped it somewhere I
have no idea but I haven't had it for
the past hour and I share this with you
man because I'm detached it was
expensive and I loved it had lots of
sentimental value to it but it's gone
man that means it doesn't belong to me
anymore when something leaves you that
means it's not yours anymore that's all
it is
I love my iron just like you love your
girl but when it goes knows that it
ain't yos done