okay Paul why is it important that you
have a dream to go after and how does
that contribute to your overall strength
as a human being okay that's a very good
and important question the for me
the term dream is used only as a
signifier and under the term dream could
be my chief goal my motive or Marat my
objective right what you will find in
studying human behavior and coaching
people and just working with people in
general but if a person's motive to do
something isn't greater than their
motive not to do it nothing happens
right
most people are seeking dreams or
setting goals for themselves because
there's something inside of them that's
not happy with the status quo or where
they're at now right you know I'm sure
you've had many times in your life where
you thought well so I'm this strong but
I can be stronger or so I've made this
much money but I can make more so there
has to be something moving you forward
right if there's not a positive to move
you forward then you can use a negative
to move you forward so for example if
someone says I don't know what my dream
is what they're saying to me as a
therapist is that they don't really know
what they want to do more than what
they're doing right now
and even though what they're doing right
now may have caused them back pain or
digestive trouble or emotional problems
they don't really know any other way to
be right so for them they know that at
least they're going to get up out of bed
every morning they're going to be able
to
they're going to be able to you know
feed your family or whatever goes
through their head because they've been
doing that but for example how many
people are in a really unhealthy
relationship and have kids and are
emulating to the children exactly how
you should never have a relationship and
they've known that and they feel guilty
about that they can even witness their
children emulating their bad behavior
but don't have the strength to resolve a
relationship and either get healthy
together or move on right so there's a
classic case when I'm working with
someone like that I've got a simple what
is your dream well most people say I
don't know right well I say well if you
don't know what your dream is tell me
what your biggest nightmare is because
that's going to be the point of greatest
stress on your body mind system on your
body mind construct so now I have a
negative motivator some want a positive
motivator well I want to be happy with
my husband right versus I want to stop
fighting with my husband right you see
that one sees what they want and is
moving in that direction but the other
ones facing what they don't want and
therefore they don't even think about
all the things they can do when they're
happy with their husband or the way they
want to be they just thinking about
getting out of a fire right okay so if
someone who doesn't have enough
motivation to get out of the fire and
they stay in the fire and complain about
it will your life deteriorate and pay
lots of money for help that they don't
apply because in this state you state a
fight or flight reaction which shuts
down your capacity for learning new
anything it's a survival threat these
people say I want to get along better
with my husband how do we do it right so
they're positively motivated so if
someone doesn't want to go in this
direction and isn't sure they want to go
in that direction then they're kind of
in a state of apathy right which means
non-participation non-committal not
caring that's a bad spot so in a
nutshell I have identified that if a
person's sense of willingness
self measured willingness isn't at least
a seven or ten scale they are not likely
to make any noticeable or significant
changes that last they might flirt with
change they might flirt with you know
getting a divorce or going to counseling
or changing their exercise program or
changing their diet but it doesn't last
if somebody has a dream bigger than
their crisis they typically will move
forward so in closing I'll quote Brad
sugar a famous Australian
multi-millionaire who who has a formula
for change he says when the desire for
change is greater than the resistance to
change change happens so why I select a
gold dream goal or a dream goal or
objective or a motive is because I need
a direction that that person is willing
to go that they have more desire to
experience in the state that they're in
now that's the formula for success and
the other key thing is it must be their
own initiative in other words if a woman
sent to me because her husband thinks
her backsides getting too big the more
successful she is at solving that
problem for him the more and tangled she
becomes the more freedom she loses and
they are likely she is to rebel which
for us as professionals as bad marketing
because we think we did a good job but
now this girl is running around
overweight and worse than when she
started telling everyone we trained her
right so with a woman like that I would
have to say what could we do together
that allows you to do something just for
you for example she might say well I
really love rollerblading
but I like to rollerblade around the leg
and I get too tired I can only make it
halfway around the leg yeah and that
takes too long to walk back I only have
half an hour and say okay I'll tell you
what is your dream to enjoy
rollerblading regularly without any
problems and just to enjoy it yes okay
let's hold that dream and let's allow
your husband to think that he's getting
his dream off because he is getting his
dream but he don't have to know that
you're not really doing that to succumb
to his control what's important is that
you're doing this for you and
know that you're creating rollerblade
freedom so you can meditate on your
rollerblades and he just gets the side
effect now I have an empowering
co-creative partner who's working for
her own sense of autonomy freedom
self-love and learns how to take care of
herself and learns paradoxically that
she can give without having to give
herself away that makes sense
very good gave him her beautiful back
she's actually finding hers but she
didn't give it to him under his control
she gave it as a gift to herself and he
just happens to get to share it with her
that's bringing a person into a state of
self empowerment trying to get people to
do things because they're fat or they're
unattractive or theirs goes through you
know like for example the world's
biggest loser to me that to me that
should be that should be a showcase for
how to never train and how to diminish
them psychologically and and those
people are what we ought to do is have a
show called the world's biggest losers
one year later and see what happens
right right so anyhow that's really the
key issues of why dreams so important
you have to have clear direction and you
either have to go into something you
want or you have to choose to get away
from something that you feel is
stressful and worth resolving worth to
change for worth enough to resolve to
change for or you're always going to
stay tred giving it's in tread water for
the rest your life thank you so much for