it's got a question from our buddy
Anthony who was dating a girl for many
years about three years right there in
high school and during those three years
they decided to may remain abstinent so
they didn't have sex for three years and
then all of a sudden she got real
religious and was like you know what
let's not have sex until we get married
and our buddy Anthony obliged she said
okay cool that's fine let's not bone and
wait till we get married on till our
girlfriend his girlfriend decided that
she's done with him so she bounces and
then three weeks later she's dating her
cousin right so he I mean Anthony's
flipping his fucking lid now he doesn't
know what's going on it's like look
bitch we didn't we dated three years we
didn't bow because you got all religious
and now you're dating your cousin kind
of weird that words crap is this so
Anthony is boiling he's angry he's
pissed off and he wants revenge okay and
that's really what he comes to Elliott
Hulse Wars how can i plot revenge
against this girl so that she can see
what she's missing I don't want her back
I just want her to feel the pain
associated with with the knowing she
lost all this right here's the thing to
revenge her and what's her revenge put
this way revenge is kind of like
drinking poison in order to hurt someone
else right so if you drink poison you're
gonna fuck yourself up and revenge
really hurts you more so than it'll hurt
the other person especially if she's
already moved on dude she does not give
a shit about you she's done she's not
even thinking about you so for you to
plot revenge against her is nothing but
a deterioration of your own energy and
it's negative energy you're bringing in
a negative energy and you're wasting
your time and energy the best thing that
you could do is work now to build
yourself up revenge is going to break
you down I know what you want to get
back at her I know you want her to feel
the pain but I felt bitch right got blue
balls over these three years and now
you're gonna go and date your cousin
kind of weird right and backwards
duh you're just angry I get it
bioenergetics go and beat the shit out
of a bed with your tennis racket scream
and yell fuck you fuck you just go nuts
somewhere right go beat the shit out of
a punching bag the difference between
just beating up a punching bag or
working out and bioenergy release
bioenergetic realities is there's the
emotion involved so get really angry let
all your emotion and anger out on the
mattress or on a punching bag get it out
of your fucking system say everything
you want to say do everything you want
to do to this inanimate object and get
it out of your system because if it
stays in your system it will rot you'll
eat at you I understand that it's going
to be using aren't you get it out
because it's unrestored school to you
and it's gonna cook make you want to do
some crazy shit like get revenge on her
and that doesn't help anybody does not
help the situation for you to try to get
revenge on her her own revenge is when
her cousin gets her pregnant and their
babies are all weird and jacked up
because of a you know chromosome
crossing and incest shit like that so
she'll have her own she'll have her own
shit to deal with karma baby karma karma
deals itself fairly there's justice on
earth right justice might not pan itself
out in the way and in the time that we
like it too but everything balances
itself out the Sun rises the Sun sets
she will get her dish you don't worry
about it it's not up to you ok
all you're doing is making yourself sick
so that's it do don't drink poison to
hurt someone else