what's up guys it's elliott i'm actually
at gymnastics lessons not me but for my
children my three daughters and
gymnastics class right now so you can
see that's the so school behind me
alright so anyway the point of this
video is just to share some insight as
to what's going on in my life right now
I just got back from the Dominican
Republic you probably saw some of the
pictures of me and my wife on facebook
and it's the first vacation the first
time that she and I really went on a
vacation since getting married over 10
years ago we've been having children and
taking care of children for the past
eight years my oldest daughter is eight
and it was the first time that we
actually got a way to do something for
longer than you know a day or two by
ourselves so it was great but that the
reason why I'm making this video is not
just to give you further insight into
the makings of my life but to make sure
that the experiences that I have not
only teach me lessons but also support
you in your journey of becoming the
strongest version yourself that's why I
do this you know it's not because I'm a
genius or I have some grand message that
needs to be shared the deal is that I'm
on this journey of becoming a stronger
version of myself grow stronger inspire
others when you see me in these videos
it's just me fulfilling that other half
of my mission is to inspire others and
hopefully some of the things that happen
my life might be resourceful to you and
that may be the reason why you stuck
around this long otherwise if you think
I'm you know full of shit I've been
called quack and charlatans and snake
oil salesman if any of those titles seem
legit when describing me then you're
probably not here and and if you know
that's what you feel about me then maybe
I'm just a good-looking guy that you
like to watch on video so anyway I
decide that I want to share an
experience that I had when we weren't
American Republic the last day that
we've last full day that we were there
went scuba diving right and I fucking
should know better because I can't swim
I might pretend like I can swim my
daughter shows me in a breast stroke but
i can't fucking swim and i just got to
like come to grips with that it's always
been this way the other kids just made
fun of me and stuff now an adult
everybody was scuba diving and so i
decided
Beckett swim I even put on like a little
life vest thing sank to the bottom I'm
just not don't swim so on my way down
I'm drinking all types of water i'm
sucking in a haha caribbean saltwater
with whatever infested you know
parasites funguses and pathogens of all
sorts so that night I was throwing up
and shitting out both ends like never
before my entire body was wrenching in
order to produce the vomit it was like
the deep abdominal wall and the pelvic
floor contracting to such a degree that
it like propelled vomit up through my
esophagus out of my mouth ridiculous
right so sick really sick falling and
then like in between vomits sitting on
toilet and taking a shit which it was
more like pissing out the ass so anyway
so you get the severity of the situation
it's clear to you right so I know unlike
most people that when you're in the
third world country and you get sick
like that even if it's just for a few
hours you had better get your shit
tested because that's your body reacting
to a parasite pathogen I don't know what
kind of could be a bacteria but a
pathogen of some sort and often times
these especially these are warm water
warm climate pathogens they are they're
Hardy so they get inside your digestive
system and they leaving they're going to
hang out there and and Greek all types
of havoc on your health you know there
are so many diseases that are that can
be linked back to oh you've got a bug
shitting in your blood so think I'm
crazy you think this stuff is like off
the walls simply because the medical
industry doesn't want you to know it
because you can't sell them very
expensive drugs to get rid of this shit
it's very hard to diagnosis so it's not
a good moneymaker so that's why most
people you know here you're talking
about parasites and they think like
you're getting you out of your mind but
if you understand what i understand you
realize most people are sick and they
don't know why they're sick this is one
of the many reasons so you get tested
and that's the point that I'm trying to
make next is that uh as soon as I got
home for me and my wife because she got
sick also
I called dr. kaylis she's my naturopath
right away I've taken courses in fact
I've taken advanced courses with dr.
kaylis and my brother and I are actually
going to bring you a course all about
what I learned through him so needless
to say he's my go-to guy when it comes
to physiological strength because this
is physiological strength if you your
physiology isn't strong your body's not
going to be strong and I knew my
physiology was compromised by this
pathogen so today got home and we both
Colleen and I we ordered a what are
called 401 H pathogen screens and
they'll be coming in a couple days and
basically this means i will be shitting
in tubes for about four days now i'm
trying to be a bit more transparent
through the pictures and videos i shared
with you guys and doing a random
journals like this one so don't be
scared that i'm going to show you
pictures of my shit i'll try to be that
at least that private unless you want to
see it i don't know but anyway so i will
be i'll keep you posted i'll let you
know i'll tell you how the test works
i'll show you all the stuff that have to
do with it and then i'm going to get
tested i'll get my lab results and then
i'll give you the protocol that i'm
using to get rid of the unique pathogen
that i may or may not have hopefully it
turns out that it's not a pathogen so
the point here is just to give you guys
insight insight into my thinking process
but also to the actions that I take
associated with becoming a stronger
version of myself always talk about four
layers right so most people you know
they get sick they want to come back
home to the gym and they want to like
pound the weights like start crushing
heavy deadlifts and like burning out do
pronounce sense for their side delts and
shit like that get back in shape me I
take a more subtle approach because I
realized that all the muscle fucking
pumping in a whirling queer shit if you
got bugs living in your gut right so see
you understand my four layers of
strength that much greater I wanted to
share this with you so that's it folks
i'll keep you posted if you enjoy these
random rant videos like I'm doing right
now let me know because it takes you
know takes me stepping out of my comfort
zone with my family and what not to film
them
and if you like them I'll make more
otherwise like quite frankly I got shit
to do kids to go feed all right peace