so our friend Eli has a friend with
benefits or what we used to call a fuck
buddy and this is someone who basically
is you don't have any type of intimate
relationship per se in other words you
don't love this person but you meet up
on regular intervals to have sex and you
call that a friend with benefits so your
friends cool we like each other we don't
love each other but let's extend the
benefits beyond just our you know our
friendship let's have sex so this is
cool fine problem is she got pregnant
right bird so now he lies in a bind
because he doesn't love this woman she
or girl she's 21 he's 26 she refuses to
have an abortion he's trying to convince
her and her mom you need to get rid of
this baby because I don't love you I
won't be there to support you I have no
money and whatever money or support I
have I'm already supporting my sister in
her fucked up situation I don't have
anything left for you please just have
an abortion right get rid of baby they
refused they're like that fuck you don't
worry about it we will take care of it
this is what the girl and the mother
said Hey look Eli fine you know dropping
seeds and bouncing is cool what else
we'll take care of the baby we don't
need your help
peace Eli is pasty he's panicked now you
don't know what to do fix is going to
ruin his life and and he's got a lot of
different ideas about it a lot of
different judgements on what's going on
funny how we have judgments after we
fuck up right ah we've become very
righteous after we make some fucking
mistakes and that's kind of where you're
at right now so the very first thing I
want to do is I'm gonna read some of
what you wrote here and I want squash
some of your illusions about what's
going on get straight to the point just
look at this thing like it really
fucking is as opposed to you know being
poetic about it and then give you some
ideas that are going to support you at a
level at a play in a place where you
really is the only place you have any
power right now right so anyway let's
move on I have a friend with benefits I
don't love her we had sections pregnant
now I explained to her a human life is
such as a baby is a beautiful
and should take place only if there are
two loving parents and well I don't want
anything with you so this is not going
to work out not only that but neither of
us have jobs or careers you're only 21
years old I'm busy helping my sister
please tell your mom to help you can
have an abortion get rid of the baby
it's only been a few weeks this
shouldn't happen this is a disaster
without a well-structured family to
raise the baby
why would you want this okay cool so you
should have been thinking about
well-structured families and two loving
parents when you were fucking right I
mean it's kind of inherent in having sex
is that there's a potential for the
byproduct of sex which is what your
children and look I don't know what the
birth control situation was but whatever
happened happened cool this is this is
what we were dealing with what I want
you to avoid is talk like this right
because all of a sudden like you're a
fundamental Christian Oh
families need two parents oh there
should be a family structure you know
what fuck that because that first of all
that's just an idea because if you look
throughout the history of mankind
the way the family structure is as we
recognize it today is very different
it's it hasn't always been this way it's
just a fucking idea that we've come up
with and we've accepted you know years
ago there were tribes where you know two
young people would have sex and the
elders would take care of the children
right I'm not saying what should be I'm
saying what is and don't start becoming
very poetic or righteous about what
should be right because what should be
is what is right neither good nor bad we
can't even judge your actions right
because you're following your instinct
you know you wanted to fucking have sex
she wanted to have sex you had sex and a
baby came not good or bad not right or
wrong
but let's deal with it on the on the
level that were the place that we're
living and the time that we're living
and the financial circumstances that you
guys are presenting in the world as it
is right let's be realistic here and not
place you know moral judgments okay
so but that other way one of the things
that you that might be helpful to you
just an idea that might be helpful to
you right is that when we have children
although they come through us they don't
necessarily belong to us and the reason
why I say that is because you can start
panicking about this child not having a
good life because we think because you
think that you have to have a 100
percent hand in the the steering and
projection of this child's life but we
live this we play this game call life
with only one hand on the steering wheel
and the other hand is steered guided by
manipulated by that which we have called
God the universe the DAO Allah nature
there's another part of this whole
fucking thing that we don't have control
over so we could place all of our
projections on what's going to happen
with our one fucking hand not realizing
that like this other hand has its own
plans and it's going to help steer this
child this child's life so we cannot say
this child's life is going to be a
disaster your you might think your life
is a disaster if you don't approach it
the way I'm going to tell you to in a
few moments because it's all based on
perspective but you can't judge what's
going to happen to this child some of
our greatest people some of the greatest
people walking the earth today come from
a home where there are no parents foster
children one parent you can't judge what
the child is going to be like simply
because you don't have both hands on the
fucking steering wheel because we never
do okay that might that might appease
your anxiety just a bit it might relax
you just a bit because for lack of
better terms or you know what it this is
my term I like saying God sometimes it
pisses you guys off but I hope you
understand what I say what I mean when
I'm saying this a lot of this you got to
really just say it's in God's hands
it's in God's hands right you did this
she's making her choice you cannot force
her you cannot manipulate her decision
because it's her body she wants to
happen but the baby let her have the
baby now you have exhausted to two out
of your three levels of consciousness
and behavior on earth you've talked
about this multiple times and it's
described in many different traditions
in many different ways I call it your
head brain your heart brain and your
balls balls brain right you already went
balls deep right without a condom you
already followed you balls already
followed your instinct fine cool she's
pregnant that's done cross that one off
you cannot approach this from the mind
because the mind the brain when I say
mine I mean head brain head part of the
mind because all you're rationalizing in
the world first of all is not going to
change their decision and it would be
wrong of you to try and manipulate them
with logic right it's sort of violence
to do this to people
right because for some reason something
in her body hormones instinct love
perhaps it's telling her she wants to
have this baby
okay now maybe for other reasons and I
can only make assumptions based on you
know the information you guys give me
maybe she just wants fucking child
support she's she's licking her chops
but the mom and her said that they don't
want anything from you so I'm gonna go
based on that information so your mind
your brain you can't fix this with your
brain right there's nothing you can do
you can't manipulate the world in any
particular way by using your your
calculative skills you have one thing
left your heart and I promise you that
if you approach this situation she has a
baby always proceeding from your heart
you're going to do a number of things
first I'm going to start with the most
practical tangible and then I'm going to
go off into outer space and you some of
you guys will follow me all the way out
of space some of you guys will just hang
out where
that with the practical right practical
here's what you're going to do and
here's why you're going to begin writing
you say you like poetry good get a
notebook get a box full of fucking
notebooks
and starting today begin writing to that
child your regrets won't come from the
fact that you had sex with a girl and
got her pregnant that there will be no
regret about that when you get old your
regrets won't be about how you couldn't
manipulate her to have a an abortion
when you're old and this child is as an
adult you won't feel regret about that
what you fit will feel regret about is
not loving this child the way a part of
you wants to you see whether you know it
or not your heart wants to yield and
melt to this child your head is saying
no way
fuck you this makes no sense whatsoever
ah no and you're using your head to
basically say heart fuck you you should
have no that's your dick earlier but hey
but now you're trying to squash your
your heart you already dude when when
the dick moves in particular 8th
Direction hearts coming along with it
and the heads you basically drag the
rest of you with it so don't start
trying to beat your body down now it
should have thought about that earlier
it's not a judgment
I'm just saying hey take a look at
what's happened and let's let's be
honest about it by you writing even
though this child may or may not ever
get an opportunity to read this while
they're young you're pouring out your
hearts feelings you're pouring out that
which is coming up in your heart and
it's going to be very emotional you need
to pour out all your emotions in a
notebook and it doesn't all have to
sound poetic and beautiful it's not all
fucking roses and puppies a lot of it
might be I really messed up I didn't
want you to be here I wanted to have sex
with your mom because she's so hot but I
never thought she was going to get
pregnant oh my god I feel so bad I feel
so guilty what am I going to do but all
that get that because that's going to be
the first shit that comes up just
fucking be honest and pour that shit out
into the fucking notebooks it's going to
be easy at first because your your your
swelling up with a lot of emotion and
you could pour your heart out in it
while you're you know you're spilling
over essentially but every week for the
rest of this child's life this is your
responsibility obviously you can't pay
for this child
obviously you can't be there all the
time maybe you can maybe you can't I
don't know physically right but your
responsibility if you could just fucking
do this I promise you you you will be so
grateful for this idea when you grow old
every week no matter what no matter how
busy your life is no matter how life has
progressed and what has happened even if
you end up with this woman later on and
this child lives with you right to the
child in your journal I haven't seen you
in seven months I bet you're right now
you're probably walking and talking and
crawling and and then spitting up all
over the place it's probably disgusting
but I a part of me wishes that I could
be there to see you if you have an
opportunity to see the child every once
in a while see the child do not grow
attached because I don't know what type
of agreement you have with a woman but
go home and write today I saw you and
you're wearing a blue jumper and a
baseball cap and it was the first time
that you ever climbed on the monkey bars
and I was so happy to catch you at the
end of the slide right maybe you see the
kid for 20 minutes that's all you get
write that shit down
so what you're doing is you it's a form
of catharsis either a couple practical
things that are happening when you do
this it's a form of catharsis you're
getting it out because guilt will be get
this is when guilt is going to really
happen when these feelings come up and
you place moral judgment on them because
of the choice you made so your hearts
going to want to spill out towards this
child you're going to want to afford
feelings or move feelings towards a
child even though you can't physically
but you're gonna place judgment on it
saying I shouldn't feel this way because
you know I fucked up I made a mistake
bom bom bom bom bom we're gonna bite
your lip you're gonna suck it down bad
move
cuz you're gonna die with guilt you're
gonna lay on your deathbed you know I
talked about the deathbed thing a lot
because we're all gonna fucking die at
some point it could be next week when
you get cancer
guess who knows or could be when you're
an old fucking man but at some point
you're going to this is going to come
back up it's gonna haunt you and guess
what that's hell right you want to go to
hell that's hell right some people might
say that you carry that with you into
the next life I don't know what tap what
happens but I'd like to get rid of this
shit get it out so it's helpful to you
also there is a chance that at some
point this child will come looking for
you there's a chance that you might go
looking for this child after it's grown
up and after the uncomfortable
discussion after the discomfort
associated with your my fucking daddy
you left me and like you just feeling
like you know such a such a weak and
feeble person because this has been your
mistake there will be a softening if you
pursue and an opportunity for you to say
you know I haven't seen you in 17 years
but for the past 17 years I've written
to you and I want to share it with you
now what you do with this is completely
up to you I know you're probably really
upset with me but everything that I've
experienced over the past 17 years
because I have not forgotten about you
are in these books and you walk away
trust me he or she will want to read
those books she'll be very upset at
first but she's going to want to read
those books because there is a heart
connection between the two of you
there's a body connection there's a mind
connection your that's your DNA over
there and she's going to be curious
about what's happening in you what's
happened in you why is she the way she
is and those words are going to be very
helpful to her or him it'll be the
greatest gift that you could offer that
child even if you pay child support it's
just fucking money those books those
journals will mean far more to those
that child then anything else anything
that you probably you were able to
provide there's an and a third thing
that's going to happen and this is you
know I'm being metaphysical now so some
of you who get upset when I move in this
direction maybe turn off the video book
by pouring out your heart to God and in
a way to the universe by spreading it by
letting it out there are unseen forces
that come to your aid that will support
you in bringing all of the positive
projections in your writing towards that
child all of your love that goes out
towards a child it through your writing
is very similar to praying for the child
and after first of all for for thousands
of generations human beings have prayed
it's not a religious thing so much as it
is it's a human act that we find benefit
in either personally or extrinsically
right there have been studies scientific
studies you know we're Buddhist monks go
and they pray in like Detroit where
there's like you know murders every day
and like they go and pray for 24 hours
straight and the murder there isn't a
single murder there's a lot of power to
it
understand that no one fucking
understands it right there's a lot of
shit that we think we understand really
don't understand and one of them is
there's a power to prayer by you writing
in this particular way it is a form of
prayer that's going to go out to the
universe that is going to send love
vibes if you will to your child that
will be felt and that will be supportive
to him or her as they journey through
life let go of your ideas about what
should be what it should look like
what's right and wrong be with the
reality of the situation and be with it
fully meaning give your heart room to
experience this child you might not love
the woman but you you're going to love
this child whether you know it or not
I'm done