our seventeen-year-old friend Kevin
comes to us with a question about young
love relationship that he'd like to get
involved with but the other half of that
relationship isn't so interested so as
the story goes he met a beautiful young
woman through Facebook they hung out a
few times they even kissed and held
hands he expresses his feelings towards
her and wants to take things a little
bit further but she's very resistant in
fact she pulls away slightly and says
I'm not ready in fact I don't think
you're the one Kevin's heart is hurt
heavy with the pain but also full with
the love for this young woman he's
hysterical in his love and he doesn't
know how to approach it what does he do
he's out of his mind he's crazy with
love because that's what happens if
you've ever fell in love you know what
that feels like you're stupid with love
you know the whole world could fall
apart and you'd be fine as long as you
could embrace your beloved if you
haven't experienced that feel sorry for
you we all go through it especially at
about 17 years old so it reminds me I
wanted to share something with you and I
typically look for metaphors things I've
read or books movies I've seen of
stories other people have taught me and
I thought of this movie The Princess
Bride if you haven't seen it you should
it's funny it's romantic eyes but it's
it's a cute little movie anyway in the
movie there is a servant boy by the name
of Wesley and he loves the woman that is
is he his master in essence you know I
think he's that she was the daughter of
the landowner that he was just a servant
peasant servant boy she would say
servant boy servant boy go fetch me
water servant boy get fetch me that that
bale of hay
whatever it was she really looked down
upon him but he was madly in love with
her she couldn't even see him because he
was just a servant boy in many ways she
can't even see you she may be
approaching the situation where she's
perhaps a little bit better
you and you're just not the right type
you might not be the right race you
might not come from the right family you
might not be from the right neighborhood
but for some reason you're not good
enough for her
Wesley loved this woman and in so doing
he beheld her beauty every waking moment
and in every activity that he did it's
very it's funny as he watched the movie
his eyes always filled with his
admiration of and beholding of the woman
I can't remember her name and even when
she basically spat on him with her
demands go fetch me water servant boy he
would look her in her eyes with a sight
slight grin in his face and he would say
as you wish as you wish as you wish was
the only thing that would come from his
mouth and he delighted in the pleasure
of beholding her and being in her
present even though she couldn't even
see him as a vow as a human being worthy
of you know anything other than barking
demands at the point that I want to make
to you is that when you're in love
you're in love and the experience is
yours do not get that confused with the
desire the selfish desire to own the
beloved you will be you will suffer
great pain if instead of swimming in the
experience of love and beholding your
beloved in other words seeing her for
what she is appreciating her for what
she is
experiencing all that she will allow you
to experience given the circumstances
you will miss all of that if you want to
grasp you want to hold on to you want to
possess the love do you see there's a
quote by Osho where he says that if you
see a flower and you love the flower
behold it don't pick it because as in
your desire to possess you'll destroy
now that's me paraphrasing in fact I
paraphrase everything I don't memorize
anything my man Kevin dude
swim in the waters of your love
experience it express it and I'll tell
you in a moment just how so let me back
up for a moment swim in it behold her
beauty behold her form
you've when you're in love even the way
she breathes your heart flutters I get
it
just the way she walks the way she
smells all the stupid things that she
does you know she might giggle and snort
and you're like oh behold it behold it
all and swimming it experience it fully
without the selfish desire to possess
now there's a difference between
experiencing and beholding the love and
suppressing it I'm not telling you to
suss press it it's there be with it
but the nature of the male figure and
the nature of the penis is to reach out
and in your beholding you're gonna feel
this urge to want to grab cousin hold
her caress her oh I just want to hold
you I want to bring you inside me you
ever loved someone so much as you want
to spike put them inside you you want to
hug them so much that you melt into one
she can't she's not available to you in
that way so you've got to transcend that
physical desire to grasp and through
your expression of poetry art or music
you will be able to allow your heart and
your body and your mind to give up or to
let out
everything that's swelling up inside
your body all right of course you can
check off on that lets the swelling out
of your dick but what I'm asking you to
do is in many ways there's a term called
sexual transmutation bring it up out of
your body and out of your primal desires
your fears and your limitations bring it
into your heart and right to her okay
this video is gonna be pretty long right
to her right to her if you're if you've
never written poetry before try it's
gonna be shitty it's gonna be bad poetry
but it's your poetry if you play music
write her a song if you paint paint for
her if you my father likes to build
Gardens build Gardens
I mean Taj Mahal's are built for men who
love their women and fetching of water
is done with the essence of love
pervading in the name of in honor of the
beauty beloved let your actions be
colored by the love that you have for
her again without a desire or
expectation from her write a love sonnet
write a love poem write a love letter
but write it because you feel love and
you want to express yourself not to
manipulate not to gain her from it you
see here's what's going to happen you're
not going to really it's not going to be
a positive experience for you if you
write this love letter hand it to her
and wait and watch Oh she'll be coming
any time now
here she comes oh I know she read it
what did she think oh I bet she really
liked it oh that part where I said such
and such a oh man dude I was on point
and here she comes here she comes and
guess what she might not even read it
yet she's been holding on to it for a
week and she's got oh I forgot I forgot
you wrote me wrote this for me
you got to deal with that well she might
read it and laugh giggle show her
friends what are you so silly
you got to deal with that you're not
doing it for her you're not doing it for
her entertainment you're not doing it so
that her friends like you better because
you're such a romantic poet doing
because you need to do it it's catharsis
you're doing it for yourself
behold your beloved experience the
depths of love but free yourself from
the desire to possess the beloved