we got a long question here from our
friend Sarah I'm not going to read it
but I'm going to give you the gist of it
essentially she goes on to say that
amongst my friends I tend to have a
level of wisdom that allows me to serve
them when they're having trouble trouble
in their lives and I offer them certain
ideas and perspectives and ways of being
that support them as they get through
their their problems and in the
beginning it was pretty interesting for
her to share these ideas and they would
be very grateful for but now they start
calling her things like prophets and
Oracle putting almost like a god like
throne under her butt and she's
wondering she is very uncomfortable this
is like wait a second guys I'm not a God
I'm not a prophet like I'm not an Oracle
of any sort so I'm just your friend and
I happen to know these things I happen
to think you know them too but I have a
way of sharing these ideas that is that
kind of gets through your skull so that
you can use them practically in your
life and what she's saying she's getting
very uncomfortable she wants to keep
serving her friends in this way but the
whole idea that perhaps she's better
than them or some sort of a prophet it's
a bit uncomfortable for her and she
comes to me because she's like Elliot I
read the comments that people say make
statements like Elliot your prophet
Elliot you're a god and and I wonder how
do you do with that of course you know
if she's coming from the same line of
work in this way that I am we share
ideas with people she realizes well you
know you're not so much a god Elliot
right I mean so how do you handle people
saying that shit to you does it make you
uncomfortable yes it it can make me
uncomfortable but it doesn't because I
have a bit of perspective for you my
friend let me come at you this way let's
uh we'll do a little bit of a history
but travel down history back up to where
we are today with regard to this idea of
a of a living God and things of that
nature or prophets & Oracle's and stuff
like that but before I do that I want to
share with you one of my favorite quotes
by Bruce Lee when he talks about you
know did I forget what movie it is maybe
it's Enter the Dragon I'm not sure but
he's talking to a young man and he
points his finger to the
to the moon and he says something of the
effect of uh you know don't look at my
finger because if you do you'll miss all
the heavenly glory
so it's like he's a finger pointing to
the moon and the person would have a
tendency to like grab on to and latch to
the finger it's a fucking great finger
and it's attached to you you must be
amazing you must be a god you must be
some sort of prophet
you are perfect right that's a trap in
that way and he'd say no no no no Nick
stop look at where I'm pointing
motherfucker you're gonna miss it if you
look at me right very profound very
helpful way to look at it for you as the
pointer and also to remind the people
who are listening to wait a second guys
I'm just pointing to all the heavenly
glory get your get your eyes off me for
a moment look it's up there you'll miss
everything so I wanted to share that
with you I've made a video about this in
the past on my other channel maybe I'll
link it up if I remember but um I
searched my other channel strength camp
for finger I'm just a finger or
something like that anyway and I related
to my fans of that particular way in
that video many civilizations ago if I
were if I could you know I'm talking
about like ancient Greek Roman Egyptian
civilizations where they had the
political hierarchy that was very much
in meshed with religion or mythology
things of that nature they would often
recognize particular archetypical
characters types and individuals and
they would recognize that this person
has a particular unique kind of spirit
right so they would say that the the
diamond or the diamond right the work
where we get the word diva or or the God
is with you right is with that person
and they would recognize that this
person was was blessed in that
particular way in that they could they
represent a particular archetype and
wherever they went
they were able to serve people with that
particular power you know
yours in mind is sort of like the power
of the Prophet the word poem poet is the
root part of it as prophet that's where
comes from so what kind of like poor
speakers that's all we do which is kind
of talkers we motivate people excite
people with our words and the thing is
that those ancient cultures those are
our ancestral cultures didn't
necessarily worship the being they
worshiped the archetype in that
individual right so if if I showed up
and and behaved in a very resourceful
way for the world it wasn't so much
Elliott Hulse that they they admired and
looked up to but the Elliott Hall spirit
right it's the spirit of an Eliot house
that they would recognize and they might
use that name or they might use the name
of another deity that they would have
created for that particular time in
place it's the spirit of it's the it's
the diamond of its the muse there's
another way they would describe it their
muse within him it's not the container
it's what's what's coming through the
container it's not the it's not
necessarily the flute right that plays
the music that makes the sound it's the
artist is end up the Spirit is spirit
breath the spiros moving through the
feet the flute right you're the flute
you're just the flute hollow Reed if you
will and then there's a spirit moving
through you so is the sound to be
attributed to the the flu or is the
sound to be attributed to where that
spirit is coming from where the breath
is coming from for the flute right and
they recognized that it was the spirit
it was this breath right the inspiration
that word spirit is written linked
heavily to the word breath breathing
aspired inspire expire so they always
pointed to the spirit of the individual
very spirited individual or you know the
spirits thank the gods not the man this
is the way it was through most of human
history up until the Magnificent
manifestation of Jesus Christ
right and Jesus behaved in the same way
and was an archetype of the Christ
spirit in that particular way in that
day and age until the political
structures at the time realize just how
dangerous a dude like Jesus really is
and they made him special now for those
of you who worship Jesus look do your
research on the history of the church in
particular the Catholic Church you know
you may or may not be Catholic but know
that a significant portion of your
ideals that you think are yours come
from the political structure of the
Catholic Church and if you don't think
the Catholic Church is Apple it is ik is
a political body then you really just
haven't paid attention to history do
your studies repeat history study
history the brilliance of the political
structure the religious political
structure at that particular time said
look this Jesus guy we can't have any
more of him so what we need to do is
make him untouchable let's make him a
god they all decided this at the the
conference of Nicaea right they all
decided it would be in our best interest
political and religious structure power
right the oligarchy to make Jesus
something of a God not the Spirit of
Christ through him but Kim himself so
you can't be him he's the one and only I
am the one and only they have him say
very dangerous thing also because then
it it it diminishes the power of that
Christ spirit showing up in other people
or and it even removes the philosophy
the idea that the very resourceful way
of saying that spirits reemerge
archetypical spirits reemerge in certain
individuals you my friend are the
expression or the reincarnation if you
will of a prophetic spirit okay your
physical body has taken in the archetype
of the prophetic spirit you are an
Oracle in that way but not to you I
think your name's Sara it's not you it's
the spirit showing up in you and it
gives you a place of humility it allows
you to move from a place of humility
when you look at it that way and
also when you explain it to your friends
the way I'm explaining it right now
don't warship me these are just the
words coming through this is the air the
breath coming through my instruments
thank the blower of the air Jesus would
say my father right I'm gonna read a
little bit of what Jesus says in this
regard also because if you study the
words of Jesus you'll find that he also
is like look not by me but through my
father it's my father
he keeps saying my father and then he
goes on to point to and I'm gonna read
him from from from the Bible here for a
moment bear with me where he says look
you can do the same shit it is for
Matthew he goes the words I speak are
not my own blasphemy but for my father
who lives in me and does his work
through me now Jesus is saying right now
right there it's not me motherfuckers
it's the spirit moving through me it's
my father moving through me he happens
to call it the father you call whatever
you want but there is a that there's
this spirit moving through him he just
says you know just believe that they
know the father is moving through me
trust that the Christ spirit the Father
is moving through me but again I'm going
to reiterate his words the words I speak
or not my own those aren't Jesus's words
just like my words aren't my words in
many instances depending on how
connected I am when I'm making these
videos I always aim to support you guys
with the words that I share but you know
sometimes I'm in the way Jesus or Eliot
but call myself Jesus the flesh becomes
a deterrent gets in a way you know I
have an ego also you know I ate some
food that didn't jive with my physiology
last night so I'm little grumpy you know
whatever it is the flesh gets in the way
so the Spirit is obstructed and its
ability to move through so you could
recognize that there's a Jesus in the
way there's an Eliot in the way there's
a Sarah in the way but at the minute you
can get out of the way recognize in
recognizing yourself recognizing others
and allow them to recognize in you that
if they aren't your words especially
there were potent gems sometimes I watch
my videos and I'm like damn what did I
eat that Degas that was good
I'll watch my videos under my holy shit
That's not me talking okay I'm not
saying I'm a Jesus not saying you should
bullshit me because if you listen
closely it's anything but that it's
received these words because they're
happening through me - and that's what
Jesus says look receive these words just
trust that they're not coming from
either coming from my father it goes on
you know and this is why I love reading
the Bible in this particular way so do
an empowered stance as opposed to
worshipping and if suppression Jesus
goes on I tell you the truth anyone who
believes in Me will do the same works
I've done and even greater blasphemy
again and of course you'll have a
biblical scholars and theology
you know have their perspective on why
he said that and what and you know how
absolutely does not mean that you're
powerful means that you know you know
you're still slaves to Jesus and in our
you know our superstition about him
Jesus is plainly sitting there saying
what I'm saying to you right now I tell
you the truth that anybody believes what
I'm saying right now that this is coming
through the Father father will do the
same works I've done and even greater
works it's a matter of trust so when you
my friend share this with your friends
of course you can take the humble stance
of it's not me it's my father but also
know that if you trust my father you
trust the Spirit you trust the way you
trust God you trust whatever you want to
call it you two can do the same thing
even greater not the nerve of Jesus to
say that about God right that you could
do even greater hey pull out your old
King James Version it's in there
so that's it folks look you my friend
are gifted in this particular way you're
a prophet in that there is a spirit
moving through you that serves the world
with ideas that have been suppressed or
forgotten and you have a particular way
of sharing it with people that allows us
to get
through the thickness and the fog of
mental conditioning I like to think that
I have the same sort of skill I mean
almost a million subscribers between my
two channels kind of says yeah I do have
that skill and I take no credit for it
whatsoever absolutely not because it's
the father speaking through me and you
could do the same thing done