hey what's up guys today we got an
interesting question from our buddy
Jonathan this is a question that I would
normally answer on my strength training
YouTube channel because it has a lot to
do with the muscles but because there's
a bioenergetic component to my answer I
decided I put it on my weird Elliot said
what YouTube channel so the question is
Jonathan was to know why his legs are
always so tight he goes on to describe
how he can use his mind to relax the
muscles but the minute he takes his
concentration off of relaxing the
muscles they go right back to being as
tight as they were before so that tells
us a couple things it tells us that you
do have some sort of conscious control
over your ability to tighten or relax
those muscles right that's important to
consider because if it was completely
subconscious we'd have a lot more
digging to do a lot of people have
really tight muscles but they don't know
why they just walk around saying and my
neck is tight my neck is tight little do
they know that they're physically
tightening their neck my back always
hurts a little didn't know that they're
physically tightening their back but you
actually realize how you're doing this
the problem is the minute you take a
concentration off it goes back there are
a couple things considered number one
energetically the legs are associated
with grounding you are standing your
ground when you tighten your legs so for
example my daughter I've got three of
them I got four children but when I yell
at a see this and two of my daughters
the older ones when I yell at them or I
you know not even yell just tell them
that what they're doing is unacceptable
and you need to change your behavior
they become very upset and they stiffen
their body I see them do this they go I
can see the legs drive back the butt
gets real tight they drive their arms
down they just do this basically they're
energetically shutting down they
basically decided I don't want to
receive what you're giving me and I'm
going to put up armor they tighten their
bodies like that so when you're in a
situation where you're your personhood
is being challenged there may be a
tendency from an early age I'm watching
my kids do it okay on
screw them up but from an early age to
tighten the body to subconscious then
become subconscious tighten the legs to
stand your ground or literally standing
your ground and then if the threat is
consistently present or you think it's
consistently present you know basically
you're always worried that you're going
to be challenged and you have to stand
your ground you're going to develop the
habit of tightening your legs right so
that's one to consider the second one to
consider which may or may not be the
case is your experiences with potty
training if you were forced to hold your
shit when you really needed to poop
because you know mommy needed to go to
work and you had to go to daycare and
the daycare wasn't gonna take any kids
if they shit themselves you've got to
start figuring out how to tighten your
ass so that you don't shit yourself at
an early age this is sort of impossible
for some kids because the the
neuromuscular connection to the anus is
not fully developed yet right you just
can't do it you just can't hold your
poop like an adult does and that's why
kids shit themselves
but you try your best because you want
to make mommy happy so what you do is
you tighten your legs you tighten the
muscles in your your glutes your your
hamstrings your hamstrings your hip
flexors you do whatever you can to kind
of tighten tighten those muscles up so
you don't shit yourself right and that
again may you know over the course of
weeks or months you may have have to do
that it became ingrained in your nervous
system and you carried it with you
throughout lucknow you're you know an
adult out of your teenager or you're in
college one of the case may be but I get
tightening those muscles that don't need
be tighten so we've got to do two things
we've got to exhaust the muscle
physically and we've got to get out the
bioenergetic or the emotional I say
emotional I mean energy in motion
e-motion
the emotional tie to the activity right
they get ingrained they get stuck in us
so when my daughter's get angry and
they're sniffing the bodies because
they're not going I hate you dad fuck
you
dad haha not letting it out right and a
part of that is because I probably
squash some of it before I understood
how the body and the mind work together
here several years ago now I tell them
look you can be angry go be angry go and
stop that's one of the things that I
invite you to do and this is what I
teach my children just stop try that
hopefully you can see me I'm just
stopping my legs in one of my older
videos that I used to describe my daily
bioenergizer warmup you see that we
finish like this buh buh buh buh buh buh
buh buh what we're doing is grounding
the body exhausting the legs exhausting
the body but also letting go of
emotional feelings thoughts every time
you hope you're basically standing your
ground you're grounding your legs if you
do that and what I would write you do do
that like 15 20 minutes student you're
going to exhaust the drive and the need
to contract those muscles they're just
going to be so tired that you can't do
it and you're grounding ha ha ha ha or
do you like my children do they just
like to stomp the ground they go I sent
him upstairs me they stomp up the stairs
this is good do that let out the sound
associated with it and exhaust the
muscle with the exercise the other one
that I would invite you to do so they're
stopping and then there's throwing a
temper tantrum my kids normally would
but they're not allowed to so again
stuffed down and and causes a lot of
muscular tension defiance is one of our
our rights as human beings and our
defiance gets stuffed because parents
don't like you to behave in a defiant
fashion right but it's still in there
and you have guilt associated with
squashing yourself after your parents no
longer
all your lives so what you've got to do
is act out that defiance with a temper
tantrum I'll throw in here for you sissy
lay down on your bed at down act help
the temper tantrum use your legs
slam your legs down hard get it all out
exhaust the muscle get rid of the
emotional ties to that tension and your
legs will soften up dude keep me posted
I hope this was fun and informative for
everyone I'll talk to you next time
Elliot's it