all right another one of these questions
about you know love and loss essentially
you know a lot of you guys are young and
you're falling in love with these girls
as you should
I made an earlier video this week or
you'll see it eventually where I say yes
you should fall in love problem is
you're personally identifying with the
experience that you have with these
girls you're 16 years old you've got a
friend here and it's having a lot of
anxiety with his girlfriend because when
they're together everything is great
but when they're apart he finds that she
other guys flirt with her she they
message each other on Facebook and and
he has a lot of anxiety when they're not
together so he just wants to be with her
like I need to be with you all the time
because if I let you go and you go to
the store like you might bump into a
friend and start talking giggling with
another man or or or if you catch her on
Facebook like what could happen somebody
might take her away from you right and
this is all the fucking anxiety so you
want to you want to bottle her up and
keep her with you all the time right
mine you understand you're only secure
when she's mine when you have her my
very immature place to come from with
regard to love and it stems from not
standing on your own two feet and
sucking her tits for nourishment titty
seconds for babies guys you don't get
nourishment from your woman in that
particular way you can't personally
identify with her love for you love
happens for the sake of love not
ownership right and you want to own
something if you're nourished by it
fully nourished by it the same way baby
sucks on the tit because it needs the
moms breasts the fucking nurses door
dies you energetically latch on to her
and your personal worth growth and
esteem isn't is coming from another
mortal from a 16 year old girl bro she
probably still has a fucking Hello
Kitty's iPhone she's your mommy now
that's what happens
she ends up becoming your mommy and
mommy mommy kicked you off the breast
when you were three years old if you
were that lucky so now you don't let
this one go right she rubs your dick
Pat's your back the sucker tip when I
talk about vulnerable love which I did
in an earlier video or one that you
might see this week I don't talk about I
don't mean giving up your own sense of
worth or stability or grounding you need
to be your own fucking man first and if
every single time she's not around you
all you could think about is how you can
get her back because you might lose her
that means you have nothing else and
like I've said in other videos men need
to have their mission what are you up to
what else are you doing
are you are you 100% completely invested
in your woman because it's a dangerous
place to be or are you living in the
virtual world of gaming you know games
or are you being creative
how are you dropping your seed how you
how you ejaculate into the world right
are you see one of the things that have
had saved me as a young man was weight
training I'd bust my nut in the gym you
understand metaphorically I'd lift
weights I started noticing why my
muscles are getting bigger oh my god I
can move more weight oh my god I'm a
great I'm a better athlete oh my god I
couldn't get an athletic scholarship oh
my god MVP I was I was building the
relationship with myself through
achievement in the world and that's what
you need to do go fucking do something
dude get a hobby something respectable I
don't even need to be respectable fuck
that give me something unrespectable as
long as you feel grounded in it can't
reiterate this enough man you got to
stand on your own two feet before you
give your balls and heart to a woman you
need to possess yourself first otherwise
you're gonna be obsessed with possessing
her that's slavery for both of you
because you don't own anyone else
if she
he's giggling and snickering and and
kissing other boys that's her
prerogative that's her becoming stronger
version of herself that's her engaging
in the experiences that she has to have
in order to grow the way she needs to
grow
now when you love someone and you see
them making mistakes that hurts even
more but if you love someone and you see
them expanding and they're doing things
that you don't particularly like because
you know you want to bottle her off and
keep her for yourself but she's
expanding as a human being you gotta say
let love do what love has to do a lot of
times love has the fucking let go and
that's how it strengthened it doesn't
mean that the love with her is going to
strengthen with your ability to love in
a mature fashion will be strengthened
done