alright this is a business question
actually out of sight I'm a fine series
com vintage I'm a big fighter series com
and i've youtube channel basically I've
about six months and above 30 ish videos
or something Chris and I'm being a
little bit of traction in like six three
subs on YouTube 5k on on youtube but I'm
not getting enough people to my site
even though I've tried so many your
channel or to your blog or when it's my
sweet baby and I getting up email so
you're trying to get people on your
newsletter because that's really the
next step in an odd job ladder yeah like
I don't know what for you over your best
ways to get people in there because I've
tried angel bumpers clickable links
ultra bunkers the description box
there's there to way there are two
things that work really really really
well one okay not gonna judge them I'll
give one is you got to give away
something really frickin awesome okay
well it down to one awesome one when you
give people too many options or too much
stuff they get confused and overwhelmed
I know what I'm looking for a solution I
don't want three books three what's the
salute
that your offer is a knockout okay daily
e-mails take that all take that off you
do it you don't tell me because that's
that okay that's not right that's not
sexy we gotta seduce of the two you
should probably pull the people that are
already on your list which did you like
they might all say he'll at knockout
video series was so dope and you say Oh
what about the conditioning one what
conditioning women oh oh yeah yeah you
see and then you take that winner and
you build it up you talk about it and
all your videos to make a really good
page that highlights all the points that
people are going to receive all things
are going to receive my reading it you
also get just some oils if you carefully
watched it and it really helped them and
that's the one thing and then you just
keep driving people to that that one
thing hey it's all about yeah it's all
about the instant knock out all of its a
knockout I'm needs to knock out guy I
want to give you x 3 is the knockout
video of course I'm instantly knock
people out you wanna not allowed but you
need to watch this video remember that
is really convincing about it right cuz
if they watch it everybody wins right
I'll sure your thing helps me to know
knock them out instantly so you gotta
get that interviews hands and you got a
relay the value I think one of the
things that we have a hard time doing is
besides just throwing our own value is
that being too scared to say how much
value on fire I'm gonna shit a little
value here guys isn't it knockout it's
not gonna be loud all over the place I'm
giving it to you for free so that's
that's one may be old on your method
because got your widget you know about
that thing or this is elliott hulse
method that's taken having to use that
I've done that then a lot I'm still
doing it because i'm creating four
layers of strength I'm writing a book
giveaway but everybody already knows who
that is when i say quality of the thread
there wasn't like guess i wanted right I
know they're all going to get min and I
said that out there's going to be
exactly what's in the water that's cool
but that's because what I've done is
build goodwill over with over several
years so since 2007 I can answer a
question people already know like your
trust Elliot else so I don't even have a
new offer anything together when
newsletter I just hate you like what I
talk about want to hear what I have to
say Michael it sign up see but that's
because it's not a pain Ellie Ellie has
always helped us with these videos Ellie
knows what he's talking about Elliot's
entertaining damn right I want more so
you wouldn't you can do that also that
takes smaller I take seven years of
putting in good karma goodwill what in
the beginning what I did want to tell
you
what I will go back to do in the world
is solve a problem and then to improve
the channel you have to improve quality
and content that is that's on the
channel so I haven't seen any get the
content but this is a digital term if
you haven't studied at Kennedy I'd like
to study all of his material because
infotainment so you it's not good enough
to be an in-form backing it up smartly
that good enough to be able to help you
with your intelligence and your ideas
you've also got to entertain and even an
entertaining culture really we don't
need anything lido and most people you
go with your pd a-- a college degree
just by searching google everything I
mean honestly but what we do want it'll
feel good and entertaining so in the
same way that your informations got to
be good otherwise it's like these guys
are just this guy's fool you also have
to get a tank because you want me to say
up what is that important
really good editing you know we make
your videos it's like they're really
just flashing you they look awesome it
could be a really good character I would
like way too fast talk to talk a bit
about myself oh that's really it's how
the information being presented and
vital info tain helpful yeah it takes I
wish I could say hey yeah three months
all right it's a good process you have
to try things test things things are not
going to work some things that work and
just kind of move I make videos for
seven years I said this the other day my
videos 27 years to get to a hundred
thousand subscribers which was where I
where I was in December December was
100,000 subscriber started 2007 chain
work februari and this debra where f of
two hundred thousand one hundred two
hundred last night three hundred
thousand so my quadrant who would that
be double fudge ripple what it took me
seven years to do in four months oh yeah
and at a big part of it hasn't been
because many years not just a fucked up
what is like I didn't get it right it
took the combination of a few different
things I realized then when I stand
closer to the camera people who are
engaged bassist and backing him I
realized that when I talking to more
conversational tone as opposed to be
educational tone but it's taking time to
figure that out we're offering you
realize might take a long time to figure
out what type of style you
it's best with your audience and then
capitalized