yo Elliot what's up guys say we got a
question for my buddy Glen lives in
college and he wants to be a
powerlifting most power lift problem is
that all the gyms that he goes to in his
City and in his University don't allow
him to lift heavy they got crappy music
I get it man you can't really go do the
thing you want to do you can't you can't
train hard most fitness gyms so he says
I need to get my own he of course has no
funds yeah because that's the way it is
when you're in college ain't got no damn
money and mom and dad are like no fuck
you you're not building a gym in a
garage in our garage so you know that's
out essentially you know those that's
what that's what i would suggest most of
you do is if you've got a garage or shed
in the backyard or something build it
out there but mom and dad are like ya
know so gleb is trying to figure out
what do i do because i got a lift I get
it dude glad this is a perfect
opportunity for you my man this is a
great opportunity for you to build your
leadership and fundraising ability man
build yourself a community gym by
finding other people who are as excited
as you are about weightlifting put your
money together and find a cheap
warehouse might the first the first
warehouse gym that I had my first friend
camp with nine hundred dollars a month
if you get ten guys to put a hundred
dollars together once a month right I
mean your cell phone to your cell phone
bill is probably a hundred dollars
alright cut your cell phone off and get
yourself a damn gym actually I wouldn't
work then you how you gonna call people
to give you money one hundred dollars a
month ten of you guys you get a garage
and then you start filling it with used
equipment that's what I did man I made
my equipment at first but you can go to
a lot of these like play it again sports
we have in the United States I don't
know where you're at you go on
craigslist people by train
equipment all the time the with full
intention to use it but you know what
they say about good intentions right
paves the road to hell right all these
people good intentions ain't doing shit
so the road to hell is paved with good
intentions I like that one good
intentions you got all kinds of good
intentions a lot of people got good
intentions but that don't mean shit
intentions don't mean shit you got an
intention to build yourself a gym and I
don't mean shit if you don't do what I
tell you to do right now go find some
friends Mike it might be a skill to
learn how to get some friends too I mean
just think of all the experience
associated we're going out making this
thing happen you will be a matter Fester
you will have built up the skills of
materializing things right matter
realizes right now it's an idea it's in
your head I built a vision board I do
this every once in a while the other day
i'll make a video about it but you gotta
really visualize you guys see it you got
to feel it the things that you want it's
up here but you want to materialize it
madam realize i love that word too so
that's it man make this happen make this
a goal set out to make this happen i
gave you a few tips tricks tactics that
you can use you're going to need the
help of other people that's a all said
and done you're not gonna do it on
yourself in your own need the help of
other people but that's great man just
one more opportunity to grow stronger as
a man in many realms done Elliott's it
what
[Music]