so today I have a question from one of
our friends who wants to take the call
to adventure I mean isn't that what life
is all about but he's a little unsure so
he asked us a question says Elliot right
now I'm facing this problem that I hope
he could help me with I'm 18 years old
University guy who lives in country a
there's a problem I really like country
a and I'm comfortable here I have
friends I have relatives and the country
itself is great but I'm not studying
what I like now I have an option to go
to country B and study what I want there
but I don't know anyone there no one the
University in country B is better but
the country itself has some problems and
I'm scared because I'm a little darker
of complexion than many of the people in
that country and I'm afraid that they
won't accept me or make allow me to be
friends with them please help so not
unlike many questions that I receive not
unlike many questions that I've answered
but your your question reminded me of an
incredible story that I read some years
ago in fact I posted it on my blog and
I'll put a link for you guys to read it
on your own also but I wanted to relay
this story to you because it's exactly
what I thought when I read your question
it's about a prince now I mean who's got
it better than a prince and he was
raised in a kingdom with the king and
the queen and they provided with him
with all the education all of the luxury
all of the things that can make a life
joyful pleasurable he was educated by
the best teachers he was afforded
everything that he needed to be fully
self actualized and at some point he
decides that he needs to go off into the
forest I think at the point that he part
of the reason why he wanted to go out
into the forest is because he felt he
had a bigger mission in his life and he
set off and let behind all of the
wonderful things that his homeland
country a had to offer right don't get
any better than that to experience what
the world in all of its confusion and
ambiguity
it's instability insecurity has to offer
this is an incredible kid and as he made
his way out into the forest out into the
world and he was warned by others
especially those that loved him that
there is a monster out there sticky
monster they called him and they said
that he likes to kill people and you had
ought to be careful when you go out
there now we have armed you with I think
the name of the story is five weapons
we've armed you with five weapons so I
mean the guys is well rounded in every
single way he's got everything that he
needs for full nourishment of mind and
body and he's got weapons and he goes
out the people are still like be careful
my friend be careful young prince
because there are challenges out there
one in which in particular is known to
destroy all men you see where I'm going
with this because your situation is very
similar those fears associated with what
might destroy who you are out in that
world but listen our prince is an
extraordinary man straw Denari boy
becoming a man and as he ventures out
into the forest he meets sticky monster
and sticky monster approaches him and
says hi where do you think you're going
this is my forest and you shall not past
in fact I will kill you immediately
prepare yourself for death and the
prince says all right bet I got you
motherfucker and pulls out a bow and
arrow one of his weapons pulled out the
bow and arrow and says you're done these
arrows are laced with poison that will
destroy you immediately and let's go the
arrow and it hits sticky monster and it
sticks to him sticky monster looks at
the arrow on his chest and says ah not
good enough they didn't give you the
right weapon my friend what else have
you got so he says fine pulls out a
sword right it's just prepare yourself
for death
Sukie monster and runs to the sticky
monster goes and it just stinks one goes
right inside the monster the monster
looks at it and laughs pulls it out
throws it to the floor and says ah not
strong enough prepare yourself to die he
has no more weapons left he has no more
arrows no more swords but he's got his
two fists and he comes out the sticky
monster ah to take him down with all he
has left he's not giving up he's giving
everything he's got even if he has a
scratch claw bite and spit his way past
this monster ah his arm get stuck and
he's looking up at the monster he says
you're going down motherfucker
ah gives him his other fist and the
sticky monster says prepare to die and
our young prince says fuck you gives him
his leg bang that leg sticks bang his
second leg and he looked up at the
monster and says I bet you think you've
got any don't you miss sticky monster
says you are no challenge for me now I
will eat you alive and the prince says
go right ahead there is a fire in my
belly that will destroy you if you
consume me if you wish take my life but
you will pay the price
the monster is shocked he stops for a
moment thinks wait a second this is
unlike any other competitor I've ever
seen any other warrior if I would have
seen in my life he's willing to give his
life to the very end and even in his
death he will succeed if I eat him he
doesn't lose but perhaps I might and he
changes his tune and says I don't know
what it is about you Prince and he lets
him go says but there's something
special and I'd like to learn more about
this fire in your belly because clearly
you have a weapon that destroys all
is that fire in his belly is what
allowed him to be the powerful man that
then took that tsuki sticky monster and
transformed him into a a bearer of peace
he begins to teach the sticky monster he
reigns in the challenge and makes it a
Ally he takes the enemy the challenge
all the things that he felt weak up
against but still persevered in the face
of that adversity down to the point
where his life was about to be ended but
did not give in to fear and he made that
enemy his ally my friend make your brown
skin make your lack of contacts make
your fear of the unknown your greatest
ally move out into the forest and with
every challenge you have you give the
only weapons you have to your at your
disposal you give everything that you've
got to your very last drop so that in
the end all of the things that scared
you all the things that push most people
away because they won't venture out into
the forest because of that monster will
become your greatest ally and you'll not
only be a stronger version for yourself
but you will be a stronger version for
others who you will inspire to go on to
the forest and use the fire in their
belly to overcome done