and now i'm part of your home phone
around job campaign and i really want to
help people i really want to spread the
message about health just like you do i
want to right now and start to write and
i really want to train people but i
can't help myself i have all these
injuries that have been wondering for so
many years I'm doing the corrective
exercise supplements seeing dr. is this
an apple shit I'm not getting better
ical other people footage is
specifically what didn't give me one top
of 10 noel kind of suck shoulders
rotator cuff impingement just really
unstable shoulders what is that manifest
a scan can't push ups or can't do
push-ups haven't been able to push up
since like 2010 like just how do you
work out I do you basically what my body
lets me do like I haven't learned seen a
lot of this mobility work I'll do like
core work like planks I'll try to
strengthen my upper back kevin rose and
stuff like that what's really limited
and this I made a video much same
question yeah but Charlie you're saying
I was talking more about like doing why
don t like training helping people that
any was kind of like confidence thing
and you said to whatever you want to do
and now I have that confidence that I
still can't help myself now you're still
attached to the old story you're still
you're still heavily enrolled in that
story that I'm injured so I not eight am
i capable right you and I'm going to say
this facetiously you love that story
you're in love with that story because
in the same way that were saying Sam's
what Sam does give us him defines who he
is your injuries define and your attacks
joy in such a way that if you didn't
have them you wouldn't know who you are
because you've been dealing with them
for how many years since 2009 right how
did 19 right so that's like 30 of look
like this big point in each other in 20
and you can we had this conversation to
hear you over here where my baby and you
came and you paid on your blog so sorry
five bucks depending on when you sign up
come here and ask the same question it's
because you love you snuggling up with
in your gear you're identifying with it
and you're
canyon with doing you showing it to me
over here and so it's you were there and
it's like it's good to puppy you got it
and your love it you got set up a
different story it's all about story you
tell yourself and your only start
selling yourself a different story about
don't worry the stories for you I can
tell you stories by yourself that will
turn you into a superstar but you can't
whom you won't tell those stories and
accept those stories until you give up
the one that you are identified with and
you're heavily identified with this
story okay and the attack on you but but
I get this you self-identified as
yourself as the injured guy right so you
being injured and not being able to turn
I love this phrase if you can't fix it
feature you can take any handicap and
make that you're saving fucking grace
that you seen the guy that has the long
slender gets on stage and he doesn't
motivational speeches like this might be
chicken he's not enrolled in a story
about why he can't do shit your
shoulders a little bit then uh not to
say that that's not a valid reason for
and I don't push ups but you can hear
you to look that story so much that it
stopping you from getting on stage
there's no stop that guy right he can't
fix that maybe you can't fix your
shoulders
I'm the guy really with injuries that
figured out how to lose weight hey and
you ask you how many people here's the
thing about marketing people want to do
business with others people that know
their story or they can relate to their
story you don't have any people have
that story and they think they're
enrolled in that story they love that
story that if they hear you see your
results and you say I have the same
story they're gonna be like where are
you going is out Holly right they that
maybe you're gonna be a selling point
but you've got to let go of it being a
crush you got to get let go of it as
it's something that is bad and you got
to let go of the idea that you're not
good enough because of it and embrace it
as something to win by
so I would say you take that thing and
that's your that's how you're helping me
hey injured folks have you ever been
injured have you ever actually so bad
that you can't do push-ups well look at
me I have a nice lean body without any
pushups i'll show you how other things
are got to figure something out have
something to offer maybe you just may be
your technique is you very strict with
diet and you do a lot of Pilates we
apply this is the next size of its
design for people that are bed waiting
that's where the guy mr. Pilates created
this fucking thing because huh yes
Joseph Pilates right see you know that
story right like he was in bed or
somebody who was in bed and you can
exercise so it's like I figure out how
to take my abs and we do bitter side hmm
rehab the soldiers so they were injured
shoulder tote
and they are exercising the bed
guy was working out people
injuries from the military
I mean nobody has heard anybody not
heard of life right create your own lies
the whole idea is you've got get over
the foolish all right if you came in
here with no legs and no arms I still
say yes solution see that the wrong
place this kind of heaven are laid out
here in bitching he's making millions of
elevating books a shout out a fucking
Facebook
oh I got a google app the app Clary
before Magna software for my computer
that i put headphones on and it dictates
the dictates offer it's called Dragon
Dictate then I talking types of shit so
you might be doing that good next
question