like many of the words in our language
maturity is one of those words that
become so sullied with implication that
it loses its true essence a lot of times
we use words that that convey at its
core a beautiful message and when you
grow up as the oldest of four children
and you go to school and you know people
have certain expectations for you that
word maturity gets thrown around quite a
bit and I'm sure a lot of the young
people watching these videos understand
what I'm saying when adults say to you
you should behave more mature why don't
you get it become a bit more mature or
act more maturely it almost sounds like
they're that word means do what I say be
more like me do what everyone else
expects you to do so that word ends up
taking on a lot of old boring dying dead
grey association but here's what I've
experienced as I grow in my maturity
through my experience and wisdom I'm
discovering that that's not exactly true
in fact maturity is one of the most
beautiful words in the world and this is
what I've discovered and have decided to
approach the place where I've decided to
approach the word from maturity is not
so much taking on the expectations or
following through with what other people
or society or popular culture think
things that you should it is more of a
yielding to your true essence it's a
more it's more of a becoming conscious
aware and displaying that which is truly
you your purest core your heart your
balls moving from a maturity that that
is unique that it's subjective that is
unapologetically you
and it doesn't mean you won't make
mistakes see a lot of what adults want
to make us understand i say us because
i'm placing myself with with most of the
people that watch these videos is that
even if you follow our ways you won't
make any mistakes well that's really
that's a really dangerous place to be
because without mistakes doesn't there's
no maturity because without mistakes
there's no experience well that
experience there's no wisdom and if
there's no wisdom there's no true
fucking maturity it's just you're
getting old and now you're following the
rules better because you're too scared
or to lack the energy don't have the
balls any longer to fight against it to
be truly you a person who is moving from
a place of maturity makes mistakes but
in such a way that he's fully aware and
can ask himself is the action that I'm
about to take or have just taken coming
from my true essence my heart and my
balls my body is it truly me or is it a
byproduct of ego construct or
expectations based on other people's
projections the biggest mistakes that
you make in life are the ones that come
from other people's expectations and ego
gratification you will never make a
mistake and you will only grow mature if
you move from your heart from your gut
from your balls from your truest essence