so people often ask me how is it that I
I have such a wide array of
understanding it and ideas people also
want to know how is it Elliot that
you're interested in so many divergent
subjects for example I recently just put
a video of one of my favorite songs by
the Beatles blackbird on my youtube on
my facebook wall and people wonder or
our shots and say Elliot I would never
imagine that you're a Beatles fan well
here's the thing the reason why I'm able
to be this way you know it may seem
strange to many people that like you
know for example I listen to country
music or or the fact that I can quote
the Bible but I call my I don't call
myself a Christian I read the Quran I
also read the Dow and in fact I am very
intrigued by the ideas of a lot of
atheists right so how is it that someone
that can quote the Bible who who has a
black face you know for example the way
I look and not be attached to the
associations with either of those things
right how is it that I you know I quote
the Bible but yet I'm not attached to
the ideas in the Bible in such a way
that it is in a reflection of Who I am
in other words I'm not personally
attached it doesn't identify me right is
in the same way that the way I look my
race like you know why should that
identify the type of music I listen to
why should that identify the the type of
conversations I engage in why should
that identify the thoughts that I'm
willing to consider and harbor the ideas
so what I want to invite you to do is to
is to realize that the biggest trouble
is when you become so attached to an
idea alright or a set of ideas a set of
virtues or in other words or religion or
philosophy that you close yourself off
to all the other amazing things that the
world has to offer even your enemy has
something very interesting to offer
instead of looking at your enemy and his
ideas
the origin of his ideas as something
evil and opposite of you and should be
shunned and turned away from embrace it
look at it there may be something there
and I found in fact that if there's
anything that people converge around if
there's any idea beautiful Asif E or
religion an art music poetry if there's
anything that people converge around
there's something potent there there's
something nourishing there and it's
worth your time to look into so that's
how you open yourself up to a wide array
of ideas and concepts and you further
you grow stronger you further facilitate
your ability to remix ideas and come up
with your own the world is an idea
playground take in as many ideas as you
can objectively look at it realistically
blend the things that are useful to you
and create your own