everybody from Portugal wants to know
how you go about setting life goals
long-term goals he watched my video on
energy management and he says that you
know it's difficult for him and he soon
as many other people to be focused and
disciplined on something so far off how
is it that I can set life goals and I'm
like I'm just trying to do what I can do
today and I'm already having problems
just doing this shit right can you tell
me a little bit more about that you're
not the only one right right when I
first started setting goals I listened
to a program by Brian Tracy called the
luck factor I'd highly recommend it
and he described one way one of the many
ways that he described a set set goals
that resonated deeply with me right
because I like you it's like you know
I'm so focused on the day to day how can
I have these big goals he said write
your obituary your obituary is basically
what people would say about you or write
what someone would say about you when
you're dead basically at your funeral
you want people to stand up and say this
about you that was so profound to me
because it had less to do with what
you're going to get in life and quite
frankly I mean I don't say this to sound
pious or you know egotistical of it in
any way but I'm not really attached to
stuff it's very difficult for me to get
to set goals like I want this thing
there are many things I want I try to
attach to things that way like I have
something to strive for but really my
journey in life is more about becoming
who am i becoming who am i serving what
kind of person am i because that's what
they're going to talk about on your
deathbed that's what they're going to
say in your obituary that's what people
gonna stand up and say it your funeral
so once you write that out I wrote this
out probably about 10 years ago I should
go and pull it out once you do write it
you should you should read it at least
once a year to remind yourself of like
what you're doing and if you are living
up to that right a day shouldn't go by
that you're not living up to what will
be said about you at your funeral do
understand and that way it's
it's a bit more abstract it's not as
concrete which causes far less anxiety
in my mind at least about achieving it
now once you've seen that right you go
you come back to your day-to-day
activity or day-to-day actions every
decision you have to make and see if it
is in tagged in integrity if it matches
up with that vision of yourself you see
so that goal is more than an amount of
money it's more than a car it's more
than a house it's who you're becoming
and then you act in consistent ways with
that now if you if you're talking more
tangible you got to ask yourself what
type of things do you value you know for
me the most tangible things that I could
describe as an expression of Who I am or
is the type of business I build and what
I do with my family so I want to do one
of my long-term goals you see which
isn't necessarily my obituary but what I
see myself actively actually doing is
speaking in front of hundreds of
thousands of people and I'm kind of
doing it already but you know I've
always envisioned this stadium like all
these people and I'm speaking and
getting them all riled up and excited
and focused and inspired about becoming
the strongest version of themselves it's
a vision right so less if a goal it's
more of a vision and I visualize that as
well
with my family I see myself having a big
yard and a pool and a place for my
children to run and play and then each
one of them growing up to become the
strongest version of themselves it's a
vision a little less than a goal goals
are very today what are you going to do
today that's going to impact your vision
and your obituary it's just a different
way to look at it good luck