one of the most dangerous words in the
English language is nice because nice
doesn't actually mean anything people
say be nice she was nice or that thing
is nice the thing with the word nice is
that it leaves a lot of room for
interpretation and what has happened
over time because I don't know the roots
of the word but over time it's become a
very surface phenomenon it's actually
something that we do regardless of who
or being or how we feel on the inside so
for example my children they'll fight
with one another argue or throw things
you know kids and we can choose to say
be nice be nice to your sister that
basically means I know you're frustrated
I know you're upset I know you want to
tear her head off but pretend in a
particular fashion that is appeasing to
us and will not hurt your sibling right
has nothing to do with the character of
the individual has nothing to do with
transforming someone from the inside or
educating someone in such a way that
they become a stronger version of
themselves that's what I do with my
children I that's what I do
with myself and through these videos and
that's what it's all about the journey
of becoming the strongest version
yourself being nice is actually a it's
violent in many ways because it's
violence against yourself there's
something coming up inside you that may
not be resourceful for the particular
situation and being nice means stuffing
it back down how many times you have to
be nice around your co-workers or the
people that you really that frustrates
you at school or would've case maybe a
word that describes who you are who your
being is kind you know words are
interesting because there are a lot of
associations although we throw words
around there are a lot of sociation x'
with different words and when you say be
kind it's not so much an act you know
it's more about being a different way
kindness comes
within niceness is what I'm doing out
here do you understand a distinction be
kind means transform from the inside
that means take a breath that means take
a look at observe and honor but also
consider how what you're being who
you're being on the inside is not
resourceful for this situation there's a
level of education there's a level of
compassion there's a level of maturity
associated with kindness because
kindness forces you to look in and like
I always say you your actions are
measured by the sentiment from which I
see it you proceed where are you coming
from so all the things that you do in
kindness are an expression of who you
are niceness not so much don't be nice
Eliot's it