hey what's up guys so yesterday I was
watching some of my favorite youtubers I
watched the video by Greg o Gallagher
he's got a pretty cool channel about
muscle building fat loss and shit like
that but anyway i watch mainly just to
see what other dudes are doing cuz i
learned by watching you know if there's
other successful people or people on the
come-up doing big things i like to see
what they're doing so I watched Greg's
video and he was walking through the
neighborhood and they were mansions and
shit behind it was fucking beautiful I
think he lives in Canada somewhere so
definitely was a wealthy neighborhood
who's walking through so I decided you
know what I'm gonna do today walk
through the fucking trailer hey what's
going on these are my neighbors right
so yeah I think I walked through my
neighborhood to at the fuck this is this
is right outside my office when I look
outside my office there's always a ton
of fucking traffic people on their bikes
homeless people walking like the one
behind me it's going on big man so uh so
i'm following super greg except there
won't be mansions but there will be
trailers that you'll see on our
beautiful walk in st. Petersburg Florida
anyway uh funny thing I just walked
outside my office and a dude who
actually works right next door
rolled down his car window and hollered
at me hey Elliot and he and I started
talking for the past we spoke for about
5-10 minutes he told me about how he
used to live in Hawaii and he owned a
macrobiotic restaurant his wife was
really big into vibrational medicine and
uh and he watched my videos and of
course he said that helped him out with
fitness and whatnot but it was you know
the spiritual aspects the life mastery
aspects of my videos that he really
enjoyed especially since he and his wife
were really into holistic health and if
you watch my videos really that's what
it's about
regardless of what I'm talking about if
I'm talking about fitness I'm talking
about lifestyle I'm telling myself
mastery of them talking about success
money relationships I'm talking about
holistic health so he realized that uh
I was offering a message about holistic
health if you enjoyed my videos so it
was good to meet him I don't get to walk
out my neighborhood I don't get to walk
around here too often so maybe I'll meet
maybe I'll bump into some new people
some other people I got friends back
there to walk with their bags of clothes
anyway so uh yeah you can see here
really see to that right now
those are the trailers in my
neighborhood they probably won't be too
happy about my camera with a fence to
show their homes but uh but as we move
now you'll recognize that we're living
in a beautiful neighborhood all kinds of
fascinating people maybe we'll have some
good conversations with the drug addicts
that frequent these blocks these streets
the prostitutes are cool to recognize I
recognize them because they always turn
their heads when a man is in a car they
walking in well I guess with a switch in
their help and then they go there and
they turn and look at you these guys in
the cars probably think I'm a hooker too
anyway I had an intention for this video
I had something I wanted to share with
you guys in this video but I guess I'll
continue I guess I'll do that so my
letter today those of you who read my
daily letter my daily post which is
always in the link down below Elliott
Hulse comm sign up read up absorb learn
be entertained by my daily posts and
sometimes there are sometimes they
strike a nerve sometimes the things I
talk about sometimes the things that
write about touch the butt hurt and some
people but I do that on purpose anyway I
find joy in tickling your funny bone a
little bit can getting people upset
because I think what happens is when we
become emotionally invested or we become
emotionally disturbed by something
another person something they say an
image a picture whatever the case may be
a song it's not because of the person
really it's not the individual or the
PERT or the the song or the picture or
the words or the idea the philosophy the
religion these aren't the things that
really affect us these are the things
that are really stimulating us in a
negative way or making ups making us
upset really what's happening is your
own vibration isn't in accordance
with that person place circumstance idea
or whatever so when we become
uncomfortable with other people other
ideas other words other circumstances
it's because there's something inside us
that needs to be recognized something
inside us that we need to check when you
get upset with somebody check yourself
first
ask yourself what is it about that
individual that is showing me something
about myself that I don't like
it's always about you take full
responsibility and never point fingers
you got to hear me with all the goddamn
noise out on this sheet Greg o Gallagher
your Street was nice the fucking quiet
man out here in the trailer hood making
a lot of fucking noise I wonder if these
people appreciate me calling their
fucking neighborhood the trailer with
I'll tell you what I'll fit right in
though so I allowed myself to do that
my first move down to Florida I was
ready to living my fucking hand outta
fuck my van right right up in one of
these sidewalks any one of these Lots
now I live there I'll tell you what I
would have probably made friends with
the trailer hood people because they
don't make me uncomfortable people ideas
circumstances don't make me
uncomfortable
because when I see them or I hear them
or I encounter these vibrations all I
have to do is ask myself how do I get
into accordance with it how do i vibrate
with like resonance so that we can have
a beautiful communication so that we can
understand and appreciate each other
that's how love happens that's how
people that's how people get along
that's how you eliminate resistance in
your life that's how you eliminate pain
and turmoil and fight and hate racism
jealousy all that bullshit that most of
us deal with
because we don't allow ourselves to find
the resonance within us to allow
ourselves to be in deep loving communion
with one another
it's a fucking choice
kind of reminded me kind of remind me
my post today on my facebook wall my
email earlier today and then Mike the
picture of me and Kanye West that I put
up on my Facebook wall yesterday and and
some of the people who became heated and
upset and how they say butthurt about my
post reminded me of a version of myself
that was a lot like those uninitiated
who commented the way they did and
reminded me about when I was maybe about
15 16 years old and a to pop rap artist
Tupac was real big back then but I hated
him I could not stand to fuck it's not
that his music wasn't good it was his
attitude I didn't like how cocky he
seemed I did like how self-confidence
and braggadocious and what are some of
the words to describe someone with
arrogance but really the self-esteem
just seemed like it was way out of
proportion with what I thought he was
and I got real tough I couldn't listen
to his music when people my friends
would have like a Tupac t-shirt on I
would look away I'll say man fuck to pot
later on many years later I began to
realize how my attitude towards to pop
but then again my attitude towards
anything that shook me and a negative
vibration because of me and no parts of
me that I was denying and their parts of
me that I would refuse to acknowledge
report to me that our heute refused to
allow to blossom that made me
uncomfortable with the others that were
successful
and that's another one for a lot of
people success why don't you ask
yourself you know when you're around
successful people how do you feel do you
feel angry jealous do you feel like you
know one of the things that the
uninitiated experienced when they're
around successful people is a sense that
you know that individual must be bad or
evil or a sellout or traitor or hater or
something about them that uh that's bad
or wrong really the fact is the issues
is you the issue is your own ability to
reconcile with your own inner King your
own sense of self-worth your own self
esteem the Tupac within you right that
party that you're denying to park was
also really aggressive in his language
sometimes I mean to say some shit like I
fucked your wife you don't a for side
anybody with a tattoo of two guns on
their stomach is an aggressive
motherfucker when
you're confronted with that that type of
aggression from another man how does it
make you feel do you feel angry towards
him you feel like he's disrespectful
because of his attitude either way how
whatever way you rationalize it you're
allowing yourself to fall out a
vibration with that person and in many
in many instances make times is because
you're denying that part of you you
denying that aggression in you well part
of you what part of your body what part
of your consciousness we party of
psychology are you rejecting your own
your own aggression your own self-esteem
your own sense of self-worth your own
kingship your own warriorship the wizard
within I used to deny the wizard within
me when I would see people who are very
intelligent and very linear in their
thinking and I would say to myself
unconsciously that well I'm not as smart
as those people so I'd have a negative
vibration about them I have hate towards
them this was an uninitiated this was an
immature version of me not saying I've
got it all figured out right now but
I've discovered a few things I've got
some questions for you what is it about
me that might be making you
uncomfortable right now and what it is
about you that you're denying what part
of you are denying what part of you are
you uncomfortable about yourself that
makes it so when you see me you get the
willingness or anybody else it doesn't
have to be me you could be to fun it
could be a successful person in your
neighborhood it could be anybody or
anything could be the most loving person
that everybody loves and just because
everybody loves them you hate them
what's that all about just check
yourself that's all I'm saying I'm not
making any judgments I'm trying to shed
light on something that the way you feel
about other people's circumstances has
everything to do with the way you feel
about yourself
done