so a friend Christopher is in massive
amounts of debt he hates his job he's
got a girlfriend that's kind of giving
him problems and he's trying to reach
his goal as a weightlifter his question
is how do I strengthen myself to such a
degree that I could successfully
navigate all of the things that are
happening in my life and I don't think
his problem is unique I think many of us
have taken on many different roles and
have many different responsibilities all
of which we would like to maximize be
the best boyfriend possible be the best
employee or business men possible be
able to have financial freedom and get
out of debt and have a super strong
badass good-looking body right I mean
that is heaven in a bag so his question
is like you know how do I don't toughen
up so I can make all these things happen
I'm reading a really fascinating book
right now called the one thing I can't
remember the name of the author right
now but you can look it up on Amazon and
this author asserts and and I found this
to be true in my own experience and
that's why I find the book so
fascinating he asserts that if you put
all of your eggs in one basket like
Andrew Carnegie once said and just watch
that basket grow you will reach your
greatest success and that basically
means you choose one thing and you
dominate that one thing and it will if
you choose the right thing and we'll
talk about that a moment if you choose
the right one or what I've also heard
described as or called the keystone
habit you choose the habit that's
associated with dominating one thing it
will inevitably trickle over into all
other areas of your life you will see
success in other areas if you just
dominate this one thing it's also been
described as the Pareto principle or the
80/20 rule that whereby all of yours
they say 80% of your results will come
from 20% of your efforts the trick is to
try to figure out what is that 20%
require you know which one of these
things do I have
hack at you know put all my time effort
energy talent and faculty into
dominating so that it will have a
tremendous effect on everything else so
for me just for example I've realized
after several years of building multi a
multi-faceted business that the Keystone
have it for me is making videos every
single day so you'll notice that I'm
uploading videos two three times a day
sometimes as I realize that when I
dominate video it impacts the way my gym
runs the way my publishing business runs
the way everything else runs in my
business is determined by this one
Keystone habit of multiple videos a day
right answering your questions so for
you in your life which includes business
includes finance includes relationships
and includes personal development
through weight lifting you're going to
want to figure out which one of these
things are going to support me we should
the one which one of these can I put all
of my eggs in and will support me not
just because of the results associated
with dominating that thing but because
of the type of person I have to become
disciplined committed hard-working
focused in order to to achieve that and
how that version of you will spill over
into other areas of life so if you
understand what I'm saying is what type
of person do you have to become to
dominate this area because you'll just
take that that you'll take that you that
knew you into the other areas and you'll
crush it okay so my advice my opinion
really and this is if you were my son to
my brother this is what my advice would
be is to get rid of the debt there is
something about financial debt that just
weighs on you like a heavy yoke it's
very difficult to run fast when you've
got an anchor attached to you and
financial debt is not going to afford
you the freedom to choose the type of
work that you want to participate in you
know because you've got bills to pay
you've got to pay back all this student
loan debt or credit card debt or a
mortgage where that's over your head you
cannot do anything when you've got this
anger this ball-and-chain associated
with financial debt so when you get out
of that hole you're going to not only
feel better about your finances but you
will feel the relief and the
physiological peace I mean your hormones
will change when you're no longer
running like a scared rabbit your
hormones will even change and that's
going to support you in your strength
training you'll be able to stockpile
money instead of dig yourself out of a
hole which is going to support you in
having better relationships
women don't general speaking people
don't want to get involved with people
who are who's got anchors you got
baggage you know and if you're looking
for a girlfriend or you're looking for a
relationship that's going to be fruitful
it's always better to show up standing
on top of a pile of cash then down in a
deep hole of it not necessarily 100%
true but I guarantee you'll feel a lot
better about yourself you'll be able to
buy things you'll be able to take your
lady out you'll be able to do things
that you can't do when you got all this
freaking debt and I forget what the
other one was but I would say the
keystone habit would be taking a
significant portion of whatever little
bit of money you have right now and
using it to get rid of your debt as fast
as possible create a plan for yourself I
had to do this I was like a $90,000
credit card debt and I I mean I'm out of
it now but it took significant sacrifice
for about three years take the next
couple years and sacrifice significantly
in order to get out of that freaking
hole and I guarantee you it's going to
support you in full expression of and
the development of you becoming a
stronger version of yourself in all
other areas dude good luck