nope before I get started with today's
Q&A I just want to let you know that you
should rest assure that I will continue
to be answering questions on this
channel and a lot of you guys saw my
farewell teo elliot video on my other
channel and we're a little upset and
worried that I won't be answering
questions anymore look this is what I
love to do I get a kick out of this so
I'm not going to stop be part of the
reason why I decided to end that show
that segment of the other channel is
because you know I thought about this
there are multiple different reasons but
one of them is but I've gotten tired of
separating the body from the mind if you
watch a lot of the videos on this
channel I answer your character how to
live psychological questions with go to
your body shake your body
tap your body breathe deep breathe into
your balls all associated with the body
often times we want to attack the
problem that we're having what we think
is happening here from here and I often
give you advice on how to use your body
to get through the circumstances in your
life that seem as if they're abstract
and really they're concrete and they're
found in your body on the other channel
I'd often have to answer questions on a
very superficial level and I would often
censor myself not all the time right
censor myself from answering these body
type questions with what's going on in
with the character which one with the
nervous system what's going on the mind
and I've decided I'm no longer doing
that you know that's a psyche sacrifice
of my integrity where I want to go what
I'm learning can't do it anymore so q
and A's will be done on this channel and
it will be in a very similar fashion to
what I've been doing all this time so if
you have body questions come here do you
have mind questions come here because
they're one fucking thing right I often
say that now interestingly we got a
question about a confidence amongst
peers and we got a friend who was able
to resolve that using many of the
techniques that I've shared with regard
to focusing on your body when you are in
social situations that you tend to be
uncomfortable with right so our friend
here he had a difficult time making
friends he had a difficult time talking
to girls when he was in groups he would
often client clenched down and clam up
and using the advice that I've offered
in multiple videos of breathe deeply
soften the musculature in your face in
your chest in your stomach and pelvic
floor speak slowly be in the moment with
people as opposed to thinking about what
you want to say
do you see listening these are all
things that you do with your body you
don't think about these things you don't
there's they're not abstractions there
are activities that you need to do
through your body and they supported him
except now the the energetic level of
the other individual is impeding on his
ability to do this what I mean by that
is when he come when he gets around
prestigious people and particularly his
professors this is really the way he
describes it he says when I'm around my
professors in at university and it's
time to speak with one of them
one-on-one so and so forth I get I get
the same anxious situation same anxious
feeling that I received prior to
learning the techniques that I use now
to work with friends and of course I
could just say you know hey dude same
fucking techniques but the dynamics are
different and the reason why I know
they're different is because I've
experienced both ends of the spectrum
and I it's very fresh in my mind so I
decided to answer this for you today
this weekend I had a big event
those who know I had the strength cape
challenged people hundreds of people
dare I say over a thousand at some point
when people were coming and going showed
up an event many of which came most of
which came to meet me of course they
were athletes that were there to compete
but at one point there was a line you
know 30 feet long people who were there
just to meet me and I had to come to
grips with this also could slow awkward
talk to people on cameras but to have
actually been able to meet face to face
people who've been watching my videos
and they're coming from all over the
world was who are brand new it was a
brand new experience for me
one thing I noticed is that being in
that prestigious position like your
professor is when you come to meet him
and then all the
for young people who came to meet me I
say young like I'm fucking old I'm just
I'm old at heart come to me me I
recognize that boy this guy is nervous
see so I'm your professor this is you
except it's Elliott Hulse and it's a
young man who wants me to sign his thing
or you know just say hello and say thank
you
I recognize right away the body language
I recognize the energetic exchange here
boy this this young man is really
nervous to meet me I have to take notice
and and this is where the maturity level
of the professor or the or the person of
prestige if you will you know that's
what your words so I'm just gonna keep
using it procedure how they relate to
you how they perceive the interaction
between you and there are two different
ways that they're going to approach this
because I can see how how they both
could be played out I'll show I'll share
how I dealt with the nervousness of the
person who came to me and the reason why
I come from this place is because like I
said it's fresh in my mind
but also remember that communication is
between two and it's not just about you
very important point that I like to make
throughout this entire video it's not
about you either you being on the
nervous end or you be on the prestigious
end never about you and if we all
interacted in such a way that we forgot
ourselves forgot our agenda forgot our
our ego if you will and focused on what
is happening on the other person and
approaching them from where they are the
world would be a beautiful beautiful
place
oh I mean that would be the end to Wars
right because how could I do to another
man or to another person to another
another civilization what I wouldn't
want having to happen to me
of course it's far more complex than
that but it's a great place to start
right Michael Jackson right I'm starting
with the man in the mirror start with
the man in the mirror always focus on
how your being for that person what kind
of space you're creating for that person
okay that's my point
anyway as I on this end recognize the
nervous
and the anxiety and the young man who
wants to come and shake my hand and say
thank you
I open my body to him and this is it and
those of you who showed up this weekend
can attest to this
what did hell you do for the most part
when you met him hey give me a hug give
me a hug
open my heart open my body open myself
up show my authenticity and my
vulnerability to you this is the
position of love of passion of opening
right it's also the position of Christ
on the put on the cross interesting huh
Jesus dies with his heart open right he
wasn't either the prophet of passion of
love love thy neighbor sacrificed myself
for you right even a dog right if a
dog's gonna give himself up to you what
does he do his arms don't do this but he
turns over boom show my belly open up it
means I'm available to you recognize the
posture of the individual that you're
speaking to so that you know even if
you're on the nervous center that under
the spectrum how you can relate to them
do you need can you relax and see that
this person is only here to help me or
which is dare I say more likely the
circumstances especially when you're
dealing with professors right you're
dealing you're dealing with very heavy
people I'm a body person and if you
figure that out for me it's all about
paying attention to my body paying
attention to my breathing paying
attention to my body language and doing
so in a way that I can relate to a
person with with where they are bodily
now if you get one of these all right no
listening to you you come to them and
you get this now you realize okay this
person again focus on the person not on
yourself
this person is closed to me is closed
off and no matter what you do as the
approacher mote more than likely let's
say your quick story anyway
more than likely whatever you do this
person is going to be close to you this
person's going to be close to you you
can you can offer him absolutely
everything you could be the best
presenter you could show up and there's
no reason for you to be nervous because
you're just like boom boom
I'm Liddy I'm quick-witted I'm smart I'm
intelligent and goddammit I'm awesome
and he's still gonna be like because
it's not about you it's about his close
body it's about his closed off this to
your energy right yeah look at the other
person read their body language know
where they are and where you stand in
the relationship right and if they're a
person of a higher vibratory level for
whatever reason when I say higher
vibratory level it just means that in
that interaction there is a if you will
in an alpha and a beta or there is a you
know patriarchy you know there's one
that's in charge and ones that that's
not and in institutions where they're
like people have been given names like
you are the president you're a student
you're fucking peon well then people
accept those roles right but they're
just ideas they're just roles given
based on institutional ideals and so on
and so forth that person doesn't
necessarily have to be a better person
than you right if he's doing this all
right and he's closed off and he's like
it has nothing to offer to you that
means energetically he's probably a you
know a bit weaker than you so of course
this is sort of a ranting video just
giving you ideas and perspectives to
consider as you relate to other people
especially those who record you
recognize that either above you or below
you I use these terms lightly but you
understand what I mean
young man was uh was speaking with me at
the after party mind you the after party
this weekend I was a little tipsy and
we're having this conversation and of
course he's you know he's wanting to
gain some perspective for himself in his
life but as we're speaking then of
course I'm reading him and I'm being
myself as we're speaking I see him he's
like this the whole time
and he and the kid is very heady it's
very intelligent he knows what's going
on he's paying attention he's
witty is smart here but his body was
very cold closed off and as I'm trying
to get my point across to him and trying
to tell him what my agenda actually is
which is I really truly believe that if
there's a strongest version of each one
of us and it's my objective to help you
bring that out you know and I'm talking
like I'm talking from a loving
perspective he's closed now for whatever
reason is closed you know we all have
our own post-traumatic stress disorder
so it's we've all got our own issues
that we're dealing with and being that
you know I wanted to open him up oh and
I'm a little aggressive there's the way
I am took my hands and pushed his arms
down and said listen this is what I want
I put my hand on his heart I was like I
don't want to prove anything to you I
don't want to take anything from you I
don't want to convert you I want my
particular answer I want this I want you
to experience this at its fullest on my
hand on his heart I want you to feel and
move and act and succeed through the
passion in your heart for whatever it is
that you want to be
he had a Star of David around his neck
and I pointed to that Star of David I
said are you a Jew they said yes but I
think he may have converted or something
like that to it he had he had whole
reason why I started to explain himself
I said no not interested I don't want
another story what I'm only interested
in is you becoming the absolute best Jew
that you can be and that means wherever
you are whoever you are whatever your
position is in life or where you want to
go I just want to support you in that I
really am NOT interested in this story
really not interested in the journey I'm
interested in you what makes your heart
beat and it's close like this doesn't
beat very much at all you don't breathe
very much at all when it's open it
doesn't matter what you do because if
you come from a place of love everything
you do will be
Jew Muslim Christian communist
capitalist does not matter to me if
you're coming from a place of love if
you're coming from a place where your
heart and your passion is open to the
world you are vulnerable and you're
willing to be sacrificed
and when I say sacrificed I mean give
yourself throw yourself into whatever it
is that you're doing throw yourself at
the mercy of those who serve you will do
well you will do good things for the
world of course this conversation went
off in many different directions but the
point here is this even if you're either
the prestigious individual or you're the
the lowly student recognize the body
language first in yourself recognize
your body are you breathing because this
is what you know you you gained this I
taught you this before
are you breathing on your life can you
feel your feet right that's a good one
it's really important one can you feel
your feet or your shoulders relaxed
are you breathing cool now all right you
do all the things that I talked about
your muscular system you relax are you
in the moment from that place you're
grounded and you have a perspective
you're from you're coming from a place
where you can gain stronger perspective
on the other person and where they're at
now read that person boy all his energy
looks very high or he looks very low
whatever the case may be he looks very
close he looks very open and then know
what's going on be aware of the
circumstances and relate to the person
in a way that allows the communication
to run smoothly and if you're audacious
enough and they're closed work to open
them up done