so our buddy al has what he calls a
speaking impediment so essentially he
chokes up and he stutters whenever he
speaks with people and this is something
that he's been dealing with all his life
he's been to several doctors it's that
serious he's been to several doctors and
his the only thing that they can offer
him is that the brains part of his brain
is associated with verbal communication
has been damaged seriously damaged and
there's nothing he can do so that's it
he's got to deal the rest of his life
with this inability to speak clearly
with it with people he's got all his
shit together apparently he works out
sounds like he's a really stand-up guy
you know the thing is that relationships
are difficult for him he doesn't have
very many friends he probably doesn't
mention it but would have difficulty
speaking with and developing a
relationship with a woman so he's
feeling lonely and he's feeling confused
a bit frustrated he comes to us not for
a answer or a solution because obviously
going to doctors hasn't solved these
problems I mean there's only so much
that we could do through YouTube videos
but a perspective and I'd like to offer
you one what I would invite you to do is
to develop to the highest degree
possible your ability to kumin it
communicate through writing in
particular writing I would say a form of
art you know because it allows you to
express yourself which is cathartic for
you and in general you know we all want
to express that which is within us and
we all find different ways to express it
you have are impeded in your ability to
verbally communicate but i'm sure
there's so much that you want to share
with people i would invite you to begin
writing and creating a platform for
yourself in order to share your deepest
thoughts or journal with those who may
be interested in the type of things that
you're interested in well as well start
a blog you know practice your writing
start a blog start a newsletter find
different ways where you could use
literature or poetry
or journaling like I described where you
just relay your subjective experience to
people through your through your website
or something of that nature and then
become a part of a community I know
there are so many different blogging
communities that if you were to take
your art and you were to subject it to
the scrutiny but also also the support
of that community outside of that which
would require you to speak you would
find those you'd find other individuals
who also either benefit from due to an
inability or just truly love expressing
themselves through written communication
and that would just be one way for you
to go about developing relationships
with other people without you having to
speak to them you know when you get an
opportunity to share yourself with
someone regardless of how you share that
part of you with them and they can see
into your heart they can see your your
the purity of your intent they will come
to love appreciate respect you
regardless of what so-called handicap
you may display later on you know we see
this over and over again in many
different movies whether you know people
who are pen pals or the case may be and
they've never met each other but they've
fallen so deeply in love through this
written communication and then when they
finally meet they're like complete
opposites but it doesn't matter because
they've shared so much of their hearts
desires with with each other that they
the relationship is solidified through a
deeper means than that of the
superficial form so that's it dude give
it a try if it's not writing try a
different form of art some way for you
to express yourself but also more
importantly to put it in a place where
other people can come to know like and
appreciate you through it good luck