got this great question one that I've
often thought about quite often myself
from our buddy Zubair I think that's how
you pronounce it anyway he says I've
noticed it's really difficult to
concentrate both on the philosophy of
oneness integration community and at the
same time maintain healthy boundaries in
other words become individuated in a way
that you become a stronger version of
yourself just sounds almost selfish how
do you reconcile this oneness of
humanity and that we're all meant to
help and serve one another and becoming
a stronger version of yourself you feels
you know his imbalance he feels as if he
always tends to overshare and he's
really sensitive to other people
and he knows that if he just accepts his
own individuality it might make life
simpler in other words cut himself off
and grow himself become strongest
version of himself but it doesn't make
sense and he wants to now reconcile this
interesting you know my mission in the
way I share it and I often talk about
becoming the strongest version yourself
because it is the first step but there's
a second part to it and you and those
you who follow me long enough for know
that it's to inspire others to breathe
life to work the word inspire it means
literally to breathe in to inspire spiro
spirits to give life to spirit spiros
breath to breathe life into and that's
why I chose that word in particular so
you grow stronger yourself and inspire
others it's a two-fold approach it's as
Jesus says allowing your cup to fill to
runneth over a cup could only runneth
over if you understand the metaphor if
the cup is full and if you want to give
you the running over of the cup in order
for the running over of the cup to
happen so that you're giving so that
you're spreading your sweet waters of
service you've got to be full enough
right fill yourself so that your cup is
running over but then we've got people
who like when I capped the cup or
they're you know they're very selfish
with the fruits of their labor or the
fruits of their virtue you know they
don't they don't want to share so you've
got you've got this sort of diseconomy
between you know
okay of course we're one and I'm of that
idea also I believe in oneness oneness
and humanity we're all of one collective
unconscious we're all of one spirit
we're all apples of the same tree we're
all waves of the same ocean right and
for a while there if you if you follow
my facebook wall especially during a you
know election time I'm a staunch
libertarian moreso in the past and I am
today you know I'm sort of evolving in
my ideas but libertarianism is about you
know look you take care of you and I'll
take care of me a lot of people don't
know but there's also a second part to
that which is allowing your cup to
runneth over and serve people Alan Watts
talks about this and one of his talks
about the philosophies of the east and
it's this idea that everyone is the same
but we're all so unique and that the
more we can grow in our uniqueness the
greater we serve the whole and they've
got an interesting balance of this you
know a lot of the philosophies of the
East East are about balance you know if
you if you look at the yin-yang bill the
entire thing it's just about balance you
know if you study like the Ichi the
whole thing is about how does this all
balance out how does the way the Dao
just balance out and then aligning
ourselves with that natural way the
earth always nature God universe always
balances itself out we when our stories
tend to create imbalance how can we
align ourselves with the natural balance
of the world
night and day sunshine and darkness
winter and spring
it's an interesting thing one of my you
know that I read a lot of Osho and he
often talks about the difference between
revolution and rebellion and revolution
is one of these things whereby Humanity
adopts a particular ideal and then we
seek to overthrow the current ideal ie
governments philosophies religious
ideals with a brand new one thinking
that the brand-new one is the one that's
going to save humanity so we've got this
idea of communism you know and uh I'm
exploring it somewhat socialism
communism I mean interesting to someone
who's a smart libertarian right I'm
registered as a libertarian it's
studying communism and socialism and how
beautiful an idea most of that is it's a
beautiful concept in the abstract it's a
beautiful concept but why has it not
worked many many different reasons why
of course you know their rulers you know
the ruling class so on and so forth you
know they're always those in power with
a concentrated form of power if you
think that you know living in the United
States somehow we're free from this in
capitalism and freedom you're fully
you're full of shit because we're we're
manipulated by the route by a ruling
class also you know everyone where your
money comes from who prints our money
why they can just keep making fun of it
more of it you know this 1% isn't just
the wealthy entrepreneur 1% are the
other or the central bank's the bankers
the people who manipulate the 99% with
what they can produce out of thin air
we've just given them permission to do
this you know so let me come back to
like practical ideas about yourself and
and this idea of oneness you grow
stronger not so that you can hoard the
gems and the goods and the fruits of
growing stronger you grow stronger so
that you can use so that your cup can
spill over and that you have the
capacity to serve more people
I know that the better I do the better
I'll be able to serve and in a selfish
way I increased my capacity to
ultimately serve I increase my personal
value am i increasing my personal value
I am growing stronger but value is
contingent upon your ability to position
yourself in the marketplace I want to
say marketplace I mean those whom you're
serving value values in the eye of the
customer in the eye of the beholder so
you're constantly increasing your
personal value so that your ability to
serve other people is increased and it's
in fact one of the most unselfish things
that a human being can do so going back
to Osho and his idea of revolution
versus Rupa rebellion the revolution is
where we use our weapons to overthrow
the outer world so that there will be a
there will be balance never works
never will work rebellion is checking
out in adopting a philosophy of personal
cultivation with the sole purpose of
personal cultivation which includes
generosity a part of personal
cultivation is recognizing that the way
the world works it's not it this is not
an altruistic idea that Elliott is
propelling because it sounds good but
the way the world works the way energy
works the way the universe works the way
science works right there's scientific
proof for this shit not just in our
activities but the act but the behavior
of our cells and atoms is balanced as we
receive we give and as we give we
receive it's it's it's all around us and
to rebel means to check out of the
imbalanced power struggle of the world
and get in touch with the way the dow
god true oneness
which is this giving and receiving don't
get caught up on one end and not the
other because if you don't know how to
receive you will have not much to give
your cup can't runneth over if you don't
fill it up feel don't feel guilty for
increasing your ability to receive
people will make you feel guilty for
increasing your ability to receive they
don't like that because they've got
their own hang-ups about that and when I
say receive I literally mean energetic
but also material means know how to
acquire the material that you need to
ultimately give the man who has more can
give more you know you can speak poorly
of the many of the ruling class but
often times you know and perhaps are
still imbalanced you find that you know
if Carnegie who in order to build his
steel trust Empire literally killed his
workers there me brought in machine-gun
militias to shoot at his factory workers
I mean it was fucking crazy but also
today I mean there are more museums and
arts expression you know libraries and
so forth
named after Carnegie because he gave his
money at some point I mean to serve I
was saying this you go kill people so
that you can gather enough so that to
give back to them but that's an
extremely extreme example the more you
have the more you'll be able to give and
the greater you'll be able to give so
you don't feel guilty about receiving or
asking for you see I feel guilty about
being selfish in that way
cultivating your own strength so that
you're stronger for other people that's
it man done