so we got a really fun question for you
today comes from our anonymous buddy who
lives in England it's 18 years old and
he asks should I bother with this girl
so here's the situation the young lady
that he's smitten with is also 18 years
old the thing is that this girl seemed
to be very attracted to black guys
according to our friend mostly African
now our buddy goes on to let us become
aware of the fact that he is of
Caribbean descent he's a quarter Antigua
but the thing is he's feeling as if all
of the men that this woman has been with
these big African men have had giant
cocks that he won't be able to live up
to he feels as if he is pretty average
down there but the thing is although
there are a lot of things that this
woman has that makes her makes him feel
as if she is a good partner he's feeling
her a little small about himself if you
know what I mean right so he's got to
measure up to you doesn't feel like he's
gonna measure up to all the giant black
penises that have been in our friend and
he wants to know what to do you know
apparently the girl's a really nice girl
he likes her they have a lot of values
in common but they've got this big black
penis problem what do they do so here's
what I'm going to offer you you've got
to consider that the most important part
what happens during a sexual
relationships sexual intercourse with a
person especially deep meaningful
powerful integrative sexual contact with
another human being is that there is not
just penis in vagina but there is a
energetic connection that happens with
that person there's heart there's an
emotion there's so much more going on
during the sexual act and building up to
the sexual act and this is very
important with regard to women in orgasm
that what actually happens with the
penis oftentimes isn't that important
and the size of your penis I'm not a
penis expert here but the size of your
penis is not going to be the limiting
factor or the determining factor as to
whether or not a woman is going to
orgasm now you do have to have a fuckin
dick and you need to have a stiff one
but the point is that the orgastic
release that a woman has the orgastic
release that we all experience is a
buildup of stimulation that happens over
time so a woman that's going to orgasm
is just going to fucking orgasm
regardless she's ready to owners ready
has been ready for quite some time right
so what's happening as you are courting
her as you're speaking with her as
you're getting her to giggle and open up
I've made videos about this before I
called it give women mini orgasms right
which is really getting the giggle
soften up open up build warm feelings in
the chest and in the genital area dude
it really doesn't matter how giant your
dick is if you've got her to the brink
of orgasm before you insert yourself
because when you make that physical
connection to commenced forth and bring
to bring to a head bring to a boil
being bring to eruption all the energy
that's building up in her because you're
tickling her all over the place you'll
be you'll be fine you'll be just then
you'll be in a great place the thing is
you've got to get out of your own way
now because you're thinking that because
first of all you're totally being
prejudiced just because these are
African man that she was with don't mean
they all had giant penises well let's
see you've seen the penises right but
don't think that it's because of those
giant penises that she had pleasurable
sexual relationships with these men she
may have been ok it may have not been
good at all he may have no idea how to
stimulate and get a woman to orgasm you
on the other hand that is something you
can learn
now you can't grow a bigger dick unless
you know use one of these a special
medication that I think I seen on TV but
that's neither you know there I probably
wouldn't try any pills to make my dick
any bigger about what I would seek to
learn more about is how to stimulate the
sexual energy in a woman to get her to
the point where orgasm is inevitable
especially if she's open to orgasm
it's difficult many people are very
rigid particularly women it's very
difficult for them to have orgasm
because of other characterological
issues right neurosis but if you got a
woman who's capable of orgasm and you
know how to stimulate her right dude you
are going to be just fine so stop
worrying about the big black dick
nightmares that your your having and you
think about how you can stimulate this
chick so that she's orgasm in the minute
you insert yourself peace