um what is your definition of truth in
the world what isn't what is what is
your definition the truth is true would
you feel about you
when you feel like truth in the world we
feel that group of the resonate with it
needs to be what needs to be considered
before we can stab anything as proof as
truth is first the subjectivity of the
individual who is looking at what is
being determined as true if you look
into the quantum physics out there and
I'm not by any means an expert but
they're realizing that the observer
changes what is being observed is
anybody familiar with this idea that
right what they do is it's very strange
as we get smaller and smaller group and
bits and particles and electronic shit
that they want to study they realize
that they're here studying of that
particle makes it disappear or it
affects the way that particle behaves so
to say that something is true absence of
that which is observing it is not so you
see and that's why a lot of time by
invitation is to go in here because if
we constantly look out here knowing
through religious and now scientific
assertions that what I'm looking at is
changing based on my looking at then
stopping me out look in what's over here
because clearly what's over here is
affecting what's out there right so if
I'm looking for truth I'm looking for
and I inviting you inviting people to
become more
objective be more self be in tune with
the subjective experiences that you have
and study yourself from afar study
yourself as a moose studying with
someone else called is all true because
if I find that this path works for me
and I walk this path and this has been
my experience and then I tell someone
else hey what were you see those
footsteps get in line because that's the
right path not realizing that that
person is affecting each one of those
what steps that I just traveled and I'm
telling him to travel expect him and
giving him hope to expect to get the
same result that I just got then I'm
being a fool so my answer is the truth
really is here what are you looking for
who are you really that's for the truth
who are you I can I can rant on further
whatever I agree who are you you know
regardless if you're a scientist or
increased you will there's assertions to
the fact that God is found two sets the
kingdom is found with it right and then
what I just described collecting what
the villains pretty fucking this stuff
off it's us