so the top comments on my last video be
dangerous is from one of our friends he
calls himself junk mail 35 thumbs up
that is you know I assume that means
that there are many of you with the same
sort of question you know for it to be
that popular you going to say is what he
goes on and say is Elliott Hulse I don't
know what to do my family is
dysfunctional aren't they all
we don't communicate emotionally and we
only speak in shallowness I seem to be
depressed I can't express myself the way
I want to in the world everything seems
wrong to me my mom doesn't have that
motherly function of comfort and
softness my dad is quiet but judges
harshly
my older sister acts like an emotionless
woman women should be full of emotion
shouldn't they my brother also is very
depressed I can't fix this dude if
you've been watching my videos for some
time you probably have heard me speak on
the ills that create this schizoid
condition where we've totally detached
from our bodies and live our lives as
walking heads like you said that we you
only speak in shallowness that word is
interesting that means you really don't
go very deep there's no warmth in your
communication with your family so I'm
not going to go into that right now
because what I'm really fixated on is an
old concept comes from the Bible an Old
Testament concept that the sins of the
parents will be passed on to the
children the children will bear the sins
of the parents and it's so true because
the way you're conditioned is a product
of the way your parents were conditioned
and they just passed that shit on
generation after generation after
generation your mom and dad are cold and
harsh unloving because their parents
were cold and harshing and loving you
speak about your mom not really having
that woman without warm womanly motherly
comfort her mom probably didn't give her
much of that so she has nothing to give
you the sins of the parents are bared by
the children and it will keep going on
you say your sister is emotionless and
cold she will do the same thing to her
children it's not going to stop it's
cyclical okay it's just I mean it's just
an observation it's not it's not a
condom
it's not a curse you know God felt it
was so angry that he said that the
children will bear the sins of the
parents no it's a fucking it's it's an
observation I will take full
responsibility for the fact that my
children have a lot of my neuroses mate
I'm fucked up we're all fucked up and my
special kind of fuck no fuck that fucked
up this will show up in them and I've
got a little special kind of fucked up
this that my parents have both of them I
mean I could look at both of them I got
I got that shit from you I got that shit
from you there's also blessings that are
passed down from one to the to the other
but there's also a very interesting
thing that happens with families
especially you know there are multiple
children and yours and it seems like
everybody's functioning from the same
paradigm of coldness detachment schizoid
right what has happened to you is it in
a lack of better terms of course I'm
being poetic here but you've been
blessed for some strange reason mate
let's say perhaps a genetic mutation
right we can look at it as evolution
evolution is happening through you or
your blessed whatever how are you gonna
look at it the fact is you're not the
same as them and you're at a point in
your life where you're looking around
and you're like oh shit ah this is all
fucked up and I'm swimming in this mess
I don't know what to do you're a black
sheep if you will and the reason why I
know that is because you wouldn't
approach me with this question if you
weren't already steeped in the
sinfulness of detachment that your
parents have been conditioning you to
receive they don't do this because they
hate you they don't do this because
they're bad people they do this because
this is all they know and your and your
sister and your brother they're admitted
in certain ways they're gone they're
lost okay doesn't mean they can't be
found but they weren't they're already
lost not you you see in sense that
there's something wrong the very first
thing that I want you to do is maintain
your grounding it's going to be very
difficult because the reason why they
are the way they are is because they
built up defenses against fears in their
lives
you can begin start to become very
entangled with the circumstances and
allow yourself to be touched in such a
way that you have to fight against it
and then it and then your defense has
become neurosis also their neurotic and
we and that's what neurosis is we build
up defenses against hurtful things in
our lives
this is a hurtful thing to you I don't
want you to become too neurotic we're
all neurotic but I don't want you to be
touched too deeply by this you're still
very soft your VIP is still very supple
you're still very feeling and that's why
you're approaching me the way that you
are with the question that you have try
to maintain that you can't maintain it
that that subjectivity or that
objectivity subjectivity I use those
words so often you can't maintain
yourself you can't keep yourself here
right
you could rationalize and you could tell
yourself stories and they are helpful
very helpful I share a lot of stories
with you that help you stories to tell
yourself ways to condition your your
mind in order to not be damaged by the
circumstances but observe your body
because the defences show up in your
body notice the tension in your
shoulders in your chest you probably
have a lot of it in your chest tell me
if you have asthma you probably have a
lot of it in your chest and that is a
neurotic holding pattern it's a physical
manifestation of a psychological defense
do you understand
notice your belly notice your legs
notice your hands your neck your face
where were you holding tension and just
bring your attention bring you bring
your attention to the tension breathe
into your balls right breathe deeply and
relax the muscles especially when you're
in these circumstances when you're
swimming in the shit stop for a moment
breathe five times just stop and breathe
five times you're feeling it
why is everybody against me why is this
place such a mess stop because you're
gonna start building defences against
the hurt stop and breathe
go somewhere you need solitude go
somewhere alone you need a little bit
more alone time
don't use that alone time to dig
yourself into depression use that alone
time to defend yourself by getting back
in touch with yourself and not allowing
your body to be damaged by the
circumstances very difficult it requires
a very meditative attitude consistent
persistent attitude of I need to be
aware of my surroundings you need to be
aware of your surroundings so that you
can get out of this shithole alive
without that much damage hopefully
you're very young if you're 14 you know
you just start to figure this shit out
or maybe you know you're you could be
older and you could potentially be a bit
wiser in whatever the case is you
clearly have something that they don't
and then tell yourself this story two of
them the first one thank you God thank
you universe thank you evolution thank
you science for putting me in this
situation where I am experiencing a
particular talents that's going to force
me to grow in a way that's unique to me
so that I can share my newfound strength
with other people in the same
circumstances you're going to get out of
this alive and you're gonna look around
and you're gonna notice there are a lot
of other kids you'll probably end up
like you know 2530 you can look back at
like and your to see like 14 year old
kids don't ignore them don't you know
them because they were just like you who
are in the same circumstances we're in
the same situations it's your it's your
job now you've taken on a new job to
help those kids
it's your objective you need to you need
to go get out alive so that you can help
them your pain and suffering is not just
for your growth it's so that you have a
perspective to share it with kids who
are in the dark okay
the other story is life goes on and that
means whatever you can cultivate within
yourself is a seed which will bear fruit
for a future generation you may have
children of your own and you're going to
do it totally differently not saying
that you won't make them neurotic but
you'll give them a new special kind of
evolved type of neurosis right I make my
kids neurotic but we hug and kiss and we
cuddle we tickle and we play and we read
to our kids I know I'm screwing them up
also because I've got some weird weird
things going on also so that's it man
you know it's guys like you it's funny I
read your question and I was so grateful
for it because it's guys like you kids
like you that give me a sense of purpose
in my life because I got through a lot
of shit right I wasn't hungry
I wasn't poor I had parents that cared
for me and I think most of all of our
parents really do care for us they were
good parents but I had a few challenges
and a lot of those challenges created a
rebellious attitude in me that fuels my
desire to to share what I've learned
with you guys through these videos so of
course it's not about me but I do you
know I want to extend a form of kinship
with you you know let you know that
you're not alone and that this is this
is this is life it's a beautiful thing
with the right perspective and if you
use the tools that are available to you
it's kind of what I hope to share
through these videos good luck man