yeah yeah there you go okay awesome all
so uh great story great story so a lot
of people who you guys giggling it back
what what are they giggling about I
don't know I don't know haha cool story
bro maybe that's a so a lot of a lot of
i'm trying to get back like to being
strictly normal right now a lot of a lot
of people probably think that yeah
Elliot he's been he's been huge for the
last couple of years and he's been
putting in the world who lost two or
three years and it's an overnight
success may even how long have you been
putting on videos and when did you see
the real growth of your of your business
and your youtube career dude you've been
around long enough to know that a lot of
everything that we're doing is brand
spanking new nothing that we're doing is
uh our parents didn't do it they
couldn't taught us how to do this in
school there was no career path for an
internet marketer much less a YouTube
celebrity and so when I look at my life
I look in all because it was like
there's no way to have prepared for this
no one could have told me that when I
started filming the workouts that I was
doing for with my clients that I would
upload them to a platform that people
would see them worldwide and they would
attract the attention of millions that
like never crossed my mind and the
reason why I say that is because those
of you who are in the audience I want
you to remember that although we have
our goals we have our plans and of
course the universe has its goals and
plans as well we could never foresee all
of the celestial aid that will come our
way you know it's it I might sound like
a hippie but uh YouTube's fucking magic
unless you'll aid to me that's I could
have never planned that I could never
have asked for it I could have never
dreamt it but the universe provided by
giving me a platform where my big mouth
could be heard worldwide and while
you're sitting there building your
business or thinking about your future
remember that although you can
plan the path you can imagine the path
you could visualize the path there's
absolutely no way that you know what the
path is going to bryn until until you
start walking on it because magical shit
happens awesome awesome thank you so and
when did you see that it really took off
and what did it do for you enjoy I mean
how long have you been putting on
YouTube videos for like seven years or
something yeah so I guess the reason why
I went that direction was big with my
answer was because you know we talked
about overnight success and then we want
to become an overnight success and we
have an idea about what overnight
success is so we go hard and have an
expectation for when it's going to when
it's going to manifest itself but that's
very rarely the case and it's been 10
years for me even five years ago I
couldn't have predicted what I'm
experiencing right now so and 10 years
is a drop in the bucket also you know
when you think about our parents if they
built business or grandparents or
generations before I was watching a
documentary on the men who built america
about Andrew Carnegie and Rockefeller
and and and Ford and these guys they
spent decades just trying to get off the
ground they spent it what would be the
equivalent of tens of thousands or
hundreds of thousands or millions of
dollars today just to get their ID or
addy off the ground so ten years
although it might sound like a long time
to some of you guys sitting there
because we live in a microwave get
everything now culture and time is a
drop in the bucket and so it seems like
it it was just yesterday awesome awesome
so any questions from the audience who
are such a big Elliott Hulse fan and
wants to ask a question who over here so
we have this guy over here he's the
owner Mark Elliott Hulse fan just one
he's it's not just one yeah yes I'm
ready to get over there boy look at I on
it what's up bud I just got a question
how did you stay motivated during that
time that you didn't get as following a
jab right now like with negatively in
all how did you stay motivating the time
dude that's like asking as a gazelle
how does he stay moded motivated when a
line is chasing his ass yeah there's no
motivation is needed when you've got the
fear of not being able to put food on
the table for your family you know I
moved down to Florida it was just me and
my wife now there's six of us I have
four children so the youngest is five so
if you could think about the timeline I
was building my business at the same
time that my wife and I were popping out
babies and I had Hills to pay yeah I
bill to pay and mouths to feed so as far
as motivation is concerned I didn't need
any I didn't eat any motivation I just
need the fact that survival was the only
option for me what I what I like about
you is that you're an athlete you're a
businessman mature almost like the
primary thing is you're a family man and
I mean you've been with Colleen for like
over 20 years right 22 years yeah 22
years and a lot of people look at you
and they will be like a cease all over
the place and like outrageous and like
smart and all this stuff but if you know
you really well you're just really a
family man and family is really
important to you can you elaborate on
that a little bit if you combine that
with the business so what does your
business provide for your family or vice
versa well I often quote Dan Kennedy by
saying choose your lifestyle first and
then build your business around it and I
truly believe that as many people admire
me and love my videos the fact is i
started making them and i started my
business for one and one reason only and
that was to take care of my family that
was to make money there was no no
question about it that I love what I do
but I needed dollars I needed money I
needed food so when it comes to my
vocation when it comes to my career when
it comes to
my work when it comes to my success it
is completely surrounding it is it
branches out of it is the fruit of my
love for my family then that's first and
foremost and my my love for myself let
me put it that way too because my family
is an extension of me so I love myself
enough to know what I want what I don't
want I love my family enough to provide
for them first to take care of them in
the way that I feel they should be cared
for you know we do a lot of
non-traditional parenting and and
because we just I decided what my core
values were first I decided what I love
what my family needs and then my
business has to fit around it so alcoa
as much as I love you and we've met
several times I've been to Europe you've
come to to Florida to hang out with me
this was an incredible gift your
invitation to come and in even pay for
Colleen and I to come and speak at year
event and I would love to have done it
but I had to just and we almost jumped
on it to colleens like what we're going
to get to go to answer damn for free and
she didn't want to pass it up but I had
to because I had to sit with the core
values and it had nothing to do with the
money it had nothing to do with my love
for Yoko and had everything to do with
the fact that yesterday was thanksgiving
the whole weekend i was spent with my on
my business because i had the shrunk
can't challenge I had a big eventful
weekend and and I couldn't see leaving
my children for another three four five
days for anything that nothing could
have told me away and so there's just an
example of it so talk about your core
values with honors and how did you
decide to come up with those core values
well I once heard that the best way to
know someone's core values is to look at
their bank statement right because we
can we can pay lip service to any core
value we want and most of the time it's
just what we aspire to which is good
it's what we hope for and what we aim
for but but nine times out of 10 it's
not exactly what our core values are and
if you're sitting here listening to this
right now right now it invite you to
pull out your october bank statement and
look at where you spend the majority of
your money and if you've got abundance
if you got excess where do you and which
we are living in the type of societies
that we do we've got more than our needs
met so we got to look at where we spend
lavishly right I'm not talking about
just being able to put a morsel in your
mouth I'm talking about what kind of
morsels do you put in your mouth so for
example for me I spend extra on organic
food and supplements I soccorso hell is
a core value to me I spend extra for the
type of water that me and my family
drink I spend extra so that I can have a
gym to train myself and colleen's
actually at the gym right now I spend
extra so that my family my children can
go to gymnastics lessons I spend extra
on their health I spend extra on my
health so health and fitness is a top
priority for me it's been my experience
and I truly believe in pain and I'm
convinced that we cannot live the life
of our dreams we cannot be the strongest
versions of ourselves we cannot fulfill
our potential if we're ill if we're not
healthy if we're not vibrant vital and
buzzing with sexual energy which is is
bodily energy there's exercise it's
eating well so that's why at the top of
the list and and and I could continue by
explaining what else I spend my money on
I spent quite a bit on education so when
you look at my bank statement amazon
which is amazon.com has become the devil
with its little one click butter and
then so i can buy any book any time I
want from my iphone so you mentioned a
book right now and I go like this I hit
the book i hit the app and i buy it so
I've got hundreds of books I haven't
even read yet x value information I
value ideas I value education so I very
willingly spend on books on courses on
nars often I I built my business because
I spent money on education I built my
business it as a professional meaning i
spent a lot of time on studying exercise
science and holistic health and a lot of
money on that and i spent a lot of money
on studying marketing i spent a lot of
money on studying philosophy so those
are two core values that I think a lot
of you got a lot of those who are
watching this can relate to and can
judge whether or not you know they're
aligned with my core values you know are
they the same or or your values
different by looking at your bank
statement awesome model so any other
questions over here ninka is going to
ask you a question you can look in the
camera over there are you yeah so I knew
you i'm sorry i don't know you I'm not
that into the pit is so but I think
you're ridiculous but I do hear that you
have a lot of YouTube videos and we
mentioned yesterday we spoke about it
yesterday there's always a lot of dumb
thinking and haters and everything going
on so how do you create a thick skin or
how do you go on even when there's
people you know saying that stuff about
you or maybe they're not but no they do
they're quite a bit quite a few people
who got negative things to say about
Elliot Hilson that's okay I think Oscar
Wilde once said that art doesn't express
anything except itself meaning that it
really is subjective and when we're
entrepreneurs were also artists when
we're building businesses especially the
businesses that we build into the day
and age that we build them where artists
we're giving the world our love for
fitness for philosophy for business for
whatever wizardry or gadget you got it's
obviously going to more than likely come
from some deep love within even if it's
purely commerce base even if your
business is purely bottom line driven
and dollar driven it still comes from a
deep desire and a love within
and I'm going to label it as art you
know your take art is taking something
creating something out of nothing when
we use that perspective when I take that
perspective of my videos being art my
products being are my blog post which
today I wrote a blog post about art if
you go to Elliott Hulse com we've got to
realize that they're going to be people
that don't like it and that's okay you
go to you can go to the finest museum
that the world has to offer and they're
going to be people who just don't dig it
they're going to be people that look at
it and say oh I can't believe they call
this art this is trash and that's okay
because it's just not was just not
resonating with the right people so what
you got to do is you got to realize that
your wizardry your gadgets your business
your poetry your are your music your
gift is for some people and not for
others and if you start letting the
people who it's not for dictate your
moods and dictate how you go about your
creative process then then you're
creating for no one yet then you're
really am you're denying yourself and
you're done denying the universe its
expression through you and you're
denying the people who really would
benefit from your art because you're
you're you're you're allowing the
negativity to color your attitude and
behavior I think one of the worst things
you can do with an entrepreneur but also
the worst thing that you can do as an
artist is to adapt to the negative
comments or adapt to the people who
don't dig your art a lot of people they
at the death to people that don't dig it
and that that way their art becomes
average and it's I think it's one of the
worst things you can do so never adapt
to people or hating on you whatever just
be yourself and that's what I love about
you as well like if you look at your
video but also in real life is that you
really are who you are you don't really
just really you're there and it's so
funny I when we were in your gym when
you do the exercise you're screaming
you're yelling whatever and then there's
mailman is coming and you're still
screaming and yelling it's just really
who you are and you don't adapt to the
mailman or if it's really who you are
that's really powerful I think of all so
any other issues yep over here if you
did it so Philippe he's an amazing guy
is from life from Belgium and yesterday
we had a Dean Jackson on so and the
injection Philippe the big fan of be
direction and anomalies and any love
Elliot and but he got a got a selfie on
stage with a video cam le le I heard you
talk about that love the lovely family
love yourself love your fucking business
another one of your videos I do explain
for our desires I'd lover in yourself
the key in yourself and what is it the
warrior and the fourth excuse me
magician the magician the magician can
you please elaborate on who are you when
and how you switch from ruelala piece of
yourself to the other one and how can I
make let's say the warrior myself strong
yeah that's a really good question the
first thing I would say or i'd like to
share is what the fish standing after
King warrior magician lover idea where
it comes from those you studied
psychology you may be familiar with call
young call young was a student of
Sigmund Freud but he was it was of the
mystical mindset meaning that like his
psychology methods revolved around
symbology dream interpretation symbol
interpretation story and mythology
interpretation and and he recognized a
cross cultural reference or a recurring
theme he would call these archetypes in
mythology and religion and philosophy
and even in movies even in pop culture
we see a lot of these recur
bring themes Joseph Campbell who is also
heavily influenced by Jung called one of
these archetypes the hero's journey and
we're familiar with the hero's journey
because we watch movies like Star Wars
and the matrix and what someone with
bilbo baggins The Hobbit and things like
that so we're familiar with this
recurring motif interesting thing about
the hero's journey is that it's also a
recurring motif in our individual lives
so that's an aside young also had
another student by the name of Robert
Moore who during the men's movement
maybe like in the 80s or 70s basically
when men started taking back their love
started taking back their spirituality
and kind of started dropping the hard
shell or armor that we've been taught to
carry for so many generations he
realized that men are far more than just
what is portrayed in popular culture as
as often times as tyrants aggressive
mean careless you know a lot of shadow
examples of what a masculine mature
masculine is so more dis discovered that
we can find balance in our in the
masculine psyche we find that balance in
the human psyche by categorizing for
general themes of our of our ego our
psyche our character and these four
general themes are king or queen our
sovereign capacity our capacity for
order our capacity for generativity or
generosity our capacity for planning for
the future particularly future
generations these are very kingly and
and sovereign characteristics and
virtues right I've got my list here and
I would wish I had it in front of me but
then you also got the warrior you've got
your magician and you've got your lover
and they and they balance out to create
these equal quarters your magician is
very much tied to what you guys are
doing here today which is learning which
is your skills your craft your even uh
the magician is also related to
objectivity and spirituality higher
thinking intuition things of that nature
and we all have that just like we all
have the ordering aspect of the of the
King we all have the generous generative
creative aspect of King pneus we also
have the objectivity and like I describe
the wisdom and the intellect of the the
magician that needs to be recognized we
also have the warrior aspect of us which
is it was which is what you asked about
so I'm going to come back to it I'm
going to go to the lover because you
also mention lover the lover aspect of
us the lover aspect is often lost
through a disconnect with our sensuality
that's the very first thing that I'd
like to share because that's a that's
one that I think can heal us all is
getting in touch with our feelings right
so we were in balanced when we can't
feel sad when we can't cry when we can't
laughs ecstatically when we can't find
ourselves able to get angry when we
should get angry you know some of us are
are so disassociated that we're
ambivalent most of our lives and that's
um that's a wound in the lover category
when we heal our lover we have the
ability to to love to love ourselves
enough to experience the sensuality of
life and share sensuality with other
people meaning sexuality and love in
that way but also communion community
you know various different types of
intimacy with self and other and then
the warrior which is kind of the
opposite of the lover in many ways but
they need each other in order to balance
your warrior aspect is very much related
to boundaries and creative aggression
the type of aggression that arises in a
balanced
mature warrior is the type of aggression
that helps us want to protect children
you know that feeling that it's our
responsibility to do right for people
who can't take care of themselves the
discipline the discipline associated
with the warrior also makes us get up
every day to do the thing that we set
out to do especially if the sovereign
aspect of ourselves has a vision you get
up every day well that vision is
important you get up every day because
you said you were going to and that's
what a warrior does he does what he's
supposed to do whether he likes it or
not because he's associated with
discipline he's also associated with
boundaries a a person a man or a woman
would have a hard time even accessing
their lover if they couldn't protect
their lover with boundaries meaning that
the warrior has to say no sometimes like
so for example my love for my family and
my love for myself a lot cause my
warrior to exorcise him self by that by
asserting that I would not be attending
this conference live as much as I would
like to my warrior had to set up a
boundary and say hey man if you're going
to be the king and the magician and
really protect your lover then your
warrior needs to stand up and say no
when it's time to say no so I don't know
if that answers our question but I
wanted to give a big overview of this
aspect of relating to ourselves relating
to our egos and and realizing that when
we find ourselves not enjoying life when
we find ourselves not enjoying
relationships when we find ourselves not
moving forward in life when we find
ourselves in any way shape or form being
less than the strongest version of
ourselves there's a good chance it's an
imbalance between these four general
quarters of our psyche
okay so Philippe why did you ask a
question whatever the reason is i think
this wisdom is of such a high order the
world really much and the world will be
a much better place technic to the text
of this wisdom you are teaching young
guys and girls so you have specifically
like how can i almost like unleash my
inner warrior that was sort of a
question where times the right Linus
yeah well the warrior carries 22 thing's
for sure that you know warriors going to
have he's going to have a sword right
and he's going to have a shield of
course you know it could be it could be
a bulletproof jacket and it can be a
newsie it doesn't matter the fact is
he's got a weapon that reaches out and
he's got a protective mechanism that's
associated with him and any time we are
and i like to use that metaphor so we
can always look at whether or not we are
building something doing something being
aggressive aggressive is one of these
beautiful words that has also received a
lot of negative association with it
because it sounds like beating people up
or fighting or yelling when really
aggression is the opposite of regression
meaning it's the moving forward anytime
you want to you're trying to move
forward in something in your life you're
being a warrior those you guys who are
there right now you're absorbing like a
magician you're taking it all in so that
you can work with it but ultimately
you're going to leave this workshop and
you're gonna go and you're going to get
to work you're gonna start writing
you're going to start making videos
you're going to start creating your
product you're gonna start talking to
people that's you being a warrior by
getting out there and being devoted to
your vision so that's a sword that's an
aggressive behavior the other one is
yours shield and of course these are
just paradigms so that I like symbols I
like I like to visualize so I visualize
a sword I mean a shield and the shoe
represents protection and boundaries as
much as we love our arts as much as we
want to build our
is as much as we we want to share and
love and build we're unable to do that
if our walls aren't strong enough to
keep out keep outside influences from
getting us off track I think I once
heard that the greatest enemy to
greatness is good good is the enemy to
great well most of the time when we're
setting up boundaries it isn't against
people who are it can be but isn't
always against people who are trying to
hurt us or take away from us or steal
our time or energy oftentimes it's just
a matter of knowing what you what you
really want what's great and being
strong enough to say no and putting up a
shield so just exercising your ability
to say no goes a long way in
strengthening the the warrior aspect I
love it this one one of your videos you
say be an omen don't be a yes no and I
love it I love it great question Felipa
thank you any other questions who's
willing to work the elk a murrain over
here I mean if somebody's used to
answering question its Elliot fellow hi
my name is Sam okay and you just
mentioned about building your business
around for lifestyle and we also
mentioned that you have four kids and
can you perhaps a regular work day looks
like for you there's a it depends right
because with children it's very hard to
have a year-round regular schedule I
mean for one thing yoko knows this
because he's got small ones you ain't
sleeping like you you think you should
write so you might plan for what you're
going to be doing you might have all
these grand ideas and creativity which
when you wake up after a long night
dealing with a child you chose not to
sleep that night for whatever reason
sometimes your plans go out the window
so you
one of the things I've had to learn was
to be flexible flexible enough to react
on the fly but also be aware that what
you think our rituals and habits that
will carry towards your success they to
also have to be adjusted to in order to
deal with your family in order to love
your family and to honor your family so
for example I'll say this the past four
days today's my first day back in my
office the past four days we were
sleeping in tents outdoors in Florida
it's still pretty warm so we go camping
and so my children and I'll were out at
the beach where the park all day and all
night long sleeping in a tent getting up
the next morning lighting fires
barbecuing all of which takes time away
from my business right and like you said
before and like I said before you got to
build your lifestyle around your
business so I knew very early on
especially since the internet was a gift
that we all got it during high life our
lifetimes that I was going to build a
business it allows me to work and when I
say work it's like look I spent 15
minutes in the morning just shit
answering some emails and me and I wrote
one blog post now making this video it's
kind of on vacation and I'm recording
this so I try to I try to integrate it
into my lifestyle if I can get up an
hour earlier while still spending time
with my children to do my little bit of
work to keep the plate spinning then I'm
fulfilling on that obligation of family
first lifestyle first and then business
goes around it thank you thank you over
here there's a question any other
anybody else yeah over there so we'll
start here
hey Elliot I was wondering what did you
learn about your titles your YouTube
video titles during the years is there a
certain strategy you apply to both
singing and would soon divers so I'm
going to give you bad advice I guess
because this is not the norm and I say
bad advice only because this is not what
everyone else is doing is what I'm doing
it was working for me but it might be
good advice for you I a friend of mine
just told me he spent several thousand
dollars going to a YouTube workshop by
the way I was like dude I'm your best
friend and you should just ask me but he
wanted to get a different perspective he
wanted to get a different perspective
which I admire and I was like that's
good because I should probably get some
new perspectives also so he went to a
workshop or hired a coach to show him
how to get more views for YouTube by
using keywords and and video titles in
order to rank in essen youtube SEO very
good idea I never did it nor will I ever
do it because my top videos have titles
that read like email subject lines or
sales letter headlines my video titles
and the way I go about it my video
titles and my thumbnail have one job and
one job only and that is to get a
freaking click so if you're a subscriber
or if you're looking at something else
and you see my picture and you see that
headline I could give two craps about
what SEO has done and i wanted i want
you to click that i want you to I want
you to react so they're reactive
headlines their headlines that make it
go home or oh what's this all about and
want to click curiosity you know awesome
great advice great advice and over there
so what's on come sprint give it up for
hustling again
hi Annie I don't know if you can stay
okay come here yeah yes hi hey buddy hi
I'm Ralph thank you for being I've got a
question already mentioned there like
eight of your tightest to get a click
what are some other strategies you used
to grow your channel and grow your
business as far as videos are concerned
the number one thing any content if
you're creating content if your written
video podcast the number one thing in my
mind is will people share this so
getting the click is important but the
real bonus is did I create something
that people are willing to show their
friends to and our people willing to
just click that share button to
broadcast it to their Facebook or to
their other YouTube subscribers or
whatever the case may be I know a video
is successful when it spreads like a
virus and and and and I aim to create
videos that people want to share that's
really what it is okay thank you awesome
so you talked about Dan Kennedy you talk
about more Carl Jung who do you learn
from so who do you learn from oh man I'm
gonna sound kind of corny saying this
but I'll back it up with something some
names dude I'm inspired by everyone I
this morning I wrote in a blog post and
it revolved around the artists that I've
attracted into my life people who sent
me paintings people who have come to my
gym to create things and my daughter my
six-year-old daughter and that's how i
finished the email that the post was to
talk about how inspired i am by artists
but uh but my daughter who's a child who
sits down and when she's inspired she
did
sit down because she gets so excited
when she's inspired either by love for
her parents love for her sisters love
for one of her teachers or one or
someone that she's going to V visit and
she makes a gift of her art and she gets
crayons she might get stickers she might
get paint and she creates something
either a picture of us or picture of
something she saw today or something
that she loves and all I could do was
all I can do is look at her with awe and
say man I I learned so much just from
watching my six-year-old daughter pour
her art her heart out for the people
that she loves through creative
expression you know so we can really
find inspiration and we can we can learn
from boy from everyone even negative
people in our lives one of the newest
things that I've learned is to first
take a deep breath and create space
between myself and someone who comes
with negative energy be it someone with
a negative comment even a family member
or friend who you know may have either
been drinking too much or they just let
her look enfora fight by creating space
and breathing stopping for a moment and
looking at that person that isn't as a
person who's coming to hurt me or
someone who's coming to spread negative
vibes in my life because oftentimes
we're reactive in that way it's like you
know we want to fight back we want to
lash out but I found that I learned
quite a bit about the other person and
about myself when I take those take that
negative energy neutralizing with space
and then ask what is it that's bothering
you or what is this all about and I
learn from them I learn what's going on
in their heart and learn what's going on
in their mind I also learn how I'm
showing up so that they receive me a
certain way so there's learning
experiences through people all over the
place look at people who make miss
stakes in your life a lot of times we
look at our parents or we look at
religion that we grew up with right you
know it might be different in your
country but a lot of us grew up with
religion Christianity kind of pushed on
us but then when we grow up we can grow
resentful we're resentful of our parents
for making us wear ugly clothes or
making us go to school or whatever
there's all kinds of resentment in
there's resentment towards religion and
things of that nature but as an adult if
you look back and you have a and you
create that space and you allow yourself
to be completely objective no feelings
at all and you look at those experiences
you really have to acknowledge how we
are who we are today all the gifts and
blessings that we have today come from
potentially I don't even say potentially
I want to say from negatively coloring
are are negatively colored experiences
from our past negative is a judgment so
of course I'm being a little bit of a
philosopher and I'm ranting I'm talking
in circles right now but my point is
that negative people negative
experiences people who are smaller than
us children even homeless people there's
always an opportunity to learn from
someone if you have on the right glasses
if you can see so that's my hippy answer
awesome where was a great dancer
the people away I learned from if I just
wanted to name drop a little bit Yoko
did a good job but paul chek has been a
mentor and a teacher to mesa for so many
years although he's been dead for 200
years Ralph Waldo Emerson has left us a
cache of poems and essays that like even
when I'm feeling lost today I go back
and I read his words loud so who's the
founder of Taoism there's so much wisdom
to be learned by by brilliant people
dead and alive that it just it makes
life that much more beautiful and gives
us tools to navigate and build in a way
that we personally want to
so too much is too much oxygen 1111 so
there was going to want a repetition so
how was training and kill you did it a
big big again lost like I talked about a
little bit what did you do man it was a
dream come true and and I mean that
literally like I dreamt it I remember
dreaming this I remember coming up with
it five six seven years ago and and
standing there amongst the hundred and
seventy athletes the thousand people in
attendance having my wife there and my
whole team and being just awestruck that
yet another dream of mine has come true
so supportive people who are listening
what did you do with one loss of
strength camp challenge and can you talk
a little bit what it is and why it was a
dream for you and how I wanted it well
the truth is about six years ago five
years ago maybe I tried out for the
CrossFit Games I'm not cut out for
CrossFit apparently because I didn't
score so well so I got upset and I said
to myself I'm going to create my own
competition but it's going to be a
strength camp challenge and it's going
to involve a good combination of
strength and power some conditioning you
know but a lot of strength and power and
and of course like with and I say this
because those of you who are in the
audience who are planting seeds right
now I share this because I want you to
know how possible it is how real it is
but I planted the seed of putting
together this thing and and it came to
fruition we had one last year which was
small and this year got bigger and my
vision for it for next year will be even
bigger so you had athletes and you had I
think a lot of youtubers lemons as well
yeah and a lot of a lot of crowd how
many people with her about a thousand
people in attendance oh yeah it was
really awesome big party we had a big
party yeah it was a good time so they
can set your dream set your goals and
plant those seeds in water room
everything that I experienced my whole
life I I could point to that's just one
of perhaps a dozen that I could point to
just today you know in other words like
just the past few months or a year that
have actually like magic come to life so
those you guys were setting goals man do
it and what are those seeds and they're
going to if my life is an example or my
life is any sort of clue that it's
possible for all of us that's what I
hope for you guys to walk away from this
whatever your dream is plant the seed
and it will come true you just need to
water it and care for it every single
day perhaps four five six ten years but
it's on its way awesomer thank you so
much
so again Elliot thinking so much and
really appreciated it to do time to
share your is coming with all of us so
one more time give it up for Elliot
thanks guys ok now what about a full of
it ok pushers which you prefer ok they
should do nível quarter break in the
nasa'a via sama federal matter De Palma
the defeated hill from a tightly now me
ma Liza favor hunger for a full time and
a bottom which hotel boutique here drive
it through Thank you Thank You Ellis
awesome take care guys have a greater