what's up guys today we have a question
for one of our friends who says that he
has two friends two female friends both
of which who have gone through very
traumatic experiences in the past
several months one of them had a car
accident it became seriously injured and
lost a friend the other one had various
circumstances in her life including some
recent deaths that has caused both of
them to go spiraling down into a deep
depression where our friend now feels
helpless in pulling them up out of it
and although he hasn't experienced what
he's experienced he has a willingness
and a desire to help people and he says
he reads lots of books and he looks to
many mentors to help him in his
perspective about how to go about life
but his friends who have these deep
sorrowful experiences that he has no
experience with no frame of reference
are greatly beloved by him and he can't
seem to even approach them to help them
come out of their ditch of depression
what does he do now before I begin this
I'm going to warn you that some of the
things I'm going to say are probably
better approached from a professional
standpoint but the reason why I want to
share these ideas with you is again to
give you perspective so that perhaps you
might be able to encourage your friends
to move in this direction or seek
professional help and I'll even give you
some resources that you might want to
absorb yourself so that when you look at
your friends you can see them with brand
new eyes and understand physiologically
and psychologically what's going on with
them and why you can't reach them in
their depths the very first thing that I
like to say is that when people offer
the advice that you should just be there
for them I think it's very shallow in
how people usually perceive that and I
even think those who say this don't
really know the depths of what that
actually is just be there for them
doesn't necessarily mean be there as a
as a sounding board for them
to talk to or to hug them or to or to
immediately just be there to coax and
coddle them while they're in their ditch
because that would require you climbing
down there with them and and oftentimes
if your energy isn't strong enough and
you follow someone down into the depths
their ditch of their depression they can
enroll you in why they should be
depressed and why you should feel
depressed for them also energy works
this way and I'm not making any
judgments about the character of any of
these individuals or what what's right
or wrong but you know that this is true
because if you're around a depressing
person long enough you become depressed
you've climbed down into the ditch with
them you've got to first of all take the
perspective that I'm remaining on the
outside here and I'm putting an arm down
there with you the most powerful people
are those who have been down there
before and have climbed out those are
people who can climb in and climb back
out but you have you haven't climbed
into that hole don't go into the hole
there with them because they will
manipulate you into the victimhood that
they surrounded themselves with again
this is not a judgment against anyone
this is just I speak frankly guys so if
you get upset with my Frank language I
don't sugarcoat shit they're in a ditch
you don't want to get in the ditch
because they can manipulate you to stay
there it's been done you can probably
ask yourself or your friends or people
that you know if this ever happened to
them energy works that way it can be
drawn but it can be uplifted now you
need to be an uplifter but the only way
that you can begin uplifting your
friends that are in the ditch is to get
them to see appreciate recognise and
fully experience the ditch that they're
in because if you don't recognize and
experience the dish in its darkness you
will have no ability to climb out of it
you'll carry it with you you'll pretend
to climb out by putting a smile on your
face
they won't pretend to be happy they will
just get on with their lives but they'll
carry the darkness with them they've got
to experience the darkness and all of
its
Ronis and all of its nastiness and all
of its visceral response in the body we
started the work of Peter scare who is a
psychologist in this particular way
particularly body psychology a very
great book by him that I would invite
you to read especially as it relates to
your friend in the audio accident
because he worked this theory out with
lots of auto accident victims is called
the body bears the burden and in
experiencing the trauma the actual
traumatic event of the car accidents or
the deaths your friends went through a
physiological response that seems a
little bit like this there is a revving
up of energy in the body because there's
a stimulation of the sympathetic nervous
system that's associated with
fight-or-flight you get into a car
accident somebody dies these are the
visceral responses these are the
physical responses associated with the
fear o fear and and loathing
but it's very rare that someone will do
those actions those physical actions
because they become confusing and
inappropriate in the world that doesn't
recognize that the body is the mind see
I'm not afraid to do these things and to
be emotive in front of you because I'm
not afraid of my body and what my body
might do I'm not afraid of going crazy
or shaking up and breaking up my ego is
strong enough to ground myself even if
my body my unconscious carries me
somewhere and there's a simulation of
the sympathetic branch of your nervous
system your autonomic nervous system
meaning automatic this automatically
happens where when you have these
traumas you would burst out in this
particular way break down physically and
physiologically in this particular way
but for a number of reasons social
conditioning is one of them there is an
immediate stimulation also of the
parasympathetic branch of the nervous
system that
someone into shock because they don't
move they go and that that feeling of
shock doesn't go away until the physical
the discharge of the energy happens and
most people keep walking around with the
shock and they might not look like that
all the time but their chest is probably
very full I guarantee you that they
don't breathe very deep at all either of
them they are either carrying around an
anxiety that makes them on edge or they
this is disassociated so much that there
you see they've either depressed their
energy or they bottle it up and anxiety
both of these circumstances which are
I'm going to give you an analogy like
getting into a car turning it on putting
your foot Jannetty on the acceleration
and then all or for yeah jamming on the
acceleration and the brake at the same
time right imagine you get a car and you
get your one foot on the brake right
parasympathetic and one foot on the
accelerator the car is is robbing
there's a lot of shit going on in there
but the car ain't moving your friend's
got a lot of shit going on but they
ain't moving what needs to happen I'm
gonna say this frankly and then I'm
gonna give you some death
frankly what needs to happen is they
need to exercise they need to move that
term exercise is also associated with
exorcism they need to exercise the
demons trapped in their body there's
shit going on inside them that needs to
come out and you being there means
inviting them to go deep into that shit
they need to experience
they've got to experience the physical
physiological response natural response
to the trauma otherwise you're going to
walk around trapped for the rest of
their lives and that's the ditch they're
in and they can't come out of it
you can't talk them out of it you can't
talk them out of it
you can't talk them out of it they've
got to exercise it out very important
now whether you're the one that's there
for them and invites them to experience
that darkness and all of its ugliness so
that they can finally be rid of it it's
not until they can get rid of the
physical physiological response of the
trauma ah that they can set it aside and
begin walking out of it
it happens physically it happens in the
body
when I went through I went through about
two or three years about two and a half
years of deep work with bioenergetics my
mentor Bob blasier deep work I went with
him went through with him and there was
a lot of that in there because we're all
carrying trauma well just have varying
degrees at varying stages in our lives
your friends have a very deep one that
was onset in adulthood but from
childhood we all have repressed trauma
that needs to come out for us to lay it
aside so that we can continue on the
journey of becoming the strongest
version of ourselves and it was very
interesting because we spoke very little
my mentor and I and by the way I do this
with people now this is a part of with
you hired me for coaching nine times out
of ten when someone hires me for
coaching and they think they want one
thing it really boils down to you need
some bioenergetics you need to get you
need to work up the energy in your body
either to bring some charge or so that
you can fully discharge he would merely
invite me to enact certain extra
physical exercises deep breathing
exercises shaking vibrating and things
of this nature to break up the muscular
rigidity that's holding back that
psychological pain your mind is your
body and he would merely sit there and
watch and every once in a while say it's
okay oh good it's okay keep going
and I just explode all over the place on
the on the mattress I'd stand up
whatever it is that I needed to do to
get out the repressed trauma he allowed
me to do and he was there for me by
merely not judging and encouraging
I'm going to end the video the same way
I began it this is deep serious work
it's something our ancestors knew and
it's something that modern science and
medicine is coming to know and respect a
lot more we don't really respect things
of the unconscious any great degree
because it's not materialistically
reducible right so we think it's
hocus-pocus but because of the ability
to track certain hormones and
neurotransmitters in the body and to
engage them in this particular way
because we like numbers and shit some
respect is coming to the anecdotes
associated with exercising you're
trapped demons again I if you understand
my language I don't say that metaphor I
say that metaphorically I don't know if
there are demons but I do know that
there's trapped trauma and it's a
hellish experience to keep it with you
so my friend study my resources take
this brand-new perspective that your
friends are where they are
first your friends are there and you
don't want to go there with them and if
your energy is not strong enough they
can pull you down and your friends are
there not because of what they're
thinking about and you can't talk them
out of it but because of what they're
feeling or choosing not to feel and they
need to exercise it out study the
resources I shared with you see if you
could find them professional help in
body psychology there's so many
different branches of neo Reiki and
therapy neo Reiki and meaning a new
Wilhelm Reich
when I say Reich Reiki and Rose comes
from Reich wilhelm reich rei CH neo
reichian that's a better way to say it
from Wilhelm Reich's
gift to West to the Western world
centering around body psychology there
many different types of it there are
many different branches of it
bioenergetics just happens to be the one
that I studied because it was a great
teacher nearby for me
not the only one even ancient forms a
body meditation like yoga Qigong
although probably better for healthy
people will bring some relief to your
friends the pain is not just in their
head as we like to believe the pain is
truly in their body and your body is
your mind
done