so I got a question from our buddy
Michael who would like to use the
internet I don't know if it's videos or
whatever the case may be books um
platform online to promote his work
apparently he's got either some art or
some ideas that he's fascinated with he
note is he knowses of great value and
would bring value to lives of other
people but he's afraid to promote
himself he said he basically feels like
he may be being egotistical
or you know self-righteous or
self-absorbed by turning like Elliott
else does the camera on himself and
promoting himself and there's this is
all a manifestation of low self esteem
and now low self-esteem comes from a
culture that conditions you to believe
you're not good enough and how dare you
ask for more
this happens in very subtle ways
starting in school starting in the home
but you know in school where you know
you're not special you're not better
than anyone else don't step out of line
don't speak up raise your hand you
belong you know mediocre along with
everybody else
don't dare try to rise above even today
there's in physical education classes
and many sports programs there's no
winner you're not even allowed to win
you're not even allowed to promote
naturally your superiority in any way
shape or form
nice oh that's a wrap but anyway he
wants to know he sees Elliott hell is
doing this and he's like you know I
respect you Elliott but how do you get
over that barrier of feeling is if
you're stepping on someone's toes or
doing something naughty by promoting
yourself here's the way I look at it it
is not only you're right because that's
what you'd like me to say no it's you're
right yes you should be able to do this
not just you're right I'm not just going
to give you permission to do it I'm
going to tell you that it is your
responsibility to promote yourself and
to promote your ideas we live in a day
and age where your ability to share
ideas share your art share your gifts
with the world has is easier than it
I've been in the in the entire span of
mankind I mean just think a few years
ago in the aisle of the United States a
lot of people can't even read I mean to
hell with the fact that there were books
people couldn't even read now
and in order to share ideas you know you
needed to first of all we needed an
alphabet then we needed to write this
stuff down then we needed to
mass-produce books and then we needed
people who could read these friggin
books and now it's basically clip on a
camera hey I can talk to the whole world
you know this video will probably have
10,000 views at some point right so how
is it that we have this all available to
us but you're sitting on the sidelines
too scared to get your message out now
that's just the medium through which
you're going to share with people you
know that's my being enthralled with the
technology that we have available to us
but now here's the thing that you got to
understand you will possibly positively
affect the lives of perhaps thousands or
hundreds of thousands or millions of
people with what you do when you put
yourself on that pedestal
now how dare you not help those people
how dare you not bring joy into lives of
those people and it doesn't matter what
you do Elliott Hulse answers questions
for people so that you know to give them
perspective on how they can live their
lives but even if it's your your artwork
perhaps you are a sculptor now you you
may not be literally changing the
trajectory of people's lives but you
bring peace and joy pleasure to the
people who can appreciate that art how
dare you put that under a blanket
I think it's written in I think Luke no
you know I'm not that familiar with the
New Testament guys but I'd know it in
fact I think it's Paul says something to
the effect of nobody likes a candle to
put it under the table you don't let a
fucking candle to put it on the table it
illuminates a candle illuminates it
brings light to and and offers its
service to everything within it's within
its sphere of influence that's what you
do when you put yourself out there
you're like a candle
light upon darkness now nobody's going
to take that candle and put it under the
table there's a purpose for it and your
purpose what you've been given and your
beliefs to share has to be executed it
is you're responsible you must do this
if you go to your deathbed not giving
the world the gift that you've been
granted because you were too afraid then
you are going to be miserable and you're
going to have to be reincarnated and try
again
peace