so we got a question here from our
friend Kirsty who has a pretty good life
you know his parents are cool he lives
in a nice house he lives in Florida
apparently but it's never left Florida
he's 21 years old he's also an artist
and he has this desire in his body his
heart is telling him that I need to go
travel I need to get out and I need to
develop myself in my art he's a
cartoonist and anime I think some sort
of interesting cartoon unique cartoon
drawings he makes so he's developing his
skill but he also feels this yearning
for adventure this yearning for travel
right you never left Florida bro and
you're 21 so I can see why you're
feeling that way I have a few different
perspectives on this but before I share
either perspective with you know that
it's coming from the sentiment of damned
if you do damned if you don't
I've said this before what you do really
doesn't matter as much as how you are or
how you how you travel the journey the
journey doesn't matter nearly as much as
what kind of a traveller you are how are
you developing yourself as a traveler
how do you deal with the perros how do
you handle the challenges how do you
receive the gifts along the child the
travel it's not the road it's the Walker
right so when I say damned if you do
damned if you don't
it can beat there could be two totally
different roads and you could walk this
one and it could be absolutely brilliant
but it also could be really fucked up
and you can follow this one and be
absolutely brilliant gonna be absolutely
fucked up
there's no fucking guarantee absolutely
none the world will have you believe
there's a guarantee but there is not a
single guarantee all these kids that are
graduating high college with these
$80,000 degrees they can't even work at
Starbucks
all the people who put their money in
the stock market and bought all this
real estate 2008 it all went away
don't let anybody fool you into
believing that there's a guarantee that
there's a safe way the well-trodden path
is the scariest way in my my opinion
right cuz then you just spent the last
80 years of your life doing everything
that everybody else told you to do and
you never really lived or produced
anything unique if everybody's going
this way go that way if they guarantee
you anything be very specific
suspicious of the guarantee because it's
a way to enslave you
I love civilization I've got this
love-hate simply a relationship with
civilization because civilization is
pretty fucking cool I mean we've got
cars and we've got running water we've
got food in the supermarkets but it's
also got it's a double-edged sword right
I'm listening to this audio program
called the history of the the people's
history of the United States do you know
how what it takes to develop
civilization how many people have to die
how many people had to become slaves
there's an ugly side to it civilizations
beautiful but I mean even just look at
the United States you live in Florida
for us to have all the oil that we use
to drive all the fucking cars that we
have people are dying right don't think
that our wars over sea have anything to
do with Patriot being patriotic or or
bad guys has everything to do with the
expansion of civilization of this type
of civilization right so don't let
civilization right the Rastas would call
it Babylon don't let Babylon fool you
into thinking that it's all right and
true it's an interesting game that
humanity's playing and we happen to be a
part of it and there's some good stuff
to it but don't be fooled into believing
that it's all hunky-dory beautiful and
that it's full of truths because there's
a lot of lies and one of those lies is
do with everyone in civilization is
telling you to do live in this world be
not of it and that means as much as you
learn the language and you wear the
clothes and you do the things that
civilized people do you also have to
honor the language of your body you've
got to listen with your heart and you've
got to move with your balls and your
body in your heart your heart your balls
are going to lead you down certain roads
that
cause of the safety net of society the
safety net of civilization it will only
be a more fascinating safe journey for
you what do I mean by this
so you want to travel as an artist but
you don't know how you're going to pay
for the whole thing
it really doesn't fucking matter how you
pay for it your heart is asking you to
make a move make a move and you gain a
certain type of strength by following
your body following your heart there's a
certain type of strength and the power
and the intelligence of your heart grows
every time you listen to it it's risky
it seems because we've been guided by
our heads that's what that's how
civilization controls us we've been but
guided by our heads for so long so when
the heart has speak start speaking
you're like oh I don't get this I don't
understand this what's going on and
everybody tells you they're all listen
to your heart I just posted something on
Facebook earlier today that said they'll
feel more and think less so many people
are so fucking indoctrinated so
indoctrinated by religion in society
civilization the thing that the heart is
they called the whole heart evil the
heart fat evil you just don't understand
the heart because you're so fucking
brainwashed you follow the heart a
little bit and it grows in its
intelligence it grows in its strength it
grows into an ability to serve you in an
intelligent way there's a magnificence
intelligence in your body but check me
out it's not that crazy because you've
got a safety net of civilization go out
my friend get on a Greyhound bus and go
to another city whatever city you want
to go to and you know what you'll find
there homeless centers there are places
where you can you can walk in tonight
and have a warm bed and a meal for free
hey civilization ain't so fucking bad
they fool you into believing you haven't
you believe that that is unrespectable
in some particular way or that you're a
failure in some particular way but
that's just a fucking story
right you're a failure in civilization
if you can't pay a lot of taxes see I'm
a success and I'd be a shitload of
fucking taxes so I feel good and the
world feels good about me but it's a
trap now what you get you get to live
off my tax money you go to yours go to
yours the homeless shelter in your city
I'll pay for that it's all this kind of
like nobody wins nobody loses but don't
be fooled by any one particular part of
this story follow your heart you might
not have all the things and experience
well your experiences will be very
different than most people's but you
might not have the trappings of what
society calls success but you will have
listened to your heart and honored
the genius within you you'd have
developed your art you're an artist my
friend and the art and artist creates
art for nothing more than art that's the
purpose of art is itself right who said
that wild Oscar Wilde the only purpose
is art is art it's it's only purpose you
produce your art and you you're also
making your life a piece of art by
having a subjective experience that that
defies what everyone tells you you
should be doing or shouldn't be doing go
my friend go it's going to be difficult
it's going to be challenging it's going
to be different no one's going to be
able to give you a roadmap for its
course but it's going to be unique it's
going to be you
you'll be safe don't worry we have food
stamps and shit right
there's clean water you live in America
motherfucker it's easy here you could
drop out of society and society will
still carry you in this country right go
to Ecuador or some shit go go live up in
the mountains and uh somewhere in South
America night really fucked lions are
chasing you the got malaria and shit and
the government probably put you in jail
just so they can hold you ransom you
look at America it's all cozy and easy
here right so bounce dude go follow your
heart and I'm not making any guarantees
about that either
done