I got this question from one of our
friends who wants to remain anonymous he
goes on and says that he's got a problem
with jealousy and insecurity with with
girlfriends or you know it says
significant other so I'm assuming
girlfriend right um jealousy here's the
thing and this is just a perspective to
consider that the majority of us have an
emptiness a longing within us due to
early childhood experiences you know we
could pinpoint it at any experience you
know namely the the the denial of the
mother when she doesn't or she takes
away her nursing you know that's usually
one of the very first breaks from
continuity that we have with our source
of life mother right and and then we go
about our lives trying to fill that void
that love that connection that unity
associated with the mother the woman the
earth something that fulfills us you
know she she gave birth to us and
nourished us through her body but that
break comes at some time and depending
how traumatic it was for the child and
this is boys in particular I'm talking
about because the situation's slightly
different with girls but depending how
traumatic it was for the boy he will
then walk around with this emptiness his
scar that he's trying to heal for the
rest of his life unless it's dealt with
and this is what we look for in other
women you know for it is often talked
about how we look for women that remind
us of our mothers and and men you know
women do the same thing with men they
look for men that reminds them of their
fathers the thing is that no woman
that's it it's a childish idea that is
you're trapped in that childish stage of
development you're still trapped or that
wounded where that wound is and we've
got to get over it because now you're an
adult and you're seeking the love of
other women but you're fearful for that
detachment may come again she might find
another man she might cheat on you she
might run away she might go away she may
change her mind about you so you got
this
purity because you're filling a hole
with somebody else and when someone else
when you've decided that someone else is
gonna fill a hole for you you're always
at the whim of their will because she
can do whatever the fuck she wants to do
right she might leave she might be taken
away somebody else might catch her eye
and she goes that's normal and natural
for that to happen is normal and natural
and for you to be aware of that is
normal and natural the problem comes in
when you become so attached to that
situation that you become anxious and
jealous and again that's normal natural
due to the wound that you have so what
we got to do is we've got to heal
ourselves first we've got to become
whole first right before we attach
someone else to us and this is not an
easy task easier said than fucking done
Eliot become whole so that uh I thought
that wasn't recording become whole so
that I can be a whole with someone else
because that's really what it am a
mature relationship is it's two whole
people who come together and support
each other right they don't lay on each
other they don't fill gaps for each
other this is what most people do they
you know they play lean on one another
what I'm telling what I'm telling you is
you support one another you might Teeter
back and forth she might need you more
you might need her more but event but
essentially you guys are both balanced
so get comfortable with yourself for
first you've got to build your own
self-esteem
it doesn't mean closed off or be
hard-hearted to women but realize that
you were born into this world by
yourself even though your mom nurse
student and helped you come out and
you're gonna die by yourself and even
though you share your life with another
person a woman or someone of the
opposite sex or same-sex depending on
your orientation that person is still
just an individual as you are you share
heart to share love but that person is
still free to go don't let that be a
point of contention for you don't have
anxiety about it it may happen we live
in a wiggly world shit happens
she may leave but be okay with it
because you're already okay with
yourself hope that helps man hobo isn't
too poetic for you and look strengthen
your own heart and then share it with
others and that's all you can do
Eliot sick