we got this question from our buddy who
lives in Sweden he's 21 years old about
two years ago he just stood up you
discovered working out it says up until
that point his life has been kind of bad
he says he says I've had a bad life two
years ago I discovered the barbell and
through strength training he built up
his self esteem to such a degree that he
found a girlfriend right and for a few
months they dated he lost his virginity
to her right and a few weeks after he
had sex with him for the first time at
21 years old she bounces she leaves she
says I don't want to deal with you
anymore and she goes and has sex with
other men
now he's distraught can't do anything
but get out but lay at home sits on his
couch all day long
and has no motivation to do anything
what do I do
Elliot okay take a look back oftentimes
when we just look back at the patterns
of our life we start to get clues right
that's a lot of what I do and I don't I
don't know anything I kind of observe
and then sometimes show you so I'm gonna
show you a pattern right it's not even a
pattern yet but you can make it a
pattern because there are certain
successes and lessons to be learned okay
two years ago you discovered weight
training now whether or not you
transformed into a manly beast with
rippling abs and and you know immaculate
looking body it's not the point
two years ago you went from having a bad
life into a purpose right so you're
you're doing something you're engaged in
something you're actively moving towards
something and your life becomes good
again right it's not so much the result
of the weight training but it's who
you're becoming through the weight
training two years ago right so now
you're a man that's on a mission you're
a man that's doing something or a man
with discipline and commitment and
you're a better stronger version of
yourself and that's attractive to women
and what do you know a woman shows up
stronger version of myself building
character ladies show up and you have
sex and you fall in love
now I can guarantee you this is what
happened guarantee you let go of the
pattern the activity the guy should
where you were I guarantee you you start
you fell in love and guess what you
probably rested on her you leaned on her
you started sucking on her right you BK
she became a soccer you made her feel
like a sucker because you no longer
stood on your own ground you never
worked you you're no longer moving in
your way you're not making yourself as a
man any longer you were making yourself
as a man you became attractive now
you're leaning on this woman and women
do not like men leaning on them oh I
think that they probably find it to be
the most repulsive thing in the world
for a man that like leans on them and
sucks on them right I don't know what
your childhood was like I don't know
what your experiences with your mother
would like but you were looking for a
place to suckle and you found that in
your woman and she was repulsed by it
and she pushed you away now what do you
do right because now it's been four
months he says she pushed me away and
she went off now I can't live with
myself I can't get out of the house
though all I want to do is sit on my
couch go back to the gym dude because
now you're going to go back to the road
that got you to where you were too able
to find love to begin with but you also
are stronger now because you learn
something don't give yourself up don't
give up the activity that allowed you to
possess yourself to begin with and don't
lean on your woman don't suck on her
right she wants a baby to suck on her
that's why they're attracted to us they
want to be sucked on but not by you
do you understand cuz you'll disgust her
and she was disgusted with you get on
your feet be a fucking man move in the
direction of something bigger than
yourself make something happen you'll
attract another woman and keep your
grounding while you're with her
done