so it's been a little while since we've
had a conversation you and I right so
today we're just going to talk right so
I have a hundred and one things that I
would love to share with you it's been
quite a while and I'm sure that you've
got 101 questions especially those of
you who have been watching me on youtube
or following me online for years what is
actually a decade since I uploaded my
first youtube videos so the fact that
I've had a recent absence and in over
the past few years two years I've had
intermittent fast fast fast thing right
I was gonna stop the video but fuck that
that fasting fasting from you for making
these videos right but instead of trying
to catch you up right now I'm going to
give you some perspective on what's
actually happening with all of us you
know given my circumstances and your
viewership yesterday I was reminded of a
story my brother had me listen to a Les
Brown video right those he was familiar
with Les Brown he's a motivational
speaker and one of the gifts that
motivational speakers bring forth are
wonderful parables metaphors and stories
and Les Brown gave the good old bamboo
growth story and for those you who are
not familiar with it i'll relate it to
you very briefly according to National
Geographic the bamboo plant right when
it is very young so you've got a little
baby bamboo plant and you planted in the
earth right it will say a particular
size right it will stay say six inches
or a foot long foot tall for many many
many years people will walk by and look
at this thing and think well it's not
doing anything right this plant is just
the same size it was two years ago
what's it doing well underneath the
surface down below within the nourishing
confines and environment of the earth
the
roots of that bamboo plant are growing
out growing deep and four years for many
many years that plant stays the same
size and it digs deep it goes deep it
fulfills its foundation requirement its
nutritional requirement it's going into
the earth and then a funny thing happens
one day the plant grows 90 feet tall in
a matter of weeks it goes from being its
tiny self to a massive tall reaching for
the sky plan that is a metaphor for how
we all grow stronger if you're going to
ascend if you're going to grow stronger
grow taller reach for the stars then
there will inevitably be times of going
down deep in catalysis right it's this
process of going down building more
roots deeper roots stronger foundation
right and you experience this all
throughout your life you're constantly
doing this on a physical level and on a
metaphysical level right and as it
relates to our experience our
relationship you and I write me feeding
people through these videos feeding you
with ideas information inspiration all
the things that you want to absorb and
you receiving it well there's been a cut
off right like i said before i use that
term intermittent fasting because it was
a fast it is a fast right the outward
expression the upward growth the extra
version is only possible to its full
capacity right because you can you can
continue to give give give give give you
can continue to try to reach for the sky
while your roots wither and shrink or
just stay the same but if there's going
to be
a stronger version of you a stronger
version of elliott hulse it is
absolutely one hundred percent necessary
that there is a going in process all the
time I don't care where you are in life
what you're doing there will be a
physical and a metaphysical going down
digging deep spreading your roots
getting into the earth of your body the
earth of your mind the physical earth
itself to ground yourself before you can
skyrocket up just like that bamboo
planning that's what's going on here
folks so you know what that all looks
like well it's easy to look on the
surface to figure out what's really
going on right I could spend the next
well you know we're going to be talking
for a little while here here so grab
yourself a drink I can talk 30 minutes
about what I've been doing in that going
down process all right that digging deep
process that growing roots process right
but that's very subjective it's very
individual what's required for you to
become a stronger version of yourself
those things that you have to deal with
in the shadows deal with in the the dark
deal with in the dirt deal with in the
soil your ground very subjective
everybody's different and if I were to
begin sharing what i've been doing what
I i hope most sound like Elliott's
giving advice again right I'm not here
to give advice I never really have been
here to give advice everything that I've
offered you through these videos has
been a matter of my experience and my
sharing what his work best for me right
there's a good chance that i'll probably
be back with more videos but guess what
i will have that much more experience
that much more depth of self and content
to share with you when i decide to do it
right so like I alluded to the best way
to know what's going on inside someone
is to look at the outside right the best
way to know someone's the depths of
one character someone's characters to
look at you know what's going on in the
outside right so let's talk a little bit
about what's happening on the outside
the most obvious manifestations of my
process and our relationship together
one of the things for sure is that with
a going down there's a subsequent going
up right I said to someone very recently
that your life is often like a
basketball right you want you're going
to bounce that basket ball up high yes
and that shit down really hard the
harder its labs the harder goes down the
deeper you go the higher you go also
just like the friggin basketball just
like the bamboo plant I need some water
good so let's continue our conversation
with regard to what that bouncing up or
with that skyrocketing growth looks like
right what that bamboo looks like for
one strengthcamp jim has evolved leaps
and bounds over the past two years shred
camp jim has gone from my warehouse gym
in the south side of st. Pete where we
at crafts crack heads and prostitutes
right to the little studio that I had on
Haynes road where most of you got to
know me because I honed my craft as a
video presenter for 23 years I made
videos lots of videos tons of them just
feeding into the camera right and then I
decided circumstances were such that it
was time to go back and grow
strengthcamp gym right strengthcamp gym
is displayed in the new video
that you see with our coaches at the gym
the things that we're doing the members
that we have we never had any members at
the second stripe camp is also busy
making these videos right what I set out
to do from the beginning was to build a
gym to have a strength camp right that's
what I that's what this has been about
from the beginning right I decided to
dedicate a few years of my life to
sharing through this camera but
ultimately the goal has been and is
being achieved that strength camp grows
up Shrek camp is not only grown up in
st. Petersburg and we have a wonderful
clientele we have a ton of clients but
strength camp is always also growing in
many other ways as well one thing for
example its strength camp media from the
very beginning I have been a publisher I
have been a writer I've created products
info products educational products from
the very beginning but when I decided to
make videos and dedicate a few years to
making these videos for YouTube I
stopped all that I stopped writing I
stopped creating in that particular way
because I wanted to give through these
videos I enjoyed doing it right one of
the things that had to happen for
strengthcamp media to be picked back up
for my websites to be picked back up to
begin making products again and to
publish other people because you know
Elliott Hulse doesn't believe he's the
only one with great information to
publish we have great trainers at the
gym will be publishing their products
mark has an Olympic lifting product
coming out pretty soon Julie is a great
dietician she'll be supporting us with
nutrition coaching we have stripped camp
co online coaching coming very soon all
of which is only possible because
Elliott Hulse had to go deep Elliott
Hulse needed to grow roots Elliott Hulse
had it too had to go down to go up
especially in areas that were lagging
right this process continues to go on
and always goes on strengthcamp also is
expanding through strength camp
international and I'm not going to
reveal exactly what that is
in fact that will be revealed to most of
you watching this because it will really
just be revealed first and foremost to
the 100 people who signed up for the
shrimp camp clinic and business seminar
that's happening in November which by
the way thank you to everyone who
decided to sign up we sold out in 10
days I'm really excited about that
because if I were just to continue
making videos inspiring videos talking
to you I wouldn't have the opportunity
to invite you a hundred of you to my gym
where I can show you what we do at
strength can show you how shred camp has
become successful through our business
model right all wonderful work all of
which could only be possible if I take a
break right take a break from making
lots of videos and you know before I
continue it a part of the reason why I
haven't shared this is because I don't
want this to sound like an elliott hulse
diatribe is all elliott hulse just
talking about Elliot Houston what's
going on belly house it's never been
that way and it never it's never been my
intention to be that my attention is to
share my experiences so that perhaps you
could glean some wisdom from someone
else's life experiences right as you
listen to me think about yourself think
about how this applies to wear in my
life am i dropping the ball not that
it's a bad thing but perhaps i need to
put things down a little bit so other
things can grow and then you're going to
reach a point where you're going to ask
yourself well i'd like to grow these
things again let me go down and figure
out and let me tell you something about
the going down process before I continue
I told you there's going to be a rant
the going down process is going into
solitude going into silence a going into
a space where you can begin to hear the
voice of your heart again right I make
these videos giving you guys all kinds
of advice about listening to your heart
and following your gut right well guess
what the rules apply here two and one of
the things if I had to give you some of
the lessons
that I've learned in my going down time
in my coat abysus is that solitude
silence space sacred space is critical
and that's what I've been doing a lot of
we also have right and I'm sharing this
all with you out of excitement because
it's amazing over the past two years
what has happened what's going what's
going on and all the opportunities for
you shrimp camp gym grows in Elliott
Hulse it's not even about Elliott houses
but the opportunities I've been able to
create for our partners and our trainers
and our coaches and our online coaches
and our clients Elliott hose can't do it
all himself everything I'm talking to
you about is less of a bragging and more
of a look at the opportunities that are
available for all of us now chef camp
Jim strengthcamp media strengthcamp
international and the strength camp
summit world summit has been a dream of
mine since becoming YouTube famous to
invite everyone from around the world
wants to come to shrink am right and
take advantage of everything that we
have in one week to come and do that and
that's what we're doing right Elliott
Hulse has had this gym open for people
to come on Mondays for open gym for many
many years and people still come but if
you want to come to a shrink appt clinic
you want to experience active meditation
if you want to learn about business you
want to take advantage of your strength
and power and compete and the should
camp challenge if you want to meet greet
speak to learn from myself and other
experts well why have it spread out all
over the place all over the year why not
have one strengthcamp world summit week
that's what's going on that's what's
happening and I want to give you this
gift the world summit also has
opportunities not just to come and to
learn in to experience and to compete
but we are looking to provide
opportunities one of the opportunities
is
for volunteers well first of all we're
looking for interns all right every
employee at truck cab has been an intern
Trent camp is growing Trek campus is
doing great work and creating more
opportunities for more people worldwide
and we're looking for interns so i'll
put a link down below so that you can
apply for an internship it's a beautiful
institution we've created an opportunity
to come I don't like to hire anyone or
marry anyone that I haven't spent enough
time getting to know their character
right I married my high school
girlfriend it should be an indication to
you that I like to develop relationships
that's what the internship is all about
it's all about you spending some time
here with me and us and seeing if it's a
good fit seeing what kind of creativity
what kind of effort what kind of
relationship we could develop together
right what are we doing and after 60 to
90 days if there's a good fit hey I want
to I want to continue to grow our staff
I want to have a big family i called
ours to echo our staff the strength camp
first family I won't have a big
beautiful family people that love each
other people that can get along people
that have the same mission same mindset
that are on the same journey we can do
it together our internship apply offers
that opportunity for people the Shred
camp challenge in world summits coming
up in November there are opportunities
for volunteers I can tell you right now
that our volunteers that have been
coming to the shunt cap challenge have
been coming the same people have been
coming back every year and they cannot
wait until we do it again it's like a
big family reunion I love getting back
together with all the volunteers that
have been here year after year they come
from all over the world it's incredible
it's wonderful it's such a gift to me
and an opportunity for you also
strengthcamp the shrunk camp clinic is
looking to partner with other businesses
right other businesses that have
internet products and services and many
of our local brick-and-mortar
through our sponsorship program living
fuel has sponsored the strength cap
challenge for going on three years that
should be an indication as to the type
of relationship we intend to build with
our sponsors and the type of exposure we
hope to provide for our friends alright
that's what the sponsorship program is
all about right we earn a little bit so
that we can put it right back into the
strength camp challenge Oh almost a
hundred percent of the proceeds goes
right to making the program even better
one of the things that we're going to be
able to do this here because of our
sponsors is have the strength camp
challenge be broadcast worldwide live
streaming right I told you there's so
many things that I want to share with
you guys and I figured like let me just
make one of these brain dump videos
where I just lay it all out here for you
right and if you're still here with me
that means we've developed a good enough
relationship where we can just have a
conversation and off to entertain you
all the time but I don't have that music
and flashing and you know be an
entertainer right I'd rather put that
aside sometimes and just be real with
you and that's what we're doing right
now finally moving forward I mean I just
explained all the incredible things that
are happening with strength camp and the
opportunities to to embrace you guys to
get to meet you too we connect to
rekindle to reunite to have a deeper
level of communication and love that's
really what it is there's only so much I
can provide you through these videos
there's only so much that I can do this
only so much energy and love that I can
project through this camera man there's
nothing like hugging you there's nothing
like meeting somebody who says Elliot
I've been watching your video since I
was 14 years old and now i'm 21 and it's
you've been like a father figure to me
the hugs big hugs I melt when I hear
that fast when there's my life in this
in this room work I couldn't even make
this video the gym because the gym is
popping talking to myself through this
camera I get robbed that the love return
the return right remember mine on job
video you put out that love the love
comes back
I've gotten to look back monetarily but
that means nothing compared to the love
back in heart and soul I can't make
videos for rest of my life and hope to
have that heart and soul connection yeah
if it sounds like I'm justifying well
maybe I am past two years has been a
process of me trying to figure out who I
am what I'm really put here to do and to
live my authentic self and it's very
difficult for a lot of people to be able
to realize that especially those who
have come to be fed from these videos
there's a lesson in that also for you if
you've watched my videos while I was
feeding you and you became addicted
right sucking on it sucking it all in
and when I pull off if you have a hard
time grounding yourself without me
feeding you without you latching on to
me then you've got a lot of work to do
when you could stand on your own feet
and not have that oral desire to suck on
to consume it'll be a lot easier number
one for you to live an authentic life
but number two to allow other people to
live their authentic lives alright I get
it I get up I get it there's a pattern
interrupt there's a little disrupt
there's some confusion about it and I
haven't been on drip sent transparent
because I just needed to go in so the
lesson here for those of you who are
latched on and who have had a hard time
with my disappearance it's an
opportunity to learn how to integrate
the things I've spoken about to be the
thing rather than consuming we're all
consumers we live in this goddamn
consumer machine matrix all you do is
consume consume consume all day long on
the phone all day long on the computer
sucking and sucking and sucking and
thinking that you're learning something
but you're really just filling your head
because nothing is embodied if you want
a true gift you want the real gift of a
late houses videos watch one of my
videos and go do the thing that I was
talking about on your own feet on your
own ground in your own way and get off
the tip and finally speaking of
grounding one of the my most proud
projects the one by which I now have the
space the creativity the authenticity
and the courage to walk forward with and
to carry and to enter and to develop as
a gift is grounding camps drowning camp
is my new company where we do camps that
offer osho dynamic meditations and
bioenergetic grounding those use watch
my videos long enough knew that this was
a part of what Elliott Hulse wanted to
offer to the world I've had to do a lot
of soul-searching a lot of dig deep
digging inside to figure out how I'm
going to offer that right I I got a lot
of resistance I got a lot of love
because of the videos that introduced
bioenergetics and active meditation but
I also got a mere reflection of my
shadow self by those of those people who
want to denigrate Elliott Hulse for
those ideas I really had to step back
and say am I am I real or am I wrong
well guess what round the camp LLC means
Elliott Hulse is real about this we're
going on the fourth camp which sells out
everything that we've done has sold out
within less than two weeks for grounding
kit we do buy out bioenergetics dynamic
meditation and in fact I will be in an
strada Amsterdam right I'm dehydrated
probably because I'm a little nervous I
haven't spoken to guys like this they're
with me it's been a while
I will be an Amsterdam smoking weed and
doing die die a dynamic meditation throw
myself oh I will be there doing
bioenergetics and dynamic meditation and
offering a life changing world embracing
vision that I've reconnected with and
that I want to share with you if there's
a new Elliot there's also a new message
there's also new empowerment there's new
inspiration there are new exercises
there are new tools and techniques and
that's what I want to move forward
sharing with you maybe is coming months
and years I appreciate your patience
with me right I truly do I know how much
you mean to me as much as I mean to you
i just explained how much love I've
received and will continue to receive
because of our relationship I don't take
it for granted what I do have to create
boundaries for myself and you to learn
to create and respect boundaries in your
own life so that you can dig deep spread
those roots get down low go in so that
you could pop out rise ascend and become
all that you're meant to be a strongest
version of you is not a destination it
keeps happening it's cyclical you don't
have one hero's journey in life you have
many thank you for being here with me on
one of my new heroes journeys I'm happy
to be here and to have supported many of
you to your heroes journeys and I'm
excited about our future together those
of you who will be attending our events
in November I'm overjoyed and excited to
meet you there and I promise you all of
you who show up at some of our grounding
camps Amsterdam California in February
New York and June you are my family
strengthcamp elliott hulse grounding
camp god loves you done