so today we have a question from one of
our friends who had been dating a girl
for about a year during the course of
the year that they had been dating they
discovered that she had an illness and
they recently broke up and she's been
not feeling so well
you know so she's questioning whether or
not she had been exposed to something
during her weak condition that is now
making her very ill so she asks our
friend who she had dated for a year and
now they're broken up during the course
of our relationship did you have sex
with anyone else
unprotected and then come back and have
sex with me I need to know this because
in order to pinpoint why I'm feeling
this way
my doctor wants to know if I was exposed
to anything in my weak condition hmm and
our friend is in a dilemma because he
has he did have sex with another girl
during the course of the relationship
did come back and have sex with her and
in fact the girl that he had sex with
happened to be the nemesis arch enemy of
his girlfriend so I mean that could
that's a whole nother
powder-keg to be dealt with so he comes
to us today wondering what the best
approach should be now if I tell her
that yes I cheated on you and yes you
may have been exposed to something
because I didn't use protection then
that alone the stress associated with
that alone could perhaps make her even
more ill this is his concern for her or
he could not say anything keep it quiet
and say no no no I didn't cheat on you
and and watch her grow ill in confusion
and ultimately you know whatever her the
ultimate end point for her is hopefully
she gets over it but if she doesn't he's
got to sit with the guilt of oh my god I
might have killed her and I never told
her very challenging place to be in and
I'm going to begin like this this is one
of those circumstances where I'm going
to say the often-quoted
and never tasteful quote you're damned
if you do
you're damned if you don't you're not
going to win this is one of those
circumstances where you've got to be
with that you're going to lose either
way but you're also going to win either
way it's a very loaded circumstance
meaning you're not going to get a pure
outcome be with that you've got to
accept that before I even move further
in any regard I need you to really
accept and own that you're damned if you
do you're damned if you don't
right now you're fucked and you can't
run away mommy can't help you you're
going to make a decision in each choice
is the wrong one and each choice is the
right one and why I say each choice
whichever one you choose is the right
one and it's because of this you are on
the road to becoming the strongest
version of yourself meaning you are a
successful person and you will continue
to breed success in your life and
there's something that you might need to
know about successful people you've
heard me say this before but successful
people don't make the right decisions
they make their decisions right and
there are many different ways to go
about making whatever choice you've made
right and a lot of it has to do with
your internal dialog and how you feel
about yourself and I hope you guys begin
to understand just the importance of
that internal dialog and personal
feelings your emotion means far more
than what you do on the outside I know
this is difficult to deal with it's a
difficult concept to grasp in a world
that seems so tangible we're so addicted
to materialism and when I say
materialism I don't mean expensive cars
I'm into the flesh - what's happening
outside us as opposed to the spiritual
realm who we are character our mind
so I can go on and I can be entertaining
in my descriptions of what could
potentially happen if you do tell her
and I can be entertaining in my
descriptions of what would happen if you
don't tell her and I think that's in
fact the route that I'm going to go I'm
going to I'm going to choose the latter
because I think it's the lesser of the
two choices and that is if you don't
tell her now this is my my feelings on
the circumstance and I don't want to say
that I'm right but I want to offer you
the perspective based on what is coming
through me what I feel about the
circumstance now again you're damned if
you do you're damned if you don't if you
don't tell her the truth
and she grows ill or even if she doesn't
grow ill and she recovers the mere fact
that you're holding on to a piece of
information that she humbly came to you
to give you've not only committed the
sin of cheating on your girlfriend and
when I say sin I don't mean you know God
is gonna strike you with it with
lightning and you're gonna go to hell
when I say sin it means you slipped damn
I screwed up boy and you screw up
because you didn't see there was
something you weren't aware of not
saying that you were stupid when you
didn't know I didn't know I I had no
idea that my dick was in her that's not
what I'm saying I'm saying when the
circumstance posed itself you were
blinded to the bigger picture and you
allowed your dick to slip into another
girl so that's a sin so you not only are
carrying the sin associated with the
describe with the the breach of trust
but now when she comes to you says
please tell me
and you don't tell her you're now going
to carry the burden of a second sin your
load gets heavier you're already
carrying a heavy load you already fucked
the other check I think came back and
fucked her and it could potentially be
making her more ill my assumption is
that it's probably not I think she's uh
again this is just my speculation
I think she's prodding because she has
your guilt and she sees that she's ill
and you probably you know you you feel
guilty about her being ill and she
probably has some sort of inkling that
perhaps you cheated and she figures that
this is a good opportunity to get this
out of you
okay and that's just again you know
that's that's food for thought but I
wouldn't let that completely carry the
choice that you make simply because that
is with her that's hers you've got to
deal with you your circumstances your
internal dialogue so but let's say she
does grow ill and you carry it you carry
the fact that you had sex behind her
back you made her sick and you didn't
tell her so that's three so it starts
piling up so if you don't tell her the
sin grows heavier the load you have to
grow grows heavier now you're damned if
you do you're damned if you don't you're
going to carry a load either way but to
move into the future carrying three
potentially three burdens to me is not
worth the acute strike of just telling
her once rip off the band-aid deal with
it you are honest you had integrity you
made a mistake you'll ask for
forgiveness and even if she is growing
ill because of the choice you made at
least your own heart is clean by
confessing and humbly asking for
forgiveness not only from her but to
yourself and to whatever higher power
you feel is animating this world
we're co-creators with the higher power
meaning that if we lie to ourselves
we're lying to the energy that guides us
and it's a block it becomes a blockage
in the flow of God moving through you
it's not a matter of God punishing you
it's a matter of you punishing yourself
by distancing yourself from him or her
or int or science so my friend my
invitation would be to first consider
that you're damned if you do you're
damned if you don't
and that successful people don't make
the right decisions they make the
decisions right and finally you'll carry
a far lighter load if you confess if you
develop your potential for honesty and
you maintain the integrity of your being
when I say integrity I mean just this
lining up integrity means wholeness your
head your heart and your balls your gut
best of luck my friend done