what's up guys good morning good Sunday
morning I've enjoyed making these videos
with you guys over the past few weeks
and I want to continue the conversation
so instead of it being one of these
situations where I'm talking at you guys
I'd like to get back into a dialogue so
I'm sure many of you guys yeah being
queries you have concerns you have
questions you have challenges there are
things that I kind of like supporting
you with helping you with and for this
to continue it might be a good idea for
me to field some questions from you guys
now I hesitate of course you could
probably sense that in my voice because
I don't want to be yo Elliot again
alright that's that guy's dead and no
judgment against CEO Elliot I mean
served his purpose in my life and
perhaps in your life for the years that
Yoel it existed but um it's time to move
on now it's an interesting thing it's
not so much moving on because in 2012 I
created a second channel a second Elliot
Hills channel called Elliot said what
alright and you might remember I would
answer questions early in that on that
channel you know 2012 to 2014 I was
answering questions mainly on
relationships dealing with challenges in
life in general on that channel and I'd
end the video with that little jingle
that said Elliot said what and then some
music and whatnot so that was kind of my
hook over on that channel and and I sort
of did away with that little hook when I
when I really just put all my eggs into
the yo Elliot basket but here we are now
and I'm I'm back to making videos
regularly and and I really enjoy
answering your questions and know
hopefully you guys enjoy hearing the
crazy things I have to say sometimes
that's why I call it Elliot said what
right because sometimes it's like it
makes you scratch your fucking head like
what is this guy talking about sometimes
I watch my videos I'm like what the hell
am I talking about here so anyway I want
to invite you to send me your questions
but here's the deal and every week I'm
going
answer one of your questions but here's
the deal put your questions in the inbox
on my Eliot set what channel and that's
where I'll be answering the questions so
from here on out I won't be uploading
these videos to both channels I'll be
uploading these weekly either q and A's
or if I have something brand new or
interesting that I want to share with
you an experience I had or an epiphany
I'm gonna upload them over on the
Elliott Hulse Elliott said what channel
so you can go click over to that and
that's where you will be able to if you
subscribe that's where you'll be able to
get the updates on the things I have to
share with you here and you know I hope
with this new venture into creating
videos again in this particular format
that I could share some brand new
perspectives that I've had based on the
experiences and challenges and struggles
I've had over the past two years I'm not
the same that's why I couldn't go back
to your Elliott I'm not the same Elliott
that there was obviously a lot of you
guys recognize that and you call me the
new Elliott and whatnot I'm not the same
exact kind of guy that I was when I made
those videos not that I am you know I've
done a 180 but I have brand new
perspectives I've had plenty of brand
new experiences and with that it just
gives me a bit more perspective and also
far more empathy and compassion for you
guys who are working through particular
struggles I think what makes my you do
my videos somewhat unique is that I can
usually offer a story or perspective
based on an experience that I've had the
more experiences I've had more times
I've fucked up
right more mistakes I've made the more I
actually have to offer you from an
authentic place when you come to me with
your questions and concerns and beyond
that I'm a wealth of knowledge on a many
different topics of course for layers of
strength they're my four favorite things
to talk about so if you've got questions
on neuromuscular strength I want to
answer strength questions I want to
answer your strength questions right
whatever you're trying to do
it's got to interest me otherwise I'm
not gonna answer it but fitness
questions physiological questions right
dealing with the body on the
physiological level right so questions
like that relate to nutrition biological
rhythms and circadian rhythms things of
that nature you know health really enjoy
that also spirituality at which is
energetic strength right at low
spirituality I love talking to you guys
on these topics of the mind topics of
the soul and especially as it relates to
body psychology you know that I have
been using and studying and working with
bioenergetics and active meditation for
many many years way longer than I've
been making these videos and of course
life mastery right what's it all worth
to grow stronger for not supporting
others we're not doing our best to have
healthy relationships build businesses
help people do good things and that's
what life match is all about so ya wanna
rap what y'all send me your questions
I'll see you there
done