hey what's up guys that Latos here in my
office and over the years people have
sent me so many wonderful gifts I've
gotten gifts from people all over the
world and sometimes I can feature them
on social media but oftentimes people
send me things and quite frankly I don't
really get back to them too quickly if
you live around here we're in my office
and we're with my friend Jess here who's
been helping me out we've organised
everything that I've gotten over the
past 2014 15 16 17 here - with things
that I have responded to because there
was a time when I was really trying my
best to write the letters and send
things out to people because that's what
I always wanted to do I want to
acknowledge people by sending them
something back but um I got busy I just
didn't have the opportunity to continue
doing that so things have been piling up
in my office and after your cleaning up
we decided to organize and now if you
come over here these are a lot of the
letters suggested did a wonderful job of
taking it I guess I'm doing this to let
you know that you've been acknowledged
if you've sent me a letter I'm not gonna
go through each one of them right now in
fact I had never gotten a chance to read
to read a lot of them you know so moving
my have someone who I haven't but just
took her time to put it in this organize
in it organizer so that I could look at
them and it's interesting - sometimes
people send me money which which is
pretty cool this person I remember
getting this this person sent this to me
and asked me to take it and share it
with someone else so kind of like pay it
forward which I thought was cool this
person sent me some cash in the mail
apparently he downloaded my lean hybrid
muscle program illegally right because
that's what happens with PDFs so on and
so forth there's so many of them in here
just marked out some of them that are
prominent like I've got a letter here
from Shannon who ended up becoming our
our intern in our lovely
at the gym he sent that to me and then
this one's from dougie so I get a lot of
very special letters from people in fact
this one
I remember you man I remember getting
your device Danny do you remember this
it was in the gym yeah yeah I'm grateful
that you went with your intuition and
you went for and you created this thing
what he's trying to do is show people
how to maintain neutral spine during a
deadlift but it's hard to and you
probably watched my videos where I coach
people with a dowel rod it's difficult
to spot yourself and that's what I think
our friends realize so you decided hey
why don't I strap once in my back and
that's what this is these jump into his
back and it kind of gives you
biofeedback over here since we're just
kind of looking around the table this I
got man I got this in about 2014 I and I
was so impressed by it looking I don't
even know what it says Jessup obviously
you probably put it in here I read your
letter bro and I was so impressed by it
I kept this in my car in my dashboard
for months like wanting to get back to
you because it I could I sense the
passion in this one I mean the colors
and I appreciate you guys so yeah I had
it there and it also I had it on my
windowsill in my office for a very long
time because I was like I'm gonna get
back to this guy well I'm gonna get back
to you
get back to you right now these are some
things that I've either just peeked into
or haven't opened yet so we'll do we'll
have a little fun but this one I know
who it's from
it's from Aaron Perry in New Zealand who
came to my bio energetic dynamic
meditation camp earlier this year and
and I knew it had suddenly to rugby knew
it rugger to do and I love Rosie I just
might not notice a paid rugby for quite
a few seasons after college in
Springfield Massachusetts
like an act this is amazing thank you so
much for sending this I'll go play rugby
again I'll put this on they would laugh
at me watching my kids play soccer
recently and I'm like it's kind of like
rugby but they cry of each other and
throw each other on the ground here's
one Lithuania I'm not gonna put your
dress up like that
and I'm always fascinated to get these
ones that are from faraway lands and and
sometimes that the male looks very
different than if I got something from
the US right like this is clearly from
us so I'm always intrigued when I see
these articulations of the utilizations
and meanings of psychedelics well why
you say to me this oh man you ride on a
track well that's wonderful
drawing upon 15 years of profound
research so on and so forth is this your
book that's what I'm curious about
Julian Julian Palmer well thank you very
much for sharing I appreciate that but
we have a lending library at strand camp
now so a lot of the books you guys had
sent me well will become a part of
strength camp as a part of our lending
library so I'll get to this but it'll
end up in our library yep
I had this I decided that holding on to
books in particular doesn't really serve
me anymore
but sharing ideas and that's what the
books were about right books were in
order to enrich myself with ideas so I
could share ideas but holding on to the
book itself is like idol worship get rid
of it it's already a part of me here's
one that looks like it's from Amazon so
uh times those are people's products
just things like whoa beard brush of
assertion right nothing else will do
send a wood premium comb and beard brush
I'm gonna have to do a brush up for you
this is like something should you put in
your pocket man these dudes various long
beards it should always be there good
all right I liked it I keep it was like
down in here so I was able to comb
through it man this one caught my eye
it's a little notebook in fact I was
thinking I need a little notebook like
this recently actually I've been writing
a lot more lately Pierre Pierre via Nene
Pierre dear Elliott thank you so much
for taking time out of your day and
having me interview you okay so that I
read in an interview together this was
an honor and I'm so grateful for this
opportunity well thank you
this is interesting I normally send a
book to those who I've interviewed
however I know you're in more of a
reflective stage of life the journal I'm
sending you is my personal favorite I've
never had a better one
thank you yeah you know what you're
right like I just said I've been getting
rid of my books and I've been writing
more I mean I must be on the same
frequency brother well this is one that
I have opened before but I am so
impressed by it that I want to open it
again and show it oh yeah oh wow there's
more goodies in here than I thought they
were I forgot about these extra goodies
I think these are pieces of art done by
the same artist that sent this to me
said that he was inspired by my saying
the body is the mind right and so he
decided to embody that idea that the
bodies of the mind in this painting I
put it on Instagram once before so and I
know he saw it see you guys you always
leave an impression on me it's not that
there is an impression there this one
dude I am so in love with this shirt I
love it I love it bro I love what's
happening here on so many different
levels I don't even know where to begin
but shits too big for me got a double X
2x man I'm gonna go there but if I put
this on I look like I have a garbage bag
this she deserves better than a garbage
bag on my chest so if you send me a
exhale or even an L coz I'm slimming
down lately I will rock this here's the
next one this is for my buddy keiondre
Schultz was a fantastic young man that
came down for a barbecue I had a
strength camp when I did my first
dynamic meditation workshop and he came
down he's like 17 at the time I was like
3 4 years ago he's a big boy so big now
that he wrote his own book it just looks
like it's
other worldly stuff this dude is uh he's
brilliant he's young and I like what
he's doing
whoo well I was really fascinating is
that he put my name next to JK Rowling's
you see that my name in lights and he
calls me the tender aggressive mentor
make up that which you will fellas
that's Elliott Hulse this one came
looking like this right you just imagine
wow what the hell is there and uh and I
knew it was from out of town it was from
out of country it's from Amsterdam and I
had it for a couple of weeks until I
opened it and I was very impressed that
hopefully we meet up when I'm in
Amsterdam later this this is mum sorry I
didn't reach out or get back to you but
the minute I read your letter and
understood what it was that you sent me
I really realized that you're up to some
really big things you and your father as
it relates to bioenergy and you know
giving people relief psychological
emotional relief through the body and
you know of course I speak about dynamic
meditation and bioenergetics and yoga
and meditation body meditation but you
know acupuncture as well as
physiotherapy myofascial release things
related to the muscle and tissue also
relieve us and support us in multiple
different ways and so what this is is a
a device and I don't know exactly how to
use it just did you to kind of take a
look at it do they have a video or
something that we excited there's two
implements no one in your right hand is
domina
here somehow I don't know how what to
use that was painful
yeah the one in the bag is this video
here they call it the aqua swing and
it's made specifically for your height
and hang out I'm sorry
would I get to Amsterdam you're gonna
show me how to use this cuz this has got
my tension right now the swing yeah I
saw that looks pretty cool people need
to do more circular rhythmical movements
in their life it's just in general yeah
so you fill in water this one it was
made for your measurements because it
goes by the width of your hair mm-hmm if
you look at what he's doing is very
similar to tai chi or Qigong movement
there's these flowing movements
especially when they're coordinated with
the breath are deeply therapeutic thank
you man hopefully we meet up this one
from Ivan Fuentes New Jersey Ivan sends
the Book of Mormon Jess he knows
something
absolutely mm-hmm well Jess was raised
as a Mormon yeah that's wonderful oh and
I sure these books I have more Quran
sent to me than any other book just by
the way Christians you're not keeping up
I need more Bibles hmm Book of Mormon
this is my second Book of Mormon I
cherish these I appreciate these and
guess what because you know you want to
spread the Testament right it's gonna be
in my strength camp lending library
absolutely and I had a great friend who
was Mormon and she really gave me a
wonderful introduction to the faith and
I I respect and I am in awe of it it's a
beautiful thing
so we also have a little letter here
from my brother
I know one feel that this book is
another testament of Jesus Christ I
believe you I believe you bro it's all
good this is not too far it sounds
Canada trans oriented a guide to love
and relationship for men who love
transsexual women so if you're a
transsexual woman that actually means
your man men who love transsexual women
be a gentleman well look you know what
there are some principles in here that's
wonderful be a gentleman and I'm curious
is there a letter that comes there's a
letter thank you for helping me become
the strongest version of myself the
reason I wrote this book is when I came
out as trans oriented I had no resources
to help guide me I had to make all the
mistakes on my own and learn the hard
way I've decided to create the resource
I wish I had back then absolutely to
help guide other men like me in their
quest for love and relationships with
trans women this book is my attempt to
make the lives of trans women everywhere
just a little better if I can help men
who are truly interested in
relationships with trans women be better
boyfriends and husbands if a trans woman
gets treated like a lady instead of a
curious circus freak if these women have
a slightly easier time finding men who
will truly love them I will have done my
job I will have improved the lives of my
girls the girls I love so much bro
absolutely I mean this is what it's all
about right
this is 100% about being the strongest
version yourself but fulfilling
empowering others that's what the other
half is a dude and as you
aim truly you you thought how can I do
it to support others how can I help
others and that's what this is about but
that's what my videos are about that's
what the message is all about you're
totally doing it trans dude props to you
thank you