we got this question from our buddy who
lives in the Czech Republic he's got a
girlfriend or had a girlfriend in Korea
and they would only see each other once
every three months or so and he says it
was cool you know they they wrote every
day and they use Skype and things were
going good but then she became
frustrated with the long-distance
relationship school started to pile up
on her and she she cut it off okay he
still loved her
but understood next thing he knows she's
got a boyfriend yeah while later she's
got a boyfriend that's in her class and
now he really doesn't know what to do
because he's like oh I've lost her
forever oh this has been my the love of
my life but now she's with another and
she lives way across the globe it was a
long-distance relationship that I was
willing to invest in but she left me to
be with someone in her class he doesn't
want to hang out with European girls he
says they're sluts
so anyway look man I've said this before
in other videos and I just want to
reiterate and maybe build on it just a
little bit but the experiences of love
is the end is the means and the end in
itself what I mean by that is that you
don't own someone you when you love them
and you can't grow addicted to the
circumstances surrounding the love for
another human being
you just have to appreciate the time
when you have it what I mean by the the
ends is the means right is that it the
ends is the means or the means is the
end means is the end the means is the
end I'm sorry what I means is the
process the time through which you are
in that love is the purpose of love not
for an end result okay so I'm talking in
circles here let me bring it back it's
the time that you experience the love
with her that is the purpose of the love
not so that you can be with her forever
not so that you can own her not so that
you can marry her not for any future
plans that you have for yourself and
definitely not for her because when you
start making plans for other people it
means that you're trying to own them be
appreciative see
the greatest danger to most people is
that they don't appreciate what they
have when they have it I'm not saying
this is for you I'm saying this is for
everyone else other people appreciate
what you have when you have it because
it's not meant to last nothing's meant
to last
nothing will out will be the way that it
always is it will always be the way it
is right now
so you relish in it see I have children
see a lot of parents go through this I
have children they're very young still
and I know that they're going to grow up
and they're going to leave they're going
to go out into the world they're going
to become their own person and I'm
already ready for that you have three
daughters they're going to find
boyfriend they're going to have sex
right they might do kinky things and my
daughter's to hear me talking about this
is strange but I know the way life works
they grow and they go and they have
their own experiences some of them might
hurt themselves some of them might have
great experiences that lead to success
that ultimately leads to bad experiences
they're gonna have their roller coaster
they're gonna have their journey of life
okay I don't own them I just experience
the time that I have with them and fully
be present while I have it do get a
girlfriend who's long-distance
relationship we were together for for
several months obviously maybe here be
grateful for that thank you thank you to
her just thank her just thank her thank
you for that time together how about
that right instead of getting all pissed
off and annoyed and and jealous now he
just send her a fucking thank-you card
thank you so much for the time that we
spent together it was a beautiful moment
in my life I wish you the best take care
dear san so you're doing a number of
things you're letting go of her for her
because you don't own her and you
letting go of her for yourself but
you're also cultivating gratitude you
know there's an amazing thing about
gratitude that when you're gracious for
a thing it comes full circle because
when you exhibit grata
when you experience gratitude when you
put your place put yourself in the place
of gratitude you open yourself up to
experiences that are similar to the
thing that you're granted grateful for
it works this way this is why when you
read books about affirmations they
always say be happy grateful for the
thing that you have yet to experience
like you already have it so for example
and I used to do affirmations a years
ago when I was flat broke I was very
thankful for the amount of money that I
was not making I would say something
like this I'm so happy and grateful now
that I earn $10,000 a month now at that
time I was earning like 2,000 dollars a
month but I'd say I'm so happy and
grateful now that I earn $10,000 month
I'm so happy and grateful guess what
happened I earned $10,000 a month and
more and more and more and more because
I always put myself in the place of
gratitude for the thing that's on its
way to me okay so now you put yourself
in the place of gratitude for the
experience that you had you're lining up
but also put yourself in the place of
gratitude for what is going to come now
your soul already knows the type of
woman that you like he mentions that uh
she's Asian so she's pure whatever
that's your that's your judgment that's
fine that's that's what the soul that's
what your experience is and the soul is
making happen through you no judgement
there but you like Asian chicks because
you think they're pure and the European
chicks are sluts ah cool that's the way
it is for you it's very subjective and
that's fine now put yourself in the
place of gratitude for receiving a pure
asian chick I'm so happy and grateful
now that I have a beautiful pure Asian
woman to spend my days with to
experience the moments in my life with
and do she's going to come there's no
question about it this has been the
story of my personal life and this is
why I say this shit not because I read
it in a fucking book or because I'm
trying to sell you something I say it
because this is what I did is how I get
have everything I
everything in my life is a byproduct of
the gratitude that I cultivated before
the thing came I say this and it's going
to sound like I'm arrogant or like I
think I have magic or something which I
I think I might think I have the keys to
some sort of magic here when I say I can
have anything I want as long as it's in
line with my soul's calling
I'm not infringing upon or being violent
towards other people and I cultivate
gratitude I will have the thing that I
want biggest thing for me now is
wondering what I what I want next okay
so that's it my man let her go let her
go not with resentment not with anger
not with jealousy let her go with
gratitude for the experience that she
shared with you and line yourself up
with the gratitude that is going to
bring you more experiences that will
enhance your life done