no matter who you are and what you do
for a living you are a leader to someone
in your life you may not have the stated
position of a leader but there are
people that look to you for guidance or
as an example for certain ways of being
in different categories of their life
now like I said you may not have been
given that title but I guarantee you if
you're a student if you're a parent if
you're an athlete if you are a artist if
you're you have coworkers it does not
matter if you are interacting in this
world if you're a part of this
civilization if you're dealing with
people on a regular basis you are a
leader whether you like it or not now
that that's clear there are those of us
who have accepted the responsibility of
leadership if you're a parent you've
accepted the responsibility of
leadership if you're in a managerial
role if you are on a sports team you
have accepted the responsibility of
leadership and when you're clear about
that there's a totally different set of
pressures that are set on you right
because now you're aware of the fact
that there are people that are looking
to you for guidance and support and
strength they lean on you they stand on
you and is up to you to be very strong
firm enough to it still withhold the
pressure of the either vast amount of
people or the depth of support you're
providing for people parents know this
teachers know this leaders in every
realm understand this but there comes a
time when every single leader doesn't
want his leadership there comes a time
when a leader says I don't want this
what did I create why do these people
lean on me how can I now continue to
support them even when I feel weak all
leaders go through this and the reason
why I know is because I study the
greatest people that have walked this
planet or that we have recorded history
that have walked this planet or we have
mythology about them one such myth or if
you will historic will figure depending
on your
position is Amanda called the Christ
Jesus now I'm not a religious man in the
traditional sense but I see the value in
the stories and the myths and the
theology and the religion that we've
been afforded and I look to it often for
advice and in a time when I'm feeling as
if leadership is weighing heavily on me
I look to the myth and the man who our
current civilization has been literally
an offspring of that of the things he
shared Western civilization is a
judeo-christian civilization and Jesus
is at the pinnacle of that myth now that
out the way even he who so many for so
many generations millions and there I
say billions of people have been
affected by over the past two thousand
years has even said take this shit away
from me I believe it's luke 22 42 you're
a scholar you'll probably correct me but
Jesus goes on to say he says to his
father to the universe to God whatever
is he like to call it take this cup away
from me take this away from me take this
responsibility away from me take this
burden away from me take everything that
you've laid on my shoulders and I've so
firmly carried up until this point away
from me the most pivotal figure in the
history of Western civilization has even
said take this shit away from me thy cup
remove it from my hands so to think that
you would feel weak in a position of
power or in a position of leadership and
that that's unique it's completely wrong
the fact is that not only has Christ
afforded us the permission to feel weak
in leadership but also gives us the
answer
to how to go about dealing with that
because in the very next line he says
but nevertheless let your will be done
within the very next line Jesus goes on
to say although I hate this and I want
you to take away from me I am yielding
to that which you are doing through me
God the universe there are so many
different ways to describe that an
animating energy that animating force in
the world works through every single one
of us whether we like it or not and we
have two options we either resist or we
yield to it but it's moving forward if
we resist we feel pain God is working
through you and your but you you don't
like it you're asking it for it to be
taken away God trying to move up through
you as if you are a flute that if
allowed if the wind is allowed to blow
smoothly through could play beautiful
music but right now you're putting your
hand on the end of the flute so that no
music can go through ok so what God is
indifferent if you can't handle this
shit he'll take his wind notice that
word wind air inspiration and give it
somewhere else because evolution is
going to happen God is going to do what
God has to do whether he can do it
through you or not now as a leader you
because we all are leaders how is it
that you are either getting in the way
of allowing leadership to happen or
using to an allowing leadership to
happen through you it's interesting
because we have psychological mental
constructs ego constructs about way
things wait the way things should look
leadership looks a particular way has on
a particular suit walks with a
particular manner has a particular hair
dress headdress big pointy hat or
whatever but that's not reality that
we've made that shit up the way God
works is the way God freaking works and
it always shows up weird that's why
Jesus was a weird motherfucker that they
had to kill well usually kill weird
dudes
especially weird used with big mouths so
part of the yielding is not holding so
strong to what you think it should look
like but letting go and allowing the
magnificence to happen through you and
appreciating what it ends up looking
like I never knew what the type of
leadership that I am providing for the
world would look like in fact there was
no YouTube when I decided to do what I
wanted to do I knew very early that I
wanted to inspire others because I'm
pretty good at it it's just kind of a
gift I know how to talk to people to get
them excited about the things that they
want to do in their lives about how they
can become a strongest version of
themselves get them to take action
towards that I am a leader but every day
I like you may be challenged with a
battle between the ego constructs and
that which God wants to have happen and
God never repeats himself it's always
going to be brand new and a lot of times
it looks like shit we don't like let go
and allow leadership to happen through
you everyone