and what's up guys we've got a question
today from our 20 year old friend who
recently broke up with his girlfriend
for a year and a half and uh and while
he was dating his girlfriend's he set
aside all of his childhood friends
because he was in love I mean it happens
time and again soul your boys they say
bros before hoes though right
take that one teach that one to your son
but so all your boys that you grow up
with kind of get set aside because you
found love you found pussy that's a big
part of it but what happens then is when
your a girlfriend who you loved they
can't give you pussy leaves you and you
go back to your boys and you're like hey
what's up guys how's going and they're
like peace out dawg peace man I mean we
don't we've been doing shit for the past
year and a half really no you anymore
you have no friends left and this is
where he finds himself and I choose to
answer this because I'm sure he's not
the only one
fuck what do I do now so circumstances
aside I'd like to teach you a principle
about how to get things particularly
from other people because what you want
now is friendship and the way you get
friendship is by being a good friend you
give away what you want to receive back
if you want power you empower if you
want abundance you give abundantly if
you want love you give love if you want
friends
you give your friendship and it all
sounds very simple so those you
understands the visit the metaphysics of
this those are you understand how the
world works right everything balances
itself out right everything balances
itself out and if you want more one
thing you put it on the scale so that
you can get that balance back it just
works
every single time I don't say this
because I read a fucking book I say this
because my life is a manifestation of
that when I want more of something I
give something when I was building my
business I needed money I needed some
help I needed support and clients
so you know what I did I volunteered as
a strength coat not a strength coach I
was a fucking babysitter of mentally
disabled children who needed some
exercise
I had nothing but I gave and then I
received do you say I give a lot of
empowerment through these videos that I
create I give a lot of inspiration and
motivation you know what my life is
filled with empowerment motivation and
inspiration because I give it give it
give it more I give it the more I get
you see it works this way so those who
are you know you're you're doing
mathematical equations about the shit
put down your pen for a moment try this
shit out here's when it doesn't work and
this is probably why I won't work for
most of you the first time but I'm going
to impart the speed of a piece of
information on you so that you can be
armed with a way out instead of setting
something aside saying it doesn't work
I'm going to give you something hey did
you remember this one it's not going to
look the way you think it should look
meaning you want friends but you've got
an idea of what friendship looks like
because you've had past experiences with
friends so when your mind's eye
friendship looks a particular way it's
all bullshit because what you're doing
is you're attaching to dead ideas shit
that doesn't exist look at you right now
those are ideas from the past you can't
carry your ideas and your conditioning
and your prejudices and your desires
into the future because you'll be too
burdened down by them to be free enough
to experience what's actually happening
so way that looks practically is if
you're going to give away your
friendship because you want friendship
look at the first person that pops up in
your environment isn't Lee you can look
these short fat knee plays video games
not like my other buddies who play
football and
and and or you know they're cooler or
something like that and they're tall or
good-looking the guys there you give
them friendship anyway because that's
what God has given you that's what you
call that stewardship you look around at
what you've got and you say well I'm
going to start taking care of what I've
got gratitude is the big part of this so
you extend some gratitude to the short
fat video game player you say you know
I'm happy that I have you in my life and
you extend your friendship to him and
guess what you might find there a really
good friend right back at you
or now here's the thing don't get
attached to that either because you
don't always receive back from where you
were you planned right so that's one of
these strange things that happen where
we think you know I'm doing something in
this direction so it should come back in
this direction sometimes it comes from
another direction but you've got to be
free you can't hold on to you hold on to
this direction because I I sowed in this
direction so shall I reap
yeah that's holding on it again like its
whole ego thing and the whole um the
idea that you're your past should
dictate your future in that it should
look the same you're you follow me you
might show friendship in this way and
then get knocked upside your head with
the best friend you could have ever
imagined it was a strangest fucking
thing because this is what happens it
comes out of he comes out of the sky
either really just like like you offer
friendship here and then a new guy gets
hired at your job you're like whoa best
friends for the rest of your life you've
got to be free you've got to be free
from any kind of constraints and you've
got to be free enough to give and free
enough to receive
okay be free in your giving so that you
can be free and you're receiving it all
goes both ways
done