so we got a question here I got a
question here from one of our viewers
about a long-distance relationship our
friend apparently has fallen in love
online and they've been dating for a
year long distance through the internet
it's an amazing time we live in four
months ago they actually met
face-to-face and were able to hug and
cuddle and smooch and kiss and commence
forth in physical love they finally got
together and the fire of their passion
grew because of the intense experience
of love not only emotional and mental
through the internet but finally
physical but our friend has a problem he
had to go home and in parting ways with
his love they promised to stay together
no matter what and she even promised to
leave her land thousands of miles away
to come and live with him she's going to
leave her family all her friends and her
native language to come to a place where
she has no family no friends and doesn't
even speak the language right our friend
who asked this question is concerned
because he wants to know if he has the
right to ask her to leave all that she
knows all that she has to come to a
foreign land for love where she doesn't
even speak the language
it's quite the pickle as they would say
so here's the thing man I'm really
excited for you because if you choose to
ask her to leave her family her friends
all that she knows to go to a foreign
land in love and passion in ecstasy
where she can't even speak the language
but she's doing it because her heart is
open to you it will be the best intense
experience you've had in your life your
entire short life you'll be so happy and
full of passion fire joy and ecstasy
your life will be great and if you
choose to make her leave her family
leave her friends come to a place where
she's a stranger can't speak the
language it's not so sure she's only
seen you once to live with you in
so-called love and passion and ecstasy
it could possibly turn out to be the
worst thing that she's ever done and the
worst thing that you've ever done
because now you've got this anchored you
got to take care of can't even speak to
damn language my point is that either
choice is going to be an intense
experience and that my friend is why I'm
so excited for you damn phone keeps
ringing
life is about intense experiences life
is about experiencing all the emotion
associated with joy ecstasy passion love
and frustration anger sadness right
that's what life is what happens is we
like to find this easy mediocre gray
lukewarm path to tread wear we never
experienced any failure any frustration
any anger we never experienced any love
I mean when I'm talking about love and
anger I'm talking about that far
extremes extreme experiences right
that's what love is that's what life is
about on this unstable planet on this
rock that's flying around in the sky
somewhere that's what it's about so
either choice is going to be an
incredible experience is going to add to
you whoever you are in your life is
going to add to your character if it's
great it's great fucking awesome great
experience intense experience if it's
bad it's bad that's awesome too because
it's an intense experiences can add to
your character the problem is most
people want science and religion they
want facts and they want beliefs they
want something they could lean on but a
good scientist will tell you that these
are just hypothesis so i can give you
facts and figures and statistics about
people who leave their country to come
somewhere where they don't speak the
language because they're in love i can
give you all the facts and figures so
that you can make a decision based on
that but it will lack the intense
experience or the trust in the intense
experience that you should enjoy as a
human being on earth in all its visceral
and passionate and fire expiry
experience I can also give you a belief
and give you religion science or
religion I can give you some religion
and give you a belief I give you
something that's based on no evidence
whatsoever but sounds poetic and
beautiful you could lean on that also
it's all based on someone else's
experience someone else's poetry someone
else's ideas so you
live from someone else's back someone
else's believe but you got to live for
you so my friend I hope you make the
right decision okay I hope you do what
you think is right because if you fail
successful people make their failures
right they say that successful people
don't always make the right decisions
but they make their decisions right so
either way it's going to be right and
it's going to add to your experience to
your character and make you a stronger
version of yourself so go fail as fast
as you fucking can hope that helps