hey what's up guys in today's article
that you could read down below I spoke
about my father's preferred method for
dealing with whiners and complainers in
the article I give his philosophy on how
problems are only problems if you say
they're problems and in today's video
I'm going to talk about three seeming
problems as well as a magic wand that
you could wave over them in order to
instantly dissolve any problems you
think you have but before we begin I'm
going to talk about three types of
problems that I often hear from my
friends family fans and people who send
me emails wanting some sort of
resolution to their issue the first type
of problem is purposeless discontent
this is essentially where everything is
just perfect everything is just fine
your life is just hunky fucking dory but
yet you have a problem with no purpose
behind it I'll tell you what I mean I
was speaking to a friend recently and
he's talking about his job and his job
happened to be a pretty goddamn good job
he was explaining all of the
opportunities available to him his good
pay so on and so forth
you know he really sang the praise of
his boss and all I mean it was a great
circumstance great situation but he
seemed to be discontent with the fact
that he was just too content so I asked
him you know what is it that you want to
do really because if you're finding
discontent in this seemingly prosperous
and wonderful place to be then there
must be something inside you that's
calling you to do something else what is
it can you share with me your true
purpose and so that we can resolve your
discontent and move you towards where
you'd like to be in life in an instant
he answered by saying I don't know so
your discontent with your circumstances
but yet when asked to share what you
would love where would you like to go
where would you proceed have you not had
this anchor holding you down and he had
no friggin clue no idea that is
purposeless discontent
you're discontent with a situation that
you have no reason to be discontented
about especially since you have no idea
what you would rather do instead people
do this often with girlfriends and
boyfriends meaning man she's a great
girlfriend man I love her a lot but
there might be more out there well what
do you want I don't know
well then you're just being
purposelessly discontented you can very
easily turn that around and choose
content for your situation you know what
my girlfriend is pretty perfect fuck I'm
just gonna leave it alone and be with
her why be discontented always thinking
that there might be something better out
there well my job is pretty damn good
Wilden be content with it rather than
purposeless discontent meaning there's
no reason for you to be discontented you
can't even give me a reason why you know
we live in a culture where content is
almost a bad word you should never be
content right this is what they tell us
you know content leads to mediocrity but
I think quite frankly that's
misunderstood misused and those who
inherently blurt it out really have no
idea about life mastery you can choose
to be discontent with your circumstances
but your energy and your the
responsibility will always be projected
outwards when you look around your life
recognize that your discontent with what
you see stems from a discontent with
self so if there's anything to ever be
discontent about with regard to your
situation its how you're looking at it
and how you've created it so yes there
should be discontent but not with your
circumstances no matter how poor you are
or how miserable you are or how much
your daddy yells at you or how much your
girlfriend cheats on you you should be
discontent with the version of yourself
that's showing up so the world gives you
that mirror so yes this content just
misplaced it should be discontent with
self otherwise you end up in situations
like our friend who has
purposeless discontent the other type of
problem are distraction problems and
these are problems that you choose to
adopt so that you don't look at the real
problem which usually is back itself
having a conversation with a friend
actually a client not too long ago and
he was explaining that he worked at a
gym and the owner of the gym had been a
great mentor to him for very long he
loves his job he loves his clients he
loves what he does there but some of the
clients particularly the female clients
who have been complaining about not
having purple t-shirts in the gym so the
owner decided well I just want to have
black t-shirts and but you know my
employee here is say that our female
clients want purple shirts and my friend
who is the was the trainer came to me
and said you know my boss doesn't listen
to me he's he's very arrogant and he's
in it he doesn't listen to what the
clients and myself want and and I don't
feel like I can move forward in my
career I don't feel like I could fully
express myself I don't feel like I could
become the strongest version of myself
under this tyranny I asked what's the
tyranny explain to me the purple shirt
story I said so you're being tyrannize
is that right word or terrorized by your
boss who's not listening to your clients
who want purple fucking shirts and so
you feel discontent in your situation
and you feel a lack of ability to grow
stronger in it you can't evolve I say
that what would you like as a trainer
what kind of training would you like and
what would be well worth your time to
build and he said I'd really love to
give workshops I really love to teach
seminars
I'd really like to lecture to the
clients at the gym so I explained to him
but the real problem is not the purple
fucking t-shirts that you're really
upset about and that you're whining and
complaining to me about nor is this
content that your clients have about
purple fucking shirts because they're
the establishment where they're being
trained by you and they're getting good
service the shirts will come your big
problem the problem that you're not
looking at is why aren't you assertive
enough to step to your boss to your
manager and say hey I would like to
teach some courses I'd like to develop
my own ideas and teach it to our clients
would that be something you're
interested in could I be a contribution
to the business by exercising my own
creativity in teaching some classes but
yet he was caught up on the purple shirt
debacle the distraction problem from the
real problem which is your lack of
assertiveness my friend and that's what
I tried to explain to him I'm them the
third type of problem you know and with
each problem there's a level of
descending consciousness or uh yeah
descending you know because problems
with content is everything's right so
you must be ok but you're still
searching for something else problems
that are distractions means you're not
even willing to look at yourself such
that you create mountains out of mole
hills the third level which is the
lowest level of consciousness comes from
people who are fucking addicted to
problems they find problems in
everything they're just problem seekers
and their problem averse and they will
never be content no matter what the
circumstances it's you know when they
done when I described levels of
consciousness you know the lowest level
of consciousness is not being aware that
you're not aware not knowing that you
don't know and these are these people
you know my dad was telling me the story
that I talked about my article my dad
was explaining to me an experience the
conversation he had with one of his
co-workers right they explained to me
that his coworker and come from a
previous shot my dad works on auto body
worker at a previous shop where he had
problems with the boss so he came to my
dad's shop where the manager there might
hear him out and hire him on so the
manager heard him out for several days
listening to his
worries about being treated unfairly at
the other shop and so he made a transfer
and asked the young man to come and
train to work at the place where my dad
is working under the new manager so
things should be well but within a few
weeks young man comes to my father who
is usually actively working on a car and
begins complaining about the new manager
my dad recognizes right away that this
is a problem seeker or a problem addict
and he says to him look guy you came
here because you have problems where you
were the manager here solves your
problems by bringing you here and now
you're finding problems with this
manager the problem is that you're
looking for problems and every time you
look for problems you'll find a problem
so don't come to me with your bullshit
problems and your addiction to looking
for negativity these are negative
addicts or they're addicted to
negativity see on the other hand you
have positivity addicts right what we
see the glass is half-full these are
people who are negativity eggs they look
at glasses as half-empty if I had to be
an ax dick addict to one of them which
one what would you think it might be
addiction to positive thinking or
negative thinking so it's about
reframing it's about your thinking right
and if you find yourself in any of the
three circumstances that I just
described you can wave the magic wand of
reframing the problem and solving it
instantly purposeless discontent is a
waste of your time look and be grateful
for what you have that's the very first
thing you do you look around and you say
there really is no problem except for
that which I'm creating very simple why
wave that magic wand over it and stop
the shit through what it is stop get on
the problems distraction problems
require that you wave the same magic
wand over it and say there really are no
problems I'm just distracting myself
with shit that doesn't really exist you
can very easily disregard the
Anker that you're carrying drop it so
that you can pick up more resourceful
activities right forget the purple
shirts teach some courses and then
finally problem attics it's a level of
consciousness and it's not as easy to
resolve but if everywhere you go there's
a problem then start thinking that it
might be you it's a hard pill to swallow
for a lot of people who have victim
mentality but if you find that you
cannot find content if everywhere you go
stinks then maybe you need to take a
fucking bath done