you when there's a prompting in our
hearts to put a particular direction
it's very it's easiest to find a
concrete goal I like lifting I like
fitness I liked athletes I like strength
conditioning booms of the condition
coach for the USA chips that's a
concrete image that's something that we
can attach to as we move in that
direction different paths are going to
give themselves to you can push the
different way you have different
experiences associated with either
taking you holy the opposite direction
or some work greater and it's usually
somewhere even better I'm telling you
that right now you're my experience
anybody like giving this advice to
several years later they always say no
I'm think I'm really happy there's this
great song it wasn't cuz your gut and
listening to a lot calling the guy Jesus
guy who is very straight he's like
there's a song I gotta remember
basically he's happy for all the she
wrote a song about like how happy is for
not getting a little shit that he wanted
because it turned out to be so much
better so it's okay have goals but don't
be personally identified with the goal
because now if you're personally
identified with that goal you're going
to build all the physical psychological
constructs associated with what that
should look like and you're going to
deny your heart along the way how many
men in particular my father's are men
attain their goal but lost their heart
kids don't respect of their wife cheats
on them and got all this money and the
thing that they wanted but they're
unhappy you don't want that to happen to
you that happens because we get too
attached to the end result aim in that
direction but now you're a unique person
is that unique experiences you have
unique strengths Tiffany desires there's
something different happening inside you
it's already there move in that
direction would be sensitive enough to
know that you might the universe might
take you somewhere else and it's going
to be better and I think that that will
be an idea that really might get because
that's really into your heart when I say
better it's going to be more an
expression your unique coaching this I
wanted me I told you that I told you
guys need someone I want to be a
personal training with your leftovers
carry around that clipboard I really
might think I'm dead serious that was my
highest aspiration was that have fucking
pool helping that lady not every time I
just want that I aim the direction I got
what I wanted what I realized that there
was more it's almost like that it's
almost like this progressive revelation
you get to the top of the mountain top
and you get to the top of Elton utilize
the hill and then you go to the top of
the next one that you're like there's a
range of mountains go to the top of the
other one and you can see for the PRT
you move progressively I wanted to be a
struggling conditioning coach for in
Division one devil a football team hi so
actually I have division 1 let's try the
conditioning coach coaches coaches come
me and Lee how I do what you're doing I
when I get out of it so bad hours suck
the pay sucks look at you you hang out
on the internet doctor people eat and
superglue is it busy so you just got to
be sensitive to reach for goal but
allowed what's going to happen to happen
is that helpful yeah go gay or cses do
go to the internship Go Go but don't be
so attached to the end result go where
it's taking you like the river carrier
battle
I've been reading bastard it says like
build your own internship and things
like that and I was just saying freaking
out doing different styles like straight
condition that's what I've been just
bring out there like this is so much
stuff in this one little category the
expected to produce this result for this
one little category and they can do it
so many days yeah try them all out do
you want to pick one that is real good
too I feel like even though i misreading
edition coach I do my best talking you
guys like you giving you insight as to
how does that be a good life I think
this is like I like this more than
lifting like it easy ideas watching you
can rest of your life so I've gone from
clipboard holder to I couldn't I
couldn't imagine this first of all it
was doing YouTube right no able to do
with their life I couldn't do it not
prescriptive that good not Egyptian it's
going to be just as magical for you