okay we got this question my buddy Troy
he's been working out for a while he's
been getting decent results not exactly
what he wants but he sacrifices a lot
puts a lot of time and energy into his
fitness and to working out he works out
hard so on and so forth the thing is
that he knows that he is giving up with
a lot of boys his age men his age young
men of 19 engaging which is hanging out
with women
partying sex drugs rock and roll if you
will and not that he really wants to do
those things he says you know that's not
really even that interesting to me you
know I'm curious about it so once in a
while I'll go out no experience it but
then I come back and I'm like I really I
wish I didn't do that but he then takes
that energy and puts it back into his
gym gym training his results are okay
and now he's starting to wonder he's
really asking himself he's like well I
look back on my when I'm old well I look
back and be regretful for taking my time
that could have been allocated towards
experiencing life with us what they call
it right you know you're a kid have fun
taking that and putting it towards a
seemingly fruitless activity weight
training that he's like I don't really
get that great results it's okay no he
says he ends up skipping his workout he
half-ass it wonders if I've ever
experienced anything like that what's it
want some feedback so it's a legitimate
thing yes in fact there are certain
things in my life that when I was young
I engaged in that that that forced me to
disengage with other things that people
say is you know selling your oats I
married my high school girlfriend right
so I've been with one woman
yeah I'm an okay looking guy and there
there are times and circumstances where
there were you know say this one was in
high school college plenty of girls that
were wanted to be with me I could have
had a harem lots of lots of pretty girls
that wanted to hang out with me and I
gave that up because of what called my
heart what was a deeper
experience that I had with one girl and
I loved it so much and I said I love her
so much still ha I like when I'm with
her I it's just we blend together
physically emotionally and
physiologically you know there's such a
great experience listen of course this
is weird Ellie's talking about how much
he loves his wife and the experience he
has with his wife was fuckin have to do
with you I gave up one thing not judging
just tell me what I did
gave it one thing that you're supposed
to do when you're young and invested in
something else I'm happy because it's a
wonderful experience it feeds me my
experience with my life what you need to
find is something that feeds you so much
that you they you love to such a degree
that you don't even think about the shit
that you're missing out on all those
things you describe that you think
you're missing out on are people looking
for something to love something to throw
themselves into fully mind body and soul
that's really what we all want we want
love when I say love I don't necessarily
mean the union between two individuals I
mean
passion about something in life okay for
some reason you know if you've been
watching my videos perhaps that's why
but you know the world tells you also in
its many different ways than investing
in fitness muscle building fat loss is a
worthy journey it's one that you should
invest in but if you're sacrificing
these things over here which really
you're not sacrificing much in order to
engage in something because you've been
told that you should it's a good idea by
someone else then you're giving one
thing up to really get it a cheap return
on your investment what you need my
friend
is something to love you need a passion
you need something that draws your heart
in and makes love to it in the same way
that my wife's or at the time my
girlfriend's did to me
so when you give this up you're really
not giving up anything what you're doing
is you're saying yes to something bigger
I never really said no to any of those
girls I really was saying yes to Colleen
my woman with your friends you're not
the kids that go out and drink you're
not saying no to them you're saying yes
to your jazz music you're saying yes to
your architectural designs you're saying
yes to your poetry you're saying yes to
whatever it is you want to love Elliott
how do we find the thing that we love
that's a topic for another video but
it's there and I encourage you to grow
sensitive to it done