hey what's up guys today's blog post
that you could read down below features
our Facebook fan friend Keith Edwards
here you'll see a picture of him a
before and after picture I found this
picture on my Facebook fan page wall
where he shared it with me letting us
know about his tremendous success in
Fitness over the past several months or
year obviously a transformation that's
worth noting if you notice in the very
first picture he looks like one type of
guy but in the second picture it is
almost unrecognizable you know it almost
looks like two totally different people
I'm not just talking about the weight
loss but I'm also referring to the the
glow the look on his face his skin even
looks different
of course he's smiling in the second one
but you can even see the smile in his
eyes I'm but what we were seeing is
literally a entire personal
transformation and that's just my
judgment based on the picture obviously
but pictures are worth a thousand words
and for good reason not much needs to be
said if you look at picture a and
pictured B you realize this man has done
tremendous work on himself and is
obviously a stronger version of himself
so it got me thinking and the question
posed today and what I sort of described
and talked about in the blog post down
below revolves around how you look and
what it says about your character now of
course people are going to judge us
regardless people are always judging us
they're judging us on our physical
appearance they're judging us on how
they feel about us based on physical
appearance now so a lot of the times the
way someone feels about you about the
way you look is very much theirs so we
can't be completely tangled up in the
way someone perceives us because we all
have on our own glasses that we see the
world what's beautiful to one person is
ugly to another so we can never really
base our self-esteem our own personal so
judgment on other people's judgment of
us but what we can do is change the way
that we feel about ourselves about the
way we look when we look in the mirror
and what really gets transferred far
more than the visual depiction of a
person is feelings feelings is really
how we communicate it I've once said
that I once quoted a thousand times
quoted Ralph Waldo Emerson in one way he
says in one phrase he says what you are
speak so loud that I can't hear a word
you're saying well in the same way the
way you feel about yourself the way you
carry yourself what you think about
yourself exudes it spills forth it
radiates from you far more than what you
say or even what clothing you're wearing
I've met people who are severely
overweight but they exude confidence and
joy and pleasure about life and they're
pleasurable to be around so they're nice
people to hang out with then there's
also obviously other people who would
physically take on the the imagery of
what the world calls beautiful but in
their presence you just feel a little
icky and disconnected so when I refer to
how you look I'm referring to looks as
an extension of how you feel and you
know that this is true you know that you
are going to look how you feel and of
course how you feel is reflected in the
responses of other people how you feel
about yourself is often reflected in the
responses of other people not 100% like
I said everybody has on their own
goggles and filters generally speaking
and there are ways that we can adjust
that adjust how we feel one of the
things I think about with recurrent with
regard to the way we look and feel is
when I was a kid I used to put on a cape
I remember putting on a cape that I got
I think I got it at the circus
went to the circus they they're giving
out capes and I bought a sword along
Barnum & Bailey sword and I remember
putting on this costume and I remember
holding this sword I remember grabbing
my sword and rolling down on the ground
jumping off the stairs attacking my dog
not really but you know playing with him
with my sword and then put it in my back
walking around the house of course I'm
about six years old but I'm feeling like
a freakin hero I'm feeling like Superman
I'm feeling like a warrior and I'm
behaving that way now when we're
children and don't see us doing that
stuff they either entertained us like I
do with my kids and when Benjamin is
acting like a little warrior I play
along with him or we laugh and giggle
and say Oh kids they're just pretending
but then we grow up and we wear clothing
we take on a physical form based on the
activities and the diet that we engage
in and then we look in the mirror and we
personally judge who shows up in that
mirror and it has a tremendous impact on
how we feel about ourselves wearing a
cape and carrying a sword makes you feel
like a freakin Superman being overweight
having bags under your eyes having
yellow teeth bad breath and whatever it
is that as a result of you not taking
good care of yourself or not really
having a self-esteem it is congruent
with self growth and taking care and
self-love shows up in the mirror is
expressed by your feelings about
yourself and like a virus is spread to
other people we are not separate our
feelings about ourselves the way we look
although we can say oh you know it
doesn't matter what anybody else says or
does is intrinsically linked we're
energetically psychologically
physiologically linked to other people
we cannot separate other people's
experiences from of us from the way we
experience the world if you study
interpersonal neurobiology
ology which is a branch of attachment
theory psychology you learn that
children learn to develop their sense of
self-worth and their feelings about
safety security or threatened fear in
the world based on the look on their
mother's face if the child comes into
the world unable to judge unable to
speak unable to understand words or
imagery or forms right kids aren't
judging you by your clothing
kids aren't judging you by how much you
weigh chill when I say kid I mean infant
infants immediately mirror and absorb
the look on their mother's face is it a
look of distress you know is it is there
famine and wars is there turmoil in the
family it shows up on your face the
woman's face is presented to the child
and absorbed by the child the child
takes all the feelings of this stress or
is it a wide open exciting happy joyful
loving face and does the baby receive
that on a regular basis or just a
worried fearful low self-esteem low
confident unstable look on the mother's
face and how does that affect the
psychology in the physiology of the
child so of course you know today I'm
talking in circles and you know not
really making any statements here in
fact I'm kind of hoping this opening
this up to conversation it has been my
experience my personal experience even
as an adult you see this look I've been
wearing earrings lately I understand the
way I look the way I dress the way I
present myself is going to have a
tremendous impact on how I feel about
myself which ultimately determines how I
project myself and the world is my
mirror so if I'm being ugly and when I
get ugly if I feel ugly I'm gonna get
ugly you see so I'm constantly aware of
how I feel about myself and how I'm
carrying myself everything from
your posture to the clothing you wear
said something about the way you feel
about yourself and gives other permit
the other people permission to judge you
accordingly I'd love to hear what you
have to say talk to you tomorrow