so got a question here from our buddy
Todd Prince he's a swimmer a really good
one he says that he's he's nationally
ranked and he's on his way to the
Olympics potentially and he's in high
school 17 years old and he's got a great
coach and it's because his coach is so
damn awesome that he's been able to
progress this far in his particular
sport and potentially be one of the best
in the world the problem is that his
coach is about to move to a better
position for him a better school better
environment for his craft for his career
which is a hundred miles away he's
inviting our friend Todd to to follow
him the problem is Todd would have to
leave behind his family his friends his
girlfriend everything that he knows and
it will also be a strain on his family
financially he's wanting to know whether
or not he should stay at home with the
comfort and the familiarity of the
environment from which he grew and he
owes great gratitude towards or take the
call to adventure into the unknown and
risk everything for what's merely a
dream I think you know what I'm gonna
say
and I'm not going to say it because of
what could potentially happen to you if
you choose the Jews following your dream
or you choose staying at home right see
the thing is most of us are focused on
like what the result is going to be like
protect perhaps you could be an Olympic
gold medalist that's not really why I
want you to go I mean that would be a
cool thing the real reason why you've
got to go is because this is that call
to adventure that every boy faces
between the ages of 17 and 23 I keep
saying that you're fucking 17 that not
only end up in the attainment of some
particular goal because we never even
know what the goal will ultimately be at
the end of it we think it's one thing a
lot of times it changes but because of
who you become when you take that
journey because now you're embarking
upon a journey that's going to require
the development of a lot of your
character traits you're going to have to
become a new person you're going to face
a lot of challenges there's that the
reason why they call it the call to
adventure is because you're going on a
fucking adventure you're going out into
the wilderness I mean these are ancient
stories of going into the desert for 40
days or or Buddha going into the into
the into the jungle or the forest and
meeting the sticky monster or even when
when the knights of the round table
write King Arthur on his guys they all
went into the forest but they all went
in to the same forest from different
directions it's this call to adventure
you've got to go out and got to do it
two things are gonna happen if you don't
do it
number one you're going to stay at home
but you're always going to be resentful
dude your and it's not going to be
anybody's fault it's just that's the
biological process it's the energetic
process if you don't take that call to
adventure you're going to feel bad in
yourself and guilty and you're also
going to look around at the people that
you stayed for and you're all you're
gonna pick fights with them
your parents your friends fuck you know
that could have been me and Here I am
with you I mean it's not gonna be their
fault really it's your fault but you're
gonna get resentful towards your friends
and what about your friends here's the
thing to do you don't owe anything to
anyone but yourself and I don't say that
in a selfish way I just say it and this
is the reality of life your friends will
have their own call to adventure ah this
could be real fucked up and when they
take their call to adventure and leave
you you're gonna say oh I gave up
becoming a gold medalist so you can go
to the army or some other shit whatever
their call to adventure is your
girlfriend same thing she's gonna have
calls to adventure too and your parents
totally different dynamic but same thing
you're gonna grow resentful they're
willing to take out a loan like you said
that's great you have good parents
they're willing to do that it's gonna be
a struggle for you and them but that's a
part of their journey that struggle is a
part of their journey they've got to
grow in that way - they can't be coddled
you can't coddle your parents by saying
look don't take out the loan they've got
to grow - and it's part of their growth
as those challenges as parents our
journey is a bit different in that way
how much can we bend to send as a bow
bow and arrow how much can we Bend and
handle a tension so that we can let the
arrow of our children into the future of
the world they're going to bend right
now it's going to support everybody
the other thing is going to happen if
you don't go besides all that guilt and
resentment is you're never going to
develop the character associated with
taking the call to adventure now it's
not to say that it won't be your last
call to adventure but you'll always look
back at the first one and guess what you
want to take the earliest call to
adventure that you get and I'm saying
this all you guys that are young when
that call to adventure comes take it
right away because you're going to be
resentful you're going to get other
opportunities trust me but they're not
going to be like the first one you'll
always have an opportunity to grow
stronger that never dies it never ends
you'll be a grandpa and you'll have an
opportunity to grow stronger by taking a
new adventure there are different
adventures each one of them but that
very first one is the one you'll keep
talking about I talked about my very
early adventures often and I use those
stories of my early adventures to gain
your respect to gain your influence
because you know that I'm I don't just
talk shit I actually do these things I
took these calls to adventure and I'm
here today talk to you about it that's
the thing if you follow your heart
because that's where the call to
adventure comes from comes from your
heart comes from your body you'll be
okay
not only will you be ok which will be 10
times better than okay because you will
have grown in character because of it so
my friend very rarely do I make a video
where I tell you exactly what to do and
of course do what you want to do but I
say take that call go done