fascinating question here from our buddy
Peter his highest calling in life he's
decided is to join the military he feels
his deep calling towards military
service he lives in Australia and that
is what he wants to do he's made up his
mind the problem now is that he's madly
in love with a woman he has a girlfriend
they're deeply in love he wants to be
with her he wants to share loving
experiences with her and continue to
snuggle and cuddle and kiss and stuff we
can't do that when you go into the
military because now you know you're
you're geographically separated of
course and you're up to something else
you know it's very difficult to do the
same at the same you know both the same
time so uh he's he's caught between a
rock and a hard place do I follow my
deepest purpose in life excuse me which
is to join the military or do I hang out
this is my woman right I mean they're
always get in our frickin way I'll
answer it back orders he follows his
inclination towards loving feelings
towards his woman right definitely one
of the toughest questions one of the
most difficult things to deal with and
I've been there but instead of me giving
you some insight based on my experience
because that's what I always do I decide
that I'll read a book for me a passage
from a part of this book right published
author far more respectable than a
fucking YouTube ranter right like myself
I'm sure you guys will argue with that
but anyway David deed is an excellent
resource every all of you should be
reading this book the way the superior
man but anyway there's a there's a part
in this chat there's a chapter in this
book and II call she doesn't really want
to be number one David deed is an
interesting dude he studied the very
ancient tantric tradition traditions of
sexuality and those ideas are so old
that they strike to the root of what it
is to be male and female without all the
political associations you know whether
or not your ideas are politically
correct didn't matter it ten five
thousand years ago or however long ago
the
those tacks were written so he's easy an
expert in those ancient traditions and
if you want to get to the root of male
and female energy sexuality then those
are the books you're gonna want to read
or you just study a guy like David Eater
who's an expert in it anyway just gonna
read this quick paragraph and send you
on your way bro because the answer is
simple when that definitely definitely
itz so here we go a woman sometimes
seems to want to be the most important
thing in her man's life
however if she is the most important
thing then she feels her man has made
her the number-one priority and is not
fully dedicated or directed to divine
growth in service she will feel her
man's dependence on her for happiness
and this will make her feel smothered by
his neediness and clinging a woman
really wants her man to be totally
dedicated to his highest purpose and
also to love her fully although she
would never admit it she wants to feel
that her man would be willing to
sacrifice their relationship for the
sake of his highest purposed Wow
most people especially women would argue
with that one but feelings are very
different different than than ideas and
the idea would be no absolutely not I
don't want you to sacrifice our
relationship you know I've been married
for many years and my wife understands
that that's why I you know she gets the
mute when I'm busy fulfilling my highest
purpose now of course that's not me
leaving but she's of the understanding
that my highest purpose is the reason
why everything works the way it works
and because she's allowed that in me
because she sees my dedication towards
it this whole fucking thing works you've
got to go ahead and fulfill your highest
purpose not only will that satisfy the
the desire in you but she will love you
more
better yet she will respect you more if
you lead your life in that particular
way do what you have to do bro
and she will be there if she's not then
she wasn't really yours to begin with