so this weekend I will be babysitting my
wife hates when I say that but watching
all four of my children my youngest
Benjamin he'll be two next month and
Isabel's my oldest seven so you could
imagine I've got my hands full for the
next couple days anyway Ben and I are
outside we're playing and he's got this
new phrase that he uses he goes under
under he whines and points at things and
says uh not uh not basically saying I
want that now this is interesting
because he has just made a gigantic
evolutionary jump in his uh in his
development in a psychological
development because prior to this point
there was no that right this is the way
human beings evolved prior to his
understanding of recognizing which is a
better way of describing it the concept
of duality everything was one to him the
where he how he was fed where he came
from and all the things have been in his
environment had a oneness to it right
but now he's experimenting with and and
using the tool of duality and in that
there is a separation between him and
the external environment which creates
tension right because there's a wanting
now there's me there's that and then
there's separation between me and that
and now I have wanting which creates
anxiety that's why he whines when he
says I'm not undines right so this is a
very critical junction for us as parents
because if we don't continue to allow
him to feel rooted in his in his in his
body essentially him getting all of his
needs met he's going to remove or
displace the frame of reference from his
body from himself and place it on the
external so there's going to be a from
having all my needs met ie my mom is
still nursing me i'm still getting love
and that's really the essence of it it's
it's the nursing that his mother's still
providing him with because he's still
getting psychological
and nutritional nourishing from his
route from from the ground essentially
from which he sprung from right and if
we sever that tie too early there's
going to be there's going to be a
displacement from his understanding that
needs shall be met and should be met to
I want that to external frame of
reference I need I i want i want that
it's no longer me getting my needs met
it's i need to to fulfill this anxiety
by placing my interest and my energy on
obtaining that which is separate from me
and then that lands you into a place
where most of us are most of us are in
that place where we are constantly
looking to fulfill this perceived need
bye-bye really trying by really just
going about going after our wants right
because needs weren't met right for the
majority of us with living in Western
civilization needs weren't met when we
were when we r inference you know within
a society in the time in a place where
children weren't breastfed to any great
degree probably the past three
generations or so you know pet mothers
started going to work so needs weren't
met for young children and they still
aren't to any great degree but I feel
there's an evolution going on so where
most of us are is we place all of our
value we place all of our energy on the
on the obtaining of things I'm not I'm
not want that I want that I want that so
invitation for you here today is to
parents mothers in particular commit to
breast feeding your children so that
their psychological not just their
physical needs are met and don't sever
that tie i invite you to to commit
before you have children that way you're
really grounded in that idea that i'm
going to fulfill all of my child's
psychological about you I'm sorry
psychological not just nutritional needs
right
and fathers husbands support your woman
support your wife the mother of your
children in a world that's constantly
I'm not I'm not I'm not focused while
everybody's running around none of their
meat needs met everyone's malnourished
everyone sick sad depressed and tired
but yet they drive fancy cars Elliott
said what