gentlemen today we have a question for
one of our buddies who recently read the
book Siddhartha and describes how a
young prince was confined in the castle
and his parents his father in particular
didn't want to allow him to do his thing
but at some point he breaks free he goes
out I think it's a story of Buddha he
goes out and he has trouble trials but
ultimately reaches enlightenment he said
that book really empowered me it really
gave me a lot of things to think about
because I'm currently in a very similar
situation where my father is a very
successful man and I grew up in a very
comfortable home and my father has
decided a path for me a guaranteed path
of success but I just have this aching
to go into adventure I gotta go do
something else now I want to maintain my
father's respect I love him I would like
to make him happy and do what he's laid
out for me but this calling I feel as if
I don't follow it if I don't go down
that road of what could potentially be a
danger adventure that I'm going to be
resentful and that's never a good place
because whenever you have the seeds of
resentment in your heart although you
putting on a face of gratitude you're
going to be carrying a sword behind your
back you know whenever you're doing what
someone else has told you to do even if
you smile I don't care if it's your boss
on campus your dad I don't care for wife
when you resent the thing they've made
you do and you ultimately resent them
the whole dynamics fucked up because
you're smiling in their face to make
them happy and you've got a sword behind
your back and you're eating on the
inside so let's play that one out will
you you follow your dad's well-trodden
path and guess what your there's
probably a 90% guarantee that you're
going to be successful meaning your dad
has made a comfortable way for you
you're gonna have all the things you
want the trappings of the world right I
can call it
to the world we'll have all the
trappings of success but at the same
time a part of your heart will be dimmed
and dying
you'll always be wondering what if what
if what if or you'll be saying to
yourself when can i when can i when can
i because if you're anything like me you
always hold on to some sort of hope like
at some point like this motherfuckers
gonna die leave me all this money and
then I could do everything I want or one
day I'm gonna build the balls and tell
him daddy I'm leaving I'm gonna do my
own thing one day one day one day one
day fuck one day one day never comes
you make one day today you understand
that one write that one down
some day is today it's the day you
decide it is then you have a sword
behind your back so even though you're
smiling you're right it began look at my
posture here I got one hand behind my
back even though you're smiling a part
of you is being dishonest so not only
are you destroying your own sense of
being but you're really also being
violent towards the other person because
you're not being fully present and
honest with them and that never works
that never never never never never works
daddy I always wanted to make you happy
but I always had this fucking sword
behind my back because I can't fucking
stand the choices you've made me make it
doesn't work out so all you want to want
to comment on Elliots how crazy Elliot's
invitations going to be well then you
choose that one choose that one but I
guarantee you you can't win you're not
gonna win if you follow your dad
I often say this take this one to the
bank - this is one of those is write
down it's an old saying you're damned if
you do and you're damned if you don't
meaning you're not going to win over
there with your dad and you ain't gonna
win over here either what happens if you
decide to take that call to adventure
and go do your thing
chances are very early on you're going
to hurt yourself you're going to scrape
your knee you're going to be hungry
you're gonna get in trouble you're gonna
have dare I say challenges and
discomfort in your life and daddy here's
the thing with our parents and I'm a
parent too so I've got to be mindful of
this your parents want the best for you
and often times when you love someone
you don't want to see them in pain you
don't want to see them challenged you
don't want to see them hurt you don't
want to see them fail you want good
things for your children so you don't
allow them to take the call to adventure
to the untrodden path where you're gonna
have to take a machete and create your
own path and you might cut yourself and
a snake might bite you you're going out
into the jungle but you got to clear
your own path now like I said you're not
going to feel a winner like a winner out
there many ways I created my own path I
carved my own path right like Frank
Sinatra I did it my way I carved my own
path a boy were there lonely days boy
were there days where I wish someone
understood what I was trying to do and I
could share my successes with I had so
many minor successes that went
uncelebrated because I had no one not
even my wife god bless her she's my best
partner teammate lover friend and there
was a time when we were estranged
because I couldn't even explain what I
was trying to do and it was so over her
head not meaning she couldn't understand
but because it was an uncharted
territory
I have no perspective she had no
perspective my
parents had no perspective there was
very little perspective for the
adventure I decided to go down and it
hurt over here and and I used often used
to look at my friends who ended up in
sales and ended up working in the
corporate world when they had a success
you know what happened they got a plaque
or they got a raise they got a pat on
the back at least you take that it call
to adventure you ain't getting shit but
no you know yet you will get shit that's
what you'll get you'll just get shit you
let shit in your shoes you cut yourself
hurt yourself but and there's no
guarantee and that's the other thing I
don't ever ever ever want you to believe
that there's some sort of guarantee for
carving your own path that's bullshit
the only guarantee is that you're going
to carve your own path there's no
guarantee for a pot of gold on the other
end you want to guarantee for a pot of
gold go work with your daddy and get
that bad pension plan and that health
insurance
go get that guaranteed shit and all that
comes with it including the part of your
heart that dies right if you want
guarantee this it hurts
and there's no guarantee only guarantee
is this and it might be a guarantee
worth gambling for it's not even a
gamble this is the gamble which one
once you go your gambling days are done
you already have this this is your
success for choosing your own path you
will own let me start that one again the
flag on my face couldn't be too dramatic
the fly in my face what the hell's going
on here the only guarantee is that you
will own yourself you are the master of
your domain you will answer to yourself
you can only celebrate with yourself but
you only answer to yourself to me it's
worth the gamble
freedom relative freedom the idea of
freedom the story I tell myself about
freedom because when I cut those checks
to Obama I'm not that fucking free but
the relative freedom in the story of
freedom the sense of freedom the ability
to make choices about when you get up in
the morning and when you do what you
want to do and so on and so forth how
you do your work I don't anybody tell me
how to do my work I want ideas from
people who've been there
I don't anybody tell me how to do what I
what I want to do no tell me what to do
of course that's part of my neurosis I
know what yours is
and to me living in that particular way
is so free and so creative and so
empowering that I would gladly give up
the well-trodden guaranteed path of
worldly trappings
but you're damned if you do damned if
you don't
done