so just a few minutes ago I posted a
picture of my facebook wall that is from
a book that I'm reading and in the book
there is a description of the law of
polarity and I describe how I've used
this idea to navigate my life in in many
instances but briefly the law of
polarity states that inherent in every
extreme is its polar opposite so we as
human beings we'd like to separate
opposites into good and bad but
essentially in the same way that you
cannot have day without night you can't
have good without evil they're one in
the same the difference is in degrees
right so up and down they're polar
opposites but the differences in degrees
depends on where you're standing right
it all depends so one of the questions
that came in was Elliot how do you
actually use this idea of polarity in
the choices that you make in your life
I'm going to use a really good example
because I spoke to you earlier this week
about the necessity for action so
earlier this week I made a video where I
talked about if you find that the waters
of change in your life are stagnant
things are not the way you'd like them
to be but they're very comfortable you
will get very stuck in this place of
resistance against action and that means
you've got to take action oftentimes
very uncomfortable action so the
metaphor that I used was jumping off the
bridge or jumping off a cliff and
learning how to fly in the way down this
is needed in order for you to continue
advancing in your life now the exact
opposite of that is true and in my life
and I'm experiencing something of a
degree whereby I need non action and not
action doesn't necessarily mean that you
sit by and wait for things to happen not
action is a form of allowing which
basically means if things are going
really crazy in your life you know I
also use the metaphor of a tornado
things are spinning around so for
example in my life you know you've got
four children I've got I have to move
now we were in a situation where I've
got a
my family my business is evolving at a
rapid rapid rate and things are going
crazy I am sensitive enough to recognize
that this is an opportunity for non
action because if I are were to proceed
forward in the trying to make things
happen meanwhile things are going crazy
I could screw up the processes instead I
have to allow or proceed in non action
in order to be the most resourceful
place for life to evolve for my life to
move forward if I interfere I know
there's only out of experience but also
out of studying if I interfere I can
screw up the whole thing so there you
have the two complete opposites there
you have polar opposites action and
allowing or non-action both of which you
have to look at and say yes it's good
it's necessary there are tools that you
need to use but you've got to be
sensitive enough to know when to use
what tool instead of saying it's all
about action and if you don't take
action you're kind of lazy or saying
that uh you know being in a place where
it's all about non action and you
actually are lazy when action time comes
um you fumble so that's it you got to
recognize that inherent in every extreme
is a say I is it cos it's complete
opposite and you've got to be sensitive
enough to know when the appropriate
action or non-action needs to be taken