hey whats up guys will late with my
video today my blog post from today is
down below sent that out already off to
a late start cuz I just got back from
orlando yesterday I spent the day in
orlando at an event that was put on by
one of my buddies kyle ash and roeder
kyle the 27 year old dude I think he's
27 or maybe even younger young guy who
started a company called startup Bros
where you teach he his buddy teach
people how to start up their companies
by selling products on Amazon mainly so
anyway it's entrepreneurship and it's is
how to teach people how to go from
having a job to building their own
business selling products that they
personally use or enjoy themselves
anyway he put on this great event at the
ritz-carlton in Orlando and he had the
headline speaker as Daymond John which
if you guys are familiar with Daymond
John you're probably known from shark
tank this is like the TV show where
entrepreneurs come and pitch their
product to a panel of investors and
Damons the black guy he's the only
brother on the set but uh but he's also
the founder of fubu clothing corporation
from way back in the day I remember
being in ninth grade rocking some FUBU
sneakers in FUBU Jersey anyway he was
the keynote speaker was great I spoke I
gave a short presentation and also spoke
with a panel so anyway I spent the night
there drove back this morning broke my
blog post an email just now and
uploading this video for you guys want
to talk to you little bit about what I
discussed in my email down below with
regards to creativity it was fascinating
to being a in a room in an environment
with other people who choose to live
their lives creatively meaning that they
got an idea that there's something
that's coming up in them through their
heart or their passion and they want to
share it with people in in
entrepreneurial venture this is what
Daymond John spoke about at it during
his keynote and about how much criticism
and how much defeat he had to go through
all the challenges all the struggles all
of the self-doubt that comes with trying
to make something out
nothing especially when it comes to an
entrepreneurial venture you know trying
to create a product that you want to
sell you wanted to create clothing for
the hip hop community and I again I
remember I grew up with hip hop in the
90s and his clothing was all the rage
back then I used to watch the LL Cool J
commercial he give he gave FUBU a shout
out in a gap commercial was you know it
was a big controversy and whatnot so
it's pretty cool it to hear him speak of
his story and to meet other people and
hear their stories of taking what they
love and turning it into a piece of art
creativity and I got me thinking about
my buddy Frank yang those of you guys
who watch my videos might be familiar
with Frank Yankees also another Fitness
YouTube creator but Frank is on some
other level Frank crates videos like
this one here that he did for me a few
years a few months back featuring myself
and being at the gym and just a couple
of the cool things you'll notice but
anyway the fact is that Frank is a
badass creator bodybuilder and will be
at the strength can't challenge 2015
coming up in November so those of you
who are going to be here you'll get a
chance to meet one of the 10 who've
already confirmed i'll talk a little bit
about that i'll be creating a video
about each of the 10 confirmed youtube
celebs what else that I want to talk
about today I wanted to put it out there
for you guys to get some feedback about
you and your own creativity and times
when you've allowed other people to
squash your creativity not allow you now
give you the space or the encouragement
or literally just shut you down when you
wanted to create something that uh that
was unique or brand new or never done
before alright I think about when I
first moved down to Florida and I worked
at a fitness gym in when these big box
gyms it's now LA Fitness it used to be
called lifestyle family fitness and man
I was a budding entrepreneur you know I
was one of those trainers they're like
I'm gonna do whatever I have to do to
more clients that's why I had the most
clients and that's why I decided to
leave him mr. mile and Jim but while I
was there one of the things that kind of
made me feel uh I'm sehun appreciated
but kind of like put me down a little
bit like hey stay in your spot soldier
stay in your lane little man was when I
create I started creating my own
pamphlets and my own flyers at the gym
of course they're giving me leads right
but I was ambitious and I was like well
you guys are giving me leads but I'm
gonna go get more I'm bringing them
business by creating the pamphlets and
then the the flyer since I just wanted
them everywhere cuz I wanted everyone to
get an opportunity to and I want an
opportunity to show my showcase my
training skills and get more clients and
I remember I made a dope-ass fire at
least I thought it was dope and I put it
up in the gym I put it up all right
around the gym you know the neighborhood
and stuff and on my off hours when I was
in training people I hand him out and
stuff when I say come and try out a free
workout with me and it was quickly
squashed by the CEO of the company the
manager got worked up got word of my
ambitions and and shared it with the
corporate structure and they're like no
this little motherfucker needs to calm
down so that was one of the things that
kind of like made me feel as if well you
know what I'm not gonna work for anybody
else that's what that's really when I
got into entrepreneurship I would have
probably worked for it I could have
definitely worked for you know I never
want to say that I wouldn't work for
anybody I would work I like sales you
know I would have been great in sales
but I would have worked in an
environment that allowed creativity that
would that would have created or allowed
me to create my old opportunities right
those are the best places to work if
you're not an entrepreneur and you're
working somewhere in your ear of the
ambitious type spirit then you're going
to want to work somewhere where you can
work up the ladder or you can exercise
your creativity and create something out
of nothing and contribute to the to the
company but you know in my situation
they just weren't having it so i'm
wondering i'm pretty sure there are
opportune time circumstances that you
faced challenges that you face
with regard to express in your
creativity where other people just
didn't see eye-to-eye with you and your
vision and you we allow them essentially
to squash us shut us down so I'm curious
please share with me any stories that
you have about allowing ourselves
allowing yourself to be creatively
stifled love talking to you guys looking
forward to reading your comments and
interacting with you down below talk to
you guys tomorrow