answer that you're looking but people
quit because they are not yet personally
identified this is me saying is now not
yet personally identified with who they
have to be to get this thing you see so
if I were to define fact I probably
bends back to say I'm a hundred pounds
overweight I probably do that since I
was a kid usually that's the way it
happens you know that 10 year old
teenager I'm in my 20s and I'm still
still really fat I've become personally
identified with that because I've been
called that a lot I look at myself I say
I'm fat
the world tells me up fat so
intrinsically a ninja that spiritual
explained I have all the evidence of
supporting that I am of that person it's
me I am this is interesting it is very
important because we think that's who we
are not necessarily what's on you what
result you've gotten based on the
actions you've taken who you are we've
become personally identify this certain
things being poor will be monthly
personally and identified if I get
anything that outside the the parameters
associated
gee or I'm uncomfortable because I'm
poor you try to make whatever so I'm not
yet personally identified I don't
believe that it's me over there I'm just
happy in the to find that I'm a fat
person trying to do lean person things
but really I just bet it happens this
way many problem you can't she can't
figure it out how to keep men what's
your problem everything it's always like
you see coming like ah this whatever get
that's because she's personally
identified with someone who has been
mouth until she believes she's someone
else this is not going to happen you
literally have to become a I talk about
this all the time because we get so
caught up in what we're getting I'm
getting back I'm getting lean I'm
getting a man I don't have a man oh very
attached to what's happening out here
and now who we're becoming you are you
and who are you becoming that's why I'm
for more interested in you becoming the
strongest version of yourself then what
you might get because what we all get is
gonna be completely different and it's
all based on what you want what you get
is not the point who you're becoming is
the point and what you do is not the
point either because like I always say
every action is measured by what the
sentiment from which it proceeds it's
coming from you you're you're a fat
person trying to do skinny shit all that
really matters is where it's coming from
that person that's so we move we have
the shit versions of ourselves we
literally have to take off the costume
in our minds first and then convince
those around us
Austin see this beer when I tell you
when it's over when you put on a
Superman he carries that sword
we connect the sword is here he goes
it's like smacking his sister's like not
a ninja and his mic is because he got
something anyway I'm sorry cuz Nicorette
the point is we've got to learn how to
detach from what the world thinks we are
and who we my den - fight with in order
to be able to rebuild another version of
ourselves otherwise we'll quit and we'll
win for number of reasons because of our
internal conversation about it Oh Louis
Berg some some projects it's very in see
it's very you're not saying it to
yourself out loud and more importantly
those around you start to behave
differently towards you start going to
the gym because you want to build some
muscle and your buddy that you play
video games or your good world around
you is trying to convince you that where
are you going they go become
uncomfortable because now they have to
change how they are towards you
it is shot that character
did all I have to do I can become so I'm
so attached to that character because of
how he was you pretty fucking cool get
lots of big giant friends and we would
all like do cool whipping things
together and go pick up massive amounts
of weight the chocolate the Hat some
pretty damn cool paper tea I need be so
attached to the coolness of that
character that I miss glory
be born again that's the whole you don't
like what you got what again doesn't
being changed
what again be be fried or what it means
come out of it
like the Phoenix you know it burns the
business doesn't just change costume
change better Phoenix literally burns it
comes out again
but it's the only way to actually get
new results