got a question from a young lady here
we're gonna call her Rihanna because her
name's felt almost like it but it's not
and we want to keep her anonymous anyway
she's 23 years old last year of
University she's in love with a man
they've been dating a few times over the
past month I feel this attraction
between us but our relationship is vague
she says I truly admire this person for
his achievements in life his passion
intellect and his beautiful heart I've
also felt that feeling of awe towards
him that you've described in one of your
recent videos physically he's an
attractive guy that likes to keep
himself fit but for some strange reason
there's a lack of lust to ride our
relationship further so my question is
can this admiration towards him generate
lust over time basically she's wanting
to know is it bird could we truly have
the bonds of relationship if I am
attracted to his intellect and perhaps
even his heart but there is no sexual
affinity for one another I'm gonna go
out on a limb here and I'm going to say
yes but not completely one of the things
we've got to understand about human
beings and it's been described
poetically in the religious traditions
as father son Holy Ghost it's been
described scientifically as the
neomammalian mammalian and reptilian
brain or the neocortex cortex medulla
doesn't matter if you want to look at it
scientifically or poetically we are a
triune being we're made up of three
parts it's a Trinity Elliott house calls
it your head your heart in your balls
and I like head heart and balls because
it is literally and figuratively head
here heart feelings are experienced here
intelligence is experienced in both and
our balls sexuality there's an
intelligence associated with all three
there's a unique type of intelligence
associated with all three and four two
people to create a deep
and with one another the deepest bond
it's available to human beings with one
another they will need to be a linking
at a warming and a relationship of mind
heart and sexuality of balls for it to
be its strongest that's not to say it's
necessary in all regards I'm sure that
we could use one to overpower the
absence of another but for the deepest
bonds of humanity to occur we not only
need to respect each other
intellectually and like you said you
loved him for his achievements that's a
very intellectual concept but also there
are warm feelings towards him that come
from the center of your body your heart
you need is very interesting oftentimes
attraction by mind will warm up the
heart but ultimately it has to sink
deeper and that's when we get into
sexual union a lot of times it starts
with the sexual union it's interesting
how in balance we become in our love to
one another it starts with boy by dicks
hard I don't care if she's an idiot and
fuck I don't love this bitch that's an
incomplete and we'll never afford you
the joy and a pleasure associated with
loving another individual if you
approach your life that way also a lot
of men that's what we've resorted to is
my dicks hard I don't love the bitch but
she looks good right so even the head is
the head associates its parameters for
beauty with this woman so you've got
that you've got the head involved and
you got the dick involve the balls that
the animality the sexuality of
individual but no heart for women
sometimes it's all heart and no head I
love him for whatever deep reason a lot
of it cuz stems from childhood
experiences what night I love him but
he's an idiot he's stupid my brain is
saying it's a bad idea because he has no
job he's on drugs and his he beat up his
last girlfriend right sometimes women
are drawn with the heart then with the
head
and then again the sexuality do I want
to open up to him so what you're asking
now is can we can we develop a
relationship with in absence of lust and
you use that word lust but I wouldn't
call it just lust lust is an imbalanced
form of attraction lust means it's it's
all dick no heart or all vagina no heart
no head what you're really asking is
could we have a deep meaningful
relationship without deep meaningful
sexual union I don't think it's
necessary in your case I think what
happens is a lot of times when there are
individuals who are contracted in there
the lower portion of their bodies come
together by hearten and head but chant
have very they're very uncomfortable
sexually it's because of neurotic
holding patterns it's because of the
inability to breathe into your balls
it's because of muscular restrictions in
your pelvic floor down in what would be
your sexual Center jordaan TN and his as
well and a lot of us we live this world
we live this castrated way in our world
because we have been taught that our
sexuality is naughty and it robs us of
our deepest most intimate opportunities
that we could have with people that we
would perhaps love in three ways
so my invitation to you my friend my
lady friend as you use your intellect to
further deepen the bonds of
understanding with this man and your
hearts warm to one another but yet
there's constricted sexuality number one
realized that it doesn't have to stay
that way now he was born as a if he was
born or got into an accident where you
know he just couldn't use the lower half
of his body and now we've got to love
each other from this portion only look
that's that's a totally different story
please develop develop the amount of
strength of love and passion that you
could through the head in the heart but
if it's just because you guys are
neurotic right just because you're
constricted sexually between one another
don't allow that to be a reason why you
don't explore the restriction explore
how you're neurotic in that way and work
together to develop warm sexual bonds
with one another I would invite you to
begin using forms of body mind body
release like bioenergetics that I show
in these videos quite often there are
some really weird sexual exercises that
open up the muscular holding in the
pelvic floor deep breathing is an
excellent way to begin the process by
warming that area one of the exercises
that I've showed in some videos and then
i'll describe now is to take your hands
take your fingers and spread them wide
place them both try to show you guys
here i'm fasting today so if you no
wonder why my energies little own place
them both over here lay on your back
with your with your knees bent your feet
flat on the on the bed or on the floor
fingers spread open your mouth as wide
as you can and allow your belly to
expand your hands should be about six
inches above your belly allow your belly
to expand and do that build up to 20
minutes of just wide mouth breathing
bringing energy down into your lower Dan
Tien
your sex center right that's where all
your sexual hormones come from you all
your sexual organs are located that's
where set muscular restriction will
literally castrate you from sexual
feeling if you don't soften that area
and made videos before also where I
teach you how to massage that area with
a with a with a ball small basketball
place it over your belly right below
your belly button and allow it to most
it's gonna be painful but allowed to
massage the muscular tension and also
the visceral tension we don't realize
that we've got tension in our organs
also all the tension associated with
that area bounce uh let your let your
hips to do this as your bouncing
uh-uh-uh-uh-uh-uh course you can't see
me but I've done videos where I'm doing
weird shit like this uh uh uh field
energy down in your pelvic floor if you
if you're a man feel your genitals
moving if your woman you'll feel warm
feelings coming to that particular area
you've got to bring your energy back
down into your sexual Center I mean
that's it if you want deep deep union
with this man sex will need to be a part
of the equation don't be embarrassed by
it don't be embarrassed by the fact that
it's not there yet speak to each other
you're both intelligent individual speak
to each other about it look we both we
like each other right I'm a virgin in
your aversion clearly we've got some
hang-ups about sexuality let's explore
this look they've got classes they've
got like Tantra classes and stuff go to
don't be embarrassed folks about your
sexuality or lack thereof we're all
fucked up sexually we're all fucked up
in our hearts and in our heads it's a
neurotic society that we were born in
civilization has damaged the physical
integrity of the human being on multiple
different levels and sexuality is just
one of them don't be embarrassed by it
look at it from what it is and approach
it practically open up your sexual
energy or so we're so grossed out by
that area of our bodies we think we're
you're really sexually liberal but we're
not we're still very sexually
conservative and that word even is it
doesn't give justice we're perverted
sexually and the way we look at each
other sexually and experience ourselves
sexually so that's it explore it with
each other if you love each other
explore this with each other but
understand that it's incomplete
especially if it's available it's
incomplete your love will be incomplete
if you don't go through this together
done