kind of question from one of our friends
about self-sabotage by the way if you've
got questions for me that you want me to
answer on Eliot says what you know these
are kind of like personal questions and
dating relationships philosophy
physiology whatever the case may be just
send it to my youtube channel this
particular one anyway this question is
about self-sabotage our friend goes on
to say that a few months ago he lost a
lot of weight about 20 pounds I think he
says and it was good until he started
cheating on his diet and they found that
he gained significant portions of that
weight back then he goes back on the
diet and loses it and then comes off the
diet and gains it and this is the
pattern that he's recognized over the
past several months and he's wondering
why he's self sabotaging why is it that
he's got great results but yet he can't
keep them because he keeps going off
track so I'm going to use an analogy for
you yesterday I had to take my car to
the to the mechanic because the wheels
were misaligned right and I'm holding on
to the steering wheel as I'm driving and
the minute I let go of my grip just a
little bit or get a little lazy with
holding on tight the car starts to
freakin drift right so I'm constantly
even if I'm going straight I'm
constantly having to like turn the wheel
slightly to the left so that doesn't
turn to the right and this is this is
annoying and it causes a ton of tension
in my body and in my mind because I
can't drive comfortably I can't just
coast right the same way that my car was
misaligned and physically couldn't
sustain the direction that I'd like it
to go in and I had to make a conscious
effort to bring it back into alignment
all the time I was driving is the same
way that your body is misaligned in a
particular way can't tell you exactly
how but I can I'm going to help you work
it out in a way that your activities
move in a particular direction now this
is the direction that you've probably
moved in for decades or very many years
of your life that caused you to be
overweight but I like this driver in the
car grab the steering wheel
and you grab the steering
we love your life by setting goals and I
always say this setting goals is like
grabbing the steering wheel of your life
you grabbed a steering wheel of your
behavior the same way that I grabbed the
steering wheel of that car and you
steered it straight and that's how you
lost the 20 pounds you made a conscious
concrete hardcore effort to turn your
behavior in a particular direction and
get a goal the thing is the same way
that I had to constantly be focused on
that damn steering wheel and couldn't
think or do anything else while I'm
driving it became frustrating because of
all the energy that's required to keep
that car straight the same way you grew
tired this is perfectly normal
per you go tired of having to force
yourself to eat a particular way or
exercise so that you can continue losing
weight or maintain the weight that you
lost so you may have done it for 90 days
but at the end in that 90 days it was
just like god damn tired of holding on
to the steering wheel the car starts
drifting your behavior starts trip then
you start gaining weight again you feel
guilty
you're grabbed steering wheel to bring
it back and this is the pattern that
you're experiencing the body is moving
the character is moving in a particular
direction which you know is bad who's
going to gain weight you grab it and you
bring it back but every time you try to
chill that fucking pattern happens again
right so what I had to do was I had to
take my car to a mechanic so that he
could fix the physical dysfunction so
that my mind could relax while I'm
driving you see the same way you're
going to have to work on your physical
body I'm going to tell you what I mean
in a moment so that your mind can relax
and not have to grab the steering wheel
all the time and you will be set on a
course that's straight all the time so
you guys watch me do these ridiculous
exercises and the videos where I'm
fucking going nuts and I'm releasing the
physical tension in my body that is the
same as taking your car to the mechanic
to release that malalignment right this
is all character structure stuff so if
you're interested in what I'm talking
about or you you need a little bit more
information to validate Elliott's
ridiculous ramp right
then I'll put some links down below
Wilhelm Reich the idea here is that form
equals function right and again I can't
tell you exactly where the tension is in
your body or in your face or in your
hands or in your legs I can't tell
exactly where it is but it's that same
tension just like I couldn't tell you
what the tension was in my car that's
causing it to move that same tension
needs to be released right you see me
doing this I'm already freaking doing it
because I'm I'm crazy I'm retarded right
like you guys really like to say so you
see my videos where I'm shaking I'm
vibrating I'm moving my head I'm moving
my face shaking out my arms bouncing
bouncing just bouncing and releasing the
tension in the body this is a form of
meditation because it causes the
neurotic holding pattern that's forcing
you in a direction you don't want to go
to go towards out right so this is what
I would invite you to do continue your
efforts you're doing a fantastic job I'm
like addicted to this shit look shaking
my hands you do a fantastic job keep up
the great work but start the body
meditations that I've shared with you I
put one up earlier this week it was a
Kundalini mode the meditation that was
designed by Osho I don't know that much
about Kundalini some of you guys are
like correcting me understanding what it
was called
it's called Kundalini meditation try
that download the music and use it shake
and vibrate your body let it go
completely and then relax you're gonna
feel such a flush of release throughout
your body it would be like you just had
an orgasm you're just gonna want to lay
there and every muscle of your body is
going to feel heavy and warm practice
this or just going crazy do some of my
bioenergy exercises the deep breathing
the bow the depression exercises that
I've showed you I've got about three
videos on depression try these you've
got to get your body loose you've got to
relate release the neurotic holding
patterns on your body the same way I had
to get the mechanic to release that now
alignment on my car so that's it my
friend I hope that helps I know will
help if you do it good luck Eliot sick
what
you
[Music]