so we got a question from our buddy
Curtis about dropping the ball basically
performing under pressure he plays tight
end in football and he is afraid that
he's going to literally drop the ball
because he had a bad experience with
dropping the ball in practice a couple
weeks ago but other case maybe and now
he can't get out of his head
this fear the feeling associated with
failure and losing and everybody coming
down hard on him if he drops the ball
right so he is really tense and his
coaches now are noticing this I like
dude you're really freaking tense chill
out right and it's difficult for him -
because he's replaying this mental movie
of dropping the ball and it's guess what
it's a spiral downward and I think you
experienced that I made a video earlier
this week it may have been uploaded
already or it may be on its way about a
student's girlfriend's orgasm face and
it's about visualization it's about
mental movies that have a physiological
response on your body you will actually
reproduce physiologically the movie in
your mind they've done Studies on like
Olympic athletes where if they put like
little like brain measure things on them
and ask them to run a sprint or to I
think they used to do this with uh or
they've done this with Michael Phelps to
actually go through the actual event in
their mind that all the same
neurotransmitters and all the
physiological responses hormones and
everything that are associated with the
actual event happen in their body there
is a very close tie it's almost like
identical to what's happening in their
body when they visualize it - when
they're actually doing the event so that
can support you or it can hurt you if
you're visualizing failure you're
preparing your body your nervous system
to fail because you're you're in
graining the pattern of failure your
brain is one of the is it is almost like
a machine where there are patterns and
as you reproduce pattern
the patterns get easier and easier and
easier easy and easy to go with all
those motor engrams well engrams what
motor engrams when it's associated with
the body movement you know
so as you further ingrain or further
facilitate motor engrams that are faulty
that don't support you because you're
thinking about them you are then going
to find it being reproduced in reality
in life Olympic athletes who visualize
themselves winning races win races
people who visualize dropping the ball
will drop the ball so you literally have
to replay that movie in your head you
literally have to just get rid of wash
out that movie of you dropping the ball
and replay over and over and over and
over in Europe again in your mind you
grabbing the winning touchdown you have
to do this and I can tell you from my
experience that this is the way it is I
look back in retrospect right I look
back at my life and everything that I've
gotten I've seen in my head before I got
got it
like for example just one small example
when I first moved to st. Petersburg
yeah I was I was living pretty poor I've
spoken about this before but one of my
clients drove me through this
neighborhood and he said hey this is Old
North East st. Petersburg and I drove
with him in that on that day and I
looked around I was like I want to live
here someday now mind you I didn't even
have a business at that time I was still
a personal trainer I was flat broke my
wife was living at my parents home with
my daughter right and I'm driving to his
neighborhood and I'm like I want to live
here I love this neighborhood just like
the way the houses looked and the trees
it was just so freakin awesome so
several times a week before I would
drive you know 40 minutes back to my
home you know where when I was living
with my parents you know telling you
things were bad I Drive through that old
neighborhood and I would visualize I
didn't know what I was doing at the time
until later on someone taught me these
techniques they'd said you know this
called
and I'm like I do that all the time I
would drive through that neighborhood
and sometimes I sit in front of a house
and I'd like imagine like this is my
house and I'm gonna get out and I'm
gonna walk up to it and I'm going to
live here someday
well some days today I've been living in
this neighborhood for about four years
now
right when I played football I was like
always playing defense they always made
me play defense for some strange reason
even though I'm built like a running
back in I knew I was running back so I
remember carrying the ball in my bedroom
and jumping on the bed like I was
scoring touchdowns I did that all
through high school there was no chance
that I was ever gonna make me a running
back I was even recruited as a defensive
player in college it was just like it's
never gonna happen but still even when I
was in college I'd hold the ball like
I'm running back and dive on the bed I'm
fucking I just I should do that again
now it used to be fun and magically by
the time I was a junior I was a running
back by a fluke all the guys on the team
injure themselves they made me a running
back so many different parts of my life
look exactly the way they did in the
mental movie I created first okay you're
going to drop the ball if you play a
mental movie of dropping the ball over
and over and over again that's why
you're tense and your coaches are
telling you chill out you've got to
replay a resourceful movie in your head
so that you get a resourceful result
good luck