I know this might not make sense and
it's probably gonna sound kind of
strange but today I'm making this video
to show my gratitude to you for you
showing gratitude to me and what I mean
by that is that earlier this week I was
unindicted with emails and a video that
I'll share with you in a moment from you
guys sharing how happy you are or
grateful you feel for the things that I
do for you basically the videos that I
make and really I don't think too much
about it I make these videos because I
enjoy making them I I genuinely feel
good to answer questions share my ideas
and whatever wisdom I've accumulated
over the past 33 years with people in
these videos and and I'm not shocked but
I'm taken back by how much of impacts of
an impact a lot of my words have had in
some of your lives the stories that
you've shared with me the the change of
heart the evolution that you've
experienced just by simple things that
I've shared in these videos makes me
feel great and then for you to share
your gratitude with me makes me feel
even more it's a weird mix of feelings
it's almost like I'm grateful for your
gratitude and it makes me want to give
back even more so I said to my wife I
was like I'm so happy I was brought to
tears almost with all of these the
gratitude and and the nice things that
you guys had to say and I also had a
mixed feeling of now i owe them right
it's almost like when someone you sent
someone a gift they send you a thank-you
card and you thank them for the thank
you card and it doesn't end it won't end
because thank you for the thank you card
well thank you for thanking me for the
thank you card and it can get crazy but
I think that's the energy associated
with that reciprocation going back and
forth sharing here's something for you
here's something for you here's
something for you and it's a dance it's
it's it's a beautiful dance that we get
involved with that really shows that we
need each other I make these videos
because my heart compels me to you watch
the videos
is that perhaps there's something in my
words that are resourceful to you you
thank me for the videos I feel good
about making more videos and want to
show my appreciation to you for watching
the videos and this is just a simple
example but we see it all through life I
often talk about dualism now there's a
balance there's a dance in all of nature
there's no winter without summer there's
no night without day there's no mail
without female there's this magnificent
duality that creates all the power that
animates the world and the power between
our communion our communication our
relationship even though it's only
through video is powerful it's very
powerful and I'm convinced that by my
sharing just a few simple words ideas or
providing some wisdom based on my 33
years of existence here on earth with
you would not only have you reciprocate
by sharing your gratitude with me but
also give you more strength to number
one share with other people share your
strength with other people and number
two feel strong enough and be confident
enough and have permission to become the
strongest version of yourself because
that in and of itself and I say this all
the time just becoming the strongest
version of yourself changes your
sentiment changes your heart changes who
you are and through transference people
change around you you become stronger
your friends have no choice but to get
stronger to keep up with you either that
or they resent you become haters and
then just fall to the wayside and that's
going to happen and that's a part of
what to expect on this journey anyway I
don't want to make this video much
longer than it needs to be so I'm going
to share Marcel friend of ours his video
showing some gratitude and expressing
some of his wisdom with me check him out
hey how you feeling Elliot I had a quick
question being that I am on my own
to building a business using my services
and my insight on on personal growth you
know it's it's it's a through my talents
and you know in the arts so ask what are
you what I'm looking to do I just had a
quick question and comment up on this
passage and one of the books that I'm
reading it's called the business of the
21st century by robert kiyosaki and you
might have read it before you go you
might have heard of it or or even read
the quote before it goes like this it
calls on those like no man is an island
entire of itself every man is a piece of
the continent a part of the main so yeah
basically I just wanted to get your
insight on that and that's it so I hope
that you have a bunch of fulfillment and
success throughout your journey and
thank you so much for checking out my
video III I felt compelled to send you
one being that I always check out all
your updates especially the Elliots have
what those are fantastic material so um
so yeah that's pretty much it thank you
so much for for checking out and have a
great week Marcel dude thank you so much
I am so grateful for your gratitude and
just to reiterate what I said earlier to
capitalize upon the point that you made
with that quote we all need each other
no man is an island you're right and one
of my favorite ways to describe that is
that we are all cells of a single
organism one cell separates itself and
decides it's going to do its own thing
it's rogue we call that a cancer a cell
that decides that is we're going to
reject the rest of the body that it's
going to perpetuate its own ideal
outside the bounds of all of the other
cells and organelles probably i'm saying
that but the organs in the organism is
diseased and we're running rapid with
this disease of cancer so for you to
recognize and for us to share the way we
share
brings healing to humanity brings
healing to the earth and I am convinced
in my heart especially when I see young
people like yourself I say young people
you're probably 10 years younger than me
we our generation when I see us sharing
the wisdom that previous generations
have rejected or ignored or convinced
against due to religion and politics and
other controlling institutions but we're
good we're coming back we're coming back
home and we're building a brand new
world through the exchange of ideas and
communication and relationship so once
again i love you guys I love making
these videos I do this because my heart
makes me do it I am just following my
heart's calling and I want to give you
permission to do the same thing I'm
going to encourage you to share the way
i'm sharing with you that's how we pay
back continue to send me your emails i
like it but the way really shit would
really pay back is to pay it forward
that's it thank you i'll talk to you
guys again soon Elliot's it