a question for my buddy Matt about
motivation and really discipline and he
didn't describing it that way but
basically he says that he watches you'll
watch my videos and there's another
guy's videos that he likes to watch and
he gets really motivated about doing
something about becoming more
constructive in his life achieving a
particular goal if even has them you
don't mention that but he's really
motivated feels good right
and a few days later he's back to the
same sluggish lazy person that he was
before watching the video and then he'll
see another video and I feel really
excited and motivated and then it
deflates this idea of excitement and
then depression excitement and then
depression is a cycle that is unrest or
so obviously is not getting anything
done because getting excited don't mean
shit and I've mentioned this before in
other videos and one of the last things
that I really want to have happen with
these videos that I create for you guys
is to be positioned as and received by
you as motivation because motivation is
bullshit motivation doesn't get anything
done motivation gets you going
discipline commitment strong habits is
what gets things done
motivation is very ungrounded right it's
very it's all up here well I feel good
when it comes tab time to bring it into
practice you cannot rely on it
motivation is just a feeling grounded
action is what gets things done
so here's my invitation to you the next
time you feel motivated
don't do anything grand and exciting or
or or set any lofty expectations for
yourself to like stay that way or
whatever the case may be get a pad and
paper and write down one or two things
that you're going to commit to doing
every single day no matter what you're
going to you're going to use that
motivation to build a machine for
yourself and I promise you that three
days after you write down let's say one
of your goals is I don't know what your
life is like but
well a very good practice is journaling
so writing I'm going to write in my
journal every single day I'll write a
full page in my journal every single day
you become a machine you don't think
about whether you're going to write in
your journal or not you do it because
you already made that commitment every
single day no matter what it does not
matter if both of your hands were cut
off and you have to use your fricking
mouth with a pen and write it in your
journal you write in your freaking
journal every single day you don't think
about it when you have built a habit
it's ingrained in your nervous system in
such a way that the brain doesn't even
have to consider whether or not it'll
get done it just gets done because you
committed commit once this is important
you guys need to write this shit down
commit once you don't need to commit
more than once you commit once to the
thing that you're going to do and then
you do it every single day that everyday
method is the is one of the most
powerful methods for reconstructing your
entire life picking something one thing
it doesn't matter again I mentioned this
before in other videos it doesn't matter
what that thing is and that thing
Internet's in and of itself is probably
not going to be the transformative
action the content of it but the context
which is the discipline that you're
creating in order to to grow stronger is
what's important I can't emphasize this
enough how important it is for you to
commit to small things on a daily basis
because that is what transforms you is
those tiny little actions it's not the
grand visions it's the tiny actions that
move towards a worthy ideal okay so stop
getting motivated you don't need
motivation now you need motivation
motivation doesn't afford you anything
except good feelings in your body the
good feelings in your body is an
indication that there's something that
you want now you get to work by doing it
every single day