great question very fascinating question
from our buddy Jan Lu he says Elian have
a question for you I have a fear of
being around successful people I find
myself to be extra shy and apprehensive
around people who have achieved great
things in life whether it be
athletically financially in
relationships academically this includes
people who have a strong presence and
people who are beautiful or smart from
listening to all these years from
listening to you all these years I know
that I need to surround myself with
people who are successful so that I
might achieve success like them instead
I tend to hang around more normal people
people told me that I am all the things
above they call me a great and
successful person myself I was told this
by normal people and successful people
yet I'm fearful and intimidated by other
people who exemplify greatness should I
do something about this what can I do to
be more culturally these people why am i
experiencing fear of fellow successful
people thank you so much great question
I'm gonna get right to the point with
the very first thing that came to my
mind when I read your question which was
you feel something there's something
physiologically happening in you when
you around these people you call it fear
because you don't know what else to call
it
but I am going to call it ah like the
root of the word awesome you feel
awesome you feel ahh amongst these
people and the reason why you feel it so
strongly is because they exemplify who
you actually are on the inside they are
a mirror for who you are on the inside
and looking in the mirror is often the
most uncomfortable thing that a human
being can do being faced with what they
are faced with what you are this is why
people go through life avoiding
experiences and challenges because they
expose you to yourself and you my friend
stand right next to people who embody
all of the virtue within yourself you're
not scared you're in awe
of these people great place to be
because when you look at them it's like
you're looking into a crystal ball of
your future you can expect to be those
people and better perhaps because as we
evolve as human beings from one
generation to next and I don't know how
old you are we remix success and if
you're amongst seven successful men who
give you that feeling of awe your
success will be a fruit of blending
their expertise or their awesomeness
into a brand new kind of awesomeness and
this is how we just get more fucking
awesome so you my friend may shine
brighter than all seven of them shine to
you right now you may shine so bright
ten times brighter seven times brighter
for someone that you're going to inspire
someone who few are in your presence so
that's really the that's the the meat of
this thing here brother as it shared a
good spot what you should do everybody
wants something to do I think just this
shift of focus from the word fear to the
word aw in your consciousness will
change your entire we change everything
you don't have to you don't have to
behave any different way you don't need
to take any action steps you don't need
to read any books or all you need to do
is switch that word fear for aw and what
that's going to do is it's going to
physiologically energize you in a
different way because you're moving from
now from now from place of fear because
you tell yourself to the stories we tell
ourselves become our physiology you're
saying the word fear the word becomes
the flesh you know saying when I say
that the word becomes a flesh it's just
a fucking abstract idea but it embodies
itself and you can you don't use words
that you don't want to become flesh in
your in your world that's a big one for
all of you listening to this don't say
or think about shit that you don't want
to have happen the word becomes the
flesh the abstract see that people who
throw these terms around you know
I love when religious people use these
terms and shit like that having can't
say all but a lot of people don't know
what they're actually saying when they
say shit like this the word becomes the
flesh it's a poetic way of saying
because that's what all that that's what
all religion it's poetry mythology which
is beautiful but it's a way of
describing the concrete realities of our
lives with poetic language where it's
don't become flesh and why do you even
use the word fucking flesh it's weird
right
well another way to put it is the
abstract becomes the the concrete the
understand the thought becomes the
reality it's another way to say so
you're cutting yourself off from a
reality that is completely unrestorable
veered you guys got like my screen on
one side the wall on the other you're
cutting yourself off from Unruh source
phille ideas fear and research that word
ah like I told you it's a root for the
word awesome do some research on that
word remind yourself that that's what's
happening physiologically in your body
experiencing all and just from that
place you will be drawn energetically
closer to the people who you are in awe
of hope that helps