one of my favorite phrases by Ralph
Waldo Emerson is every action is
measured by the sentiment from which it
proceeds that essentially means that
what you do doesn't matter nearly as
much as where it's coming from so I
answered a question for a friend the
other day about whether or not he should
punch someone that's been irritating him
in the face right well it really doesn't
matter if he punches him and what he
does will only be measured by where he's
coming from with it so if this guy that
consistent consistently irritates him
and is ruining you know the lives of the
individuals that are around him and my
friend proceeds from a place of being
rooted in his manliness being rooted in
his sexuality being rooted in the earth
standing his ground being firm being
grounded and decides this guy needs to
be punched in the face so that you know
there's just something that needs to
happen he punches the guy in the face
he's proceeding from a place of strength
pragmatism firmness and empower but if
he punches the guy in the face but he's
proceeding from a place of hysteria this
guy like he irritates my eyes guy's an
asshole bang and he punches him in the
face he's coming he's proceeding from a
place of hysteria a weak place he's not
in control he's not grounded he's flying
off the handle like this it like the
phrase describes he's flying off the
handle Aust himself the handle what you
do you have control where you're on the
handle when you fly off the handle that
means you've lost control both
situations are the same punches them in
the face
punches in the face one is it's coming
from a strong place one it's coming from
a weak place every action is measured by
the sentiment from which it proceeds
there are two different types of punches
even though they both gave them a black
eye Eliot said what