this question is from Oh Kailyn he's our
friend from Istanbul Turkey and he goes
on to describe how his mother passed
away only one month ago Galen is now
having a hard time studying in school
he's 17 years old and he's exam times
are coming up and my man he's having a
hard time studying and focusing in class
he tries to go to the gym to sort of
work out can't do it doesn't have the
energy and says that all you can do is
sit and play video games look Oh Kailyn
I don't know your real name buddy but
your world literally and figuratively
because the mother is the womb and the
nourisher of the individual human being
in the same way that the earth is the
originator or the creator and the
nurturer physically of the human being
your entire world has just collapsed on
you only four weeks ago for you to be
able to perform at the degree that you
did before your mom passed away is
totally impossible it you need to mourn
for four weeks is not enough and not
only that I my assumption is being a boy
being from the Middle East my assumption
is that you've stuffed your tears in
you've stuffed the sadness down because
it's not macho it's not manly to break
out in sobs and tears like you did when
you were five or four years old right
but that the tension the muscular
tension that an energy that you have to
produce to hold back those tears hold in
that sadness will give you produce so
much lethargy you'll be so tired and so
worn out and so unavailable for anybody
or anything because you're so busy
swallowing your tears now this becomes
chronic so you might not even know it
again I'm just assuming this you might
not even know that you're swallowing
your tears but it
comes chronic where you do you become so
stiff your body is so rigid that you
don't even know you're doing it and
again this is all based on assumption
I'm gonna go out and say that's the
absolute best approach for you right now
is number one to be with the situation
your mom died and you might might not do
so well in your exams don't worry about
it the exams aren't nearly as important
as the feelings in your body as your
health as your mental health as your
character not nearly as important you
can do those exams again your mom only
passes away once and the opportunity for
you to mourn is here right now be with
that it's a far more important thing and
the next thing I would offer you is an
idea that might support you an exercise
that might support you in breaking the
tension in your body
breaking the shell that's holding your
sadness and sobs in you gotta break it
it's in our mind and it's in our body
we've got to rid our body of the tension
that's causing us to hold in our
emotions especially deep emotions that
bring cleansing to the body and the soul
like sobbing like crying one that most
men have a hard time doing what I'm
going to refer you to is one of my
breathing videos where I either show you
how to lay on a stool you know the the
bioenergetics tool where you stretch
your body or simply just do the bow but
I've showed you this before you pin your
shoulders back and you lean back I want
you to stretch the entire front of your
body the front of the human body is
associated with tenderness it's soft and
there's not nearly as much much muscle
an aggressive muscle like the long
muscles of the back you're going to need
to stretch those open and breathe deeply
open your mouth you might start feeling
like you're shaking you might feel like
you're vibrating as you do these
exercises search my channels you'll find
the videos that I'm talking about where
you stretch your body and breathe you
might feel like you're shaking and
you're vibrating that is the emotion
trying to break free
right that might be enough to get you to
start choking up and crying but if it
doesn't you have you have to cry there's
no question about it this is what I'm
telling you you need to do you got a cry
you got to get you've got a sob you've
got to get the tension out it's there
for a reason we don't hold it in we
can't hold it in breathe deep deep into
your belly practice deep breathing what
that's doing is it's charging your body
and expanding your energy from within
but then we've got to sort of chip at
the body a little bit to get it to break
down until those tears so or sobs in
particular when I say sobs I mean the
convulsions in your body associated with
deep crying from warning or loss not
necessarily tears falling down the cheek
mimic the sounds of a cry after you
breathe or while you're breathing so it
would be something like this until you
can just totally let go let your brain
shut off and allow your body because the
emotions are in your body let your body
fall into the rhythm of crying
hah hah hah hah
you see what I'm doing it's like
staggering the sound coming out of the
body you can start with just deep sounds
and I would invite you as hard as this
is for you man I'm starting to cry
myself I'm crying for you I would invite
you to call out to your mother when
you're making that sound
mama-mama ma-ma-ma-ma-ma and you're
gonna break down into those tears go
with it my man go with the tears let it
all pour out of you you're gonna feel so
refreshed you'll feel brand new but you
gotta get it out you gotta let it out
you got a more and you got to do it not
only for yourself but do it for your
mother because she wants you to live the
most pleasureful joyful full expression
life that you possibly can i know this
because every mother wants that for her
son all right my man it was helpful to
you good luck
Eliot sick what