hey whats up guys the very first thing i
want to do today's thank all of you who
participated with me the other day when
i asked you a question i asked you what
would a stronger version of you be like
so if you took a moment and just thought
about it what would i look like what
would I be like what would I have if I
were that ideal that strongest version
of myself in these four areas we've got
vocation the work that you do the
service you provide to the world you've
got education your level of mastery
you've got health and fitness which is
pretty self-explanatory and I'm in a gym
is that's what we do here and of course
relationships and I was really pleased
to read all of your responses I enjoyed
hearing the things that you guys had to
say and learning a little bit more about
you and as I was reading through the
responses i began to notice certain
recurring themes and today i want to
talk a little bit about maybe even ask
another question as it relates to one of
the recurring themes that I notice and
the area in which i'd like to speak a
little bit more with you about today is
relationships and the question is how do
we grow stronger when we're in an
environment with people who are set on
not becoming stronger versions of
ourselves themselves so for example if
you are fed up with being overweight
you've been overweight your whole life
or a significant portion of it your mom
and dad are overweight Grandma and
Grandpa overweight your brothers and
sisters your friends are all over weight
eating fried chicken pizza two liters of
coca-cola and french fries and potato
chips every single day and you decide
I'm fed up I had enough I could be more
I can have more I could do more I'm
gonna make this happen but yet every day
you come home and you got to face them
you got to face the nasty food they eat
and you might even have to face some
criticism when dealing with these people
who quite frankly our loved ones so the
question really is how do we grow
stronger in this environment without
creating animosity towards these people
without creating division separation and
criticism against the people who we love
and who are in our environment I'm
really excited to hear what you got
I have to say about growing stronger in
an environment that is set on not moving
forward with you and the key to the
answer and response would be were you
able to or how could you maintain a good
relationship with those people while you
grow stronger so drop your response down
below I'm really excited to read what
you guys have to say about it and I'm
really excited to be participating in
this conversation with you guys so I'm
looking forward to hearing what you guys
have to say and I'll talk to you next
time done