what's up guys hey we got a really tough
question from our buddy Mike who's been
married to a woman for five years they
have a four-year-old daughter and from
his perspective it's very important to
point that out because there are always
multiple multiple perspectives from his
perspective she's not working very hard
and trying to keep the relationship
going because every time he tries to
approach her with the things that he'd
like to work on with her her
communication shuts down she goes into
the bedroom turns on the TV basically
ignores him turns to a cold shoulder
they have separate friends he he worked
70 hours a week to take care of the
daughter and the wife and he comes home
and he says that the house is never
clean he doesn't she doesn't tend to
take care of the child way a mother
should take care of the child and he's
basically he's at a loss he's like look
I want to make this thing work out we
have a daughter but man she's not giving
she's not helping this circumstances and
she doesn't want to talk to me about it
what do I do the story goes on and he
says well I bumped into an old friend an
old female friend in fact I dated her in
high school and at first they began
talking of course when you are not in a
happy relationship and you meet usually
someone of the opposite sex and you
start talking about what you're unhappy
about in your relationship with that
person the dynamics of the triad the
threesome starts getting really weird
and by divulging the circumstances that
he's unhappy with upon this new woman
they now started growing in their mmm
warm feelings for one another
and and they were very tiptoe which at
first because they know what's wrong you
don't fuck other women when you're
married and have children but uh but hey
nature took its course and they had sex
now they both afterwards felt guilty
about they said we can't do this and she
says to him you know you better figure
out your marriage thing because look if
we're going to be together you got to
get rid of her that is that right I'm
not in and they decided not to have sex
anymore she says it's not right I'm not
going to have sex with you while you're
with this woman now you're gonna make a
choice now Mike is trying to figure out
whether or not he should
says should I work things out with my
wife and pray that things get better
right
of course you made a mistake hey look we
all make mistakes nothing wrong with a
mistake patch it up move along right
it says or tell her how unhappy I am in
the relationship and asked for a divorce
meaning he's going to say look that's it
I'm done with you I'm gone or third tell
her I've cheated and hope she forgives
me when she probably won't get a divorce
and lose my child in the process okay
very first thing I want to share with
you that I've said in many videos is
you're not going to win you are going to
be a sacrifice you will be the
sacrificial lamb you're going to have
pain regardless of what you choose so
gear up for that my friend where you are
right now is a circumstance that is you
you have no there's no way out of this
just get that into your head I think
that needs to be the disease to be
shared very early on with many of us in
our circumstances is that there's no
back door there's no sneaking around
this there's no light at the end of the
tunnel there's no there's no path around
the pain you will have pain receive that
for all it's worth whatever choice you
make there's going to be sacrifice you
cannot win beautiful thing about that is
that successful people don't make the
right choices because neither room or
right they're all right they're all
wrong but they make their choices right
so it's all about the stories you tell
yourself be okay with that
now I'll share some insight and some
invitations with you number one your
dealings with this other woman I want to
get that out of the way take heed this
is one of my warnings to all of you
never share very rarely does Elliott say
never when I say never it's because I
know this one never share the intimate
details of your relationship especially
if it's in a negative fashion with
another woman
never no matter how bad things are going
on with you and your wife and you need
to deal with that we'll come to that in
a moment don't share it with another
woman
because what you've done now is you've
taken the energy that should be you
should be investing in with the partner
that you've chose to train with marriage
is a training write that one down make a
mean marriage is a training marriage
isn't a beautiful union that's bullshit
the churches have lied to us the world
applied to us
Disney lied to us Church I mean um
marriage is a training it's a training
it's a training like you go to the gym
to build something up in you never take
your circumstances that should be
invested never take the energy that
should be invested in the circumstances
of your training and give it to anyone
else spilling that out is a it ruins the
dynamics and then now you have not only
this because now you're here's the deal
you're opening up a can of worms and
energetic can of worms because now
you've divulged your the circumstances
of your energy between you and that
person you've chosen a trainer in your
life with with another energetic source
another human being and all the emotions
thoughts feelings sex that will
ultimately come out of that can of worms
now you got to deal with that shit too
so you got to women know you got three
women cuz you got a daughter too and a
daughter without her daddy he's always a
problem
you got three women and women bro ah one
problem you someone once told me that uh
Richard Branson who's one of the world's
greatest entrepreneurs says that uh you
have no problems in life except for your
health and a friend told me that you
said he had a meeting with him and he
told him that and I said okay yeah cool
and then I said except for women you
don't want women problems you don't want
problems with the feminine that's one
problem you do not want to deal with
because it is it's so deep-seated and
the roots of it delve deep into our
hearts and our sexualities that our
psyche you don't want women problems
yeah three women you got three big
problems haha hey you got a laugh about
it don't bring another woman in bro
Oh
their problems and not to say that this
is a negative statement about women it's
like it's a lot that women are allowed
to deal with it's not as easy as just
having sex and smiling so the very first
invitation I'm going to make to you man
is do not take any action with your wife
with this one still in the picture
you've got to cut off from her even if
you decide to leave your life it leave
your wife it has more to do with the
your commitment to life training and
what you may have chosen for yourself
about yourself and in your situation
with her and your daughter in absence of
this can of worms you don't need the
extra can of worms get rid of her even
if at some point you find another woman
don't let her interfere with what's
going on over here this is the first one
get rid of her
don't leave this one because you're in
love with that one and don't leave this
one because that one's making you
because you're going to take the shit
and you're going to get you're going to
redevelop in this one she was a part of
this shit you understand you got to get
rid of the extra woman it's not say that
you shouldn't leave this one it's not to
say that you shouldn't have another
woman I know I'm repeating myself but
not that one
okay very really they put my foot down
when I'm doing that a lot here today
because you know these are tangible
circumstances get rid of her first and
foremost so that now you can bring back
100% of your focus and concentration and
go to where your problem is and hey the
world is your mirror the people in your
world are your mirror and she's showing
you some shit about yourself that you're
not willing to look at I'm not saying
you need to work out the marriage
because I think marriages are supposed
to last right because Jesus says so I
don't give a fuck mag divorce right I've
happened to be married and things seem
to work out well but I'm never gonna go
out there say marriages need to stay
together it's the union of man and woman
it should not be separated that which
God brings together shall not be
separate fought that we still have to
live on this plane on this planet in
this world and sometimes decisions need
to be made okay but if you leave her
without dealing with the demons that
going on first in you I always say that
look at yourself first then you're going
to repeat this drama again and that's
why it's a training marriage is a
training and if you fail in this
training without fully observing
exploring the reasons for its failure in
you not her always come to yourself
first why is she showing up like this
and how might I present myself how might
I be to have her be different not how
can I change her how am I being to
receive this then you're gonna go you're
gonna go you're going to do the same
shit with another woman and another
woman another woman another woman
another one right and your daughter is
gonna carry that shit with her too so
you'll see what's going on with you too
she gonna see the way type man you are
she gonna go find a man just like you
too she gonna have divorces you know the
separation of so many marriages is an
energetic issue it has to do with our
lack of willing to take responsibility
for ourselves and our actions and
responsibility for the way the world
shows up your world is your mirror you
don't like what you see in the mirror
it's your fucking fault and she's she is
your closest mirror she's mirror you
gotta face every fucking day in fact you
put yourself into that mirror and you
made a third mirror look at your kids
look at your daughter that's a mirror
too so I would say in all selfishness
because I am selfish I'm very selfish
it's all about me and how I can get
stronger that's really what my life is
about me first me me me me me me me I'm
not going to walk away from a marriage
knowing that there's weaknesses in me
that's not allowing me to become a
stronger version of myself I fucked up I
have to figure out what's going on here
inside me that's making this happen okay
take your eyes off of her
now one of the things you mentioned here
is uh asking for a divorce okay hey
check out that's like leaving the
tornado instead of going to the I of it
where you can manage it sometimes you
got to check out maybe you fucked up so
bad that you got to check out you got to
start all over again you say third tell
her I cheated on her and hope she
forgives me what she probably won't hey
I tell you what
tell her you cheated on her tell her you
cheated on her
because being real is the very first
approach is the very first step to
getting this whole thing worked out with
yourself be real with yourself very
first thing I always offer be honest
with yourself that's it no judgment I
don't make any judgments just say just
let's just be fucking real for a moment
be real with yourself and you got to be
real with her cuz ain't gonna work out
if he real with her so whatever happens
when you say you cheated on her and
wherever whatever sentiment that
proceeds from she's going to receive and
you're gonna see a mirror of what you
actually are and if however she responds
know that a you gave it to her you did
that but you got to tell her honesty is
just really honesty goes so far beyond
just being honest with that other person
what honesty does is it liberate cyou
from the holding of that pain now it
doesn't mean that you won't get another
pain she might punch you in your eye she
might kick you in your nuts and say I'm
out of here
you might have to deal with losing your
daughter but I said you're gonna win and
you ain't going win so that might be one
that you lose but you got to be honest
just an invitation
and that's it man there is no answer
there's no right answer here know that
you gotten yourself into a pickle made
your bed and now sleep in it it's going
to be fucked up prepare for the
fucked-up-ness but also know that the
pain the failure the darkness the
fucked-up-ness that you've attracted to
yourself is a training all of these
things are a training now how are you
going to evolve how are you going to
grow stronger to lift this weight is
really the question at the end of this
whole circumstance how are you going to
go stronger and that's it get rid of
that other bitch done