awesome an interesting relationship
question I've been doing all
relationship questions today from our
buddy in Mexico who's kind of dating two
different girls he's got his options
open right now and they are complete
opposites he's got one girl who he says
is really fun she says she has sexy
tattoos and she's just like kind of free
loving and really enjoyable fun bubbly
exciting sexy right and they have
awesome sex together but the problem is
she's kind of flighty she doesn't have
she doesn't know what she wants to do in
life she doesn't give a shit what
anybody thinks about her this is all
very attracted to him she doesn't know
what she wants to do in life and she's
kind of like you know she shows up late
but she is fun as hell when he's got
another girl right and she's got her
shit together she's the one actually
told him or encouraged him to go to
college she's really smart she's focused
concentrated she has goals the other one
hasn't evolved she has goals and is
moving in a in a strong and mature
direction in life the problem is their
sex ain't so good because she's she's a
little she's kind of stiff she's she's
kind of you know uptight a little bit
she's great in life
next sucks in bed great in bed
sucks in life what do you do oh man
that's gonna be the dilemma for the rest
of your life because it's all of our
dilemmas for every single one of us
because I can tell you here's the thing
you've got to decide what you want
because if you take this one right you
take the really sexy one you're going to
have awesome sex all days of your life
she's going to be lots of fun you were
just going to enjoy every single
intimate moment with her but she's gonna
drive you fucking nuts because she's
gonna show up late she's gonna forget
stuff if you decide to have a family
with her she's gonna be the kind of like
the kids diapers don't get changed oops
I forgot but hey let's go fuck and your
life is you're going to be frustrated in
with her it that's an archetype that's a
particular type of woman that's a
particular type of person but it's a
particular type of woman and it's you're
almost going to find that you've got one
of the other in most cases you're it's
not totally black and white but to find
a gray is going to be difficult okay so
yes enjoyable now here's the thing you
can focus and concentrate on reaching
your goals and just like you know
completely turn off to her while you're
doing your thing and then come home and
then you're gonna have to totally change
your character when you come home and
just lay loose because she's loose then
she's a loose woman yeah but she's a fun
woman and she's one that you will enjoy
her company but she's gonna drive you
fucking nuts
this one over here you're going to have
a great life together because you're
you're both on the same path with the
same goals with the same values and
you're focused and concentrated she's
mature she's responsible and she's going
to get you where you need to go she even
encourages you to go to college if you
said where you meant that one huh so
you're gonna have a great life but the
thing is your sex is not going to be
awesome right you you're gonna I mean
all sexes is good I mean I eat bus nuts
can't complain but it's not going to be
as fun as it is with her what kind of
life do you want do you want a life
partner that's gonna support you but you
know maybe you don't get blowjobs and
maybe you know you don't have wild crazy
sex like you once had right are you
willing to give that up you got it like
you'd ask yourself it's not right or
wrong I'm not here to tell you which one
it is it's just these are the two types
of women that you're probably going to
experience over and over and over again
in your life either in reality or
perception of course I said that there's
a spectrum but generally that's the
archetype you know she's more masculine
in her ability to get shit done you know
she's more like a dude and that's not to
say that she's not a feminine woman but
she's more
and concentrated it that's a masculine
trait she very feminine that's why you
know she's so sexy she's so yielding
she's so open she's so carefree but
she's gonna drive you nuts because she
doesn't have the focus and concentration
of the other one so really it boils down
to how you are going to adjust your
character to meet the demands of the
relationship because if you go with this
one you're going to have to be forgiving
because she's going to be sort of ditzy
you know she's not going to put gas in
the car she's gonna forget to pick up
the kids from daycare she's going to be
late all the time she's gonna look good
Frankie's got tattoos and you like to
say she's gonna look good she enjoy you
know enjoyable sex she everything's
gonna look right the house is gonna be
clean you're gonna have a lot of money
she's gonna be focused and concentrated
on time the kids will be clean right
things will get done but you know the
two three times a week four times maybe
that you're gonna end up having sex you
know it's not going to be wild orgy sex
what do you give up it's up to you