so today we have a question from our
friend Jeffrey he says that he's an
eighteen year old college student with
ADHD I've never felt like I'm utilizing
my full mental capabilities and always I
feel burnt out I'm so disappointed when
I see I failed an exam I know you can
relate because we both share some of the
same experiences with ADHD can you offer
any advice on how to improve my peace of
mind as well as my efficiency thank you
very first thing my friend is to stop
labeling or stop accepting the label
that the world has given you to describe
a gift that they don't understand the
way I experience what they call
attention deficit hyperactive disorder
is this way we are all balls of energy
and we are unbounded balls of energy
meaning that our energy is not bound by
our physicality right I described in a
video yesterday how I can increase my
frequency or my vibes to such a degree
that I affect the people around me part
of the reason why are you guys enjoy my
videos is because of the vibes I give
through these videos I'm projecting my
vibration or my ball of energy out into
the world to reach millions of people
through these videos I am not bound by
my flesh you see we're all born with a
certain capacity for expansion of our
ball of energy
some people's ball of energy is bigger
than other people just based on
circumstance born that way DNA whatever
the case may be those of us whose ball
of energy whose force field of energy is
bigger than the typical individual a bit
more extraordinary is going to find it
very difficult to fit his ball of energy
into the confines and the direction of
civilization what I mean by that
when your very expensive with your
energy like I am and like you happen to
be and you go to school they are going
to ask you to shut your energy down into
this pod you're going to need to sit
then they're going to ask you to begin
directing your energy so number one
they've closed your energy down sit
there be quiet raise your hand be quiet
be orderly get in line right here I am
and here's where they're trying to bring
you understandable I get it nest they
begin directing your energy in perhaps
ways that don't really fit you so it
begins with pay attention and listen to
this person who's talking to you about
what their draw writing on a board and
then pay attention to this to this book
about something that they have decided
it's important for you but really it's
not even the teachers the teachers have
become puppets for the for the for the
for the oligarchy because what happens
is especially in the United States at
this particular point the school system
had the power has been consolidated by
the central government so an essential
government is owned by banks
corporations and ultimately whoever's
ruling the world in this particular way
and shit rolls downhill so whatever
we're being taught and how we're being
taught comes from what the shit uphill
wants us to be brainwashed with it might
go against your nature and if you're
somebody who has very expansive energy
and you're being forced in this
particular way to close your energy and
then direct it in the direction that
you're not comfortable with you're going
to freak the fuck out they call that
ADHD they call that you can't attend and
you're too much energy ADHD is a fucking
gift bro but when they give it a label
and they call it a sickness and they
give you medication and they try to heal
you from your gift you not only become
you start feeling guilty about who you
are and what you had and what you're
doing
but then you become fragmented right
because you there's a part of you that's
moving in a particular direction right
your body because that's really where
our energy comes from it comes from here
this is where we express movement is how
we express ourselves movement is how
energy is built up and moves out and you
start feeling guilty about it and and
you're fragmented that's what I'm saying
because now they're asking you to use
the one tool that they find to be the
most the ease used to control you with
you know Pavlov's dogs you know it's all
combined conditioning and now you've got
your head going against your body your
body's moving out your heads like shut
up shut down right so you've got
cognitive dissonance got your user
fighting against yourself so now you not
only are an expansive person who's been
shut down directed when I hate yourself
Yesi so I get it what do you do okay
you've made it this far you're 18 years
old you're going to college you've got a
bit more freedom in your way of life
right you're out of your parents home
perhaps and you know they're agents of
of oppression as well and now you can
start making your own choices about
lifestyle so on and so forth what are
you going to do with yourself now right
because now after they've done all that
to you they say well what are you going
to do with yourself now son
what are you gonna go be oh fuck how am
I supposed to know gonna be when you
guys just shut me the fuck down directed
me fragmented me and said go out to the
world make it big succeed we've got to
undo the conditioning and that's what
I'll share with you in this video
you've got to undo the damage that
cultivation society conditioning has
done to you and this is not a judgment
on society or civilization because I
kind of like this shit without
civilization there would be no video
cameras for me to talk to you through
there'd be no internet there'd be no
cars I mean I kind of like this fucking
game but you can't get lost in it we
give you some tools to help you navigate
this game especially when you're in
pensive dude like you and me number one
understand that we all operate on
frequencies meaning that nothing in the
physical world is actually physical you
know I mean if you just if you talk to
physicists they understand it's like
well you're hitting this you're tap
you're banging on the table but it
really is not solid it's vibrations it's
particles and vibrations doing this and
one it's a vibration vibration the way
you measure vibrations is to frequencies
you're this way and there are different
different frequencies create different
versions of expression right a frequency
that creates the the table that you
knock on is very different frequency
than water very different frequency than
air very different frequency than the
sounds you're hearing through the
speaker in your computer to receive me
but it's all frequencies
knowing this you've got to tap into
frequencies that are resourceful for
being grounded being focused being
centered do you see feelings are
frequencies and the way we tap into the
frequencies that allow us to then direct
our energy in the diet in the way we
want to it's through meditation
you've got to meditate in order to bring
your frequency into a place where you
are grounded and the type of meditation
that I engage in and which has been a
blessing to me for a decade are sound
frequencies binaural beats I meditate
with Willie there are so many different
brands of it now and there's even apps
and stuff but they call them binaural
beats all the sync is what I what I use
they should pay me royalties
well I they should pay me affiliate
income but they don't have a very good
chili program so I listened to this and
look I explained a science to a degree
that's a lot of physics I kind of
understand and point you in the right
direction but all I can say is the shit
is magical I began listening to it and
magic happens over the course of days
and weeks when I'm consistent I become
more grounded more focused more
concentrated more creative more
intelligent because I'm tapping into
stronger frequencies or more social
frequencies rather than the chaotic
frequency that are fragmented stuff down
and misdirected person ends up in ok
meditate number one I said it a hundred
times I'm saying it again because it's
that important number to exercise like I
said before your body is how you express
yourself if your body is tense tight
weak and in balanced your expression of
your energy is going to be just that you
are a ball of energy energy is moving
out of you if you are cramped in some
areas the energy that is going to be
cramped in that area if you're if you're
over the expansive or loose in some
areas of your physical body your energy
will take on the same characteristics so
when I say exercise I really mean
structural integrity focus on your
posture joint integrity exercise
routines like BOTS like yoga and a lot
of bodyweight exercises a well balanced
strength training routine one that takes
into consideration muscular imbalance
and structural integrity and then listen
very closely to the second half of my
advice with regard to exercise this is
critically important you need to do
rhythmic base exercises now I say walk I
mean this one of the things I've been
saying for years also get up every
morning and walk just walk walk for an
hour
got to walk for an hour when what is
walking it looks like this right right
if you don't see my feet you like what
I'm doing I'm bouncing right now I'm
going left to right I'm picking up my
feet I'm marching
what does this look like vibration
frequency right so you also need to
engage in exercise that not only create
structural integrity but you need to
engage in exercise routines that get you
to vibrate so I often do weird shit and
I tell you guys you should you need to
vibrate and shake just uh flike this
there's an exercise there's a little
trampoline that a lot of people use
called a rebounder and they just do this
every day they get on a fucking
trampoline and do this that needs to be
included in your routine there's no
question about it okay and then number
three diet
now when I say diet there are so many
different diets to get many different
results what I'm asking to do is to get
enrolled in a diet that cleanses your
that doesn't muck up and in fact
cleanses the your expressive capacity if
you eat foods that slow you down and you
should be able to pay attention very
closely to your reaction to certain
foods right this is how I know that I
know mostly when I eat something at
night the way I wake up the next morning
like that fucked me up heavy foods
you've got to eliminate toxins from your
diet I'm talking about processed foods
you've got to get them out of your diets
and you've got to increase the amount of
foods that help flush your system out
and support metabolic processes high in
enzymes right friend of mine told me
this is the other day you're talking
about enzymes and probiotics and there
are the only two things in your body
that actually work everything else is
structural they're mechanical so you
want to eat foods that are high in
enzymes raw foods vegetables and
foods that are high in probiotics what
I've been doing recently is I've been
eliminating many of the foods from my
diet I'm on an elimination kick right
now I'm thinking we eat too much food
and most of our food is very damaging to
our physiology so what I do is I do
micro fasting I've done videos about
this on my other channel but basically I
just take in micronutrients including
some enzymes and probiotics
I got amino acids fatty acids and greens
supplements in there I need that all day
long that's what I eat all day long tons
of energy I feel great at night because
you know I'm a bodybuilder to strength
you know I am happy in this particular
way so I eat a normal meal at night it's
usually some chicken or beef and some
vegetables and I feel good this way this
is a diet that works for me but you've
got to figure that out for yourself what
I'm saying pretty much basics the other
thing is you got to drink a lot of water
there's all types of ideas about water I
drink Voris osmosis water a friend of
mine it's really trying to convince me
about Keegan water these are the things
you need to do to take care of your
physiology to diet number three and this
is kind of where it now we're getting to
how to because what I just shared with
you is how to free the constraints of
your energetic expression right you've
got to meditate to bring a solid rhythm
to your frequencies you've got to
exercise to bring structural integrity
to your physical body and then vibrate
that body shake that body and you need
to cleanse your body and support your
body with nutrients now finally what are
you going to do right what are you going
to do after that because that's here
that's your tool that's your weapon
that's how I often say this is your
weapon this is your tool this is your
game piece those three tips take that
with you to the grave but now when you
do it your game piece you now need to
direct your energy in a direction that
is resourceful for what God wants to do
through you not what the world has told
you you need to do okay when I say God
that's just the labels just name it's
whatever you want to call it
but there's some animating force that is
that is sort of guiding you in the same
way that there is an animating force
that guides the Acorn into becoming a
tree the particular type of tree that is
going to be and the way the branches go
just like a a corn comes out of the
ground and move and then the trees
branches move in the direction that's
going to grow you too if healthy and get
out of the way grow in a unique pattern
just like I'm looking at all these trees
out here some of them are the same type
of tree but they all look very different
because they're moving in the way that
God or the the The Blueprint creator of
all this thing has asked it to you've
got to move in that particular direction
also get in touch with that and a part
of that is getting in touch with your
particular way of understanding the
world and then expressing it so I'm
going to share with you my tool okay
now I'm going to share with you this is
this is just one way that I like to
teach myself things I like to learn I'd
you know and what I'm trying to memorize
something and same way that you're going
to need to memorize when you're school I
draw pictures you see and this is maybe
an interesting one to you guys i might
make a video about this one day because
it's movement and self-expression i drew
this one about a month ago this has been
sitting here right and i got colors
that's the other thing right strongest
version of you movement expression
functional anatomy muscular system
disintegration told toward integration
see these are all ideas that i'm using
to put together as perhaps a video
series or a book or something and what
i'll also do is check this out here's
another whiteboard that I created a few
months ago okay you see I even draw
pictures they're resourceful for me so
you got to get in touch with your
learning style your learning style is
going to be just as unique as all the
trees that I'm looking out out out here
a really good program that talks about
learning styles is uh advanced learning
techniques
I believe that's what it's called by
Brian Tracy I'd invite you to get that
study that study that like a madman
because there's so many different tools
and techniques that you could experiment
with to find out what works best for you
I discovered very early on that I need
your pictures I got to draw pictures on
any colors I need to look at shit to
really absorb it and then what I need to
do which is really cool because this is
how I make my way in the world I've got
to teach it in order to really embody it
you see so the more I make these videos
the smarter I get because I'm teaching
really I'm teaching myself oftentimes I
watch my videos I'm like hi who thanks
for telling me that Elliott Hulse so I
teach and I've got to express the thing
that I'm trying to learn you know
oftentimes I share things with you guys
that it's because I'm trying to learn it
myself and I happen to think it might be
resourceful first so I share with you so
that's it my friend very long video I'm
sure i'ma check the clock yet your gift
did
the world seeks to destroy your gift
don't let them use these tips that I
shared with you in this video to
maximize your capacity and expand
yourself such that your gift can be a
gift to the world
done