we all today we got a question for my
buddy Thomas he's uh he's looking for
some advice on meeting the parents he's
in a relationship that's getting very
serious and the young lady is from a
very religious Hispanic family and it
would be very respectable in her
father's eyes if he were to come and
introduce himself before the
relationship started to grow even more
serious than it already is
he says you have any advice on this I'm
nervous because I really love this woman
she told me not to worry that her
father's a pretty nice guy and he won't
turn her away she says that he just
wants to make sure that the guys his
daughters are dating aren't messing
around and just looking for a good screw
right but he says I can't help it Eliot
I want to make a good impression the
best impression I want to walk out of
his house that night with him thinking
damn that's the guy I want to see my
daughter with so he has a lot of
appreciation for this woman he says he
doesn't want to just fuck her in fact
she's a virgin and she doesn't wanna
have sex till they're married she's 21
he's 23
both are college students intelligent
ambitious and both are on the right path
to becoming the strongest version of
themselves man you got a lot of stuff
going for you brother cares about her
deeply wants her father's approval how
do I go about this because I'm very
nervous a number of things do things
specifically number one you I invite you
to get over the idea that perhaps there
is something that you can do that will
influence another person at a visceral
level meaning you can never know how a
person is going to receive you you can
always offer yourself in the most
resourceful way that you deem fit for
the circumstances you do your best but
you could never get hit on this so
you're a hypnotist never get him to say
this is the type of guy I want to see
with my daughter
damn he's perfect right cuz you never
know what he had for dinner last night
he might have had sausage and peppers
and he's all fucked up and stuffing his
diarrhea and his wife was yelling at him
earlier because he's been farting in his
tanks and you show up and he's like who
is this guy and then you walk in wearing
Cologne that makes him even more sick
and he's like I can't stand him ah I
don't know what it is but I want to
throw up he forgot that he had the
peppers and his wife hates him cuz he's
farting and that smell makes them even
more sick you don't know what's gonna
happen bro never get attached to what
you would like the circumstances to be
in the future all you can do is one
thing and that's not to say that he
won't love you I'm just saying
release yourself from the attachment of
what it's going to look like you set
your intentions but never the details
because the details gonna work
themselves out you know what's gonna
happen so be okay with that be okay with
what could potentially happen even if it
doesn't match the story you go for
yourself right I'll be attached there's
only one thing you can do and this is
the second half of my piece for you
there's only one thing you could do my
man and that is to be completely
authentic transparent real and just
yourself and damn it it sounds like
you're a cool dude and I often say don't
get caught up in what to do focus on who
you are because what you are who you are
speak so loudly we can't hear what
you're saying be the thing right and
that's why you know personal development
so goddamn important because it doesn't
matter what you do is who you are my
friend and I'm giving you permission to
be authentic because it sounds like
you're an awesome dude
you know I can only go by what you write
here but I'd say show up and just be
yourself and then receive whatever
happens also know that relationship is a
ongoing process of course first
impressions are very important but no to
that what impresses is only 50% of
what's being impressed upon you do your
part God the universe her daddy are
going to take over for the other half
you're not in full control here before
you meet her father before you go into
the circumstances before you walk
through the door that day give yourself
a moment of clarity Claire
meditation you're way up in your head
and we all tend to be up in our head
especially when we've got arduous
challenges ahead of us but I invite you
just to take a moment to clear your head
perhaps the day before the day before
clear your head of all the stories and
let it go become at one with the moment
as you're clearing your mind and carry
that serenity with you when you approach
the father a number of things are going
to happen when you do that especially if
you take some time perhaps 24 hours
before you go number one when you shut
off your brain and you become at one
with the moment it's just been my
experience let me know in this shit a
long time beautiful ideas are going to
pop into your eye into your mind about
what you could do that you would have
not seen before because of your anxiety
you're going to say to yourself you're
going to be sitting there completely
clearing your mind of course you have
the intention on being a great example
for this father sit there gonna clear
your mind off Suns gonna pop into your
head
she said that he loves cigars I'm gonna
bring my box of cigars
you see something like that sit there
clear your mind says my father really
likes sausage and peppers and all so
much it's gonna rise up into your
consciousness because it's it's
unconscious a lot of things we take in
you taking lots of information
unconsciously and it settles down into
our body when we shut off our brain it
pops up right that's why when you can't
remember someone's name and then you let
it go it pops up so a lot of magnificent
shit's going to pop up into your head if
you turn if you if you clear it you know
if you cut so full you can't put
anything at it empty it so that
beautiful stuff rises up and you're
gonna be like ah why didn't I think of
that what you couldn't think of it
because you're all anxious to shit
overthinking sure if your brain for the
wild meditate
and when you're presenting when you're
being with him when you're in the
circumstance proceed from the same place
of a clean slate have no have no agenda
except to be authentic loving and open
with the gentleman that's it
that's a lesson for all relationships
bro done