so got this question from our friend who
is friends with a girl at school and he
just wants to remain friends with her
but everytime they start having
conversation you know they become a bit
intimate in their speech he starts
feeling like he's falling in love with
her now they're not boyfriend and
girlfriend at all at all but he
recognizes warm feelings his physiology
your body
my friend is telling you oh I'd love to
just rest in this woman and that's
really what she's providing for you
that's really what women amongst many
many many other things but
physiologically provide for a man is a
place to rest right that's where we
ejaculate that's right what happens
after you ejaculate you rest we build
our our energies and we can rest in a
woman and a good woman is one that your
body feels it can rest with can relax
with and that's what's happening you're
recognizing the physiological responses
in your body towards this woman that's
saying why do you do when people fall in
love they do this Waiting to Exhale
right why do you exhale what happens
when you exhale you rest so there's a
physiological response towards this
woman that makes you want to rest but
his head and saying no no fuck that shit
I feel it but I don't want to have any
relationship with it whatever reason
right that's a choice you've made your
body's telling you one thing your head
is saying another perhaps it's for the
best but he starts getting jealous when
she talks to other guys so he doesn't
want a relationship with her but his
resting place ends up having someone
else crawling in it when he gets real
anxious right because your body sees her
as a resting place and now like there's
this other dude that's like he's getting
real comfortable with her he finds he
that there's a resting physiological
response in his body to so he's over
there talking to your resting spot and
he might be resting or thinking about
resting in her spot which you would like
to possess your body wants but your mind
is like no this is not fair and there's
all this fucking confusion going on here
how do I deal with this man I don't want
her but I do want her and when someone
else has her I feel horrible I want
get upset well here's my invitation
haha it's gonna be a shitty piece of
imitate piece of advice it's a shitty
invitation but don't do anything just
live with that pain because that is the
pain of life you're going to experience
that pain all lifelong forever
everything you do there's going to be
this battle between pleasure and pain
your body feels pleasure towards this
woman you're getting you're creating
pain about it there's this there's this
need for discharge in charge
it's that yin-yang experience of life
it's this Adam and Eve this good and
evil it's this thing that happens in
life where there are two there's a Sun
and there's a moon right and what you're
experiencing is pleasure in pain and
it's a battle none of them win right so
don't get too upset when there's pain
right so for example there's pain when
you see someone resting in your body
spot right might not be your spot but
your body's like so there's pain there
well don't get so attached to the pain
that you go in you like you beat up the
guy you feel resentful towards him and
then you yell at her and I want to be
friends with her anymore because now
what you've done is you've associated
with the pain too much and that's a
dangerous place to be because it's only
50% of the point the coin it's only the
other side of the coin it's only 50% of
the deal don't attach to the pain when
you start feeling pain recognize it for
what it is it's a part of the game it's
a part of life and when you have the
pleasurable feelings in your body
experience them them also experience of
also you experience the pain of course a
limb pain don't do anything about it you
experience the pleasure when you're with
the girl unless you had a couple of
drinks you'll probably do a good job
exercising the reality principle and
saying no it's best if I don't have sex
with her it's best if I don't make her
my girlfriend but there's going to be a
pleasure associated with the instinct of
your body and pain that you're creating
with your rejection of it and you're
going to experience this everywhere
unless you decide and here's the thing
unless you decide
to take action in one of those
particular directions either you cut it
off completely or you decide to make her
your official resting spot and guess
what with each one of those even when
you choose you know a great experience
right let's say let's say you choose the
one to break up with her net or - yeah
to break up completely and not be with
her now what you're going to experience
in that is painting pleasure again they
keep showing up you can't divide this
shit right so you're gonna you can make
her yours but there's gonna be pain I'm
sorry I keep forgetting you're gonna
break up with her or gonna make her like
you're just gonna ignore her but there's
plain pain and pleasure again there's
pleasure of knowing that you're relieved
from that particular situation as long
as you don't turn your head and look and
every time you turn and look ah
there's going to be pain because you
didn't end up with her so you're fucked
damned if you do damned if you don't
choose to break up with her you're gonna
deal with pain and pleasure choose to be
with her you know what you're gonna
experience pain and pleasure there's
going to be the pleasure of finally a
resting spot where I can just relax my
physiology and my energy and my biology
all of my self into this woman but at
the same time there's going to be the
conversation about but you know what I
really just want to go play hacky sack
with my friends or I want to go play
video games or I want to go and and
study I want to go get a job all the
other things you want to do that she
probably would get in your way because
girlfriends look we get in each other's
way girlfriends get in your way
husband's getting the way we get in each
other's way until we learn how to become
whole and integrate but that's in a
different video so you the real answer
is you can be damned if you do damned if
you don't so I'm saying don't do
anything but if you do you'll still be
damned
done