so I've got a lot of questions here from
multiple different people about
themselves or friends of theirs going
through bouts of depression and the
questions usually revolve around what do
I do to help myself in this state of
depression what do I do to help this
friend who's in a state of depression
and also Elliott it seems as if you go
through bouts of depression as well
which I is I'm always transparent with
you guys about how was it that you
seemed to move out of it so quickly and
then almost seemed to be stronger on the
other end you know few people are asking
this now before I get started let's make
a clarification about what I'm
describing when I talk about depression
because there are some people who I'm
going to be sound controversial when I
say what I'm about to say that have
adopted the pharmaceutical and medical
industries definition of depression
being something that is a lifelong
holding that someone carries with them
and they are now medically ill because
of it and they get to take all types of
medication for many many years and you
know they live with this personal
identification with what should be a
season in life depression is normal it's
normal to go through these bouts or
these seasons where there is chaos and
there is entropy there's frustration
there's confusion there's craziness in
your life it's happening intrinsically
and extrinsically you can personally
identify with the circumstances and the
feelings associated with that bout of
depression and stay in it forever if
you'd like which will chemically change
your body you will change you're right
yes there's a chemical imbalance and you
will probably now have to take
medication to balance that out
especially if you don't deal with it
holistically recognizing the integrated
nosov the universe yourself your nervous
system your thoughts the foods you eat
the behaviors you engage in things of
that nature taking responsibility for it
it's not a knock on anybody who has
clinical depression what I'd like to
offer are ideas that support people
who recognize these bouts of depression
in their lives and in others that one a
bit of perspective on it and perhaps a
solution or an idea that might support
them in not only dealing with the
depression while you're in it knowing
how to handle it but also recognizing
that it's probably one of the best
things that could have ever happened to
you and I'm going to explain why I'm
going to use a few different I'm going
to read essentially I've got a few
things I don't do this very often when
we read to you from two different ends
of the the thought spectrum one is very
poetic and religious and the other will
be very scientific and concrete if you
will because even those words that are
so-called scientific are also very
abstract if you will you know we talked
about a lot of things we don't actually
see in science but either way the reason
why I do this is because I find that
both science and religion can offer you
perspectives depending on what you're
most receptive to as to the realities of
your depression the natural cycles that
you experience in life and why it's not
only why it's good for you to go through
these cycles because you will evolve you
grow so the very first piece that I want
to read is from abdu l-bahá and he's
one of the founders of the Baha'i
religion faith he goes on to say that
the mind and spirit of man advance when
he's tried by suffering the more ground
is plowed the better the seed will grow
the better the harvest will be just as
the plow follows the earth deeply
purifying it of weeds and thistles so
suffering and tribulation free man from
the petty affairs of the worldly life
until he arrives at a state of complete
detachment his attitude in this world
will be that of divine happiness man is
so to speak unripe the heat of fire of
suffering will mature him look back to
the past times and you will find that
the greatest men have suffered the most
there are other passages by abdullah
bhai where he also uses the metaphor of
fire and gold where the the purity of
the gold is dependent on the heat of the
fire he also talks about a sailor who
has seen very rough waters being a far
greater sailor than the one that has
always been on easy easy waters very
poetic very religious very metaphorical
but the idea is that there are things
that we recognize in nature and in our
extrinsic world that point to the
reality for the ground to produce strong
fruit strong trees it needs to be dug up
really deep you need that you need that
pain you need that suffering you need
that digging you need that turning you
need that turmoil to get rid of all the
impurities that allow the sea to grow to
its fullest potential if you just drop
it on untitled ground the sea won't grow
or it won't grow very well generous
Ansel so very poetic I read now
something from the other end of the
spectrum that might be helpful to other
people who see the world from more
scientific light all machines in fact
must eventually break down and
scientists have confirmed that the law
describing this energy exchange in a
machine applies to all energies in the
universe this fact of nature is often
found and spoke of as the law of
increasing entropy entropy simply put is
the amount is the measure of an amount
of randomness or chaos in a system and
the law of increasing entropy is an
expression of the fact that the universe
is increasingly moving toward a state of
increased disorder and randomness left
to itself with no energy input from the
outside an energy system will tend to
break down and become increasingly
disordered our car will turn to rust and
fall apart a mountain will eventually be
worn down and so on even the expansion
of the universe itself is a movement
direction of increasing disorder
increasing entropy yet we can plainly
see that many things in the universe
tend towards increased order the
opposite of what is predicted by the
second law of thermodynamics is that
life itself has evolved as Adams became
molecules than amino acids proteins
cells multicellular for life social
systems and so on definitely a process
of increasing order and obviously
against the flow of increasing entropy
how can this be this seeming paradox
puzzled scientists for over a hundred
years until prigogine discovered the key
that order arises not in spite of
entropy but because of it
part of what he is describing or
alluding to is to the fact that there
are dissipative structures in the
universe there are dissipative or open
systems where human beings for example
are an open system or dissipative
structure where we take in energy and we
discharge energy right one of the most
obvious examples of that is we eat food
and we shit we eat food we shit we
inhale we exhale right so we're a
dissipative structure we're taking
inward dancing or an open system with
the environment we're not by ourself and
the environment is not separate from us
right so with that understanding that
we're dissipative structure I want to I
want to go on or I even highlighted this
burgers inc all these open systems that
evolved by growing by taking in energy
and matter from the environment and
dissipating the resultant resulting
entropy into their environment
dissipative structures so that's what we
are now dissipative structures flourish
in unstable fluctuating environments by
being plastic enough to handle the
variations in changes in such
environments the more ordered a complex
system is the more entropy it must
dissipate in order maintain its
existence conversely each system has an
upper limit due to the level of its
complexity of how much entropy it can
dissipate this is a key point if the
fluctuations from the environment
increased beyond that limit the system
unable to disperse enough entropy into
its environment begins to internally
become more entropic or chaotic right
it can't handle it can't handle it you
can't handle what's happening in your
environment the world is changing people
are changing your girlfriend dumped you
you you have a lot of financial stress
so this is happening to the open system
if the excessive fluctuations continue
the chaos eventually becomes so great
that the system begins to break down
until finally a point is reached where
the slightest nudge can bring the whole
system grinding to a halt breakdown
right this point which provision called
the bifurcation point by Furyk it means
to divide into two branches a decision
point a moment of truth either the
system will totally break down and cease
to exist as an organized system or will
spontaneously reorder itself in an
entirely new way increased incredibly
this reorganization is non-causal and
nonlinear with what went before it is in
no way predictable from prior conditions
own only the probability of a certain
outcome can be determined the change is
a true quantum leap a death and a
rebirth and the main characteristic of
the new system is that it has a
capability to handle the fluctuations
the input from the environment that
caused the initial overwhelm and
eventually breakdown of the old system
you break down and then you build up
stronger do you see this is what happens
with open systems either it completely
breaks down and it dies right which most
people the depression leads to death to
a degree or it grows stronger it
reorganizes at a higher level in pre-k
Gene's words the system escapes to a
higher order out of chaos comes a new
order a more evolved system the new
system has the stable builds stability
and is able to move easily is to able to
move easily in the easily exist in the
previously overwhelming high fluctuation
environment but the fluctuations
increase again to a level beyond the
system's new and higher capability for
dispersion of entropy the process will
repeat its just keep fucking happening
resulting in new internal chaos and
other reorganization at a new and yet
more evolved level
fucking hate reading to the camera but I
thought this is important for you guys
to hear so you can see that the Mystics
and the Philosopher's you see that their
religions and the science all point to
one reality when it comes to entropy
depression frustration anxiety pain
disillusion it's just a natural part of
the process of becoming a stronger
version of yourself
it happens to us spiritually and it
happens in the world physically so my
point here is to show you multiple
different ways to see how depression is
not only normal it's essential and be
grateful for it because it allows you to
reorder yourself at a higher level
every time I experienced a bouts of
depression I come out on the other end a
different person doing different things
but it's because I'm aware of what's
happening and I'm looking I'm aware I
want to see the opportunities as they
present themselves to my to me instead
of falling into the depths of a spiral
down depression because I'm personally
identified with what is happening when
I'm upset and this is what I invite you
to try and experience do not latch on to
your depression do not personally
identify with your depression see it as
you see winter and winter always leads
to spring and summer again see it as you
see nighttime nighttime becomes daytime
again see it as you see the breaking
down and the building up of your body
catabolic anabolic it is a process
that's natural for spiritual evolution
and physical evolution in the world
I'm done