what's up gentlemen today we have a
question from one of our friends he's 21
years old but he was born with a
condition called spina bifida that has
left him wheelchair-bound
he's a very active gentleman he engages
in wheelchair basketball he plays rugby
he kayaks he does a tremendous amount of
activities to keep himself moving and
it's a clear indication that he has a
high self-esteem he feels good about
himself although he is in a wheelchair
this is great this is awesome this is
incredible the only concern he's having
now is there are circumstances in which
he needs to assert himself aggressively
and he can't find a way to confront
people because he's sitting in a
wheelchair ''tis several feet shorter
than them how do I go about this because
clearly this is going to be an issue
that will follow you your entire life
you understand this and that's why
you're asking this question it's
something you're going to have to deal
with because this is your plight and
you've got another 50 60 years on this
planet how are you going to confront
people it reminds me of when my oldest
daughter was very young maybe two three
years old really when children start
asserting themselves they start saying
no they start knowing what they want
they become tyrants in a way you know
this why they say terrible twos and
stuff like that so are two years old my
daughter's behaving in ways that I'm not
satisfied with and I've got a teacher
something and I talk to her you know you
can't punch the little girl in your
class things like that and not knowing
any better not raising any children at
that particular point I would I would
stand tall it looked down at her and I'd
say is well you can't do that you
punching people in the face because you
want their binky is not a good idea
right and my wife at one point
recognized that I wasn't getting through
to her now women are generally a bit
more in tune with how to behave with
children they've got oxytocin they've
got different hormones that bring them
more into communication they can
confront children a bit easier
especially if they're you know it's your
own child and my wife stopped me one day
when I was speaking to his Abell and she
hang out this is what you need to do she
gets down on her knee she gets down on
one knee and looks Isabelle face to face
and begins explaining what needs to be
done what's appropriate nuts what's not
appropriate and engaging with her at
that level face to face interesting that
that word confront Latin con meeting
with front meaning face lookup the
etymology etiology etiology I can't
pronounce the word of the word confront
with face now if you're seated and
you're looking up at people and you're
looking to confront you like to confront
them you're gonna have a difficult time
because you're not with face your face
is at his belly and he's way up here
you're never going to connect you're
never going to make that communication
potent and visceral with that individual
in the same way that me standing several
feet above my daughter looking down to
talk to her never really connected with
her on that on that visceral level on
that body level when I say visceral I
mean it a feeling level so here's my
invitation to you and and I'll tell you
how I came to this also when you find
yourself in a circumstance where you
need to confront someone maybe not
aggressively in the in a way that you
need to beat the shit out of them you're
in a wheelchair it probably won't happen
you know I'm sure you understand this
you're not looking to fight but you need
to assert yourself in certain
circumstances where someone needs to
understand something you see there's a
very big difference between aggressively
asserting yourself with the will to to
be violent and confronting someone being
with faced with another individual so
that they may come to understand what
you're trying to portray it's going to
take quite a bit of skill and practice
but you will find that
people in your environment will respect
you deeply and they'll know exactly
what's going on when you say these magic
words when you say these things and
here's the thing because you're going to
have to invite the other person to
participate with you you're probably
going to have to wait until there are
you're not gonna be able to use this
every day you're gonna have to wait
until there are circumstances where you
really need to use this tool and you say
to the person without ever giving away
what it is that you're feeling at that
particular moment just yet
someone's wronged you maybe they don't
even know that they've wronged you you
know but you like to rectify the
circumstance so you say to them excuse
me sir could you please do me a favor
and of course you're a man in a
wheelchair he wants to do you a favor
sir could you please do me a favor come
around the counter and come over here
and then he's going to come close to you
and then ask him just ask him say would
you mind coming down so that I might
speak to you he's not going to say no
unless you know it's one of these
circumstances where like you know he
screwed your girlfriend and now you guys
are gonna knuckle up which probably
won't be the case it'll be something
like you know a restaurant where someone
didn't understand your order please sir
may you come down I'd like to share
something with you I need to tell you
something okay and when that person
comes down what you are now actually
doing for the first time is being with
faced with someone
confront your with their front
prior to this you're looking up at them
trying to explain something and they're
never at your level okay and that's one
way to make this happen
what you've got to understand about
communication is that it's all about an
exchange of energy body language is the
first place where someone perceives your
energy that's why they say that what you
speak is not nearly as important as what
you are where I've said this this is a
Ralph Waldo Emerson what you are speak
so loud I can't hear a damn thing you're
saying right people perceive your body
language ninety percent more than they
actually get your words okay so what you
do with your body is going to be very
important and how you invite
them to participate with you using their
body is going to be very important with
that for that exchange of energy so a
number of different ways that you can do
this beyond simply just having the
person kneel down next to you so that
you can speak to them is to touch them
when you touch someone they're
immediately for the most part you know
I'm not talking about hysterical people
of course the comments section is always
filled with people who have you know
devil's advocate which is great but you
got to understand I'm coming from a
perspective that perhaps we're all
level-headed individuals you know and
and if you're dealing with people that
are that Kate and in that moving in that
way then simply move off you see okay
don't when they come down put your hand
of course he's going to come close to
you and he might put his hand on your on
your chair if he does that that is a
good sign because it means he's he's
willing to work with you put your hand
on top of his hand it's awkward at first
touching is always awkward at first but
because it's stimulating you see what
happens is we get caught up in the um in
the actual confusion of the stimulation
as opposed to the simulation itself so
people get uncomfortable people feel
they've got uncomfortable feelings but
they don't know what to call that's why
we say awkward when you put your hand on
them when when there are so many
different circumstances through which
people feel awkward when you stare at
them we just just look at someone and
breathe it's awkward it's very awkward
and the reason why it's awkward is
because people don't know people are
stimulated and they don't know what to
do about that and they're in a very
resourceful place when you get them in
an awkward circumstance when you make
people feel awkward they're far more
receptive because they don't have an
immediate behavior they don't have an
immediate response for it awkwardness
comes when you don't know what to do
next you're like oh right so you put
your hand on his and he goes own and you
teach him what needs to be
done next listen to me closely you say
and you in part your piece while looking
in his eyes the entire time I gazing is
very important it's a bit of course it's
confrontation it's with face you've got
to I gazed let to look at people in
their eyes when you're speaking to them
especially if you're trying to portray a
potent message something that's
important to you something that you'd
like to have done not too long ago I had
a live coaching session you know once in
a while someone will hire me to work
with them for a few hours whatever
they're dealing with not too long ago
was a gentleman he was about 6 for quite
a bit taller than me I'm about 5 9 and I
needed to impart some information on him
now you guys who watch these videos you
have no clue how tall I am because I'm
looking right at you whatever level you
put your iPhone or your computer but
with him you know I have to come across
as listen you've got to you need to
respect what I'm about to say you need
to receive what I'm about to say but I'm
looking up at him in the circumstances
that we the circumstance that we had
what we were doing the exercises that we
were engaging in I couldn't ask him to
come down
he wouldn't it wouldn't be appropriate
for the circumstance and it might not
always be appropriate for you to have
the person come down so like I said with
regard to touching you're going to
create a circumcision where now you can
impart your energy upon that person and
I remember having this conversation with
the gentleman and before I as you set
the scene for what you're about to say
this is all so I'm dropping a lot of
stuff on you guys here today one of the
most important things you got to
understand is that when you were going
to impart information you've got to set
the scene we had to create an
environment for them to receive it to
become receptive right you're going to
make them help them yield into what
you're about to share we've got to
seduce that's another way so he comes
and I need to seduce him into being in a
receptive mood for what I'm about to say
to him and I simply do this
I put my hand on his heart right here is
about this much hold my hand on his
heart and I said you listen to me you
say you see now that person is not
confronting me but I've got my hand on a
very a very potent area of the body
filled with all types of energy the
heart we've got three centers that are
filled with most of our our grew our
energy for receiving and delivering
that's the head most obviously that's
why all you see is my fucking head when
I make these videos is that's how I'm
getting you but there's also the heart
and just getting heart to heart with
someone you know mono e mono face to
face heart to heart heart to heart no to
heart to heart talk is it's not
figurative it's literal sometimes you
literally need to get on the heart level
with someone to con hearts to con
passion right to work with them on the
heart level so you put your hand on
their heart if they're taller than you
or even shorter than you sometimes one
of the things I do is regard to the
heart level of the heart is you know I'm
the giant in my house
taller than my wife control of my
children and if I really want to impart
my feelings towards them on a heart
level my wife I squat down so that I can
Harbor at the heart level and sometimes
it takes quite a bit of maneuvering I'll
have to squat down she'll have to put
our hands over me and I have to come up
underneath so that our hearts are
touching when your hearts are touching
when you're hugging someone you're
exchanging very potent energy with them
my children also you know people like
the hugs I hug I'm down at the hip when
it's time to show my love to my child
the heart literally has to be engaged
with heart so that's it my man look this
is cool you recognize the need for your
ability to confront understand the roots
of what that actually means with face
get face to face with people but know
that it's an exchange of energy that
matters more than what you're actually
saying and if that means you can simply
touch that person's hand touch their
heart or lower your tone one of the
things that draws people close to you is
if you slow down and lower your tone
especially if you're looking deeply in
the eyes change the energy if
everything's hectic and crazy you take a
deep breath and you talk slow and
controlled it's one of those awkward
circumstances where people are like they
don't know what to do so now they have
to engage with you because your energy
is so potent powerful and contrasting to
the environments done