we got this question from our buddy C
Spencer he goes on and say that I keep
trying to change people although I don't
even follow the things I say when they
don't listen to me or they don't seem to
understand what I'm saying I just keep
bothering them like pester them it has
come to the point that it is as though I
am torturing them I really want to stop
this but I don't know how I can't help
myself I apologize I say I won't do it
again
I truly am remorseful he says but I
forget I'm gonna go and do it again this
has to stop
that's cool man you know what the very
first thing I want to do is congratulate
you for being self objective that
basically means being able to remove
yourself from yourself
and look down on yourself as if someone
else is looking at you right now it's
they look down on I mean like looking
down like poor you but like just looking
at yourself from from the side like holy
shit like look at what I'm doing a lot
of people so wrapped up in their own
subjectivity that they can't see
themselves and I think that's probably
one of the most if not the most
important success tool is to remove
yourself from yourself and look
objectively and be realistic about like
I'm an asshole right now or damn I'm
doing a good job goes both ways you got
to be able congratulate yourself when
you're fucking boss but you also got to
look at yourself and like I'm a fucking
asshole so good for you next you know I
can I can relate to you a little bit
with regard to compulsion and that's
really the issue that I want to wrap
this video around right now not so much
what you're doing telling people what to
do and I have some ideas about that also
but let's first deal with you with your
compulsive nature because I'm very I
feel the same way I feel very compelled
right you when you say your compulsive
it means you're compelled to do
something I've got all kinds of
compulsions and impulse you know if
you're impulsive that means you just do
it you feel the compel the the compost
right the compulsion and then you're if
you're impulsive you just you split it
you spit it out that's what you're doing
you got you're compelled to say certain
things and you are impulsive you don't
shut the fuck up you just say it so when
I was a kid I grew it you know I grew up
in Long Island New York I went to school
and in elementary school I was
considered a you know a distraction you
know an ad dat HD you know the H is
important hyperactive child and you know
it was unreal for the learning
environment I suppose depends on what
you call learning to have this kid me
always blurting out in class always you
know I'd get up and I'd walk around I'd
say whatever I wanted to say raising my
hand fuck that I said what needed to be
said when it was time to be said because
I knew the answer or or if I had to say
something to someone across the room
even though the teachers talking about
some shit that none of us care about I'd
yell across the room and I'd say it and
I get it right because the way the
system is designed you need to sit down
and shut the fuck up and that you know
that yelling out and burnout and being
very compulsive just don't work in this
system works pretty well for me right
now though so you know I had to take
medication and they had you know I had
to learn how not to be that particular
way and an medication enforcing someone
doesn't really work so I grew resentful
to that because of that and you know I
grew up living with guilt
for my for what's happening in my body
you know and you're starting to
experience that right now because you've
got this compulsion and you're looking
at yourself objectively good but if you
can't stop it or you start to lose
friends or things just start don't work
out for you in life you're gonna feel
guilty about who you are guilt is one of
these things where you've got a moral
judgment placed on a natural impulse
what's happening in your body is natural
and I say natural I don't necessarily
mean that like you know natural like the
same way you take a shit but natural in
that this is who you are it's an
expression of who you are based on your
DNA or genetic structure your
experiences birth order there's so many
different things culture and it's just
happening you know it's it's a it's
spontaneous and then you put it you
place a moral judgment on it so you're
gonna start feeling guilty about
yourself as I did until I discovered
something really powerful number one was
the idea that there's nothing wrong
with me and there's nothing wrong with
you your particular brand of compulsion
telling people what to do now that might
be we need to talk about that later
maybe we'll talk about in this video
depending on how long I want to talk but
the fact that you're that you've got
this particular impulse doesn't make you
a bad person but you've got to find a
way to discharge a resourceful way to
discharge what's happening in you right
you it's if you could just imagine the
energy begins being stimulated in your
body it starts rising based on the
experience the circumstance if someone's
talking about something and you think
you have the answer and then the energy
starts rising in your body right you
feel it you'll know that the energy
begins rising in your body and that
you're ready to spit something out
because your jaw will get tight right
because at first you're gonna start
talking you're gonna start like wanting
to hold yourself back your belly may
become tight mine that's the first thing
that happens to me my belly becomes
tight I tighten my belly and I'm like
and when I tighten my belly it's almost
like I cut myself off from my balls and
then you create an ungrounded energy so
now you're not you don't have your feet
on your ground on the ground anymore
right you're not breathing into your
balls you're because you're ready to ah
explode right you just gotta get it out
right and you can't keep yourself bad
notice yourself to notice how you feel
in your body when you're about to start
telling people what to do how are you
breathing can you feel your feet any
longer or do your shoulders start rising
right coz this energy rises in the body
start getting like this notice yourself
just pay attention pay attention to your
body this is what I'm this is what I'm
asking you to do I often answer these
questions of the psychological character
with the body go back to your body
how are you breathing are you breathing
deeply softly do you have muscular
tension in your face your jaw your neck
your shoulders your hands notice like
you know do you start like doing this
with your hands or start tapping your
feet right means you've lost control
calm your body down or you know what
just look at it first just look at your
body recognize what's happening and then
instead of trying to make yourself not
speak out look at how you could relax
your body
now forget what needs to be said or you
think needs to be said all together
right whatever this person is saying
just look they're talking go go blank
wah wah wah wah wah wah wah wah and then
go be yourself real quick apologize be
like oh I was thinking about something I
don't know whatever but come back to
yourself you might need to walk away for
a moment say I'll be right back
your best bet is to stay right there
though right in the heat of the flames
and begin noticing fuck my shoulders ok
I'm tight oh my jaw hmm starting to
grind my teeth I'm starting to chatter
I'm starting to go to bite down hard boy
my belly's starting to feel sore because
I'm not breathing that's where I am
right that's my issue always it's my
belly I'm not breathing and then try to
be with it in other words don't judge it
but recognize what you're doing look at
it and usually awareness of a thing
especially if it's unrest or swell
causes it to go away you don't have to
force it to go away it'll just go away
let your body melt in that particular
way ok
now sometimes the energy is rising so
fast and you're jamming it back down
happens so aggressively that you feel
like you're going to explode this
happens to me and this has happened to
me before in that case you need to
remove yourself from the circumstance
and go and fucking explode okay so I
describe my experiences as a child or
you know I ve go is a lot weaker when
you're a child and you just whatever
happens to need you just do it at least
that's what it was for me maybe that's
why they gave me pills as an adult I
still take classes so I go to classes
sometimes and I remember being in a
class early earlier late last year in
fact and and we're there's some
demonstrations going on
the girl who's demonstrating you know
she's using one of the other
participants to demonstrate on you know
is this form of exercise if you will
she's doing it all wrong and she's a
four-year student now I'm a one year
student I'm looking at her I'm like fuck
you're doing it all wrong
in my you know in my head I want to burn
it out like you do you want to say
something but I'm like no no holding it
back but it came so fast and I jammed it
back so quickly that I had to I
literally just got up and walked out the
room and when fuck Ida let it all out I
just had to go fucking scream everybody
thought I was nuts but I don't give a
shit haha
everybody thought I was nuts but you
myself in the circumstance sorted so
they didn't disturb or hurt anyone but
it rose so quickly and it has to get out
because if it doesn't get out
if you don't discharge the rising charge
in your body grows pathological you end
up having like twitches you end up
having like muscular pain visceral pain
so many of us have heart attacks because
of that think about that that energy
rising like I described before a lot of
it gets trapped right in our fucking
lungs we can't breathe right your
heart's going to explode that's how
people get heart attack so so fucking
stressed out because they don't
discharge the rising energy in their
body through exercise bioenergetics
that's basically what I'm describing to
you mindfulness which is what I
described earlier with regard to your
muscular system but you have to do this
every time we suppress an impulse
it grows perverted and when I say
pervert it doesn't mean that you want to
touch little boys penises I mean
perverted in that it becomes a
pathological or a pathological
expression of it will show up later
right you know you know if you're angry
and you don't express your anger it
becomes rage right people who have road
rage it's
it has nothing to do with the fact that
uh that you know someone cut them off in
traffic has to do it that you've got
months of repressed anger that I'd like
advantageous snap rah and it's ugly when
it snaps especially when its projected
towards another human being right so you
start jamming it down jamming it down
jamming it down when you want to say
something in these circles without being
mindfully aware of what's happening your
muscular system or discharging it
appropriately at perhaps another time
even right you can go home later and the
charge seems like it's subsided but go
home and beat the shit out of your bed
go punch a punching bag and yell
vocalizing the the charge is very
important it's really important to yell
yelling is really critical to the
release of this built-up charge it sort
of reduces a lot of tension in our inner
tube so that we could finally breathe
deep once again and and that's it man
yeah if you don't let it out it grows
ill and then you end up having heart
attacks cancer all types of diseases
that people are we're becoming we're
coming to this point where we're
starting to recognize a lot of it's
psychosomatic we're creating it we're
doing it ourselves but it's because no
one's offered us these release valves or
the mindful awareness that I'm
describing these videos done