yo Elliot what's up guys today we've got
a question from our friend a he wants to
remain anonymous when a doesn't stand
for anonymous it stands for what his
real name is we'll just call him a and
essentially a his girlfriend was
recently diagnosed with Crohn's disease
and those you who are familiar with this
disease is quite debilitating I have a
couple friends who have suffered with
Crohn's disease and it's not a pretty
thing oftentimes they're in severe pain
and the thing is that the medication
that the doctors put her on has
suppressed her immune system so ever
since the diagnosis she has been on and
off really sick all the time and she
can't she just can't work she can't do
anything she's looked poor energy low
energy because of a mix of the disease
and the medication now a has tried to
share various different holistic
approaches to helping her heal herself
Crohn's disease in many ways can be
rehabilitated through diet and lifestyle
there's incredible book titled patient
heal thyself by jordan rubin i were
there several years ago very incredible
health practices that we should all
consider but this guy had Crohn's
disease and you'll look on the cover of
the book there's one picture of him he's
like really gaunt lee it looks like he
was in a concentration camp and there's
another picture where he's all jacked up
and looking good and stuff and uh and
again i have had friends that have been
rehabilitated to a degree from the
disease but uh but she can't participate
in any of these healthful habits he says
because she lives at home with her
parents and maybe her parents have had
nasty habits and maybe that's why she's
sick but anyway the thing is here he'll
goes on to also mention that she doesn't
have a dream it's interesting that you
put that in there because you describe
the entire question and then you say oh
by the way she doesn't have a dream
that's great man he wants to know what
can I do to help support her become the
strongest version of herself given all
these circumstances so a man you
to answered your own question by sharing
the fact that she doesn't have a dream
what I want to do is ask you what your
dream is buddy why are you with this
young lady are you with her because you
want to develop a life with her do you
want this to be your life partner do you
see yourself living the rest of your
life or significant portion of it
together with her raising a family
together living together and having a
future together because that's you know
one of the things that we do when we
find women we decide is this going to be
my life partner if you feel that she's
gonna be your life partner then you've
got a dream and all you gotta do is make
sure that she's on the same dream boat
that you're on or because really you
know all of this really is contingent
upon the sentiment from which of
proceeds are you with her because of
guilt you feel like you should a lot of
times that happens especially when
someone that we love gets sick we stay
with them because we should we're
supposed to she was really cool when we
were dating earlier on she got sick and
now I can't leave her cuz her life's
bucked up and I'm gonna make it more
fucked up so that's called moving or
proceeding from the sentiment of fear
guilt is a byproduct of fear and it
never works out really well you know
oftentimes we say that we stay with this
person out of a sense of loyalty but if
you dig deeper oftentimes it really is a
sense of guilt no judgment I'm just
saying make sure that you take a look
clear look at what your underlying
sentiment is your real reason for being
with her right let me and you stay with
her cuz the pussy's real good I don't
know did you ask yourself that question
what is it that is keeping me with this
woman and if it is your dream for your
future together then man you just got to
make sure she's on that same but with
you by enrolling her in that vision
recently we did a every month I do a
live Q&A for all of you guys all you
shrunk camp all my numbers and someone
asked what I thought were the most
important things for a relationship to
last you know given that
and I have been together for so long and
I I kind of deferred because it was like
one of the last questions after two
hours nice a question I was like Colleen
she's in the other room what do you
think babe what is it that allows a
couple to stay together and feel so
strongly about each other for so long
and she as she always does give such a
brilliant and insightful answer she says
make sure that you trust that your
partner and you are committed to the
same vision for your lives I mean I kind
of was like take him back on my damn you
should be answering these questions
calling but she was like just that you
have to have trust that the other person
is as committed as you are this is the
way she said it you have to have trust
that the other person is as committed as
you are to the vision for your life
together damn that was good so you got
to check that out man is she is
committed to granted that this is the
vision for you I'm going to kind of go
with that one because it's far more
interesting than you like the pussy and
that's why you're with her that you're
that you're you've got this vision for
life together and if you can really get
her to enroll in that dream really have
her visualize and and feel in your body
at a visceral level what that could be
like how beautiful a future that might
be then it's a matter of having her
understand that I'm as committed as you
are let's do this thing one of the
things that's going to be associated
with that is you getting a little
healthier how about we buy you some
healthy food in the house even though
mom and dad can't support you right
because then it's more it it's far
easier to get someone to agree to taking
action steps towards a stronger version
of themselves if they do have a dream
right you know given given that i often
sound like a sexist when i say things
like it's okay for a woman to have a
dream of being a mom and wife you know
her dream doesn't have to be a fucking
astronaut
that doesn't make you make this doesn't
mean that you're winning more as a woman
because you want to be an astronaut or
you know a banker but perhaps being a
good mom I don't think there could be a
better goal for anyone on earth male or
female than being a good parent will you
say babe imagine we could bring forth
offspring that will serve other people
and make this world a better place
because we're so awesome we're stronger
versions of ourselves so this is it
madam I'm trying to help you with this
dream but I think you need to get clear
on what your dream is with her get her
on the same damn boat and then move
forward either that or cut it off done
Elliot's it what
[Music]