it what's up guys it's been a little
while since I set up this tripod and
wrapped with you so I figure today after
about two weeks of mayhem I set up the
camera here for you guys and do a little
bit of a recap or reflection on the
experiences I've had the past few weeks
so those who have been following channel
for a while those of you who are shrimp
camp fans you know that I had the shrimp
camp challenge last week now before the
challenge the wednesday before the
challenge challenge was last saturday
not this saturday just past saturday
before that thursday i was lucky enough
to interview a lot of very fascinating
people those of which many of you know
Dana Linn Bailey Brandon Carter Owen rsd
Tyler and a few others that you'll be
able to watch those interviews over on
my strength camp channel probably in the
next few weeks to few months we've got
so much footage from the past two weeks
that I can't promise you when it will be
out but it will be out for sure so if
you're not a strength camp fan or you're
not a subscriber to my strength camp
channel make sure you do that if you're
interested in seeing me interview play
Barbara Walters with these people it's
probably a little bit more like Arsenio
Hall than Barbara Walters but I think
you'll enjoy it either way so reflection
reflecting man tell you what I woke up
this morning and I dropped off the kids
at school got to the office that's my
office here set up the tripod and stared
at this camera for about 10 minutes
because I don't know fuck to say cuz
there's so much that's gone on I didn't
know where to begin and I think it might
take me a little while to get the ball
rolling again especially with regard to
gathering my thoughts and presenting
them to you in an entertaining and
informative way but today is just gonna
be a jumbled mishmash of my experiences
over the past two weeks cuz it's been
plentiful it's been abundant so we into
those interviews on Thursday then Friday
we also decided to take everyone who
traveled to Flora in order to do those
interviews with me to a beach when my
favorite beaches
down st. Pete and have a little fun we
had lunch we chilled out a little bit we
spoke we made some more interviews and
videos I think if you're a subscriber to
many of the other people's channels
you'll probably see pictures and videos
of some of our escapades so definitely
sign up and check out Brandon Carter's
and Owens and Frank yang created some
period fascinating fun pieces for you
guys at least he recorded them I don't
know if you got loaded uploaded them yet
but go over to check those guys channels
out we did that on Friday it was a great
day on Friday Friday evening we went
over to the florida state fairgrounds
where we set up and had registration for
the over 150 competitors athletes that
came in and tried out their skills for
the truck cab challenge we had three
winners in each category and if you
follow me on instagram which you should
you'll get a chance to see those guys
and learn their names and see what it
takes what kind of people are rewarded
with strengthcamp king status challenger
king status so go check those out
saturday alright so that was a challenge
than sunday i packed up early that
morning took my four kids wife and
mother-in-law out to fort desoto beach
we did camping we set up we we've been
camping for about the past six or seven
years it's interesting when i first
started my business I first started
strengthcamp I first started making
YouTube videos I was broke but I had one
thing in mind and one thing only and
that was creating experiences for my
family by not being able to buy afford
to buy them really expensive things but
I had the desire to give them tremendous
experiences and one of those experiences
I want to give them was to live outdoors
for a little while my parents grew up in
Belize so they kind of grew up outdoors
dirt floors and shit like that so when I
grew up in New York and my neighbors and
friends from school were going camping
and I said
mom and dad why don't we go get a tent
and go camping like our friends dude
they laughed they said no no no no son
we came to America so we don't have to
sleep on dirt floors about 20 how the
pendulum swings because now my kids have
wonderful beds to sleep in but I take
him outdoors to sleep on the dirt so we
do that we set up fires we set up tents
we um a bonfire and when I said forest
fires we go fishing and I even had the
pleasure of teaching my oldest daughter
how to play softball we were playing
catching and and she was hitting the
ball and my son Benjamin learned how to
ride his bicycle it was the first time
or was the last time I will be teaching
a child how to ride their bicycle so
those you guys who mojo most of you are
much younger than me when you have
children and when you're ready to teach
him how to ride a bike just comment or
send me a message saying Elliot I'd like
you to teach me the way of bike tutoring
bicycle tutoring for children because
I've been done I've been doing it for
the past ten years and I almost got it
down to a science I mean my oldest it
took us a little while to the several
weeks to get her going my youngest man I
took all the training wheels threw him
out there and he picked it up he fell
down several times but he picked himself
up also so it's got some bump knees and
bruises and scrapes and stuff like that
but hey it comes with the territory
right and he's a big boy now so you
could ride his bike so that was uh that
was sunday we set up tents than monday
even though we went out to the park out
to the beach to go camping i came back
to strength camp to do open gym because
i knew they were going to be a lot of
awesome people that had been traveling
to florida to watch the the challenge
and attend our after party who i forgot
to mention that yeah Danny if you got
some footage bro throw it up for the
after-party right here yeah so there are
people that came from all over the world
to either compete watch or party with us
that weekend but anyway so we saw them
on monday for open gym and then I went
back to my campsite we kept camping
until Thursday
which was thanksgiving thanksgiving
spent some time with my parents and then
friday i showed up back at the office
turned on my computer for the first time
in several days and recorded an
interview with my friend elko who owns a
company where he consults entrepreneurs
and how to build their businesses
particularly through the internet in
amsterdam and a funny thing i mentioned
it in the interview and those who are
subscribers here you can go back to the
last video or the i think was the last
video and I spoke about core values in
that video and i mentioned how although
i was being offered a free flight and
stay along with my wife you know a nice
vacation to answer damn i knew that i
was important for me to spend time with
my children especially after the drug
can't challenge I wanted to go camping
real bad I couldn't wait to take
benjamins trailing training wheels off
so I decline and my friend he'll go and
I we five we've been friends for quite a
while several years and he totally
understood so I said hey dude if you
want to do skype i can do that also so i
showed up here and did that skype
interview on friday friday night was
Colleen's 26 up 26 man he is like she's
26 still tender 36 she's 36 years old
she looks damn good because she works
out she eats well she drinks water she
takes care of herself just like her
husband and our children so health is
very important to us that's why she
looks so damn good at point 2 36 and we
had a really good time with my siblings
hers friends family so on and so forth
at our party which was to move to parts
of the party first part we did up at the
canopy which is a restaurant / bar club
in st. Petersburg by the way I haven't
drank alcohol in about three months but
we had a great time we had an open bar
and some bottle service and stuff like
that and then we took it over to suite 6
which is one of our our clubs in st.
Petersburg and I hired a male
entertainer
to shake his booty for the ladies though
there were at the party I thought it
would be funny I thought it would make
Colleen blush I thought the women would
get a kick out of it I show us he'll got
a kick out of it in fact we're really
kick me was at the end of the
performance when the young man was ready
to be paid he came up to me said hey
Elliot I didn't want to say it earlier
but I'm a big fan of your videos so that
was a little those little cool little
strange my wife freaked out even more
you know much less having some dude
shake his his panties it is panty booty
all over the place now it turned out
that he watched my videos so I guess
that's the type of crop that I'm I'm
building those are type of guys that are
watching my channel in fact I'm always
fascinated at the broad array of you
fascinating dudes watching this channel
so that was Friday night Colleen's
birthday Saturday and Sunday for her
birthday we were trying to figure out
what to do since we have such beautiful
beaches we went out to the beach went to
the don cesare spent the night at the
hotel the children had a great time I
had a great time and now I'm burnt out
and uh and we got back yesterday so here
I am just ranting with you guys this
morning and besides just my reflection
and recap of the past two weeks I don't
have anything to offer you guys that's
dumb still I'm still mentally processing
all the craziness that went down but one
thing you can look forward to amongst
all of the others all the other videos
and stuff is the launch of my king book
all about becoming a stronger version of
yourself and I use the symbol of a king
to represent that co-authored it with
chris barnard who took one of the four
sections on strength training as a part
of becoming a stronger version of
yourself I wrote the other parts on
physiological energetic and life mastery
strength so those you guys who've been
watching for a long time and sometimes
get a little confused because of all of
the information I have out there the the
plethora of videos I've made almost to
the point where some things i say
contradict
I said in the past because I'm always
evolving so I figured why not put them
all together in a single document a
single book and offered to you guys it's
called King and it also is accompanied
by a very special initiation course that
I'm going to share with you guys
probably in about two weeks so that's it
that's what's going on the land of hosts
hope everything's going well with you
guys i'll talk to you tomorrow done