welcome and every can have the human
part time we add map but anyways man so
so just just to kind of catch us up a
little bit man how did you become the
kind of truth seeker and that you know
re laying the truth that you are right
now just a just a kind of brief summary
are you recording this or this is this
you know it's recording now okay cool
alright so then I'll elaborate you know
it's funny that you said earlier that
you caramel-colored skin and and here i
am with like I've got big black lips and
blue eyes it's like what is this guy
what's actually going on there and I
grew up with that stigma I guess you
could say I'm like what are you kid
growing up in a neighborhood that's a
long island which is they say is one of
the most segregated suburbs in the in
the in the country and and Here I am
kind of stuck somewhere in the middle
and from the age of five I'm being asked
and I ultimately would ask myself what
the hell Emma what am i what am I I've
got no like all types of strange ways to
figure out what you are when you're five
years old and one kid saying yeah look
at your dick if you look at your penis
and it's brown then you're black if your
penis is pink then you're worried and
I'm like I look at it I'm like I'd still
somewhere in between so I could never
really get an answer and and I guess you
know try to keep this story as succinct
as possible I I at one point set out to
figure out what am I and I came across a
book by a guy named Rallo may called
man's search for himself and here i am
in sixth grade you know i'm like 12
years old reading philosophy by Admiral
amazed when I like the most most
influential philosophers you know for
were authors on the topic of philosophy
and I'm 12 year old kid like Rita what
man search for himself that's perfect
cuz I don't know what I am and I'm
trying to figure myself out and that
just led me on a lifelong journey of
trying to figure out
out who I am so when you asked me about
these truths it's simply because I've
also discovered along the path of trying
to figure myself out that everyone else
is trying to figure themselves out too
so when I start saying these things on
camera it resonates with people because
they're like oh yeah you know I have the
same problem although on the surface I
look like I know what I am deep down
most of us are struggling with that
question what am i what am I here for
what am I supposed to do and there's so
much confusion I think what I offer is
kind of permission to explore that sure
that seems like it's something that's
going on a lot more now than ever before
I guess what the internet and stuff like
that but now it's like we're getting all
these permission slips to be able to be
more of ourselves like we have a guy
named elliott hulse up here who is a
strength guy and he does a lot of you
know strong man shit and he stands up
there and talks but then we have another
guy who's a tech guy who's up here
talking then we have another guy who's
talking about you know psychedelics and
all these things and they're all doing
basically the same thing is giving us
permission to be more of ourselves I
think that's that's huge right now do
you see that being something is that is
kind of a turning point maybe right now
you know this whole Maya calendar thing
that was supposed to happen like a world
is supposed to end you know this year
with the Mayan calendar I think a lot of
people went about it the wrong way and I
am by no means of scholar on the subject
but you don't have to be a you don't
have to be a scientist to realize that
we're at a huge global conscious
awakening and it's because of the
fucking Internet I mean there's no two
ways about it I have conversations you
know everyone's Allah engage in like
comment conversations with people on
facebook and like they're citing all
types of incredible ideas and books and
referencing different articles and
videos and I'm like this person's
putting together a great case for
whatever it is that they're trying to
either convince themselves or convince
others of and then I go and I'll click
on their profile it's like the kids 12
I'm like wow this is crazy you know
there's a lot of there's a lot of
benefit to it but there's also I think
other thing that I end up doing that is
that's helpful for this whole stage of
our our our development as a race of
human beings is that although we are
expanding in the abstract we're learning
a lot more to have a conversation with a
12 year old kid that that is is
referencing all the things that they
reference is incredible but then we also
end up living in an abstract world
because all of everything we do is hear
everything we do is in the clouds
everything that we do is through did the
digital technology and very few people
embody any of it so we're losing a lot
of our bodily expression our bodily
knowledge our physical wisdom in order
to continue expanding our consciousness
reading thinking you know observing
taking in and but not really digesting
so it's it's it's kind of it's an
interesting time that's the time where
sometimes right diggings there's there's
a point to where knowledge becomes or
can become detrimental once you
accumulate so much and then you have to
actually start applying some of it right
yes I made a video this week and it's
probably the second time i made this
video I the message was the same but I
basically said listen turn off all the
gadgets stop reading books stop asking
questions on forums choose one workout
program just choose one and it doesn
have to be the right one just go like
this bullying and pick one and then
stick with that one because it's ended
doing that you gain power it's not in
doing the right thing because guess what
the right thing today you're gonna read
an article tomorrow that says it's the
wrong thing you know it's all so
abstract you can find a hundred
different ways to convince yourself into
or out of things but when you actually
do something you gain what is
unavailable when you're reading and
that's called experience experience
leads to wisdom you got to fucking do
something and that's a big part of our
problem right now is we're thinking so
much and talking so much that we don't
actually do anything a lot of the
knowledge that we're getting now a lot
of the things like you said is is
basically in our heads or in the clouds
and whenever
it's in our heads a lot of times that
leads to this duel dualism you know so
just like you said every for every
exercise we can pick there's always
going to be someone that says now that
exercise sucks or or for every diet that
we choose oh there's another one that's
better or whatever but what we will you
you talk about is actually doing it and
manifesting it within your body a lot of
people talk about this as becoming more
conscious within our hearts and be using
this word of heart consciousness and a
lot of indigenous people a lot of you
know ancient cultures and stuff put a
lot of emphasis on their hearts do you
agree with that we we've come to a place
where we've conceptualized that the
brain or the mind which is a better way
to describe it stops at our neck so it's
like we've got the the cortex and
neocortex and that's basically it so if
you're thinking it's all happening here
what we physically forgotten I mean it
doesn't take again it doesn't take a
scientist to look at a picture of the
nervous system to realize that wait a
second your brain doesn't stop there
there's a big thick tube that drops way
down into your pelvic floor which is
called your spinal cord and that offer
your spinal cord there are all these
branches that go out and they tie into
your muscle to tie into your organs atty
to your stomach your heart they go all
the way down into your feet so where did
your brain begin and where did it end
just because we we use this part of our
brain to analyze and calculate doesn't
mean that this part of our mind isn't
just adds or perhaps more powerful
because it's this part of your mind that
beats your heart like are you beating
your fucking heart right now can you
take responsibility can you take
responsibility for beating your heart
right now what did you have for
breakfast can you take responsibility
for digesting your food right now you
can't take responsibility for that that
you is the ego and we've become very
attached to the ego we don't realize
that there's an entire magnificent
energy the about this magnificent mind
that's doing fifty percent or perhaps
more
the work for us but yet we we ignore it
as if it's not as intelligent as this
brain nobody who grew that baby in your
belly who's growing you right now are
you growing your bones right now you
just worked out right okay cool see you
wait and you did some bench press who's
growing your muscle you didn't grow your
muscle you just beat up your muscle see
who's doing all that there is another
mind and I say other mind just because
of what you described as this dichotomy
which is truly not a dichotomy it's a
unity that we are our bodies so why have
we and I know why we have culture and
done this to us religion has done this
to us but we're at a place where we
ignore and almost hate that which comes
up in our body and when they speak of
when the agents talk about following
your heart which is also cinema
synonymous with I see you've got a
Christian cross up there and you're on
your wall if if you study if you if you
work with you know the Catholic Church
and you have ever done this what you're
basically saying is that there's a unity
there's a Trinity between the mind
father it's the father mind up here that
we become so we worship but we've come
to worship out of balance to the Sun the
Sun is more like Jesus the lover the
feeler Jesus was a feeler he was a lover
he came in and basically used his
passion they say The Passion of Christ
to to invite us to follow our hearts and
then there's this the vertical plane the
plane through which animals behave the
way we call the Holy Ghost the instinct
how is it that we're so up in here with
the father that we forgotten the Sun you
call yourself a Christian but it's like
you don't listen to your heart and the
Holy Ghost which is what ties the whole
thing together give it whatever name you
want because if you studied science
they'll call it the the neocortex the
cortex the medulla it's a Trinity it's
always the Trinity they can call your
your mammy lien which is your the heart
brain the mammalian neomammalian and
reptilian brain this Trinity just keeps
fucking showing up the problem is we've
chosen one piece of it and if ignored
the Son and the Holy Ghost or the cortex
and the medulla or the
a the mammalian and the reptilian part
of our consciousness we can't have one
without the other that's what's crazy to
me is that the more you you look into
these philosophies and religions and
science and things like that they are
all saying the same exact thing and I
mean it seems like even going further
than that like once you start to dive
you have these beacons you know of like
that you kind of look to that kind of
guide you in a direction or that kind of
give you permission to accept the ideas
that you have all of those people are
saying the same thing that the Paul
checks the you know the the Elliott
holes the Jack crews the Daniel by tell
all these different people are saying
very very similar thing just from their
own from their own unique perspective
it's it's funny because the limiting
factor in all of this are the symbols
that we're using to describe it it's all
one thing except you can your symbol
might be quarks and bosons and electrons
and his is animals and burning bushes
but the fact is they're all trying to
point to the same thing so it doesn't
matter what words you use to describe it
and the problem is that there are all
types of associations with the words you
choose to to adopt you see which is
where we get screwed up this is where we
become idlers of false prophets because
these false idols are our things words
are things ideas or things and we hold
on to well Jesus Christ is my thing and
that's it so I don't want to hear or
believe or talk about or consider
anything else that might actually make
sense and then the same thing on the
other end of the spectrum it's like well
my idea is that science is that's it and
that's all but then you also have to
consider well you know there are parts
of science that we just we might think
that we'll figure out or that we have
figured out already but really what it
boils down to it you look at like
quantum mechanics which a lot of people
say is this quackery it's because the
final answer is I don't know I think the
best place to be in all of this is I
don't know let's talk about it let's
enjoy the conversation that's what
gnosis is gnosis and Gnosticism is let's
talk about this shit because it's pretty
fascinating but let's not hold on to it
and become personally identified with
any of it because really the minute your
grasp it you lost it living within the
mystery huh embrace it ah embracing it's
so much fun it's and it's so much more
fun to write that's way I see it it's
like I don't want to be right and I
don't want the truth I'd rather dance
because you know what when do you enjoy
the dance while you're fucking grinding
not when a song has ended why are we so
so attached to getting to the end of the
song here it is I don't I just want to
keep dancing the Alan Alan Watts murders
that says he's great do you ever listen
to any uh any old Terence Mckenna so
that he may have a book of his that I
haven't read yet he makes such a good
this this type of guy he's really good
with words and he'll say words that are
just so off the beaten path that you
never heard of any has it's real funny
voice he kind of talks like this but uh
he he just kills these ideas man like
he'll take this idea of language and he
says language and he goes off on it for
a long time how languages is so limiting
to us and that the words that we use
your word for you know let's just say
loves is a popular your your word for
love and the meaning for you is totally
different right now than it is for me
and then it's totally different for you
as every moment goes by and the
conditions around us change the word
becomes different all the time but we
say I love you or we say let's let's
let's have love instead of war but we
don't even really know what that means
like and it's always means something
different and you can't prove it right
prove love so you tell you a woman that
you love her and she says prove it how
the fuck were you gonna buy her
something we're gonna say i love you how
many times you say you love me you
cannot prove love and that's kind of
like you know why does the science hop
on that one and the same way that like
we're trying to prove god it's like okay
well you know once you prove love while
you're at it it's just what this is one
of those things it's like you're not you
can't because it's experiential it's
there is so dynamic there's so many
different pieces to it I don't think at
our level of consciousness we
we're going to figure it out but let's
dance with it a lot of a lot of two
right now people are trying to disprove
all of this stuff as opposed to just let
it be like nuts that's that that kind of
leads to a conundrum here is like we're
trying to disprove all this stuff and if
we kind of get close well then what do
we have left to live for you know what I
really like what the the hero's journey
you know I heard you talked about this
before but man that hero's journey the
Joseph Campbell talks about and not not
only that but every every myth that has
ever you know been around talks about
this journey that we go on and the
journey is the myth itself like mmm
that's it the journey is the myth itself
that's so beautiful hey Joseph Campbell
brings it all together for us so how
have you do you think that when we go
through a lifetime we experience this
myth add the hero's journey as a whole
does it seem like a cycle to you we keep
we keep doing this hero's journey is it
a daily hero's journey is it a lifetime
is it a does it exist within the earth
and the Sun and those type of things
it's kind of an abstract question but
well I'll give you an abstract answer in
the same way that there are days in a
year and years in a century and
centuries in eons is the same way that
there are journeys I mean you're going
on a hero's journey in the minute you
wake up every day and every time a woman
goes through her monthly cycle and every
time the the nature changes we're
constantly evolving and I think there
are stages like you know he describes
just camel describes that we're going to
see recurring over and over again you
see so to say that there's a final point
is like saying that when today and we're
all done you know it's just an
ever-evolving thing it's like that it's
like that Trinity symbol it's like we
just keep doing this and it keeps going
around and around and I think sometimes
we're looking for we're looking for a
a purpose or we're looking for a meaning
as if it's going to go bang at some
point but it never does so the only
purpose and meaning is that which we we
adopt while we're playing this game
while we're doing the dance we kind of
choose so we're going to do the mom bar
we're gonna do some slow dancing but and
that becomes your journey that becomes
your purpose that becomes your mission
it's like what kind of dance are you
doing it never goes boom done you said
something that relates to this I heard
was this feeling that you get in your
heart you know that tells you what dance
to do this thing that that kind of urges
you in that direction that says this is
your this is your job this is your duty
go do this that you know you have to do
even though everybody around you is
saying no don't do that shit you know go
go get a real job go you know go get
your degree go do this go do that you
said if you don't do that if you don't
listen to that that feeling that you're
basically disobeying like that is God
running through you're disobeying that I
thought that was just fantastic it was
brilliant i love that yeah you really
are because again the Trinity this is
your passion and of course I rant on
science and I rants on religion I go off
on both because I I'm not satisfied with
anything so you know I go off on the
idea that there are so many Christians
it's that would cite parts of the Bible
that say that you shouldn't listen to
your heart you shouldn't follow your
heart because your heart will lead you
on certain path lova you know that are
no good so on and so forth that they
will find in you know parts of the Old
Testament was like don't you realize
that the Sun you're doing this what the
what do you call yourself a Christian
but and you hold jesus the son is like
right here motherfucker yeah how so
honestly Father the Son the passion of
christ why do you think you worship
Christ cuz he's a passionate
motherfucker so now you don't listen to
your heart right again so yes to answer
your question over so elaborate on what
you're saying you'll eat you're cutting
out a big part
of what a human a human being is a
triune being it's Paul MacLean even as a
book that's that's that describes this
in a very scientific way but there's a
try you in mind why separate one from
the other it is the most inhumane thing
that you could possibly do the problem
is we become attached to what we've been
conditioned to believe the father the
head is a very easy thing to manipulate
someone by you can't manipulate someone
who's in their passion was in their
heart try to manipulate three-year-old
kid who wants ice cream he's all here
he's all in his balls and heart it's not
going to be an easy fight but by the
time he becomes 13 and you're like oh
you can't have ice cream because he
doesn't know dinner's not done he's like
I right cool because you already he's
already done cut him off on the rest of
his body so in the same way and I'm
starting to ramp in the same way that it
that in many instances a three-year-old
or a baby will not even fear because
we're trying to condition them at that
age but a baby a newborn is hungry for
milk guess what it's going to get what
it needs if nature follows its course
that baby will be satisfied I don't
think that ends when we grow up the only
difference is that the hand of our
earthly father instead of putting the
bottle in our mouth the hand of our
Heavenly Father or the universe will
always take care of us if we speak our
hearts the same way the baby screams and
there's a bottle in his mouth I open my
big fucking mouth and say this is what I
want this is what I'm going to do it I'm
not going to stop kicking and screaming
until I get it I'm going to get it and
not only is that a nice idea which would
be great to talk about but I've done it
my life is a byproduct of me saying I'm
gonna do what I want to do this is what
I want I'm gonna go down kicking and
screaming I'll die before I not get what
I set out to get I got it now the
biggest problem is what I want next and
it's it's doing him and it's it's it's
it's not thinking about it and saying
like we have all these a lot of these
misconceptions that goes with the same
thing that you've been talking about but
you know the secret and all these things
I ask and I shall be given to
like this we we focus enough intent but
nothing happens without the action and a
lot of times the people's words the
things that we're saying a lot of times
all we're really trying to do is
describe what is fucking happening to us
you know as opposed to coming up with a
novel idea or anything that's like well
man I think that this worked because you
know week ago I was here and now I'm
here but you're just describing some
abstract idea that just happen to be
happening while you were haha what
you're doing whatever it is you're doing
that's amazing so we're talking about
this transition and unifying all this
stuff let's talk about some of the ways
that we the practical ways that we do
this so what I'm referring to here is is
some of these natural we talk natural
all the time we're always saying talking
about nature and this and that so we
have these four big huge natural
elements noble elements if you will one
of them is air right and so breathing
things like that so how do we utilize
the hand of the universe and the hand of
nature to begin to manifest this this
unification of our of our brain in our
body or our brain in our hearts or
however we want to uh to talk about it
breathe into your balls because now
we're talking about nobby Tony Robbins
has it has a way of describing us also i
mentioned in a video that's gonna go up
this week he says you have to have a
state of strat state of story in a
strategy it's always fucking three crazy
right state storage strategy and your
your state your state of being and
basically how you are feeling and the
way you're feeling dictates everything
else that's like and unto my example of
the holy ghost or in the way alien house
subscribes at your balls the way I
describe it is your head your heart and
balls you got three minds essentially in
in in like Taoism Chinese martial arts
they call it the the different dime
tienes you know that upper lower admit
Don TN it's always three when someone
says that guys
got balls it's very indicative of what
that actually means it means he's going
to do something that guy's got a guy who
has balls is a guy that's going to do
something so tying the whole thing
together means accessing your Holy
Spirit accessing your courage that's the
whole thing you know the whole thing
about like the baby who screamed for
what it wants its like because he's not
impeded by anything it's this is what I
want and I've got enough balls to scream
and cry for it even my you know my
children around four or five six years
old sometimes I'm like point in my
daughter I'm like you've got some balls
like to even ask like you just I just
gave you this and that you're asking for
that I'm a game you've got some balls so
the there's two things there's the the
abstract virtue or character trait of
courage it's courage courage is the
virtue of the balls all right so so
that's that's a story what story are you
going to tell yourself in order to make
this happen because stories are very
helpful to us you know there's so many
different ways that you can talk to
yourself you talk to you talk yourself
into doing something but physiologically
that looks like being in your body
deeply enough comfortable in your skin
they would say enough to take action in
a particular direction now this is not
your strategy you sometimes you've got
to figure out your strategy as you go
but you've got to be embodied enough
courageous enough ballsy enough rooted
enough in your own sexuality in your own
beingness to just say I'm going to do it
and physiologically exercise wise what
that looks like and mind you there this
is these are ancient forms of exercise
that may be studied martial arts and Qi
Gong and Tai Chi and yoga and the chakra
system this all sounds like crazy you
know woo mystical shit but it's like if
you really stop for a moment pay
attention to it you'll realize it's
pretty scientific and all the guys that
try to prove it in the West
they put them in jail like Wilhelm Reich
just like lock them up it's like you
you're a fucking quack but if I could
describe it in the most practical
pragmatic terms it means breathing down
into your pelvic floor and the only way
you can breathe down into your pelvic
floor so that you can embody all of the
inspiration that comes is when you
soften the muscular system around your
jaw because this is you bring in air
you're inspired right we like that word
inspired inspiring doesn't happen here
inspire is breathing in that's what it
is spire spero is the word spirit
breathing it happens here and then
there's a wave in our body then it moves
down into our pelvic floor through our
stomach into our chest and if we have a
soft inspiration way a soft respiration
wave we are grounded and we are sexual
and we are confident and we're strong or
what I call tender aggressive and when
you come from that state of tender
aggression you can totally attack the
world with not a hint of second-guessing
yourself it's just an attitude that
comes with you I recently read this book
I'm reading this book I guy named
daniela bolelli he's got a book called
on the warriors path and this is what
he's describing as a warrior said the
quintessence of a warrior for one is to
be able to to follow one's vision no
matter what and then going along into
this he begins to start to break down
these these male and female energies or
this head heart or head heart balls into
becoming this exactly what you said this
kind of a tinder Warrior because without
the tenderness who gives a fuck if
you're a warrior right like it doesn't
matter because you become too too rigid
and you don't enjoy the fruits of your
labor so who cares if you're a warrior
and then on the on the flip side of it
who cares if you're just a you know if
you just enjoy life and you sit around
and join or whatever there's no there's
no balance between it all
so though the complete the completeness
comes whenever you can do whenever you
can do both then you got a time all
together because I mentioned Wilhelm
right before they put him in jail you
got fucking died in jail because you
know he was a crazy dude but he was
basically trying to prove the existence
of Chi he called it or go but um but he
described and the other thing was he was
highly sexually charged all of his books
and all of his he basically created the
sexual revolution in the 60s with his
books but the way he often described the
energy flowing processes in an
individual was in how they had sex and
he basically was like you can basically
you can look at someone and see how
their energy is distributed in their
their physique he called a character
structure and determine what their sex
life sex life is like and they gave them
different names and the person that's
too rigid the phthalic narcissist the
and for females it would be be the the
the neurotic type for both is a
premature ejaculator just way too
charged up you know warrior everybody
thinks a warrior looks like this guess
what you're a premature ejaculator you
know as soon as your dick gets hard you
bust your nut right and that's the
sexual dysfunction associated with the
rigid type the rigidity type is also the
neurotic and also the Box assist as far
as men are concerned very attached to
holding up a particular facade you know
particular persona was like yeah guess
what do you fucking you bus you're not
too quick then there's the oral the oral
type these are there's so many different
variations thereof I'm giving you just
different extremes the oral type is also
dubbed the lover very soft very like
loving you know doesn't make any enemies
friends with everyone easy to get along
with they're almost like you can't help
but fall in love with them they're just
nice they're just really nice sexually
that guy because we're just talking in
terms of men the type of guy that can
probably get it up
because he's kind of laid back enough
it's tender enough but he's the kind of
guy that will never have a good orgasm
he'll just keep going he can stroke for
like half an hour hour goes by when it's
like when he realizes his girlfriend's
board he's like all right I guess I got
to ejaculate and it comes up one has too
much charge the other one has no charge
at all or a very low charge the balance
is where your I'm aggressive enough to
go after and get what I want because
I've got spine I've got I've got
aggression and that's very sexual but at
the same time I know how to breathe I'm
saw um Alexander Lowen broke down the
body in this way he said that the
tenderness and if you look at a dog
right the dog is very tender here the
tenderness happens in the front of the
body the aggression happens up the back
of the body so if you imagine like when
a dog gets angry what does it do
attention up its muscles back well we
get frustrated angry tense up our back
they say you have your back up and then
when someone's very relaxed and soft the
or belly like a dog when the dog wants
to love you what does he do shows you
his belly so we've got to balance this
and that's why strength training fucks
this up in so many ways I can't really
body bill too much anymore because I get
all tense here I'm gonna try to just do
deadlifts and build up my aggression and
then just stretch and soften and tap all
this I tap and stretch and soften I make
this as soft as I can make this as hard
as I can so when I come at you with the
aggression that you like I'm at my woman
with the aggression I'm coming hard I'm
attacking hard but I'm leaving saw you
see it's this regression say it's so
crazy how we can pile up so much pent-up
energy and emotion in an hour you know
the front the front of our body like
I've been breathing and and working on
you know meditating and you know all
this shit for several you know many
years especially within the last year
and a half and just recently I actually
felt like I was able to breathe
like after like 16 years I was like holy
shit I was just able Ivan had a fool it
amazing years like this is crazy see
everybody it's funny that you say that
because everybody thinks they're
breathing so they ignore the topic
completely yeah the only reason why I'm
so fascinated with it and I'm sure you
feel the same way is because I actually
breathe guys I know what it feels like
it it's fucking awesome so you just
you're so jacked up but excited about
everybody like what the fuck I'm
breathing right now you're talking about
you like get out of here breathing why
is he always talking about breathing cuz
I know what it feels like and it's so
incredible yeah it comes and goes cuz
like my wife knows tujhe you know she's
she's my partner in this whole thing so
she knows I'm not breathing she's like
my sex drive is low my performance is
low but then just the way I am around
the house it's like you're not breathing
you're not breathing go breathe and
she'll tease me and be like I go to dr.
Glaser who's might one of my therapist
or go away on your stool or go lay on
the ball like I have two sets off in my
belly by laying on a little basketball
and massaging it uh so she's like go do
some bioenergetics and and come back
when you're done go breathe and we do
that though man like you you you will
drift into this you know this female
energy a little bit and then you gotta
you know you don't get too far you kind
of you want to be self-aware enough kind
of care yourself oh shit i'm being a
little too this way and then sometimes
we'll drift over to the aggression side
be a little bit too oh god I got it kind
of you know like it's a it's a balance
man a balance of becoming I think a huge
part of it is self-aware which I guess
can only come with experience more
experience more experience different
experiences things like that you know
what we're fighting culture though too
you know what they say that it's a
male-dominated world that men rule the
world you know it's not so much a penis
driven world is not the physical penis
that rules the world it's the male
energy that's ruling our world and we're
living at such a time of Go Go Go
aggression more bigger beat war more
usual thing so to be living in a time
where that's the dominant energy it's
very difficult to just love relax
stretch breathe be at peace you fuckin
can't because all
around you is go come here the war drums
Go Go so you know it's just it's a sign
of the times we this is the day and age
we're living in because we're so male
and so aggressive we have things like
the technology we're using right now you
know I mean you if you look at different
cultures the West the West made its way
because of its aggression because it
became so head dominant because it
became so male and if you look at
countries like India where like you know
they don't die of heart attacks they
don't they're not unhappy for the most
part they're all Hindu and they're all
just kind of enjoying of course I'm
being prejudiced in a way but they don't
die of heart attacks but it's like one
of the same time it's like but they
didn't make the internet they don't have
GM motors you know they don't have
Hollywood they don't have new york city
so you got you've got like too much on
one end where it's like we all die of
heart attacks cancer and impotence and
then you have the other side was just
like well they have no technology and
everybody's kind of poor but they're
okay that it's poor because you know the
dirt so it's like with which one
hopefully now it's kind of a marriage
between the two since we have the
internet we're finding out there's so
many good ideas on that side of the
world as well as the internet with this
out of the world like you and I are you
know we're all chatting right now over
you know thin air yeah but what we're
chatting about Eastern philosophy so
hopefully that can kind of kind of turn
the tides a little bit yeah it's got to
be an integration of the two it's got to
be that tender aggression it's got to be
that yin yang it's got to be that
catabolic anabolic it's got to be that
positive negative it's got to be that
female male penis vagina we can't have
all one without the other otherwise we
suffer we are suffering because of it
yeah so let's talk about the another one
of these noble elements or natural
forces water so water is hugely
important to life right yeah absolutely
i mean we're made up of water right what
is it like 90 / saw diaz water i once
heard it described the human being as
being
a big hairy sack of water with teeth
that's okay that's pretty much what we
are yeah we carry sacks of water yeah a
lot of a lot of that still doesn't
register for a lot of people right like
it doesn't register on on a couple of a
couple of ways for one we're still not
drinking that much water you know you
see people walking around with you know
coffee and sodas and sports drinks and
energy drinks things like this and then
on the other side we are totally void
for the most part of quality of water
and and then we can go into it even
further so I don't know if you've seen
you know I watch this documentary
recently talking about water and how
water we don't basically don't know shit
about water scientifically right so
water has can carry memories water can
be structured or unstructured coherent
you know all these different terms and
things that we can carry information
within water and water you know all
these different crazy things and it
seems like we just not we're not up to
speed with many things about water yet
we might not understand here and that
word understand i'm talking like that
word a lot lately because it's like you
know understand what is that what do you
call it understand like we're standing
under I think understand is actually a
bodily experience because it's like it's
standing under it's like underneath that
which is above so anyway that's just my
weirdness but um I if we embody things I
think we we don't have to think about it
we don't need any facts about it you
know if we're living enough in our
bodies but we our energy has moved so
far up into our heads that we don't feel
what's happening in our bodies the
easiest way that I could describe what
happens so that you have a you know an
abstract idea so that you can say maybe
I should bring some drink some water
besides the fact that you probably feel
like shit but you don't know that you
feel like shit is how is it what's the
fastest way for electricity to to move
it's through water right i mean you drop
you drop a electricity you know a live
why
into water that whole thing sparks like
instantly yeah right water travel I mean
electricity track almost fastest through
water if you consider and of course you
know there are different ways you can
describe it but that our nervous system
is literally another as our electrical
system it's the fast-moving system in
our bodies not our hormonal system which
is slow moving these neural transmitters
and the connections between them are
right I think about doing this and it
happened boom boom boom you know
somebody something drops on my toe mook
it's quick as a three but if there is
not enough of the carrier of electrical
impulses from your you know a fairly
apparently then there's going to be a
lag in response you're not going to be
as smart you're not going to be as quick
you're not going to be as vital healthy
you just you're not gonna be as
intelligent if you don't have water in
your body because your brain your
nervous system cannot work your
electrical system has too much viscosity
because there's not enough water in it
so if you want to be smarter you want to
think better if you want to have you
want to be stronger because ever
basically all of this all these things
are functions to the nervous system
would have better sex won't have a
better life you want to make more money
drink little fucking water because your
electrical system will work better we
had a guy on recently Jack crews who's
talking about water and he was talking
about fluoride and he's talking about
how fluoride is a dielectric blocker
like that's why we have this big thing
about fluoride nobody knows why it's
good or bad or why it's there why is it
in our water and this and that well what
he says is that this is a dielectric
blocker so goes right in with what
you're saying is it doesn't allow
electricity to flow through the water
like it should wow really that's
fascinating i have heard many different
things about why it's not good but
that's a new one to me yeah why do we
have to scoot why are we so smart that
we gotta screw with what mother nature's
most plentiful element on this earth is
like we got to make it better right here
we go human beings always trying to make
shit better it's like oh we're gonna
make water better by adding shit to it
yeah you know and I'm ranting I had too
much coffee today anyway but you know
you can always argue depending on your
philosophical standpoint you can always
argue
that oh but human beings we we do so it
such good by reading the water of the
bacteria's and the viruses and the
pathogens that make us sick okay but it
depends on if you look at it that way
you're looking at it from a very
egocentric point of view you're looking
at it as well we're better organisms
were more important than the parasites
right and of course we don't want to die
that's our biggest problem is that were
we're so afraid of our mortality that
we've created a situation now where we
don't die in fact we're not even allowed
to die if somebody was to take his own
life he's like it's illegal can't
fucking take your life it allowed to die
right and we've gotten rid of so many
pathogens at least we think we have
we've just made them come back stronger
and we got to keep fighting them because
you can't beat nature so it's kind of
like masturbation you could set you
could say to yourself yes we've done so
much good by impeding the infection of
our bodies by these pathogens but also
you could say yeah but you know what you
also made them stronger and eventually
they're going to come back and kick our
asses 10 times harder whenever we fuck
with nature we get fucked up you can't
progress is an illusion it does this
like we're talking about ok good Oh
looks like you're winning it looks like
you're winning on till you lose it looks
like you're losing your losing you're
losing you losing until you win we can't
get attached to one part of it winning
is all we want oh we beat the pathogens
they'll fool yourself news the pathogens
are coming back like they got these they
call him like like monster terms yeah
damn right mocks adjourn go earth though
nature come and get us cuz it's just
part of the fucking process I was
listening to this daniel quinn he wrote
the book ish mile and all these all
these uh really cool books and that's
what he was talking about is we became
scared of death and we started seeing we
started to to produce agriculture and
things like this and now we're at this
point to where we're trying to kill
every pest every weed everything and
it's in turn has done exactly what
you're saying has increased the
population to
point to where we don't die and we need
this food now because there's so many
people and the more the more food the
more people going back and forth so
we're like racing to our death and at
the same time you know we're eliminating
all these all of these organisms that
are essential to our survival because
we're trying to survive we want to win
it's so crazy you cannot win just stop
we need to just stop we're not gonna
stop because a lot of money invested in
all this shit so masturbation we're just
playing with ourselves huh we can't take
any this shit too seriously you know
people people don't like me to may argue
with me like Elliott Hulse like I'm kind
of like giving science a bad name or I'm
kind of like I don't know what they
think but it's like really I'm not
attached to any of this I think it's fun
I think it's a game it's interesting to
watch but it's like but don't take it
too seriously guys cuz we're not gonna
win you cannot win they play the game
that's the thing if we realize we
approach it like a that's why I laugh so
much it's a game enjoy it it's pretty
fucking cool I mean we we've come up
with some really bizarre ideas to like
battle nature I mean the things that we
do to beat against nature it's like oh
we're clever that was good that was good
but but it's a boy nature's gonna be
like boom gotcha you put your hook we
put your fist down and they just gonna
knock us out so just like the earth is
we can't win just but enjoy the dance of
course people don't like to play around
that idea of it being a game you know Oh
scary it's almost demonic yeah what are
your of the devil can't believe Satan
that's Satan shit oh whatever you want
as long as you realize that that's a
game too and I hope you're enjoying it
because if you're not then it's not
worth playing exactly good go ahead I
wasn't say what are some of the ways
that you you kind of balance that whole
technical technology versus nature thing
you go camping and you kind of get
outside and earth get barefoot or do
things like you know sungazing or spring
diving things like that kind of really
connect you back into that whole web of
nature do you do things like that
okay so here's my story this is the guys
of course it's all about fucking story
I'm not right I'm not wrong there was
the time I'm very rebellious I always
want to fight I've kind of gotten over
that a lot over the past few years or
therapy and stuff bioenergetics I'm not
as angry as I once was I don't have to
prove myself and I don't have to fight
like i did you know 34 years ago good
thing I was fighting back then cuz it
you know got me to where I am now now I
can kind of chill out a little bit but I
used to try to fight against where we're
going as a culture like you know too
much technology we're two separate from
one another there's too much too much
too much and I literally want to live on
a farm I wanted to go and like milk cows
and have my kids run around barefoot and
you knows like who cares if there was
chicken shit in our food because it all
came from the earth and it was because
my parents are from Delise that's how my
dad grew up he grew up with chicken
chicken and mangoes like that's the way
it was and I just had a hankering for
that and of course it didn't work out
that way and the story I tell myself
right now because you know I'm fully
enrolled in this matrix I'm playing the
matrix game and I'm pretty I'm kind of
enjoying it you know I don't hate paying
taxes but it's like who doesn't but but
it's like I'm playing this game so I've
come to a place where it's like I'm not
going to fight it because it is nature
also i mean we we like to talk and we
were just doing it just now which is
false we like to talk about of ourselves
as if we're doing something to nature as
we're going against nature as we're
fighting nature as were but really wait
a second i am nature your nature right
technology is nature all the smog in the
air from the cars is fucking nature I
mean nature did that nature made us it's
it's all nature why am I gonna fight so
what I do now the way I live my life is
I finally embraced like the beautiful
shit that we have I mean it's great that
we have washing sheets Hey look I'm
happy that I have two SUVs of course I
gotta pay taxes so that we can drop
bombs on people and take their land so
we can have oil it's not a cool thing
but it's like I do like the air
conditioning in my my suburban it's like
so what am I gonna do am I gonna like
I'm gonna fight are there other
things that I'm fighting for it so it's
like I'll let that one go when it comes
to the food it's a look it's easy enough
me to get organic food and other farmers
in my city okay you know i'll spend a
few extra bucks and I'll get that it's
not a fight because they libera here so
I'll buy raw milk or whatever it is that
we're using at that particular time from
them what I'm not gonna let go and la p
I'm not gonna go like I used to when I
was really fanatical I dry like our to
go get healthy food it's like you know
what if the supermarket has organic I'll
get it I had I don't have the energy to
fight where we're going I'd much rather
just let go and see where it takes us
and contribute by sharing my heart with
people as I go with the flow the best
that I can what I'm good at doing is
coming up with idea sharing it with
people and getting them excited about it
as I've done that since I was a kid so
that's my contribution hopefully these
ideas change the the culture a bit so
that maybe you can live a little bit
more comfortably not give ourselves
heart attacks and can with the way that
we're living but if not hey at least I
you know did my part I thought it was
fun while I was here dude that's
beautiful i think that that's part of
that hero's journey you you kind of have
to go through that part where you're
like i just want to fight you you rebel
you want to go against and then finally
you realize that that is all you as well
or it's it's that's that dragon inside
of you that's that you're fighting
against me you realize if you just
accept it all just like you said like we
are not we are not different from nature
we are not outside of nature trying to
do this or do that we are nature so as
soon as we realize that we are then
maybe we can kind of get on with our
existence and be able to dance a little
bit more rather than looking for the
time to where we can defeat culture or
defeat these earth these uh you know
monsanto and these big companies and
these things like this what we call it
bad and there we go again with this with
this contrast we call it bad but it's
like do you know that it's bad okay
what's they're doing some strange weird
shit of course it's it's very abstract
it's very strange i mean they're
splicing animals with the crop and it's
like and like they're finding that it's
like make
turn into like half mutants but it's
like well maybe that's what earth wants
do maybe maybe nature wants us to fuck
with the DNA and then turn us into life
mutants maybe like the next incarnation
of human beings is gonna have like gills
and then we could thank now Monsanto for
the fact that we could breathe
underwater now but will be fucked up the
land let's go on a bus I don't know why
why am I gonna fight it's happening if I
have a vote out because I'm conservative
to a degree if I have a vote I'll be
like no I'd rather not because I kind of
like the way things are but that's also
being a impeding to evolution and I
don't know what evolution is it's going
to happen why fight that makes a lot of
sense it's um it goes back to that thing
that you're saying just just living in
the mystery and enjoying it cuz we have
this idea of a singularity man's always
popping up and you know how we're gonna
merge with machine and create all these
fucking crazy BOTS and all this stuff
and and it's it's sometimes it's scary
to entertain those thoughts but not when
you let go of it you know not when you
cut let go and then just let see and
just do what you enjoy doing you know I
love the way that Alan Watts put it so
great to me the other day because you
know we all always have in these little
quarrels within ourselves or hopefully
not always but so I go on and listen to
this little Alan Watts talk and he's
saying look I'm an entertainer first of
all that's what I do it right pane I'm
not trying to get you to believe what
I'm saying at all all I'm doing is
entertain I'm sharing ideas with you
that entertain me and that entertain my
friends and things like this and that's
all we're doing here is entertaining
each other did you listen that's from
that's the first that's the opening
statement and your it so that were you
listen to so yeah I think so isn't that
great and I take that same position I of
course adopted it from alan watts it's
like I have nothing to prove please
don't believe me don't follow me don't
listen to me completely ignore me if you
wish I just feel like talking about this
stuff if you like it hang out
if you don't okay goodbye yeah no hard
feelings maybe we maybe you could share
a beer later and talk about the bucs
game but yeah no hard feelings exactly
I'm not trying to win I'm not trying to
win you over I'm not trying to make
something happen just a fucking
entertainer in the same way it's just
like I'm entertaining these ideas and I
happen to like talking about it all
right Elliot so give us a give us to end
us out here give us something tangible
when it comes to getting from our head
and I know you you you have you've
talked about this already but something
that we can do to get from our head and
we can practice from our head into our
bodies breathing technique that you do a
bioenergetic technique that you do
whatever I started out and I have an
analogy for this meditation and
bioenergetics and bioenergetics is not
very different than a lot of the the
movement meditations of East
particularly yoga I've been doing a lot
of Olympic lifting lately and I really
part of the reason why I chose it
because I knew I'm going to be really
good at these lifts I gotta stretch lots
so it was kind of an excuse for me not
to go to yoga class because I didn't
have the time but force myself to
stretch a lot so I can lift anyway so
that it there is a way to do it by
turning off the brain I found that for
myself and most people i know it doesn't
work so easy and that's meditation
that's basically just sit quietly and
turn your brain off and if you and
because we as we described before the
brain is in your body one of the very
first ways you're going to find
meditation happening is when you stop
twitching you stop tensing your muscle
you're sitting there you're feet are
tapping or your hands are tied or you're
squeezing your ass cheek or you're
you're holding your belly in you're not
breathing it's all muscular attention
but you're doing it so as you turn off
your brain your body starts to relax so
that's going from let's say that's the
dog and this is the tale you know which
what's happening to dog tag wagging the
tail to tail wagging the dog so it's
like you move from this way down
I found personally that it's far more
arduous it takes a long time it's just
you know I have a very hyper mind I
think most people do so it's more
difficult for me to go from this way
down so what I also include and I think
you really need to do a little bit of
both is going from this way up and what
I do is well bioenergetics is a form of
releasing muscular tension by allowing
the emotions that you're holding back to
come out and that looks like just
yelling screaming kicking throwing
temper tantrums saying gibberish or
whatever comes up in your your
consciousness I mean if you let yourself
just free associate with the words that
come up in your from you you'll say some
of the weirdest fucking shit and you're
like I didn't even know I was thinking
that like where did that come from but
you're literally holding it all in
you're holding all these emotions in and
the word holding is very indicative of
what happens we use a muscular system to
suppress or depress our hearts we
depress our sexuality we depress our
creativity we depress our emotion so
there's so much depression because we're
so busy depressing ourselves we're
compressing we're depressing or holding
it in and if you give yourself and this
requires a lot of courage which in again
this is the second time we're talking
about courage I think Courage's is the
iron quality in this day and age you
need courage now to grow if you have
enough courage to literally let go and
open your body up to in it to a full
experience of catharsis just let it all
that would exhaust yourself then what
happens is there is a relaxing of the
entire nervous system that accompanies
it your brain no longer has to hold you
don't have to you use your muscular
system your nervous system and your
brain to hold yourself back anymore
because you've let it all out and
there's there's an immediate softening
of the respiratory wave let me spoke
about before right you soften your
respiratory wave guess what that tender
aggression comes back your sex life's
better you breathe deeper you feel
better when I have I have every once in
a while I have people come and you know
they visit me for some sessions
oftentimes the very first thing I do
with them is bioenergetics and the
number one comment that I receive after
they're done is I feel like somebody
just washed my face with a cold wet
cough that and it feels like someone
just picked a big weight vest off of me
they feel soft and clean because you
literally exercise that all the demons
we're holding demons in there are demons
of anger they're demons or frustrations
sadness they're demons of joy you know
what's the last time last time you
laughed deeply so I it this way that
meditation from the mine down is almost
like the Sun warming a block of ice if
we think of ourselves as tied up in a
block of ice the Sun is a big warm
energy that slowly melts the ice we're
bioenergetics is like taking a chisel
and a hammer and going like that to the
throat to the heart to the ball breaking
it down one is very and the other is
very combination of the two thank you so
much my friend it's been awesome by the
way your video that you made their brain
slave no more is that well thanks dude
but that's that's i think is my favorite
video of all time that videos so i'm so
glad you decided to put it up that video
is so good like the emotions that it
that it pulls out of me i can only speak
subjectively on this but the emotions
that have pulled out of me just by
sitting there watching it was was pretty
pretty extravagant oh thank you very
much for for putting that up man awesome
you got it man i'm so happy that i can
do that you know it's the second time i
made a catharsis video the first time I
never really gave anybody any context
for it and it got really misunderstood
so the second time it's funny I was like
okay we're going to we're going to put
it
in context by adding some words to it so
the plan was to was for me to go into
what dr. Glaser who's my mentor would
call process work so you're about to go
into process work so you open up your
respiratory wave open up your breathing
and then you start moving and then
whatever comes up comes up the plan was
just to record that and then I was going
to write something and then speak it
over it but it's an amazing thing
happens when you free your body from
those demons or that much I call them
neurotic holding patterns when you free
your body from that muscular tension
that's done done to yourself all of a
sudden it's almost like and this is of
course words are going to screw this up
it's almost like you get out the way and
God starts talking through you because
you're not there anymore your ego is
almost gone you've exhausted your ego
and you become an open vessel almost
like a flute now that's hollow hollow
Reed I think it's describing some
spiritual texts you become a hollow Reed
and I literally SAT up from after doing
the process work i SAT up and the words
just flowed out of me so what you're
hearing on that video because you might
notice that it's very difficult to hear
it's because the air conditioner was on
and the audio wasn't set up because I
wasn't supposed to speak but i SAT up
and I just started talking and those
were the words that had to be said and
we tried our best we're like man how can
you get it so that doesn't sound so
muffled because we didn't plan on you
saying these things and luckily we you
know we're able to pieces together
somewhat but you know if you do go and
watch it just realize that that's why
the audio so bad on it it was you get
the point I think it's even better the
fact that you can't really hear it
because you have to watch it like four
or five times and then by that time you
really understand what the hell's going
on good good we're really out for me
yeah good you have you ever done any
floatation tank work jumped in the
sensory deprivation tank thing like that
no I haven't it's an interesting little
little bit I would be curious to see
what you thought about it I'll look it
up I'll see if we have something like
that around here I'll give it a shot be
cool
we just before we close out how do we
get ahold of you for one but dr.
glaciers work you mentioned him a couple
times oh yeah well he's kind of a
private dude but he owned say uh he owns
bioenergetic press which is the
publisher of all of Alexander loewen's
books and Alexander loan is was like one
of the founders of bioenergetics so if
you if you google bioenergetic press
you'll get to dr. glaciers website and
he has training programs he's he's my
therapist he's been my mentor for
several years and actually tomorrow
morning i leave for four days to begin a
would be a post PhD graduate type
program which I don't have a PhD but he
knows how much I love to work so i'll be
taking for the next couple years
probably wow we look look forward to
hearing i'm sure you're going to share
some of the stuff that you learn from
their look forward to it yeah yeah
thanks and to get to elliott hulse le
whole stock strengthcamp calm now that's
my gym website I'm such a mess that's
true and then Elliott Hulse calm like I
still have to put stuff on it if you
just go to youtube and search elliott
hulse that's usually where you'll find
all my videos and then facebook that's
where they are most active at social
media Facebook and YouTube yeah cool man
once again really appreciate you coming
on appreciate the videos you make so you
sharing sharing your shit in the in the
in the face of all the adversity man
that's your responsibility right you
gotta do it that's right actually guys
have a great day if you to manage it
buh-bye
you