hey what's up guys la hell's here on
another Sunday morning sermon today
we're going to talk on a topic that most
you guys are probably very familiar with
especially those are you watching this
on a strap cap channel and I would say
it's pretty common knowledge that the
amount of calories you take in as it
relates to the amount of calorie
expenditure how you're using those
calories will relate to your overall
health and your level of body fat right
we know that if we take in more calories
than we're actually utilizing and
processing that what happens you begin
to store body fat right the calories
that are unused end up piling up in the
body in a way right and you end up with
obesity in fact in the United States in
particular we have an epidemic of
morbidly obese people these are people
who take in so much consume so much but
expend so little that they get sick they
bloat up to a point where they're
they're ill it's it's morbid it's
pathological they're sick we also have
the fact that there are empty calories
or negative calories right there are
foods that we can take in so called
foods that we can take in that require
more energy to break down then they
provide to your body right we call these
negative calorie foods right a lot of
junk food falls into this category falls
into this right and then also we have
the third of the three problems
associated with overconsumption and that
is taking in calories in the wrong
macronutrient ratio for you right you're
just taking in the wrong amount of stuff
and it leads to again pathology or just
not being the strongest version of
yourself right we'd have to look at it
like it's pathology it's simply like
look you're just you're not performing
at your best because you're either
taking in too much you're taking in the
wrong kinds or you're taking in the
wrong ratios now as cut and dry as that
is
as much as we accept that as a truth for
the most part right those you were
watching this I want to use it as an
analogy related to the consumption of
information right and this is something
I've been working on something I've been
thinking about something I've been
personally processing over the past six
months or a year or so and that is
number one we take in I think because we
have so much information at our
fingertips these days we take in so much
information that we are not processing
that we're not embodying that we're not
using right that we become inflated we
become fat we become obese
we also have the taking in of
information that does not serve you
right this is like junk food information
right when you eat Twinkies and dong
dongs and Ding Dongs and Twizzlers and
shit like that
you're taking in you are consuming but
it is not only not adding to your body
it's picking away from you there is
information I'm telling you right now
you know people are going to I know some
people can argue with me like I'll you
need to know well do you really you're
taking in from information that does not
serve you in fact it is a fact I'm
putting my foot down
some of the shit that you guys are
consuming is detrimental to your health
that your mental to your mental health
your emotional health your spiritual
health you are consuming in all the joy
of consumption just like a junk food
junkie and it is hurting you and then of
course is the consumption of the wrong
ratio of stuff right you're you're
taking in stuff in an in a in an
imbalance way you're taking in
information in an imbalance way meaning
that the food that you're taking all the
information that you're consuming
doesn't serve your greater purpose it
doesn't mean that it's wrong like carbs
aren't wrong right what are you taking
in the right amount for your metabolic
type meaning it's right for you who you
are and what you're becoming it's the
same thing with the information taking
in information for information sake is
not a good idea right it will make you
sick so you got to think in terms of you
know what is the most important
information in what ratio for me right I
once listen to an audio program by Earl
Nightingale I think was called lead the
field and he says you know there's that
the three most important types of
information for you to take in he says
number one this is his opinion
number one is know that know your
history really which i think is super
important everybody should be kind of
studying their history right and I think
that another one was ah your language
right you should know the origins of
your language right not saying that I do
this I just study history I love history
but I'll study the origin
language that much to any great degree
get a good handle on your on your
language he says and then the third is
information specific to your vocation
right don't go reading a whole bunch of
stuff and engaging in a whole lot of
consumption when it doesn't add to your
vocation who it is what are you up to in
the world right does taking this in
right knowing football stats or baseball
stats really contribute to your overall
objective in life overall dream vision
you know part of his most people aren't
in touch with themselves to know what
their purpose their vision is but that's
another topic altogether we want to get
to a place where we're taking in the
right ratio of information for us right
so one of the things I'd like to share
with you is a is a process of getting
rid of information info fasting right
because in the same way that when you
take in too many calories you grow
beasts you take in too much information
you grow constipated what happens when
you get constipated that means you're
taking in so much you're taking in too
much you're taking in crap all right
most people who become constipated
because they're taking in bad stuff that
dehydrates and stresses their body they
got a sympathetic response and their
assholes think theirs tightens up and
they can't poop right dehydrated dried
up pieces of crap in their colon and a
stressed-out system they can't shit
because they're taking in the bad stuff
and then you know of course if you're
taking in the wrong ratio of information
it's let it lead to constipation because
you're unable to do anything with it I
can't do anything real with this I can't
practice this I can't embody this it
doesn't do anything to me too much trash
and then all lead to a stoppage in your
productivity a stoppage in your value to
yourself and to the world a stoppage in
the embodying in the practicing in the
processing in the utilizing of the
information that you're taking in this
is super important so much so that one
day
share story with you back in April last
video I shared with you guys I explained
to you how in April something happened
it was my birthday is in April right I
had like a rebirth right around my
birthday which is typical we'll talk
about that later on but at that time
several revelations came to me right is
what meditation and prayer does several
revelations came to me one day I as I
was waking up a lot of revelations come
to me as I'm waking up I realized that I
needed to get rid of all of my books
I needed to fast right what do you do
when there's constipation or obesity
right you gotta you got to cut back I
had to fast somebody's pulling into the
driveway this is I don't know who it is
all my teammates know not to show up
here on Sunday I bet you this is uh
somebody either wanted to come to the
gym or maybe a fan we'll see you ain't
cut I'm not turning off the camera so
stick with me here so uh yeah I woke up
one day and I immediately went to my
office I began collecting boxes and you
may have seen this in one of my
catalysis videos my office look like a
mess and I was putting away all of the
books into boxes so I can get rid of
them are you doing sir oh you're here to
help out with the bathrooms you building
bathrooms you Mr Clarke son oh yeah he's
building a bathroom some bathrooms and
showers and locker rooms at the gym
that's though okay great so as it
relates to my experience in getting rid
of books I gave away 90% of my books man
I had no choice my body my mind my soul
just prompted me to purge too fast to
get rid of it it was heavy I had as you
know a loads of books right maybe not as
many as ty but I had library uh
bookshelves and a library in my office
and and I got rid of 90% of it what I
needed to do and what I think was really
important during that process was I had
to decide what the most important stuff
is for me to consume I'm over consuming
I've over identified and I think that's
a big part of it most of you got to
realize is that identification with the
information over identification with
books over identification with the
consumption of videos
and uh and information right so many of
us get that ego gratification for saying
look at the new thing I'm reading look
at the new book I have look at all my
look at all my books look how great I am
for all that I can consume right and
then there becomes an identification
with it right anytime we have an
attachment or identification with
something that is external right and
information is external information is
dead right Osho talks about how anything
that you read anything that you receive
anything that you get outside of
yourself right as opposed to Revelation
is someone else's and it's old it leaves
no room for mystery it leaves no room
for growth it is holding on to being
bogged down by someone else's words and
ideas from a long gone time right Osho
talks about burning Bibles and shake it
just burn up all the books because what
he's trying to do is have us understand
that it is within that the deepest and
most profound and most important
information right the most important
information for you is already here they
call the Akashic records sometimes right
it's already right here not the point of
the video point of those videos to share
an experience of mine getting rid of 90%
of my books such that only the most
important books to me you should say I
have one bookshelf it's about that high
about that wide boom I have one
bookshelf that I'll keep in my house
that I do keep in my house and if the
books cannot fit on that bookshelf I
don't keep it I get rid of it now of
course I try to stick it into every nook
and cranny in that bookshelf but it's my
commitment to remain healthy and fit to
avoid overconsumption of information and
constipation of information bogged down
this ego identification with all the
information by keeping it limited to
that simple bookshop I'm not telling you
to do that not saying that you should do
anything I'm saying right now at all
because it's once again that's Elliott
Hulse telling you this is my ideas and
it's old right minute you watch this
it's already been it's already past I'm
just sharing something with you that you
know it's been a resource to me some of
you need to read more fucking books
that's the truth the truth is
you guys are taken in just like fat
people who take in too much junk food
you take in pure junk information right
you're on snapchat all day long you're
scrolling on Instagram all day long you
think you're educating yourself cuz
you're reading fucking memes right just
cuz it's on a square and as a picture of
a famous person don't mean that it's
right or real and that snapshot of
information that you think you're
nourishing yourself with is candy right
this is this is junk food information so
some of you guys
the fact is you do need to read some
books you need to go to just like
somebody who's obese and who's eating
the wrong food need we need to actually
bump up your calories a little bit with
some of the right foods some healthy
foods right so so I'm not saying this is
for everyone right I'm not you know cuz
some of you they're gonna say Elliott
Hulse is say is an ignorant bastards
telling people not to read book that's
not the case ma'am yeah I gotta clarify
these days they gotta clarify I can't
just assume you guys are in the same you
know you're thinking the same thing I'm
thinking so uh
information fasting book fasting is also
related to right and I think this is
this topics important for this day and
age but it's also related to breaking
down getting rid of dying to parts of
yourself particularly that are no longer
serving you that your ego is identified
with a big theme in these past current
videos that I've been making for you
guys is a matter of letting go breaking
down dissolving parts of yourself that
no longer serve you right and my
question my invitation our dialogue here
today because I'm hoping that you can
share with me down below is what do you
need to get rid of what do you need to
let go of what do you need to break down
and dissolve chop off remove
identification from in your life so that
you have the room to grow right your cut
if your cup is too full you have no room
for evolution no room for growth what
ideas what beliefs right some of our
beliefs some of our most deeply held
beliefs are no longer serving us right
that's like eating rotten meat
Oh meat Oh
food oh shit that you know because daddy
hated and cuz granddaddy hated my
great-great-granddaddy hate it now I
gotta eat it well it's making you sick
but you gotta be real self reflection
being self objective is very important
on this path so yeah be real with
yourself like is that shit helping you
so your beliefs even your most deeply
held beliefs dogmas superstitions books
ideas consumption what could you get rid
of what could you let go of so that your
cup could be a little bit more empty and
you might be filled up with something
new let me know share down below done