okay the the John Rodriguez that's what
he calls himself John wants to know
about this concept of energy management
he watched my time management video
before and he said he recently heard
someone describe this concept of energy
management there wasn't no what I think
of it and how to how to utilize it the
thing is John I think you've got it
confused a little bit the term is a bit
confusing John wants to know like you
know if I eat enough of the right food
and if I get enough sleep will I be able
to have energy to do the things and to
develop the habits that I want to be
able to to do well yeah that's a given
it's basically a given that you're
taking care of yourself anybody who is
going to be a high performer in any area
of their lives realizes that you need
sleep you need exercise you need good
food so it's not about managing that
it's not about managing your ability to
produce energy
what it's about is recognizing your
biological responses to particular times
a day how what how and when do you have
energy so for example I know that I have
my most energy on my smartest on my
brightest early in the morning right so
when I do that here's the thing what you
actually managing is activity or yeah
activity you what you're deciding to do
is to take the most important activities
of the day and do them when you have the
most energy so for me the most activity
most important activities in my day
usually are making videos on Monday and
Tuesday's the very first thing I do when
I have all of my best energy is I make
these videos right so I'm I'm managing
the activity based on my energy right
excuse me so it's not necessarily that
I'm manipulating my energy energy is
what it is that's why I refer to your
biology before your physiology you've
got to actually become sensitive to when
you are at your best and then you want
to take the most important activities
and put or the ones that you can only do
when you have that type of energy and
put them over it at that in that
frame and further everyone that's
different I have friends who get their
best work done between 10:00 p.m. and
and and three o'clock in the morning
right but they've trained themselves in
that way they've got the most energy and
their most focus and the most
concentrated their most at peace because
you know neo phone doesn't ring that
time of day and you know you know I get
too many emails so they do all their
work then they know themselves well
enough that that is the best time for
them to produce because of the energy
associated with that time you're also
going to recognize and I mentioned this
in a talk that I did this weekend that
there are seasons of energy so we're
talking like microcosm we're talking
daily but macro Kazem the macro
experience of energy fluctuation you're
going to recognize in seasons there are
times when bro I'm just I'm balls to the
wall hardcore move fast get it done les
ball out and work seasons and that might
last like for a month two months three
months maybe you know and I could just
go go go go go nothing's getting in my
way and then there are times when like
man I just don't even want to open up
the laptop I just cannot do anything
what you got to do is take full
advantage of those go-go-go times when
you feel really energetic and get as
much work as you can done cramming in
because there will guarantee as the Sun
rises and it's sense that there will be
a season when you're like you know six
months later when you're like dude I
can't do anything so what you've got to
make sure happens and sometimes it's
difficult I know especially for me
because I've got a family that you don't
take vacations during your your your
hardcore time when you got all that
energy don't take a vacation don't plan
vacations but you really you know these
seasons happens and you're unpredictable
yeah so sometimes like I'm camping with
my kids and I'm like I just want to work
and make sure that when you are
physically physiologically unable to
work like you're just burnt out or you
just it's that season of rest reaping
and sowing consuming and producing right
that you
chill the fuck out don't try to work
when you're in a season of chilling
because the work is going to be ten
times harder to do that's going to come
out crappy so energy management is more
of a sensitivity towards the type of
energy you are producing that's coming
up in your body and then orienting your
activities to be most closely associated
with the productive times and then
you're down activity for your at least
productive times that's it dude good
luck