so our buddy Kristian Sandor believes
that he deserves a better woman so
here's his history he grew up being a
fat loser essentially and no one really
liked him especially women never paid
attention to him when he was younger and
you know high school whatever the case
may be then he went and lost a lot of
weight you got got in really great shape
and all of a sudden chicks are checking
him out right and he's now moving from a
place of these bitches wanted nothing to
do with me and now here they come and
his attitude is you're not good enough
you're not good enough you're not good
enough hey now I'm alone that's his
problem so he knows this is his attitude
is it he's become very what he calls
proud you know arrogant in a way because
he spent so much time digging out of the
depths of dysfunction being a fat loser
to now being a winner and all of a
sudden checks are checking him out and
he feels as if he should be able to
choose one that perfectly fits the new
and more you know far better version of
himself and he's right you do you don't
deserve to be with someone who's a loser
if you're a winner right but the problem
he's having is that now he can't no
one's good enough and it's frustrating
because he would like to be with
somebody but he always finds himself
turning away once a woman actually is
attracted to it so here's the thing that
you've got to understand or what I've
experienced right because I'm one of
those types of people I'm they type a
phallic narcissist hard-worker move
forward get out of my way I'm going and
if you can't keep up base that's just
been my attitude towards people my whole
life I mean I grew up as an
extraordinary athlete you can't hang
piece right what ends up happening when
you're moving that far that fast in that
direction is that you don't have time
for people and that's exactly what's
happening I am working out I look good
chicks checking me out ain't got time
for you yeah woman because I'm moving so
fast cuz I'm doing so good I've
experienced that if you slowed
and learn to appreciate the virtues that
may be completely opposite of yours that
are presenting themselves and another
person you will actually grow stronger
so for example you're looking for a
woman that can match your newfound
beauty right well if you're if you move
in such a way that you will only bring
in those that have the same virtues as
you right for me for example would be
friends that can only move as quickly as
I can in in the direction of growing
muscular strength you know training
partners or building my business right
you guys just can't keep up peace if a
woman can't keep up with your sexiness
you've got to recognize that there is
something in her also that will support
you in growing stronger and these
virtues come in the form of empathy
compassion courage patience persistence
loyalty these are all different things
that you might not have yourself right
you've got a lot of strong virtues that
move you forward you've got a lot of
aggressive virtues but maybe the more
the softer virtues maybe the ones that
more are more associated with enjoying
life instead of attacking life will be
found in these women or in friends that
you're rejecting we become very
self-centered especially people like you
knives I think we're probably pretty
similar we've become very self-centered
because we're doing our thing and we
wonder why other people can't keep up
but we lose out on so much if we don't
slow down and realize that those people
are moving very quickly in a direction
that we are not moving in and because
we've got blinders on we don't realize
the beauty that they're presenting my
invitation to you would be the minute
you start comparing your woman to you
because that's not that's dangerous
right there you don't want a woman
that's like you because now you're
competing with her right she's competing
with you and then it's a penis contest
with your woman you know what that look
for the things look for the virtues look
for the beauty that she's exhibiting in
a opposite direction that you can
appreciate and you might also be able to
integrate into you growing stronger good
luck dude