so a lot of people find it strange and
even obnoxious that Elliott Hulse refers
to himself as Elliott Hulse so what is
this about I feel like I owe you an
explanation because I do it quite often
and the associations with a practice
like that are far more shallow than the
place I'm coming from when I refer to
Elliott Hulse so the very first thing I
want to share with you is that there's a
core being beneath the facade of the
characters we all play in life when I
say character I do don't necessarily
mean the yo Elliott character that I
play when I'm you know doing my strength
training videos or even you know the
character that I am molding as I you
know move forward in my profession I
mean the person we've been told we are
that's attached to the name we've been
given since the time we were children
since the time your children you've been
told what you should be like what you
should do what's appropriate what's not
appropriate which you should aspire to
and then we build defenses psychological
defenses against things that we find
uncomfortable experiences that were
traumatic also we find ways to move
towards things that are that feel good
and these are all these old mold our
character they all mold who we play all
of this is very superficial all of this
is layered on top of the core individual
who you really are deep on the inside
you know I even I call that the
strongest version yourself the strongest
version yourself is a process of
removing the layers especially the Unruh
source four layers of character build up
that deter you from be seeing the true
essence the true being that that's deep
within you so I formed a attitude of
detachment from Elliott Hulse so when I
say Elliott Hulse i'm referring to
Elliott Hulse and I say you know Elliot
hell's this all is that really what I'm
referring to is this
imaginary character in my mind and
through which you receive me through
what you experience me that i'm
referring to it's not me i'm not elliott
hulse I've done a video about this I'm
my strength training channel where I
call it I'm not elliott hulse and I'm
doing deadlifts two different ways I'm
not Elliot host the fact is I I and this
I who is this I I keep referring to well
this I this essence this being this
watcher that's experiencing this what's
going on the play of life is not Elliott
Hulse so I want you to understand that
when I would I refer to this Elliot host
character it's not from a narcissistic
place of placing putting myself above
someone or something else in a hierarchy
whereby I need to refer to myself as if
I there's some sort of kingship you know
Elliott Hulse right it's not a position
of grandeur from which I refer to
Elliott Hulse it's a position of
detachment I am NOT Elliott Hulse and
when I refer to him it's simply that
character that you've come to know