this is my answer for almost everything
and I'm going to sound funny saying it
but breathe into your balls you're going
to learn how to breathe into our balls
and that basically means we've got to
take back our bodies from the mental
prisons that we've created for them and
it that prison manifests itself in the
neurotic holding patterns that I
mentioned before that do not allow us to
breathe deeply we're holding our bellies
type which is the reservoir of our
sexuality our pelvic floors our bellies
our chest our shoulders and neck our
face our eyes they're riddled with
tension we've got to loosen the body
going to soften that muscular tension in
the body and learn how to ground our
energy through deep breathing and the
more thing that you need to do is to
recognize just how brilliant you are to
trust yourself first to trust your body
trust your feelings trust the emotion
trust the brilliance that's coming up in
you that you don't have to do get in
touch with what's happening in your body
and honor that before you honor anyone
else's opinion before you honor anyone
else's suggestions or conditioning we
live our lives through our own bodies
experience through our own movements be
with that first be with you first row
you first and
don't give other people and other
people's ideas the opportunity to
imprison you or the growth and the
brilliance that's what they do sometimes
we meet up with people and a lot of
people come to us for help because
they're like seems so sup dude just like
they want it now like right about it an
email like how they they want this inner
fire they want this energy they want to
go out and do all these things they see
us doing in our videos but when we meet
them a person a lot then those are the
ones that don't follow through it's like
they got their satisfaction writing it
out rather than that it's like yeah they
did an amazing trend yeah absolutely
because they did in their mind they
actually already did that we like to
think and we like to talk because that's
what how we've been taught in schools in
schools we've been taught that it is
virtuous to think a lot and have the
right answer raise your hand so people
go about their lives thinking and
talking you know what they do in schools
out there's no fizzy they've cut back on
physical education and they cut back on
the amount of time that kids get to go
outside for recess but you know what
they're doing more of thinking and
talking we've been conditioned this way
it's true man I agree if you lie the
cultural conditioning today is kind of
bass ackwards but I always think of the
analogy of how everyone's like so
concerned about eating factory farmed
animals and like we need free range and
wild fed and like and I really when you
look at it when you look at our school
system when you look at the food we're
fed and these pills that kids get put on
it's like in a way the human race is the
biggest factory farmed animal oh wow
that's so funny you're right we really
are you're six years old but you're
being judged on how well you sit down
shut up and follow directions so you're
literally literally creating a crop up
children and adults who have no no
permission they're looking for
permission how do you recommend people
recovering from that like it's stopped
reading stop stop stop studying stop
looking for stuff to Allah frame it any
more answers don't buy any more books
stay off the website now what are you
gonna do
and it's very uncomfortable because
people again they feel comforted by the
fact that they they watch the video
about working out today i watch the
video about working out today now
consciously they're not they know that
that's stupid but somewhere in there is
mine there's this babe satisfies the
desire to work out so it's already been
quite does that make that oh yeah man I
hear you I know I know some people that
like a big game day no they come back
from the bars and they like sauced it
like they just played a football game
I'm gonna play the long game we just
watched a football game Ryan wonder why
you're out of shape so funny yeah we
live in the abstract you live in our
heads I think that's why we do you and I
with regard to our mission in life is to
get people to use your body because
that's where life happens life actually
happens in movement that's where it all
happens down here doesn't happen up here
this only helps us with the idea okay
exercise is good now don't read about it
don't think about it go even if you do
the wrong thing I say this people all
time look don't try to find the right
thing to do don't try to find the
perfect thing to do do something even if
it's ass backwards and wrong get it
going because I promise you you'll
figure it out as you're going along but
the success happens as you're doing it
that has been thinking about it
researching it there's so many fat
people that know more about that weight
loss than I do what does that tell you
yeah we could it be more in line with
you on there
like the idea of perfectionism are like
everything has to be right before you
get started is really just a rational
excuse not to do it do the thing and
have the power that's what Ralph Waldo
Emerson once a two and I believe that
with the bottom my arm do the thing and
have the power most people wait till
they have the power which doesn't happen
they want to have the power episode they
can go do the thing like people who want
to get in shape where they go to the gym
it's just as stupid you do it so that
you have the power to do it yeah and
that big on top of that code I think
there's one from Albert Einstein about
nothing happens until something moves
absolutely man good boy none of us are
any of this you're not what your skin
reveals you're not your bone and flesh
you're not your name you're not your
ideas you are so much more than that I
think it's more of a trusting the
brilliance in your body trusting that
part of your brain that part of you that
beats your heart without me having to
think about it that part of you that
grows a baby in a woman's stomach
without our having to do it the part of
you that replaces cells all over the
place without you having to do your at
replacing your settle who's doing it
it's that brilliant party you deep down
within your peripheral nervous system
when we breathe deep we're honoring that
peripheral nervous system that's when
the shut comes out oh do you have any of
you have any screams that you do or any
kind of things in the gym where we were
trying to tap into that that extra push
that you do to get yourself fired up
there are two exercises that are
magnificently powerful for unleashing
your motility but they're very different
they're strange in fact that there are
three they kind of like build on top of
each other something very similar but it
looks like this Oh
Oh
this is where our ego is right our ego
right gift so the morning come at your
face though