love this question from our buddy Nick
here who's graduating high school this
year and he wants to go to a university
in another city the problem is his
parents don't want him to leave their
hometown I assume and will not support
him in going to the University outside
of their hometown and apparently his
parents are a bit you know I use this
term it's my term overbearing they don't
seem to allow them to go out he's
constantly being grounded if his grades
aren't right and he's got a pretty good
GPA he feels as if he if he left his
parents house and went to the University
in a new city he would become a stronger
version himself of himself you'd be
growing up in absence of the tyranny and
that's my word of it of his oppressive
parents the problem is that he needs
their support in order to go to apply to
this school to pay for the school so on
and so forth so now he's torn okay so
here's here's the way I'm gonna ask you
to look at this my buddy my friend my
young friend embarking upon the journey
of life feeling the call to action but
yet being in it in able to do it because
of you know those who control you at
this point you're 17 years old I assume
it's not going to be the answer you want
to hear and it's probably not going to
be the most popular answer but here it
is allow your parents to control you
just a little bit longer you're 17 years
old on doesn't mean that you don't
really feel this call to action and in
fact it may be a good opportunity for
you to grow up and become a stronger
version of yourself but you're still at
an age where you're going to need your
parents support especially if you're
going to go through University or need
their financial support you're going to
need their moral support and you don't
want to at this early on in your adult
life you don't want to break ties with
your roots you know there may come a
time ultimately where you've got to kill
the master so to say you know put your
parents aside and man up and beer be
yourself I'm not feeling like that needs
to happen just yet and here is some
encouraging device advice if I
it's a device also so it's a it's a idea
device right very rarely do i edit these
videos so if I say stupid things
sometimes just realize like this guy
doesn't at his videos just whatever
comes out is what needs to be said
anyway what I would invite you to
consider is that for years of university
is a drop in the fucking bucket dude it
is nothing it seems like it's the whole
world is going to crumble down on you if
you don't take this leap onto into
adventure right now but taking four more
years and allowing your character to
incubate under the tutelage or the
tyranny however you want to look of it
look at it of your parents it's not the
end of the world in fact I think it
might be okay I think it's better for
the long-term relationship that you'll
have with your parents I think your
parents again this is all a lot again
when I make these videos they're not
always based on fat they're based on the
information that I get from you guys and
the feeling I get while reading it the
feeling that I get is that your parents
are good people I don't think your
parents are out to hurt you I think they
might be a bit overbearing
overprotective but it doesn't mean that
they're they're the type of people that
want to see you hurt or to hurt you okay
that's just a feeling I get and I'm sure
you'd agree with me right if not let me
know so you don't want to sever ties
with them you don't want to get on bad
footing with them you don't want to ruin
that relationship with them there's
going to come a cop become a time when
you're forced to assert yourself now
here's an interesting thing of course
I'm beginning to right now with this
video and the interesting thing is that
we're all called to action at some
particular point in our lives some of us
that call to action or the courage
associated with taking action in our
lives has been so suppressed to early
childhood suppression that comes out in
whimpers some of us it comes out very
explosive in very rebellious about the
time that about the age of 17
23 what you don't want to have happen if
you do decide to ignore the call to
action for the better for the bigger
picture for the betterment of everyone
is to forget that call to action for
years from now when the opportunity
rises again and now you've got to go get
a job you got to go out into the real
world the real world is another form of
and the real world including whoever you
go work for if you decide to work for
someone and the government is another
form of parentage patriarchy right and
then you then what ends up happening is
we submit to that authority once again
and never go out in our call to action
we never build up the courage ever again
to do something dangerous so that's it
dude I don't wanna make this that much
longer than it needs to be I say take
your parents's advice do what you're
told right now not because you're a
bitch or a bastard or or week or on
couragous or you know anything that it's
negative you do it for the greater good
and realize four years as a drop in the
bucket and in four years time you might
even be stronger in your ability to
approach your call to action and make
your stand as a man in the world
done