got a question about our friend who's an
underdog that nobody takes seriously and
when he tries to become a stronger
version of himself as he grows stronger
in himself he faces a resistance of
other people who just don't take him
seriously and I can relate to that I
understand what you're going through in
fact all the greatest minds that have
ever lived on this planet always seem to
face that I mean you think about Jesus
and Martin Luther King Nelson Mandela
just passed away me these are men who we
revere well after their death now Mount
Dell is going to be like a hero but
during a lifetime during his lifetime he
I mean spent maybe 30 years I think in
prison you're always going to resist
your always going to face resistance
from small minds especially if you seek
to expand beyond the boxes that they put
themselves in you see especially the
people that are closest to you they are
in boxes they're comfortable in their
boxes and when someone tries to step
outside that box they're going to do
everything that they can in order to
draw them back in because you make it
very difficult for them there are two
things that you do when you try to
expand yourself when you try to become a
stronger version of yourself in the
midst of those who have limited
consciousness number one by you taking
responsibility for your own personal
growth you kind of shed light on the
fact that they have it so they're not
taking you seriously because you're
sharing ideas that are beyond the scope
of their understanding it's merely a
form of jealousy you're they become very
angry with you because you're doing
something that they themselves know they
should take personal responsibility for
doing also right and the other thing is
we feel content by knowing how to relate
with people where we put them you see
the minute you meet someone or even
worse when you have your own children
and you're soon you're talking about
your parents and your brothers and
sisters you build up a place for them
through which you are most comfortable
in relating to them right so they know
you says that he's the youngest I didn't
get to read it
reading his email for you but he's the
youngest he's young as he's always been
the youngest he's always feels like he's
been babied well great so the world your
particular world your sphere of
influence or the people that are around
you have put you in that place so that
they know how to relate to you and they
grow comfortable in that if you show up
one day and don't relate to them in that
same particular fashion they grow very
frustrated because now it requires work
they've got to recategorize you see we
do this to each other we categorize each
other right we find a particular place
where we'd like to see that person and
we stick them there and then we make
them mental slaves we literally enslave
them with our expectations for them
you've got to be this way you've always
been the baby how dare you try to expand
beyond the box that I put you in this is
what the world does I face this this
channel has nothing to do with lifting
barbells most people know me they come
to me because of my understanding with
regard to fitness and strength
weightlifting strongman bodybuilding
things of that nature but when I came
out and started making these videos
about God and consciousness and becoming
a stronger version of yourself and their
souls evolution and dealing with the
people in your life and dealing with
girlfriends and dealing with do you see
well you know when I began his channel
the first three months perhaps longer I
mean I still get it sometimes stick to
lifting barbells you fucking meathead
Elliott you're so much better doing what
you're good at you don't know what the
fuck I'm good at they think that I just
know how to weight weight lift stick to
what you know best Elliott stop talking
all this religious philosophical
esoteric bullshit
psychological bullshit okay I'm a
bullshit all right simply because you've
come to know me a particular way but I'm
not staying there motherfucker I'm
growing I'm growing all over the fucking
place and so are you understand that the
problem is not you it's them don't
resent them have empathy for them
because of their lack of understanding
their lack of personal growth and for
the fact that you're trying to enslave
you
and you won't let them keep doing what
you have to do regardless of what other
people have to say about it if you feel
these things these words that you're
studying he says that he's studying some
new books and he's got some new ideas
and he's he's playing with these new
concepts that are new to him and perhaps
very new to the people he's speaking
with right in whatever realm you do it
because that's what the God in you
that's what the universal I that's what
the spirit do universe whatever you want
to call it that would that's what it's
doing through you that animating force
is doing through you that first
heartbeat when you were in utero that
saying impetus that caused your beat to
take it's your heart to take its first
beat is the same impetus that is driving
you towards reading these particular
books and expressing your particular
ideas about it in a way if they reject
you they're rejecting the God in you and
that is the greatest form of violence
against another human being is not
seeing the brilliance in them right so
pity them empathize with them and don't
ever do this to other people that I
could you take that to the bank I'll say
that for sure I put my stamp on that one
that is one of Elliott's now shouts all
right I don't have very many of them one
of my doubts is when you have these
particular experiences that you do not
like don't do it to other people because
that's going to be the tendency you'll
grow in your abilities to assert
yourself your Sirk your self-confidence
you might ascend beyond the expand yinz
of your your parents your brothers and
sisters and those in your sphere of
influence but remember where you came
from
so when you have younger people friends
siblings that are trying to emerge
themselves you invite them you encourage
them that's a part of the reason why
you're experiencing within your
experience and your experiences aren't
your experiences just for you your
experiences or so that you can share
them with people that are coming up
behind you and when I say behind I don't
mean lesser than you I mean
chronologically or experientially are
behind you that's why I make these
videos
I happen to put myself in certain
circumstances I've been shared I've been
given certain circumstances born into
certain circumstances it caused me to
have a shitload of experiences then now
I can share them with you that's why I
do this not because I'm really not
because I I know something that you
don't know but because I've had some
experiences and this is how I've
navigated this portion of the journey
I'm supporting you with that so it's
your responsibility to continue
exploring the things you're exploring
making art the way you're making it
because that's really what you're doing
you're creating a form of art and when I
say art I mean you're mixing your
experiences your ideas and the new
palette of colors that you're you're
beginning to deal with into the painting
of your life don't ever stop exploring
don't ever stop expressing yourself it
is your responsibility it is your right
and when they see you doing this in
absence of any attachment to their
feelings about you when they see you
courageous enough to be the strongest
version of yourself regardless of them
they will look to you for support later
on even if it's your parents they'll
come to respect you because you didn't
fall victim to their violence I'm done