good morning guys today I'd like to
begin with an invitation to the
childhood obesity summit it's an online
some of the friend of mine put together
he was really interested in finding
expert opinions on how to rid the earth
of the stigma childhood obesity if
that's hot if that's even possible but
anyway he interviewed myself interviewed
my brother who's brilliant and my mentor
Paul Czech who's brilliant and some
several other experts on what we think
could eradicate this problem that we're
having in our culture so if you're
interested in hearing what I have to say
about that there's a link in the
description down below it's also in my
blog post to register and listen to it
for free I believe and then you can
purchase the mp3 formats for later but
anyway you can take a look at that today
I want to talk a little bit about you
know when it comes to parenting we're
also talking about leadership and
parents and leaders are in a position
where where I don't want to say in
control of or lord over other people
because that's not really ever the case
we never actually lowered over anyone or
control anyone what we can do and what
we do do besides you know straight-up
slavery and shackles and chains what we
really do when were an environment where
we're looking to influence other people
is we control energy now I know that
sounds like some hippie shit but what
you need to understand that it's far
easier far easier to recognize the
physiological responses the
psychological responses in our own
bodies to stress and challenges rather
than trying to tell other people what to
do while under stress and when there's
challenges and we all are under stress
and we all have challenges I mean
anybody who has children knows what I'm
talking about trying to get out the
frickin door can be a problem to anyone
who runs an organization anyone who
they manager anybody who is in
leadership in any particular way shape
or form understands you've got to deal
with challenges and stressful
circumstances but the unrounded leader
the ungrounded parrot the parent and
person who is not rooted in their own
physiology busily tries to manipulate
and change other people in circumstances
out there they want to tell people what
to do they want to yell to the top of
their lungs trying to get things across
to other people and you know at some
point parents become physical you're not
listening to what I'm saying so they
want to grab you and shake you and make
your do it right what those people don't
understand what those types of bosses
don't understand what those type of
parents don't understand about human
behavior is that in order to influence
someone else we must first check
ourselves so for example if you would
like I think a great quote by Gandhi
right it's been over quoted a thousand
million gazillion times I've seen
Instagram quote memes everywhere with
the little Indian guy wearing glasses
says be the change that you'd like to
see in the world well that is a profound
and brilliant way to put it if you want
your children like I refer to in my blog
post you want your children to practice
healthy habits you want your children to
drink water then you yourself should be
practicing healthy habits and drinking
water if you want your workers if you
want your friends if you want anyone in
your environment who you're hoping to
influence in a positive way to take
action in that direction you yourself
must first take that action I remember
when I was a kid when we would find
ourselves bored as all kids and
developing nations do right because
we've got so much available to us get
bored that's fucking crazy right with
all the toys and the video games and the
opportunities available we get bored so
when I would say to my
dad dad I'm bored he would tell me I'll
go read a book and that became a mantra
to him when he saw us not doing engaging
in anything constructive
my dad was has always been a proponent
of engaging in constructive activity
using your time wisely he would say go
read a book go read a book you guys are
just sitting around here go read a book
you're not doing anything go read a book
well the thing is he said it toes blue
in the face and we never read any
fucking books we never read never read
any books we were kids and and in
retrospect and I love my dad he's
probably going to watch this video but
he knows what I'm talking about I want
to say this I've never seen the man read
a freaking book in my life my dad wants
us to read books and he understands here
right that it's a good idea for my
children to read books because it's
going to advance their education and
they were going to become something in
the world if they absorb new information
by reading books but at the same time
first time I saw my dad read a book was
the Bible about two years ago right so
it never really worked out that way he'd
say go read a book and we kind of say no
or roll our eyes or pretend like we're
going to read and go do something else
we weren't allowed to say no to my dad
so we would go and pretend to do
something else I also grew up with a
friend whose parents he was an only
child his name was David whose parents
when I would go to his house were
constantly reading books I go into the
house and his dad would be sitting there
on a couch reading a freaking book his
mom would be in the kitchen reading a
book or she and then she'd come down and
sit in her special chair and she'd read
a book never once that these people ever
tell me and they had a library they have
big old library in the house books
everywhere never once that these people
tell me Elliott you need to read a book
Elliott you need to read books reading
is good for you I just used to go to his
house every weekend and I'd see these
people reading books as I got older you
know I spent 79 spent a significant
amount of time at my friend's house as I
got older when I was uh towards the end
of college I started to have this um
especially when I left college I started
having this
longing for a return to stability I
think all of us who graduate college you
know around the age of 23 you know we're
supposed to go out into the world at the
same time every time you're going out
into the world
you're also hoping to bring along with
you grounding activities that's why you
know if you like a little kid it's going
to sleep over someone else's house the
grounding activity of bringing is teddy
bear right those are you left for
college I guarantee you you probably
brought Little Bo Mentos little things
that grounded you in your upbringing in
order to keep you feeling safe when
you're venturing off into the new world
one of the things that made me feel safe
one of the things that affected me to
deepen it in a deep way we're books and
I had to think back as to how the hell
did this happen because my parents never
read any books we never had any
libraries but it really did it flash
forth in my mind became very clear to me
at that moment I am getting a sense of
console Minh is that the right word a
sense of safety and security because of
the experiences that I had in my
friend's home with his parents reading
books and I'd read books I feel safe and
fun like I was with my best friend at
his house those people controlled
energies mr. and mrs. Chauvin they
controlled energy they controlled me to
control the environment not by trying to
manipulate it by telling people what to
do or telling us what to do but by they
themselves taking on the character in
the habit that they would like to see
reflected in the young people in their
homes this extends itself across the
board far beyond just that of the
relationship between child and parent
but like I said even amongst your
friends right how much of an energetic
anchor are you how strong and potent is
your power to change your own character
your own habits your own thoughts fears
hopes and dreams in order to change the
people around you now this is not a
hundred percent every single time it's
going to work that way but I can tell
you one thing if you don't change the
people in your circumstance the change
the people in your sir in your world
don't change after you've evolved I can
guarantee you this a number of things
will probably happen they will seem
seemingly disappear you won't have to
push them away because you're evolving
because you're becoming the type of
person you'd like to see in the world
because you're becoming the change you'd
like to see in the world your world is
going to change and sometimes it
requires people disappearing and it'll
just happen that way a lot of us become
very arrogant in our choices right my
stop smoking and because I stopped
smoking anyone who smokes needs to get
far from away from me beyond you ill
smokers doesn't have to work that way
the simple fact that you don't smoke
means you're not going to be going on
smoking breaks anymore you probably
won't be chatting with those people you
don't have to push them away your energy
will take care of it your character who
you are your thoughts your habits your
hopes and dreams for having a healthier
body guess what you probably start
talking to people reading vegetables you
won't have to force it you don't have to
force them but they're going to be
attracted to you because you're a
vegetable eater do you see how this
works so I'll leave you with this let's
open a dialogue friends about what we
might be able to do in order to change
ourselves so that we could see the
reflection of our strongest version the
best that we could be in other people
had a conversation not too long ago I
said I'd leave you with this but I just
remember this one had a conversation too
long ago with a friend and mentor of
mine and he says uh Elliot be very clear
and cautious
about what you're teaching people
through your videos what you're teaching
people at your gym what you're sharing
with your students and your customers
and your fans and your friends because
you're essentially creating the world
that you're going to ultimately live in
your you you're going to sleep in the
bed that you made right you make your
bed and now you're sleep in it and if
you're putting out videos if you're
putting out information you're putting
out ideas if you're putting out a
character a way of being that is not
conducive with what you would hope to
see the world as right imagine you come
back I'm going to come back in two
generations and my vibration has
reverberate 'add through multiple
lineage multiple people and I come back
and I see a bunch of people acting real
arrogant and angry and fearful and
hatred and hateful I can only expect to
have that be the reflection if that's
the way I've been I've been carrying
myself so I'll leave you with this once
more what kind of vibrations are you
setting out what are you setting up
what are you setting the world up to be
like for future generations imagine you
could be on a fly on the wall and you
come back in a in a hundred years and
you can see the butterfly effect of what
you've created with your with your if
your thoughts your character and so on
and so forth would you like what you see
right are the people sick overweight
fearful and jealous angry hateful
prejudice biased and
and have all sorts of illness mentally
and physically or is a world where
people hug one another and smile is it a
world where people make good choices
about the food that they eat is it a
world where the water is clean in the
air is fresh it'll be completely
contingent upon the way you think and
act today done