so gentlemen today we have an
interesting question for one of our
friends about sex transmutation
in fact he's read the book Think and
Grow Rich by Napoleon Hill and it's
perhaps the most mystical and I think
misunderstood
chapter in that book again Napoleon Hill
Think and Grow Rich for those you who
want to go and read it but it's called
sex transmutation and in the book he
alludes to the fact that there is an
energy we call it sex energy within the
human body that can be can be used to
either produce riches because the book
is about building business and riches
and empower in the world or through the
through extending that sexual energy the
masculine energy into the literal
feminine a woman so there's this idea
with regard to sex transmutation that if
you don't have women you're going to be
a better success in the world so you're
not having sex with women meaning you're
going to have now all that sexual energy
to go and achieve your goals fight in
the world and to be a winner right so a
number of things our friends offer our
friend offers here number one he says I
haven't had sex with a woman in three
years he's 25 years old and he says well
I I'm not that good at attracting women
number one and number two he says but I
jerk off every day
when I watch pornography and a jerk off
every day now he's concerned that
although he calls himself an
entrepreneur and he's got a tremendous
career he seems to be a go-getter he
seems he very much in the world doing
his things
he is feeling guilty about jerking off
every day because how is that somehow
going to lessen the potency of my sexual
drive my sexual transmutation into
challenging and winning in the world so
I'll begin like this prior to the
physical expression of sex be it the
expression of a penis or a vagina the
way you show up in this world is an
expression of our sex I'm a man my wife
is a female she's a woman and the sexual
act itself the union of penis and vagina
the literal act of screwing there is an
energy there is a spirit there's a power
there's a consciousness that's
associated with feminine and masculine
and they both have very distinct traits
about them and if we come to understand
how to hone in Harbor and use the power
of these contrasting energies we really
become a mastermind we really take full
control of our life and we really can
become a success both in business career
riches like Napoleon Hill and have a big
beautiful healthy family and a wife
who's very satisfied or a girlfriend
right now I'm just describing my life
but very satisfied with your discharge
of sexual energy into her and into the
home
your physical sexual energy meaning
fucking and procreation like for
children
it's the management of the energy more
so than the management of your dick and
even if you have a wife or girlfriend
and you're having sex every day with her
or if you're jerking off the physical
act of evacuating of discharging the
sexual energy in your physical body
I don't believe and of course there
there's so many arguments with regard to
this and there's even science behind it
I'm just offering my experience I have
no I have no proof right now I do
research on this all I can offer is
what's happened to me there is very
little especially if you're highly
charged and I think this this is why the
ants one answer won't work for all
people
I'm very highly charged I've got a lot
of sexual energy not meaning I've got a
jerk off twice a day and fuck my wife
every night meaning I've got a lot of
vitality very vital in that way so I can
I can I can insert myself into the world
I don't say all this so you guys so I
sound like Elliott Hulse is fucking
amazing and I wish I was alien house I
say this because I've structured my life
in a particular way and I've made use of
certain innate qualities but I've also
built up certain things that I knew were
weakened imbalanced in myself so that I
can win in the world right Think and
Grow Rich I think & Grow Rich I do that
and have a happy healthy huge family and
satisfied my wife like I did last night
she satisfied me we satisfied each other
we say thank you after sex
so how is it that you can do this well
with regard to women and when I say
women of course it's the embodiment of
sexual of the feminine energy in a human
body so women are humans before they're
before they are women just like you're
you're human before you're a man so this
is no knock against women this is just
how the feminine energy shows up in a
body with a vagina and it's so funny how
the penis and the vagina are embodiments
of the actual the way the energy acts
masculine energy goes out like this
masculine energy builds up and goes out
right right so when you have an idea for
a business it's very masculine to think
of the idea you're charging yourself
it's fucking foreplay you charge you
charge you charge you get so excited
that you stand up and you're going get a
loan from the bank you go and build a
website you go and make some videos
that's very edge Acula Tori it's very
discharging you going out into the world
men and women have this energy but the
penis that's what it does it's like a
gun firearms discharge your firearm huh
the vagina the physical structure of the
vagina I've made videos about this a lot
of people get upset when I talk about
penises and vaginas fuck you about that
the vagina absorbs yields it takes in
its softens and opens up through an
external environment that allows it to
do so that's why women need to be
romanced more than men they need the
room this smell good they need flowers
and they need a you know a nice
environment and they need to be told
nice things and and lay back so they can
take what is it would be tents right
this is even better
take what's tents and open up oh so nice
when the vagina just it's all it's ready
it's opened up it's opened up it's
opened up because of an external
stimulus sometimes internal to but this
is you know I'm describing like the
black and white of it
the desire for both is in each sex but
the physical structure dictates what one
will want more of most men want to
ejaculate right even if you're
homosexual men and you take it in your
body the desire to ejaculate is there
because you have the tools for a Jack
ulation the feminine and your whole
attitude will be about that that's why
they say he's on a prowl you know a guy
who's out looking for women he's on the
prowl because he's going he's looking
for somewhere to ejaculate women on the
other hand don't go out and ejaculate
the vagina
it might go out with a with an
aggression look meaning I'm actively
seeking what are you actively seeking
the sucking in the pulling in the
drawing in of ener-g you know when when
you have sex with a woman and she's
really desiring you the vagina almost
sucks the energy out of the penis it
like they ever notice this
so the woman's going out to look for
something to absorb that's what the
vagina does
here's how it works here's how you can
have both and it really requires a good
partnership between yourself and your
wife or your girlfriend or you know I
know your question was about it is about
jerking off jerking off you don't have
these problems so keep tracking off but
you haven't been with a woman in three
years so I'm gonna say dude you got to
figure out sexual dynamics and go bring
a woman into your life to balance you
out now that it's necessary you have to
right but if you want to enjoy what it's
all about why not spread your seeds in
the world with your entrepreneurial
endeavors spread your seeds in
proliferation and sexual unity just my
invitation just what I did that's all no
judgment
the man and the woman first have to
respect each other and the reason why I
say that is that it's not so much a
bowing down to the other person but a
recognizing of how the sexual energy in
that other person is being manifest and
I'm going to start with how a man might
need a woman to be so that things work
because it goes both ways but of course
we I talk mostly to men you've got to
give your love to your woman when the
time is appropriate
meaning you walk through the door she's
wanting you either sexually which is you
know what 15% of the time 20% of time
depending on who you are but really to
engage with her to speak to her
women want that when we want you to talk
to them that's how they that's that's
their aggression that's how they let out
that's how they discharge they want you
to just listen I want you to listen they
want you to care about what they're
wearing they want you to desire them
smell her hold her let her know she's
desirable she want her she wants her
home to make her comfortable she doesn't
want to be in a stinky how like dudes we
can have socks that stink on the floor
and this is like you know I'm gonna
sleep women doesn't don't want that
because they're absorbers and she's
absorbing your stinky fucking feet keep
the house clean
do you see go home and engage in the
sucking action of the feminine when
you're there when you're with her give
it all to her when you're with her
here's what has to happen
that's sexual energy this is where
sexual transmutation comes in that
sexual energy that you're giving to a
woman and mind you you know flipping the
switch is not easy we've got to find
ways to be able to flip our switches
when you walk into the home and when you
walk out of the home and we're the
reason why I say the home is because in
my genre in my way the home is the
woman's
my home is all my woman's I have one
spot with my laptop and I'm a hammock
and that's it whatever you want babe
whatever you want baby it's your home
I'll pay for it all - I want you to have
it
the hell am I saying you got to be able
to flip the switch between being with
your woman and taking the same amount of
potency the same Drive same energy to
give her and then give it into your work
that's sexual transmutation it's taking
the same drive to to make happy your
domestic situation and drive it into
your work into your career into your
entrepreneurial venture and sever off my
wife knows when I if if she calls me and
I'm working say but work right sometimes
she gets that sometimes you get hooked
and the reason being is I'm fucking the
world now when I say fucking I'm
literally I'm giving my sexual energy to
the world I'm making videos right now
she knows when I'm making videos babe
don't call me I'm with another right
keeping myself it looks different though
the posture the posture when you're
giving yourself out in the world isn't a
dick energy and this is why we have to
separate ourselves from the physical
sexual dynamics it's really the
energetic sexual dynamics because I'm
being very masculine when I make these
videos because just look at my body and
you'll know this about a man it's very
masculine does he someone he's on his
toes he's moving forward he engages when
I make my videos you know what I look
like so you guys don't see me from the
side we're making a video this is what I
look like what I'm making my videos I'm
like this I'm engaged I'm what is that
firearms I'm firing I'm giving my sexual
energy to my thing thank to my craft to
my work to my art this is my art ah
when you're with a woman you know check
it out this is what I look like when I
go home right it's all sexual energy but
one's penis and one is of my mind and
heart passion I take the energy the
sexual energy from down here I grow it
up and I give it to the world
now you'd only be so ungrounded that
that's all you do and you never have sex
with a woman for three years and you're
25 years old bad idea you got to do the
other one now check this out this is
what sexual energy looks like when I'm
at home your body is your mind folks
right it's here it's more of a it's more
of a leaning forward with the hips like
a home and it's like hey baby I'm home
what does that look like besides that
the sweat stain hey I'm open I'm
available to you I'm giving you myself
right on the world ah at home ah say
anyway I'm having a lot of fun with you
guys today I'm really charged up today
Monday's I usually am because I rested a
lot though during the weekend because
when I go home I rest in the vagina and
my wife creates house smells good got my
hammock you see so it's more of a
management of your sexual energy than a
penis and vagina thing it's not to say
you can't have a girlfriend you can't
have a wife and still be a success in
the world but you've got to know how to
manage it a woman who doesn't understand
because like I said I'll try to go both
ways a woman who doesn't understand your
energy the sexual energy the dynamics of
the sexual energy is going to nag you
because you're going to go on to the
world you're going to be aggressive and
if you're mindful here's the thing
you've got to be mindful also it takes
both and you come home and she wants all
of you and then when you decide you're
going to leave but a lot of women do
this to their men I've got a homework
babe I gotta go do thing I got to go
into the world she becomes very jealous
a jealous
woman not jealous because your fucking
other woman but because you're you're
working too hard you're doing too much
out there make sure now here's the thing
make sure you're giving her enough right
don't fuck the world more than your
fucking your woman but if you're giving
everything you have to your woman and
it's and you say okay babe I'm going
this way and she goes jealous needy she
wants to suck suck on you more you guys
that's a problem you need to educate her
and the same thing with the man a woman
needs to be loved I know this sounds
sexist right in the Bible right men love
your women and men and women respect
your men but it is what it fucking is
it's sexual energy women respect the
fact that your man is going to work now
of course we live in a world where the
sexual dynamics are all screwed up and
we're kind of flipping scripts right now
and women work outside the home and men
are staying home with babies right
whatever that is no judgment again
alright I wipe asses every day I want to
Nast this morning babies I've got lots
of room all right but but I'm just
describing to sexual the black and white
once again of the sexual energy men
you've got to love your won't you give
yourself to your woman if you come home
and you're still you're still this way
you're still thinking about your career
you're still thinking about work you
still think you're thinking thinking
you're so angry about what your boss
said to you you're not available to your
women no wonder why she's upset with you
no wonder why she wants more of you you
come home and yield just I mean an
erection although it looks like it's
aggressive an erection comes about
because you relax relax relax into your
woman relax into your home give her
yourself give her your love adorn her
show her your appreciation let her know
how to
hireable she is that's what the feminine
wants is to feel desirable worth being
inserted into right of course there are
all types of sexist associations with
the shit that I'm saying but hey I got a
big mouth a woman wants to feel fuckable
she wants to feel like she's worth being
fucked and it's up to you
to give that to her if your sex life is
horrible with your woman it's your fault
you're not making her feel fuckable
enough it's all about it it's all about
the way we make each other feel right
and not a day goes by that my woman
doesn't know that I believe she's the
most beautiful woman in the world
I look deeply in her face and I kiss her
she knows without a doubt she is the
most desirable woman in the world
and with that type of extension of
sexual energy towards my woman in home I
have more than enough to flip it off and
give it to you
done