hey before I start ranting on this video
the very first thing I want to do is
extend some gratitude and say thank you
to those you who have recognized that
the elliott hulse that you've seen on
camera for the past several days and in
fact every video recorded this week is
not the elliott hulse that you're used
to in fact it's not the elliott hulse
that i have come to know over the past
several years either so again the main
reason why I want to make this video is
because I I am grateful of the fact that
I have so many people that are concerned
about me now we might not know each
other and we just exchanged bits through
the internet you know the cloud in the
sky you guys write comments and I make
these videos but two for me to recognize
that you see how different I've been
just sheds light on the fact that how
close we actually are you know I know
many of you know a lot about me and you
watch me every single day and you can
tell when the look and Elliott's eyes
isn't what it usually is and I tried to
deny it I tried to talk circles around
it I try to as Elliot house often does
philosophize about it but here's the
thing it's true I am NOT myself I am not
feeling myself and I just got out of the
office with a really good friend and
mentor of mine and we spoke for two
hours on what this what's going on there
are a few different ways to approach
this number one is this it's merely
evolution human beings evolved but I'm
hitting a rough patch so it's not just
smooth evolution you know because I
there's a lot of anxiety there's a lot
of frustration there's a lot of
confusion in me I'm tired I'm burnt out
and you could see that in my eyes and
you know this so what's really happening
and the conclusion that we came to is
that I've made some poor decisions over
the past several months about my
nutrition lifestyle and even my training
that has without getting too much into
the training aspects and died and the
philosophy there with within it has just
become a situation where my body has
become too much for my soul to carry
it's too heavy I've gained too much
fucking wait
I mean there's no other way to put it
I've gained so much weight that my body
might the soul can't express itself
through me the way it should now it's
it's not just the body weight but it's
also the pollution associated with
eating foods that are wrong for my
metabolic type I know better than to
start eating diets participating in
diets that are more of a bodybuilding
type diet they just don't work for me
I'm sure they work well for other people
but there's a particular diet that works
well for my metabolic type that my
body's used to that allows my brain to
be as quick as it should be well as my
nervous system to be as sharp as it
should be and allows Elliot Hills to
express himself and its fullest and then
there are diets that fuck that all up
and I've been eating diet I know better
you know sometimes we make decisions
that uh it's almost like I want to try
it out wanna see you know even though
you know the answer sometimes you know
what's going to happen you still do it
and I did it and and the same thing goes
with the training you know hypertrophy
type training does not work well with me
because it restricts my motility and
I've used that word before and a lot of
people don't know what it means but it
it's how soft the muscular system is in
order to allow full energetic or
emotional expression and I'm an
emotional fucking guy figure it out and
what makes my ability to express myself
verbally through these videos verbally
and physically because I move a lot if
you haven't figured it out my face and
body is always fucking moving is the
softness in my muscular system my
ability to breathe deep bodybuilding
training doesn't allow that so those
things coupled with just the you know
the tremendous change in my life due to
the popularity of these freaking videos
has just been a a whirlwind it's a
perfect storm for for the depths of I
guess you could say depression that I've
put myself into so I could assure you
that everything will be just fine
because I figured it out and you know I
my soul figured it out I understood this
I felt this I knew I was going against
what my body actually wanted when I went
down this road but I'm back on my diet
which is
a paleo like intermittent fasting which
I'm coming to discover is not just great
for health you know their health
benefits but psychological benefits
associated with restricting the the
quote-unquote hunger impulse within the
body you it's almost where you allow the
greater you to control the lower you or
me you know fuck I don't wanna talk for
everybody but I know that when I can use
my mind to come my body that I am in a
stronger place and intermittent fasting
allows me to do that back on the road to
that back to athletic training you've
seen me doing Olympic lifting it's great
because there's a challenge for me
Olympic lifting is brand new to me in
many ways and and it's athletic it's not
it's not narcissistic like bodybuilding
and I was actually becoming narcissistic
through the bodybuilding not just
physically but psychologically so that's
it again the main purpose of this video
is to extend my gratitude say thank you
for your concern your care and dare I
say love for Elliott Hulse and to let
you know that yes we are in relationship
with each other even though it was just
bits on a screen and I love you as well
and that's why I extend myself through
this service of sharing my journey
sharing my ideas and supporting you as
you grow stronger