so if you hate being on any sort of
media isn't it weird being married to a
guy who's in the media all the time yeah
I love watching him I love watching him
on camera he's such a natural I sit at
home with the kids
I just watch him on the computer watches
every single video and we'll watch him
over and over because the kid loved to
see him really so I mean he goes to work
and then okay so you you've been around
well obviously for a long time married
ten years okay today they're 18 years so
since you guys would be okay that's a
whole another like I'll ask about that
but um so you've seen him sort of like
progress in terms of like how he is on
camera like basically you see yeah I
mean he's only been on camera for I
guess six years okay um you say 2006
maybe he started getting on camera okay
before that he was just doing personal
training and so like I always wonder
because I always wonder like what it's
like to see someone that you know and
you know I'm better than probably anyone
yeah what it's like to watch that person
on camera to like is there I don't know
it's a weird is it like what you see on
camera is exactly what I see every
single day in my living room okay or at
our dinner table right or at our
breakfast table it is it's like it's a
he'll call it he's a show but really
it's just he's just doing what he does
that's him that is him
he is lecturing and preaching and it's
like he practices on us just great
because I've learned a ton but that's
just how he is I mean he is constantly a
show to watch
okay now has he always been like this
yes maybe not to the extent or to the
with as many topics but he's always been
passionate about whatever he was doing
at the time okay
I mean it's definitely gotten bigger and
more intense true and his mind is
expanded a lot I mean I remember in
college he used to listen to Alan Watts
the audio programs I don't know it's
like philosophy and that's when I
started seeing that transition into like
bigger thinking but up until then it was
you know strings getting stronger for
football and stuff right interesting so
this this part of him it's like it's
always been there like that he's always
had that inquisitive like nature yes
yeah and I know he's he'll tell story
about how he's always asked like what
are you what are you what are you and I
remember even from when we were in high
school he would always be searching for
himself and I was like I didn't know
what the hell he was talking about like
what do you mean you're looking for
yourself
me me is like you know I'm just trying
to figure out who I am and you know
what's on the inside and I'm like I
didn't get it I didn't get it until I
would say until even after we were
married I didn't get it but he's always
been a searcher he's always been trying
to figure out what's more than just my
bones in my skin and my muscles like
really where where's the God in me or
where
the life force of me you know he's
always like I don't know do you find it
weird cuz I think when you look at
someone like Elliot who's so he's he's
obviously physical right you look at him
and you can tell that this guy puts a
lot of people's work into his body do
you find it maybe you're used to it but
do you find it sort of weird that
there's this whole other element that's
more deep well I don't know I don't want
to see well maybe I mean I think a lot
of people when they see guys who work
out they just think oh this is what
they're all about right but there's
obviously with his youtube show and
stuff like that there's a whole lot more
there I think it's funny to watch other
people's reactions to it I mean for me
it's just the way it is right but the
same when he works hard at his body he
works hard at I mean works hard to
developing his heart and he works
started developing I see him working at
developing some other aspects than just
his body so then when it comes out right
it's just his free and natural way of
being I think it is weird like you don't
see him any muscle heads that are like
studying philosophy and sociology and
you know all those crazy things that he
studies but for me I've just always
known him like that right so it's not
even fourteen-year-old Elliot there was
traces of interesting
I mean I wonder at him and his brothers
having conversations especially as
brother Ellis like responsible
conversations and I'm like you know I
don't know where it came from
okay even in this early twenties in 1915
1920 thinking just totally outside the
box okay so you're just like you used to
this down here okay um now in terms of
the delight the celebrity does it does
it affect I know it's weird right yeah
does it affect like other parts of the
the relationship like is there is there
ever a time where you just like whoa
like this yeah never okay I I can't even
think of like what you're almost I don't
know it's like my kids tell me they are
their dad is famous and they'll tell
other people that their dad is famous
right another peep they'll be like what
did what's she talking about I'm like he
just has Lily YouTube channel and he
just he just talks on camera so they see
him on you know video all the time so
they think he's famous right but well
within our community he is certainly
famous and I think like if when we go to
San Diego when what was the room people
yes right but it hasn't gotten to a
point yet where it started to affect you
guys no no I mean and again I'll say
even from when we were in high school
college no matter where we go people
know him even before he was on film it
would just seem like wherever we web
people we were on our honeymoon in like
Aruba and he knew someone on the cruise
Edgar well we went to a restaurant when
we were in San Diego when we were out
there San Diego and he news like it just
seems like it's always been that way so
now it definitely is a little bit more
right we went to UM we took the kids to
the high school which is a religious
type school a couple times up in
Clearwater and like then that afternoon
you got an email like oh my god I can't
believe you're up a high school I didn't
know you were i watch your channel all
the time so I mean it's like he gets it
but it hasn't affected us I mean okay
besides affected travels you know people
that he goes that is that affects the
family more than anything okay not
negatively it's just it's such a major
right okay something I wanted to touch
on this is maybe like I sort of
resonates with me and when he tells a
story it's something I'm really curious
about is he tells like he talks about
the times where things were tough in
terms of like getting the business off
the ground and things like that and I
always wonder for someone who's like the
partner of someone in that position is
it frustrating yeah
again we've had so we're very very open
our communication is always flowing and
he is he said to me very early on if we
decide to you know go forth and get
married and have a life together
it's going to be a roller coaster I mean
he's he has said this to me many times
that before we committed to each
you know we were together in high school
college but before we actually got
married and decided to have children he
was very clear and knowing him for that
many years beforehand I knew what he was
talking about he said it's not gonna be
easy it's not always gonna be roses
because he's you know up and down up and
down um and he I know he does crazy
things well the tea always does crazy
things it does things that people
usually aren't willing to do that
usually put us in situations that make
things a little difficult right he loves
to be uncomfortable right loves to be
uncomfortable I can't we just be
comfortable for a couple months no he
likes to be uncomfortable um so I mean
it's he warned me ahead of time that it
wasn't gonna just be a smooth easy ride
you know he's you know he's been told
before why don't you just go get a job
in a hospital as a health care
administrator you know start working on
that path you get benefits and you get a
nice even salary and you could live a
nice life I knew from very early on
that's not what I was getting myself
involved with right and just so I just
knowing him since he was so young it's
been pretty easy for me to adjust and
the fact that I have faith in him no
matter what even when we like were
struggling to the food on the table I
had faith that he was doing 110 percent
to make it work and I always knew that
his priority was us rose his wife and
his family so at no point was I like oh
he's trying to make money to go buy a
new car or oh he's trying to make money
so he can go on fancy vacation you know
it was always like knowing that his
priority is his family and that I know
he's doing everything he can you know
people like well how come you just kept
having faith how come you just kept
trusting that he was gonna finally make
it and I'm like well it I committed to
doing that right and
I wasn't you know I would never consider
not doing that that's so I mean AHA
there has been frustrating times that
were like you know he's working as hard
as he can work he's working as many
hours as he can work and still things
weren't easy right but again he likes to
be uncomfortable so it's like when we
were in that type of situation
he would always just work ten times
harder right and somehow make it work
okay so it hasn't always been fun it
definitely hasn't always been easy but
just knowing that he's always given it
way more than anybody could possibly
give you know like you think like Oh
someone can work this hard but then he
like just goes beyond that and looks
youngg right what do you think he's
capable of so like in those in those
instances where it was really trying
like what what did you do to or was
there anything that you did to find that
that reassurance that we definitely
prayed a lot more okay during those
times I remember praying with him and
you know I think your faith becomes a
lot stronger when you go through times
like that yeah so I know that we did I'm
thinking of a couple of years where we
did go back to go back to our faith a
lot stronger right you know you fall
back on God when things are difficult
right so that really helped and then I
mean just being thankful for what we did
have whenever I'd ask him for money for
like the mortgage or for food you know
whenever I'd like say okay I'd you but
however much money and he would give it
to me and say just thank God don't thank
me thank God and just constantly just
being thankful for what we did have and
and just keeping that gratitude at the
top of our type of our heart some type
of our mine
it's just rather than thinking like oh
my god how are we gonna buy groceries
next week it's like well let's thank God
that we can buy groceries this week and
then focus on next week now I know hey
we have kids at that time too I mean it
isn't like it was just he and I when the
more kids we had the more mouths to feed
and think we don't have to worry about
groceries now but I mean it was it was
tough
so did did you ever have any I'm sort of
like I'm speaking from a place where I'm
like I can I can relate to some of the
things you guys are talking about and a
lot of like almost watching or speaking
to you and being around Elliott it's
like I'm hoping it's sort of seeing how
things are sort of playing up for me
right now did you guys ever have any
concerns about having more children or
anything like that given the way the
situation used to be um well
we always just got pregnant okay with
Isabel with our first one we kind of
knew that we were gonna have our first
child and then after her it was just
like Oh looks like we're pregnant again
okay it's like we're pregnant again but
again I know we have faith that if you
work hard God will provide right so I
mean and again I don't know if it's just
blind phase I don't know if it's
stupidity but I honestly and when every
time we found out we were pregnant we're
like okay here we go again
let's get you know get back to work and
keep pushing forward but I mean there's
always that fear like oh my god a
minister eventually came around please
we're getting looking up looking better
and he's only two and a half right and
we just have faith that when you work
hard and you you have your intentions
set in that direction that it's gonna
work out and again he likes to be
uncomfortable so even when things start
to get you know like we used to use
credit cards we used credit cards for
years Simone was born in August of 2008
and on September 11th 2008 so a couple
weeks later we decided to pay back our
credit cards so every Monday was like
$400 would come out of his account to
pay back our credit cards whether we
liked it or not that money was coming
out of the account right and we didn't
have $400 a week to pay back credit
cards right but somehow every Monday
that money would come out of his account
and it was just like it was crazy that
we decided to do that but he was a
priority to get out of debt and it was
what we decided to do and had faith that
it was gonna work so you know having our
third child figure out like okay well we
used to use our credit cards to buy gas
and groceries and now all of a sudden
we're gonna have to use the money we
have for gas and groceries and pay back
so again he likes to like be in
situations where he's constantly
challenged and then like having to rise
to the challenge and it's that's
difficult for me too because I like to
be comfortable
like to just know we're gonna have this
we're gonna even if it's not a lot I
don't need a lot
I need healthy food a car that drives a
roof over our head I can shop at Target
for clothes I haven't I don't have high
expectations or high needs and neither
does he
but if we're here he wants us to be just
a little bit uncomfortable to get to the
next level I'm not necessarily to get
fancy or things but just I think to push
himself just to see what he can do and
that guess that gets frustrating
sometimes cuz I can't we just just chill
just chill right like now this year
student loans between the two of us I
want to see be it like at one point it
was like eighty-two thousand dollars in
student loans and it dropped like sixty
cuz we've been paying like the last ten
years
well I hover along we've been at ecology
and paying back student loans because
like this year we're paying off student
loans and two months he paid off his
student loan two months now we have all
my student loans to pay back using by
the end of this year we're gonna have no
student loans I'm I can't we just be
comfortable for a year he's like no we
have this is gonna get done
suits rather than just like being okay
it's like no we're every month they're
not so no $200 we're sending them as
much as we possibly can to push me to
the limit so that I have to work that
much harder next month right yes now one
thing that I've noticed with you guys is
um and like I have to give him credit
for this cuz no I'll give both you guys
credit obviously but um I noticed that
he he puts a lot of time in with with
the kids and a lot of a lot of like
people I know who have attained a
certain level of success they end up
sacrificing something and it's usually
it's usually the family but I've noticed
that Elliott he'll come in and
he looked like taking the kids somewhere
when you leave because he has to go pick
up the girls from practice gymnastics or
something how did you guys well I would
say back when he was working I mean I
remember when we first moved to Florida
he'd leave at like 5:30 in the morning
to start training clients at 6:00 and he
wouldn't get home until after I think
the gym closed it maybe 10 so we gave
him at 10:30 or maybe it was dat 9 suite
so he would never see Isabelle
man I mean there were months when he
worked at the gym here in st. Pete that
I mean weeks would go by and he worked
like 70 as a week I think you worked
three months straight without taking one
day off right from like 6:00 a.m. to
10:00 p.m. and we sometimes drive down
to see if he just to have lunch with him
so you at least get to see us for like
half an hour a day right um so it hasn't
always been this way but as he's been
able to end and since he quit that job
and again put his job months after we
bought our first house why he would do
that this is Elliott but he started his
own business which now is obviously a
successful business but um so it hasn't
always been like this where he's been
able to take the time but you know as
he's got his systems in place where he
knows he can work Tuesday's making
videos and Thursdays doing non you know
he he has his schedule so and and again
I he doesn't just say what he says he
does what he says because his priority
was making time for my family his value
is freedom family so it's like he knew
what he wanted and he created his
business around that so being able to
take the kids to gymnastics or to
CrossFit or to yoga you know wherever he
takes he's created his life right around
those core values you know we talked
about this at dinner the other night
it's like it's not like he just let the
business fall into place and then fit us
into it it's like he established his
family and has kind of made his business
fit into his priorities of life right
you know we he's even talked about like
having a trainer come here to train the
kids rather than ask me you know taking
them somewhere else a little bit more
convenient yeah I mean there were years
that like he just and still he comes
home from work and sometimes I sit on
the couch and his work until the minute
we go to bed right so you know as things
have gotten financially more stable he's
been able to have the freedom to have
more time with us but um yeah he he puts
in time this weekend he's gonna have the
kids all weekend from Friday a five
o'clock til Sunday afternoon okay yeah
he's gonna have them from this two days
so it's Elliott him in the case and the
kid okay that's the first time you said
all four of them from overnight how do
you think he'll fare how's it great okay
the kids are usually more well-behaved
when mommy's not there really oh yeah he
just he beasts lets them do whatever
they want and they're happy to do
whatever they want right there's no
rules there's no Pete is kind of less
than easy saying I mean he does if he
does bath and bedtime what you supposed
to do okay so with the kids there's
there's for for what
what part of him do you see each kid
ah is about she's the oldest and she is
clearly genius material she is a big
thinker she is ridiculously smart and
inquisitive right and he says she got it
from me but I'm pretty sure he got she
got it from him um she's she asked deep
deep questions from the time she was
able to talk she would ask questions
that are just above and beyond what she
should even be thinking about so I know
that's cuz I think I'm smart but I don't
think I'm Elliot smart he would argue
with you but so I know that's what she
got from him Emerson's generosity and
Merson has a big big heart and she is
just generous with her time and her
things and and he's very much like that
if he has he'll give he doesn't like to
hold on to stuff he wants to give it
away right
Simone's hyperactive energy Simone is
like balls that just bounce a little
place like she is a ball of energy and
when he was a child he was very much
like that from what I hear his parents
say and still you know you get him going
and he'll just be bouncing all over the
place too and Benjamin we don't know yet
I mean she he definitely looked like a
little clone right he's Elliot's clone
but personality-wise Benjamin's just
laid back and I guess Elliot can be laid
back but his I don't think his
personality it's quite obvious yet right
okay interesting yeah
they all got something from them so what
what does the future hold for
oh no more kids yeah oh we are done and
we are so done if Elliott wouldn't have
gotten his uh snip done when Benjamin
was 6 weeks old be definitely be on baby
number 6 by now Wow yeah but I knew we
were done with number 4 and I I made him
promise me once I have this baby do not
let me convince you that I want another
baby because I knew I run it for and
that was it and of course after what
Benjamin was born I was like maybe we
should have another baby
no so this is you this is your have more
right you would have 10 more I wanted to
Wow okay I knew I knew four words main
limit and even with four I feel like I
can't give each one enough right me no
matter how much you give you don't have
48 hours in one day to define a month
for four children so yeah he would have
more I was just my fourth pregnancy was
really really hard and I just yeah and
we got our boy right you know it was
just the icing on the cake you know if
he was a girl we probably would have had
six children yeah because I didn't want
an odd number I'm just a little bit
particular about that so he would have
gone and had six kids what is it what's
it like in the house with it's like a
circus it's like a three-ring circus I
mean there's stuff going on in the
playroom there's stuff going on in the
living room there's kids dressing up
there's kids running up and down the
stairs there's Isobel Flemming her door
to keep the little ones out way there's
someone come wipe my butt
there's kids trying to escape out the
front door kids trying to escape over
the gates kids I mean it's just it's
crazy there's always something
it is easy last night I ran out to the
store and it came back and all four of
them were like sitting on the couch
watching a movie that Elliott had put on
and I was like wow like that does not
happen very often well for them to be
sitting down at one time quietly does
not happen yeah sounds like you guys
have a very full full yeah life but
that's like it's a blessed life
definitely yeah yeah okay everyone's
going to be they they're gonna want to
get a glimpse into what it's like to to
be something that is always when people
ask me like you know how did Elliott
build his business how did he go from
like being a personal trainer to being
where he is now he's rebellious right
and just that that spirit in him that
says that I don't have to settle for
what I'm doing I can always do better I
can police I don't have to just follow
along with what everybody else does and
says and be like a sheep um but even
beyond that I think his biggest quality
like his most what what makes him stand
out from lots of people that I see that
are just in their miserable jobs and
it's his courage I mean he is there have
been times that we've been scared like
what are we gonna do and he'll he'll act
in spite of his fear we will do the
thing that seems the scariest that will
get him to where he wants to go right no
matter how scared he is because people
like wasn't he scared to put his job
wasn't he scared to commit to paying off
his credit cards wasn't scared to any
thousand of those things that he's done
that are
just like why did he choose to do that
and it's like well because I don't know
where he gets the courage from but
somehow regardless of how scared he has
been at different parts of his life he's
chose to do it anyway right and I think
that's like that's the essence of him
it's like don't let your fear stop you
from getting to where you want to be
right because there are so many people
that I you know that hate their job that
miserable and their marriage or in their
family situation you know and they just
stay because it's more comfortable the
easiest thing to do right but they're
just scared that you know what what if I
do put my job and try to do something
else they're scared of failure right I
think to be able to see him
time and time and time again knowing
he's scared he'll tell me he's scared
but then to still do it anyway that has
inspired me I mean we've had our babies
at home all our babies were born at home
is it no okay
so when I see what he can do and then he
is able to encourage me and able to
support me I know he's coming from a
place of experience doing things is
afraid to do knowing that there's gonna
be a better outcome than if I just stay
doing what I've been doing right you
know so he's only like always led by
example he never asks me to do something
that he hasn't done or never app tells
people to do what they what he hasn't
done himself right or he'll say like I
haven't tried this but you know you
might want to try it but he will usually
come from a place of experience and a
place of just facing your fears and
doing it anyway I mean that's that's
awesome yeah yeah I think even the first
time I met him that's something that I
want to wave it that was like I think
that's huge right I think if people can
get anything from him it's that don't
let your fear stop you
from living the life you want to live
right because sometimes you know you
just have to take that first step and
then it's like you throw yourself in
there and somehow you figure it out
right but if you never take that first
step you just stay back in that old way
of being and you never know and so what
have you failed I mean there's worst
thing that can happen you know and he'll
always say like think of like the worst
thing that could possibly happen if you
quit your job you know so you have to go
live back at your parents or you know
what's the worst thing you happen if you
can live with the worst thing that can
happen then go ahead and do it
like he's a smart guy yes I wouldn't
even use the word well-rounded because
well-rounded just seems so underwhelming
right
he's just so expansive I guess that's
the were just expansive that it's just
you think you know who he is and then
he'll come home from work and I'll be
like I just read the most awesome thing
on this website and I'm gonna like the
child psychology that now he's reading
this new book about child psychology and
we've always had discussions about the
connection between the child and the
mother and I just come home with some
new totally new idea or totally a new
topic of interest and delve into it for
like a month and I'm like where did you
come up with an idea to start
researching that and he'll just it's
just so expensive and when you think you
know it right when you think you know
him there's something else let me ask
you something do you think okay I won't
I don't want to frame the question what
do you think has kept you guys have been
together since you're 14 right what do
you think is kept you guys so like
interested in each other cuz you see a
lot of people that are together for a
long time the way you're speaking about
him it's like yeah yeah this guy's oh he
is right well because he I mean first of
all he's never boring right and I think
I am his rock I'm his steady I am his
constant right and he is my fluctuation
and my change in my excitement right so
it's like we both can rely on each other
for what we don't have in ourselves
right um cuz I mean for him you know he
Epson flows he is all over the place in
terms of business and what training he's
doing this month and what diet keeps
doing this month
and what always all over the place just
very it's almost yeah but I am is
constant right I am what is there all
the time and can be relied upon and can
ground him right does a pretty good job
grounding himself but and then of course
I just think he's so awesome he's fun he
makes me laugh we just get each other is
there anything else you want to add
before I mean what you see is what you
get
thank you for the interview that was
amazing
yeah all right