we got a pretty weird question here for
my buddy Nick and I'm not saying you're
weird Nick I'm saying your situation is
a lot different goes on to say um after
an introduction he says I just finished
my first semester in college and I did
terrible
krasin ated with my papers didn't study
for finals while the work is easy I
didn't put in any effort part of the
reason I'm in college is in order to get
the student loans which I'm using to pay
off legal debt and get off of probation
okay I've watched your other videos on
this topic you know he just says my lack
of effort is me wanting to break out of
social norms and do something else my
correct he says I feel like I'm stuck in
life what I want to do is train and go
stronger I had knee surgery in April
don't let me train the way I want to
train bla bla bla still bugs me I also
mentioned I'm on probation I've been for
a year and a half completely ruined my
life and I have to pay an exorbitant
exorbitant
I think that's the word you're looking
for oh he says absurd
sorry absurd amount of restitution which
I'm doing by getting loans from going to
college I have a curfew at 9:00 p.m.
which has ruined my social life I
haven't been laid in over a year
everyone I know is away at four-year
college I'm a community college which is
in a different County so I can't hang
out with any of my friends I'm here and
I can't leave I don't know he's on
probation so we can't go anywhere spread
all this once I get my fines paid off I
can start living again please consider
answering my question Elliott so our
subject is frustrated annoyed and bored
with my life okay real strange because
you're using loans to pay off your legal
debt and in order to get those loans
you've got to go and basically go to
jail because that's what school is just
Jail for you right now it's a place for
you to go just to do time really you're
just doing time you should do time so
she can earn some money to pay off your
legal debts for whatever
trouble you I'm assuming you got into so
you're in prison
here's the thing here's why you're
thinking it's so fucking backwards
you're putting yourself in prison to pay
off legal debts the legal debts will be
paid off but now you're back in prison
because you're gonna have to pay off the
student loans so you're spending time in
prison school you're in school for the
wrong reasons you're not in schools you
want to be in fucking school you know
that and I'm not here nor there with
regard to you going to school I'm trying
to bring some logic not even logic I'm
trying to shed light on the illogical
choices you've made my friend so you do
your time to get money to pay off a
mistake that you made and you're going
to have to pay off the payoff money that
you're doing time for right now it's
completely idiotic I'm trying to I'm
trying to draw a picture for myself in
my own fucking head when I you see me
looking off in a distance like this I'm
talking to you guys it's basically
because I'm trying to I think in
pictures so I'm trying to draw pictures
for myself in order to offer to you so
get your life is in shambles because if
this choice the choice that you've made
in order to pay off your debt by going
to jail and then paying off the debt
that you're paying your debt in jail to
pay off again is in any way shape or
form a reflection of the type of logic
you use then I could probably guess why
you have legal debts and you have to pay
off these restitutions right you
probably made stupid decisions and the
fact that you're you say that you're
sick sad depressed you know your life is
in shambles it's a mess you have no
friends and so on and so forth is
probably once again a fruit of the root
issue which is I don't think you think
too much
I don't think that you sit down and kind
of like consider before you behave
before you act
and coming from a guy who says follow
your heart follow your instinct there is
a difference between grounded action
rooted in your heart's desire and
hysterical idiotic behavior and my
friend I don't say this because I want
to put you down that's not it at all I
don't want to call you names or anything
but I want to be completely realistic
with you here and shed light on the
on the facts of the situation and the
fact is you are not thinking before you
accurate your your um you're not
thinking things through you gotta use
your fucking head
hitties your head sometimes and the
choices that you're making are stupid
okay
and I wanted you to see that with regard
to your student loan and paying off your
debts and then you would have to pay
back those fucking deaths and those
debts don't go away see if you use
credit cards and be better off because
everybody knows that mortgages and
credit cards are completely forgiven
fact I think Obama's got this new thing
where he's like oh forgiving student
loans and shit - I think I read that on
the internet the other day so really
like debt doesn't mean anything in
America anymore because I mean our
country isn't fucking is in trillions
and trillions of dollars of debt and we
keep borrowing I mean it's all a fucking
game really it's not like back in the
Bible days when like you know you you
owe somebody something so you got you
have to give them your firstborn
it's all fucking it's a bullshit ass
game but uh when you owe the government
cuz that's what student loans are that
make no mistake folks that universities
and banks are quasi government
organizations you could lump hospitals
and doctors and the medical systems in
that and they're also they're quasi
government mean that meaning that
they're subsidized by the government and
they're backed by the government and the
government don't fucking play you don't
pay your taxes you don't pay your loans
they follow you to your grave or they
come to you with a gun it's now you're
dabbling not only with the local
government and you having to pay back
legal debts and you know hopefully some
of those are private you know you're
working with a lawyer private lawyer you
could take some your take your time to
pay him off in installments I don't know
what it is but I you're dabbling with
the United States fucking government and
US government don't fucking play we drop
bombs on people and shit for no reasons
of course I'm being facetious you don't
wanna fuck around the government
my invitation to you my friend would be
to set up yourself to pay off your debts
by working them off get out of school
you're wasting everybody's time you're
you're wasting taxpayers money too
because you're not gonna pay back the
debt and I'm gonna probably have to
fucking pay it back taxpayers and have
to fucking pay it back paid off you know
do something upright for once in your
life go and get a fucking duck grind
your nose job a job where you just gotta
fucking go dig holes like that Disney
movie with those kids out in the fucking
desert
go dig fucking holes and take every
single penny that you got to pay off
your legal dues you're looking for
backdoors with this University loan
bullshit you're wasting everybody's time
go dig some ditches go and sweep the
street go and carry garbage and pay off
what you're supposed to pay off because
in the end you will have learned so
you're not learning shit in school
that's why you're failing you will have
learned a number of things besides
getting out of debt but you will have
learned how to set a goal and achieve it
I don't care how you make that money
just make it make it back right get a
job start a business right so our little
business of your own right a lot of
people like you who are getting trouble
a lot of times it's because you at a
subconscious level in unconscious love
if you reject society and and if you
create your own means you might be more
apt to follow through create your own
job create your own business but either
way without selling drugs are hurting
someone earn the money to pay it back
you live you to develop the character
structure associated with a person who
sets a goal and attains that you will
live and everything that comes with that
patience persistence consistency
discipline
so on the end of you paying back your
legal debts you will have had a real
education not Community College bullshit
that you're failing because you're
trying to get student loans and backdoor
the whole fucking thing again so that's
it dude I'm done with you man pay off
your debts the right way grow stronger
through these experiences I'm happy you
had these experiences I'm happy fucked
up now dig your way out of it and grow
stronger don't