got this great question from a friend
who says uh he starts out he wants to
find other people in life who are as
passionate his he is and I'm just gonna
read his it's a pretty long email but
it's really fascinating to hear the type
of language that our friend uses I says
Elliot you may have been down this road
before yes and that's why I took your
question ah I was hoping you could
elaborate on this in your next video or
blog or reply in a message anyway he
goes on and says I've been working
towards my dream since I was 16 years
old I put myself through college because
I wanted to become an engineer to
develop state-of-the-art technology and
impact the world in a technological
sense I'm 23 years old now and working
as an electrical engineer developing
state-of-the-art technology on fighter
jets fucking cool I live life in
overdrive I'm working 12 hours a day
because I love this shit I spent a lot
of time swimming running working out
again because I fucking love this kind
of shit training for Ironman
I'm always furthering myself mentally in
them as well as bring it to I always
want to bring it to another level
studying the human mind body nutrition
and philosophy I'm up on the days that I
don't have to be to work around 5:00
a.m. to pursue this shit in reality I'm
either working on my career working on
expanding myself or sleeping I own my
fucking life and I love it living a
comfortable life and going with the flow
has always made me cringe I always get
shit because people label me is obsessed
crazy or an overachiever with a
condescending tone no one can understand
that I'm never happy with where I'm at
in life and I'll always have to push it
to that next level that's what life is
I'm doing extremely well financially as
an engineer but all I hear about at work
is how I should save my fucking money
live on the bare minimum and save now
for retirement fucking pathetic I felt
this way since about 16 years old and
people think I'm fucking weird but
everything everyone can go fuck
themselves they'd rather go out and
sleep get hammered three nights a week
and sleep their time away just to look
back and realize how they've how little
they've accomplished
I've always hear about how passionate
others are then you start to realize how
much fucking bullshit they have 95% of
people are fuck
worthless how the fuck do you find
people they're truly passionate about
their life goals ambitions I feel that
people like me are so far and few
between it's hard enough to find one
another let alone surround myself with I
really hope you see this ah dude 23 man
I think we're cut from the same fucking
cloth same exact cloth man when I was
working towards building my business my
career I possess the same neurotic drive
that you have right now my Judas was 10
years ago for me and I got everything I
want and I was disgusted with anybody
who who wanted less and I'd watch people
older than me you know with their
businesses I see how they're all doing
it wrong and they're miserable and every
ounce of my being was either pushing
away from those types of people which
like you said we're about 95% of them
and just creating this contrast between
me and them because I'm a hard worker I
know what I want I'm smart I'm strong
I'm intelligent goddammit I own my life
right
you understand that attitude had no time
for no one else no time for anyone else
and the minute I got close enough to see
what was going on beneath the facade of
most people I was disgusted needless to
say I had no friends sound familiar
who needs them I'm busy I got shit to do
they're nothing but fucking anchors
it's a great quote in the luck factor by
Brian Tracy that uh was really important
to me and he says that successful people
seem as if they're alone a lot of times
but they're not alone errs really
they're loners meaning that they
successful people truly successful
people and if you listen by Tracy he's
got a you know there's is there's more
to it than just achieving your goals
when he says that successful people have
no this is another one of his quotes no
surface acquaintances no casual
acquaintances everybody in their life is
significant and they belong there right
I remember hearing this I must've been
about twenty-three years old doing my
thing and thinking boy where the fuck
are these people where are these people
that I can be a loner but share my life
with and of course I had my wife and I
and I have brothers and stuff but I
wanted people that share the same goals
as me right loved life the way I did one
of the lift weights
wanted to build businesses right the
things that I that I was driving towards
and I even prayed for that type of
person and people came and people went
but what I didn't understand about the
people that were coming that I'm now
starting to learn mind you ten years
later and I'm giving you this foresight
I'm not telling you what to do I'm
telling you what you're going to
experience most likely if you're like me
the acquaintances that I did make and
and the people that I did grow in a
relationship with were means to an end
and I realized that I never developed
really strong heart felt can lick
relationships with these people because
I was surrounding with that surrounding
myself with them simply because I saw
how they could advance me do you see and
I know that you're thinking the same way
you want to talk to people that that are
doing the same thing you're doing and
you help advance one another it's an
interesting thing that when you surround
yourself with other people that are just
like you
that way they more than likely if
they're not involved will see you merely
as a means to an end also so here you
have 95% of the people who can't relate
to you anyway because they're completely
there they're off on totally different
adventures right there are those our
adventures also getting hammered three
days a week sleeping that's an adventure
they're off on totally different
adventures and then you find a small
percentage who are just like you but
they never really loved you and you
never really loved them you love what
they can do for you and the relationship
works as long as you can keep scratching
each other's backs if you will okay bear
with me because because I'm going to
brick home full circle I'm gonna tell
you how to surround yourself with people
that are gonna bring pleasure into your
life so you don't have pleasure yet and
you should maybe you shouldn't because
you're still slaying dragons like I
talked about in that Frederik Nietzsche
video a couple weeks ago you know being
a lion
you're still slaying dragons go and slay
those fucking dragons when you're
slaying dragons you don't have too much
time for pleasure but it's gonna creep
up on you
you're 23 years old and you know what
you've accomplished most more at 23
years old than most people accomplish by
midlife so you're going to grow wiser
faster don't make this mistake because
most men in their 50s don't realize it
until they're in their 50s hopefully
you'll be like me and you'll figure this
stuff out when you're in your early 30s
I feel like an old fucking man cuz I did
so much so early and you're on the same
path okay so this is so slay your
fucking dragons be be a badass you know
you don't need anybody but there's gonna
come a time when you realize I'm alone
and I can have all the money in the
world and I could have all the success
and all the winds in the world you know
I can put up this entire facade because
really that's what it is in many ways
also you know you're building up you're
building up what you you you seem to
look like you know I have nice things
like I talk articulately I'm smart I'm
strong and I'll fuck you up in any way
you see I'm saying so it's narcissistic
it's purely foul your your classic
phallic narcissist like takes one to
know one
but um you're gonna get to a point where
there's no pleasure in that the next
goal doesn't mean nearly as much as I
just want to hug I just I just want to
like laugh with a friend I just want to
sit down and enjoy a conversation with
someone who isn't necessarily up to
business right now
why does it always have to be business
why can't I just like why can't we talk
about something you know just philosophy
I like to talk about philosophy alright
this is what I like to do actually when
I sit down with my best friends we have
conversations like this but just sit
down and chat about life those people
are in the 95% that you're disgusted by
I promise you a good a lot of a mirror
in there and the reason why you can't
see them is because you've built up such
a stark contrast between who you are
because you need to in order to slay
some fucking dragons and those other
people but those people who seem like
they're just going with the flow or
being comfortable they've got something
you don't they're content okay unless
they're complaining now if they're
complaining about their plaque then
they're they're just they're they're
losers but you're gonna find that there
are people that like you know I've got
friends who've got regular nine-to-five
jobs you know like that fireman and like
a UPS drivers and I got one friend he
came here for a video the other day and
uh he worked out with me and he helps
from job to job either he's either
laying tile or he's like doing mason
work like he's all over the place the
dude never complains and he's always
happy
we're completely diametrically opposed
except for when it comes to straw man
you know but we can't talk about
anything on any other level and I love
him I love him because he lives a
pleasurable life and shows me how to
find pleasure in the things in my life
believe it or not there are times when I
look at my life and I'm like boy I wish
I could just chill out and relax right
doesn't Eliot houses love life look so
relaxed like nice trust me dude that
neurotic drive for more that faut Phalke
narcissist
attitude has to be tempered in me often
that's why I meditate
compassion generosity loyalty love
pleasure joy peace of mind warmth are
all founded at 95% that can't figure out
how sharp hard focused and strong we are
they don't need to be and you don't need
them to be like you do your work
appreciate others around you for who you
are and let them into your soft spots
that you've been protecting with your
hard driving attitude trust me you'll
live a more balanced life and not only
will you be a great achiever but you'll
know how to breathe and love as well
good luck