people study what they study not because
it's what they love because they think
it's what they've got to know to
maintain status quo or in whatever their
social circle or tribal circle is that
they use as a means of measuring
sorority yeah so bunch of guys get
together how big is your benchpress
what's your 40 and are you having sex
with my girlfriend or how long is your
dick or whatever that's really what bows
down to so long as your dick
whatever yeah it always comes back back
and I always remind them not to get
overly invested in that anyhow because
nothing satisfies a a woman fully except
the head of a child so no matter how big
your dick is you're just fantasizing
that you really have the capacity to
fully say shape no matter how much you
put your ear massive penis and some girl
she still ultimately wants to be so full
it's gonna split her in half
Wow crazily of the difference between
six and seven inches or one and one and
a half inches against the 7 inch child
head I mean the head of a watermelon or
cantaloupe come out it's like okay it
really boils down to who's got the
capacity to play their instrument as
opposed to who's got the biggest bat in
the room right because come coming up
against your kid's head it's nothing and
they're all playing someone else's
instrument this is my point
yeah that's brilliant yeah when you
really understand what she's looking for
and what it takes to actually get her to
let go and say oh right it's a child
dressing through that thing right and
here we are thinking you know we're
worried about an inch here there yeah
like oh you know but it comes down to
the magic but even something happened as
opposed to where we started this
metaphor yeah which is accumulation of
life read this many books right yeah I
have this many certifications I have you
talked about this you have all these on
the wall but you haven't made
okay yeah she's not making any babies I
don't care how big your dick is how many
have a football hey I took all these
courses and brain sex my wife left me