yo what's up its Elliott and I'm here in
the new strength camp gym see here no
I'm joking I'm actually just in my
backyard but this is what I've been
doing on my training lately you can see
I got my pull-up bar I got my TRX all
right rubber matting where I do some
kettlebell training and whatnot
mostly bodyweight training when I'm
training here in my backyard so this is
not the new strength camp this is just
my this is my at-home gym I'm probably
gonna get power rack I'm pretty sure I'm
gonna get a power rack and put right
there do a couple other cool things and
as that develops I'll show you guys more
about that I love having a home gym good
place to get away and just meditate on
my workouts rather than you know have
all the distractions at the gym I like
to focus in be by myself and this gives
me the opportunity to do that but this
videos not about me not about my
backyard gym
it's about strength camp believe it or
not right
strike camp and strength camp as you
know has been growing steadily over the
past 10 years in fact this year 2017 is
the 10 year anniversary of shred camp I
started strength cam in 2007 and this is
our ten-year anniversary I'll tell you
more about that in another video because
that's not what this video is about
either this video is about you and I
linking up and our brand new shred camp
location and Acworth Georgia if you live
anywhere in the Southeast United States
and you've been wanting to get to
strength camp this is your opportunity
strength camp is growing we're going to
have six new locations with six
ambassadors running those locations
strength camp ambassadors coaches people
who want on their own strength camps and
to support the world and becoming it
stronger self by coaching because I
really believe that coaches are kings
coaches are the people that bless others
by helping them become their stronger
cells and and we're doing a grand
opening for our first ambassador
location which is Acworth Georgia was
about an hour outside
of Atlanta and I want to see you there
it's later this month
the dates will be I put a link down
below with all the information I think
it's the the weekend of the 22nd April
22nd April 22nd 23rd we fly up there to
22nd I'll be doing my own workouts cuz I
got to stay strict on my grind so I'll
be doing some work out there
there will be workouts conducted by our
strenght camp ambassadors who are the
new owners of the strength camp Georgia
location and we're gonna have some
barbecue you gonna have some fun it's a
grand opening take some pictures say
what's up hugs high-five and all that
anyway I'm excited to meet you there I'm
excited about strength camp growing I'm
excited about you growing stronger
through our strength camp ambassador
program and if you want to open a
strength camp in your city you can learn
more about that with some some of the
links that provide for you down below
and that's it man have you been on
camera for a while
maybe I'll get back soon we'll see a lot
of food on my plate a lot of things
going on and hey the more I do the more
I grow the more I have to share with you
and the more we all grow see you next
time