okay this video is for young people who
are looking to get a job this is a
foolproof plan guaranteed to work if you
follow my plan you can lead a horse to
water but if he doesn't drink you try to
kill himself so the responsibility is
yours follow I plan you will get a job
by taking a little bit of time but if
you focus and you're consistent with
these steps you're going to get it step
one your attitude now what I mean by
that is that you've got to look at
yourself as a servant you're looking to
go out there and help a company get
better you're not looking for a job
that's all about mindset if you go out
there looking for a job with your hands
open and you're you know it with a gimme
attitude or a expectant attitude like
someone owes you something you're going
to prove from the wrong place you're
proceeding from the wrong sentiment
you've got to go about it as I have some
value that I'd like to share with
somebody I want to serve your company
with my my my my skills alright so
that's the attitude then you're going to
do research on one two three companies
that you absolutely love there's
something about that company or the the
owners of that company or the the start
is that company that you admire and
you're going to learn everything about
the history of that company you're going
to learn everything about the seeds of
the idea that brought the company to be
down to the all their struggles and in
their current state and situation you
want to know everything about that
company and take good notes because it's
going to be very important for the next
step you're going to appeal to the
highest level individual in that company
he's a guy just like you and I or a girl
he you know this is an individual who
has a has a beating heart and who was in
love with their project so you got to
understand that the the companies that
are going to thrive in the next error in
the new economy aren't the big nameless
faceless corporations that are
dominating right now we know what
happens when you work for those
companies because lots of people are
suffering and in that type of that type
of economy is slowly eroding you're
going to be looking for companies that
are small creative light on their feet
they don't have time for for bullshit
they don't have time for
for to be pandered to by people who are
looking to be leeches they need creative
smart people that are going to support
them and they don't they just you know
they won't tolerate anything less so uh
there's an individual who had a plan to
put this business together and he's got
a heart and he loves his business you're
gonna find out everything you can about
that person okay now we're moving on to
understanding the person the psychology
behind the person that started this
company you want to know everything
about that person down to how many
children he has where he grew up and
what favorite beer he drinks right and
then you can find a connection point
with that person okay that's important
you want to see how the two of you are
like in some way shape or form if he has
he likes football then and you like
football great doesn't have to be
anything spectacular it has to be
something that you guys connect on next
you're going to try to appeal to him
through mail this is my suggestion send
a priority mail FedEx UPS box something
big and clunky something that's you know
wrap it in Christmas wrapping paper or
send him a pizza my point is you gotta
send him something that's out of the
ordinary he's always getting resumes and
resumes aren't going to work they're not
going to get through to him he's a
creative guy hold on the sun's getting
in my eyes here he's a creative guy and
he expects creativity from the people
that are going to work with him so send
him something very creative a gift of
sorts but in that package you're going
to let him know that you are that
there's something in his company you
love his company but there's something
about his company that you feel can be
done better you've done a lot of
research and you think that you could
support him in fixing this small flaw in
his company you know you might not want
to call it a flaw but just something
that he can do better he's gonna be very
excited that you're approaching him
about that wow someone has an idea for
me that could support me and my company
and getting a little better so now he's
thinking of you as a consultant you're
not a job seeker you're a consultant was
all very important and you will give him
a call later on that day so call him
later on that day or the next day say
hey I'm such-and-such that uh that's
essentially the letter and the box of
pizza or the the box with a gift in it
earlier
today and I want to see if he had some
time for us to speak I have something
very important I want to share with you
those words are very important you want
to say that I have something very
important that I want to share with you
and he's gonna be all ears when you meet
him when you get through the door so
you've already gotten past all the
people who write resumes those guys
they're morons they don't know how to
appeal to human behavior psychology and
quite frankly don't have a network
properly so now you gotten through the
door and you're going to pull out that
connection point the minute you meet him
you're going to bring up who won the
bucs game or when the Mets game what are
the case may be whatever that connection
point that you know you have with him
bring it up what's the first thing
you're going to talk about you may end
up talking about that thing the whole
time you might both realize that you
have doberman pinschers you love dogs
and talk for the next half an hour about
your freaking dogs this is great people
want to hire people they like right so
you want to be friends with this guy now
this is none of this is to be
manipulative these are just basic get
along with other people skills but I'm
showing you the steps to take so that
you can get a job then throughout the
course of the conversation share with
him your solution hey look you know I
noticed that uh that when we download
files the picture files from your
website that they don't upload quickly
to two cell phones smartphones and I
think I have a solution for it now you
can't bullshit him you actually have to
be creative and have a solution for
something that he could do better it
might not be mind blowing but it's
something that you think he can do
better and offer it to him he will hire
you you will get a job you approach the
situation as a servant and as a
consultant you appeal to the to the
desires and the humanity of the person
who runs that company you get through
the door like I told you you will get a
job try this out for a month it might
take you six months it might take you a
year but try it it'll work keep me
posted comment down below let me know
how it works out for you if you land a
big job I'm gonna be really happy for
you but you will
you
Elliot's it what