our buddy signed 400 is his youtube
username has a really difficult
situation on his hands basically he's
dating a girl right and he wants to
break up with her what's so difficult
about that except her dad is his
football coach and he is I think he says
he's the QB of the football team
starting quarterback and you're dating
your coach's daughter tough and her mom
is your math teacher how the hell know
how do you deal with this situation
where you want to break up with this
girl right for whatever reason and
apparently she cares a lot about you and
you don't it doesn't seem like you have
any animosity towards her perhaps you
just you know you've got other things to
do you're focusing on on math and
football perhaps right but it's time to
end the relationship for whatever reason
and you've got this network of
individuals and relationships that
you've got to navigate in order to do
this tastefully you know tactfully this
is great this is awesome because now you
have to exercise one of the most
important interpersonal skills that you
will ever have to use and that is being
completely honest and pointing out
delivering and dealing with what they
call the elephant in the room or the
800-pound gorilla in the room that's
what they call it basically there's
something here and we can't ignore it
bringing it to the forefront and talking
about it in a grounded and mature
fashion here is what you have to do
you've got to say something you can't
the worst thing you can do is to just
kind of like II this is what most
spineless little bastards do they ease
their way out of it by like well I'm
just not gonna answer her calls anymore
man spineless I'm not going to uh you
know she's gonna want to hang out with
me I'm gonna say no or you're gonna
ignore her and then you're like every
time her dad passes by you looked down
and like when you go to math class like
the teacher asks you how you're doing
and the whole thing is gonna be so
uncomfortable it's gonna drag out it's
going to eat at you like a disease from
the inside out if you don't deal with it
like a freaking man and that's what you
can do you got to deal with this shit
like a freaking man
if possible I don't know what your
relationship is with with the entire
family but it sounds like you're a part
of it you need to call a family meeting
I know you're only 17 I know you're not
a part of their family but they will
respect you and you will develop strong
integrity you'll feel good about
yourself when it's all done when you
bring them around the kitchen table and
you explain that you know you've been
spending some time you and Sally have
obviously just spending time I really
appreciate you guys I appreciate your
family but right now in my life I feel
like I need to move on to other things
and you say that oh it's gonna cause you
so much pain it's going to be difficult
but you say that though especially her
parents will respect you more than they
will probably respect any other guy that
she dates for the rest of her life I
promise you because no especially in
this day and age with text messaging and
shit when I was a kid when I was in
elementary said that always when I was
in a high school in middle school when I
first started dating girls I'd have to
poll the house phone and their dads
would pick up and i'd say i'd have to
say hi mr. de dona this is elliot can I
speak to Adriana that was my first
girlfriend in middle school and he'd say
Oh things going bro but I I'd have to
talk to that most I mean most kids these
days most of you guys if you're watching
this in your young it's like it's just
if you send little text messages you
didn't call anymore so to show up and
talk to the parents face-to-face sit
down you call the meeting now not an
arrogant way but in a mature grounded
way like someone who's becoming a strong
young man you're going to earn
everyone's respect she's going to be
hurt but her parents are gonna support
her even more in her getting over the
break up because they realized that she
has been with a mature grounded strong
young man up until this point they're
gonna want you back because they're just
gonna be so overwhelmed with how awesome
you are so then now it might not work
that way but that's what I would say I
think about my daughters and if the
situation was the same and I was a
football
and she was dating one of the kids and
he came to me instead of just ignoring
her and came to us and spoke to him I
would respect the kids so damn much I'd
be like come back anytime buddy all
right so that's a dude integrity
integrity integrity grounded strength
start growing it now peace