so you always hear me talk about
following your heart listening to your
heart and following your heart so
somebody asked me a real good question
yesterday on Facebook
he says Elliot how do I know which of
the voices in my head because we all
have conversations in our heads which of
these voices is my heart how do I know
when I'm following my heart and not
following something else so to answer
that the very first thing I want to
bring to your awareness is you've got
three brains in your body of course this
is my rendition of it you've got your
head brain heart brain and you've got
your balls brain right if you look at
the brain itself it's actually set up in
three different parts you've got three
different parts to your brain you got
your neocortex cortex and medulla and
they sort of correlate with the head
brain the heart and the balls for
today's purposes we're going to talk
about the head brain versus the heart
when are you following your heart when
you follow in your head when are you
following the ego or following love okay
very strong distinction that needs to be
recognized before you make a big
decision in your life so very first
thing you got to recognize is that the
part of your conversation in your head
that is rational logical mathematical
that makes sense that's factual that is
based on what other people have told you
historical that is your head brain that
is your head brain giving you all of the
evidence all the concrete supports for
the decision you're about to make two
plus two equals four it's a no-brainer
right that's what they call a no-brainer
it's very obvious the part of that
conversation that's completely
irrational completely illogical makes
absolutely no sense two plus two equals
seventeen or zero right that part of the
conversation that's also tied to the
emotion of what you're about to choose
man this feels right put on paper it
looks stupid on paper it doesn't make
any sense it's not factual it's not
mathematical but it feels right that is
your heart and in the same way that you
have to fall in love hearts associated
with love you
got to fall into that decision nobody
rationally chooses makes a concrete
evidence supported choice to fall in
love that's why they call the shit
falling you have to let go and
completely fall into that situation well
the same way you let yourself fall into
love which is scary very important the
reason why they call it falling is
because there's nothing comforting about
falling it's scary shit you completely
have let go and you're going to fall on
your back or on your face right why do
you think they say fall in love the same
way that you give up the rational
explanation and the need for
mathematical evidence to fall in love is
the same way you're going to make that
decision based on your heart right you
can make that decision to quit your job
because there's a creative adventure
that you'd like to take on right travel
the world whatever it is you know there
are things that every one of us has deep
within our hearts that makes no sense
whatsoever that we want to go do well
you can't wait till the numbers add up
to do that then you've got to fall just
like you would in love fall into your
hearts calling so you get that the point
is you you're following your heart when
you're scared that's when you know
you're following your heart that doesn't
mean that you're going to do the right
thing doesn't mean that your heart is
going to send you down a path that's
cozy in fact most of the time it's going
to send you down a path that's dangerous
and that's why you're scared because the
math doesn't add up but if you're
looking for a distinction you want to
know the difference the choice that
scarier is probably your heart talking
Eliot's it what
[Music]
you