hey so we got this question for my buddy
Nick who's about to graduate from
college he's he's already got a job
lined up in online marketing he says
which seems to be cool but you know on
the other hand I'm going to explore
working for myself at some point and
there are a few things that I really
enjoy I enjoy writing drawing and
personal development there are three
major fields that I'm passionate about
which one of those three should I invest
my time energy resources into to develop
so that at some point I can break away
from the nine-to-five he says he says he
thinks he should do one thing really
really well instead of three on average
well my friend let's begin I'll be as
quick as your question was ten minutes
is usually quick for me
personal development was one of your
things personal development is less of a
thing that you're going to offer and
more of a thing that you are you're
constantly in the midst you're
constantly swimming the ocean of or the
stream of personal development that is
another term for becoming the strongest
version yourself and you are constantly
becoming a stronger version of yourself
you're constantly evolving hopefully
each layer of development is a more
resourceful one for your time meaning
you grow in wisdom that's really what
personal development or growing stronger
is its wisdom paying attention reading
the signs and omens in your life
becoming intimately involved with the
workings of your physiology and
psychology coming to understand yourself
and navigate yourself be a tremendous
self manager observer and lover that is
all that encompasses personal
development and becoming the strongest
version yourself and my man what I've
always shared through these videos is
that what you are means far more than
what you do and if you are a super
awesome badass because you've constantly
focused on personal development then
everything else that you do is going to
be great right because you're always
taking a self
Jack the viewpoint to be part of
personal development you're always
looking at yourself objectively and
you're also honoring your subjective
reality it's kind of a dance between the
two so you are personal development that
is the growth of the human spirit is
personal development right and if you
seek to serve people with personal
development know that you only have to
be it for them for it to be transferred
into them but you know that's just
that's an energetic exchange but my
friend you happen to have two other
things that are tangible and people can
absorb they can consume it tangibly so
that you can support them and becoming
strongest versions of themselves and
really my man your mission is my mission
and won't you steal my mission I want
all you to steal my mission become the
strongest version of yourself and
inspire others of course i trademarked
it but use it my business part is made
me trade market the idea is that the
sentiment from which its proceeds is one
that I will die for and I encourage you
to make that your motto in life I am
becoming the strongest version of myself
and I am inspiring or empowering two
things you know inspiring power I use
them interchangeably inspire means to
breathe life meaning that the person was
dead when you inspire someone you
breathe life into them inspire bring
life brings spirit to a person who is
consciously dead and there's so many of
us breathe those blessings into those
people when you meet them and as a
function of your writing independent art
empowering is a little different because
many of us are gaining in life gaining
wisdom becoming the strongest version of
ourselves and they just need a little
kick in the ass or a little piece of
information to take it to the next level
so we inspire and we empower my friend
make that your own
all of you I beg you to make it your own
because we need this okay now writing
and drawing my man we live in the age of
communication and if you have a means by
which to take the content of your soul
and spread it through media that needs
to become a paramount an important part
of everything that you do no more or
less than personal development because
personal development happens when you're
sleeping you go to sleep at that time
because you're personally developing
right it's a personal valence when
you're eating personal development is
when you're having sex with your
girlfriend or wife because the better
you are the better you stroking dude
these are all the everything down to
what your poop looks like you're not you
never get away from personal development
so it's not one or the other but your
your skill in writing and drawing needs
to be sharpened honed in on it's
beautiful because you think that you're
you've got all these other these
different things that you're interested
in but really it's one thing it's become
the strongest version yourself in
inspiring others and you can inspire
others through your writing and drawing
and here's the thing communication is
the umbrella on which under which
writing and drawing is going to fall
right because they seem like they're two
different things but they are both needs
of communication dude draw comic books
write and draw why I tell you there will
be so there are a lot of young people a
lot of I say young but it definitely is
young of spirit those were seekers who
would engage in jest they would absorb
they would digest they would utilize
your stories of growing stronger that's
really what it always ends up being
through comic book format where you're
drawing and writing you see or become a
really good writer writing it writing
and communicate writing in video I say
and of course I think video is more
important because you can see my eyes
but if your thing is writing that's your
gifts go with writing and really get
great at writing really get great at
writing and then
you're drawing into it you see now
you're starting to now you're starting
to become a creative human being you're
not just a writer
you're writer jar you created something
brand-new now most novels most adult
novels don't have pictures but you're
just going to stick in like weird little
pictures that kind of depicts something
in the in the novel just randomly
because you're a creator because you can
remix so my man you are doing everything
well continue studying all three things
because they're all one thing and they
all fall under the banner of our mission
to grow stronger and inspire and empower
others done