got this question here from our boy
about changing seasons changing energy
he says yo le I got a question for you
about how our energy changes with the
seasons a few months back he talked
about how if becoming winter it was
becoming winter and you like to meditate
read and do other introverted things
think spring is right around the corner
I was wondering if you could share with
us some things you like to do as the
days get longer and seem to have more
energy on an unrelated note he says the
Red King warrior magician lover this
past weekend and it was great and
recommend it to other people so that's
cool you actually read my book right
recommendations so with that being said
I'll recommend another one for you
it's called staying healthy with the
seasons by Elton Hoss
I believe it's HAES Melton Haas but um
it's more of a reference book to give
you a just some ideas about how to stay
healthy with the seasons and what type
of physiological changes are happening
within the body as the earth does its
rotation around the Sun and changes its
position in the cosmos we are related in
that particular way you know we're on
this piece of dust or whatever this
piece of dust is doing affects us we
tend to think that that's not
necessarily the case especially because
we live in a society that is against the
body is against health but the fact is
if you are sensitive to the changes in
your body you will realize that shit I
don't feel the same in November as I did
in July and it's okay it's normal it's
natural and as I've been exploring and
experiencing and working within myself
over the past several years I've become
more sensitive or attuned to the changes
in my own body and energy during the
seasons a resource like the book I just
shared with you but also being very
mindful of and even journaling your
tendencies from year to year during
particular seasons you can you can
navigate
the type of energy you expend or
cultivate and how you go about your life
from season to season you know it's
funny because I watch my videos I've
been making these videos for several
years now and I can watch videos from
the summertime and you know fall so on
and so forth and I look at myself and
I'm like I know what kind of person I
was at that particular time now of
course there are so many different
factors you know obviously there are
physiological changes based on the diet
that were that we're eating or the the
stressors in our life with our family
with career what kind of exercise
program are you engaged in are you
consistent with your exercise but also
we've got to consider that the
environment the earth the weather all
contribute to you know how I'm
particular how I'm feeling during
different seasons and I can see it
reflected in my videos that's sort of my
way of journaling and paying attention
one of the things that I've embraced
right and of course this idea is not
mine but I'm experiencing it now and and
I'm and I'm navigating my life in a way
that honors this is that around
Thanksgiving time right when our
ancestors would lose like harvest time
so now you're kind of like you're you're
sort of chilling out a little bit right
you're not planting and plowing but like
you are in the spring but you are you're
cultivating you know your your recouping
your energy they're eating a little bit
better because you actually have the
crops of tea and you know we would
engage in celebrations at that
particular time it's no wonder that many
of our holidays are in this winter this
downtime of the the annual season and
then the energetic season of the
individual
I've of course created a lifestyle for
myself but also honor these changes by
chilling the fuck out you know once
winter time comes and the world says oh
it's Black Friday and you need to go and
start spending more and every company is
like sale sale sale sale bottom line
bottom line bottom line do as much as
you can before the the tax season ends
right there that's really what it's our
entire world revolves around a economic
machine right so you know you bust your
ass they want you spending and you got
to bust your ass from Black Friday right
which is the first shopping day of the
shopping season they call the fucking
shopping season now which is a little
weird but anyway the shopping season
right right after Thanksgiving - up to
Christmas right and we like we're in a
frenzy buying shit stepping on people so
we can buy stuff and then if you are on
the other end of the Commerce seesaw
your boss is breathing down your neck
quotas hit quotas meat quotas go to
parties right because all the companies
they have to spend money during this
time of year so they can write it off
before the before the the fiscal year
ends right so there's all this turmoil
and activity during a time where there's
less sunshine and there's less energy so
you really are just beating a dead horse
during this Y in times cultivating time
this hold dark time of the year
hold dark in female receiving
cultivating nourishing time of the year
you're beating the shit out of yourself
most people beat the shit out of
themselves not realizing that you know
the world is making you neurotic because
of the demands they placed on you
because that's a shopping season and you
got like exams - I love that one like
you're in college they trained us this
way so you go to school and it's like
this semester is ending so it's so funny
how the semesters ending with the with
the end of the fiscal year so they they
sort of sort of train you
right this machinery this matrix they
sort of train you to insert more effort
and just like squeeze out the last
vestiges of energy that you have in your
body during a time when really you
should be chillin fuck out so that you
train that way and that's this is you
know it's during that time of year you
think it's like the most wonderful time
in a year right that's how the fucking
song goes that we should all be feeling
really good about ourselves but you know
most people kill themselves during that
time of year suicide rate how is it that
suicide rate goes up during the most
wonderful time of the year because
world's making us sick during the most
wonderful time at here it's really the
most wonderful time of year because it's
supposed to chill the fuck out don't go
to the super samal and spend all you've
gained through the years through the
season of sowing to buy shit that you
really don't fucking need to work extra
hours so that you can meet quotas and
have bigger write-offs for your for the
fiscal year end it's completely
psychotic we're crazy in this way and if
you can I would invite you to check the
fuck out of the entire miserable mess we
know that we'll go Christmas shopping
anymore we don't we just don't do it now
maybe I'm a Scrooge that way and I back
off my work I back off the intensity in
the amount of work you watch watch my
channels during December and so forth I
look different
because I'm usually staring off and like
blah blah blah I'm kind of I'm totally
like I'm gonna different I'm sleeping
there are my might I'm not nearly as as
intense as I am right now see I mean
like we're coming out of this spring is
coming and I'm becoming more intense I
don't have to do anything the energy
just Rises in me and my intensity
increases watch my videos from go boom
right ahead go go to December watch my
videos I'll talk a lot and I've got a
lot to offer but I'm you know I'm
generally staring off and I'm more in my
head because you know my my body is
chilling chilling out keeps texting me
okay anyway
now things are changing and during the
time of year that is associated with
sewing with putting in is when it's not
normal and natural zoo littleness the
Sun is out longer the days are are a bit
longer it's warmer so you're coming out
you're thawing out from all the icy
cultivation of the winter don't think
that wintertime is is is necessarily is
a waste or toward chilling out in that
particular way yielding in that
particular way is a waste because it's
it's the mo it's the springboard through
which you gather your momentum for the
spring in the summer the more you can
chill out during the winter the more you
allow the energy to go in right the more
you'll be able to produce later on
that's why again you know a female
winter is considered female dark cold
female what does the female do it
cultivates it brings in and it in it
inside now here's the thing the energy
is very active on the inside it's not so
it doesn't move out like during this
time of the year when you're exerting
yourself and you can see it on the
outside it's not that it's it's gone
it's not that Energy's gone but it goes
in just like a woman who is cultivating
life in the womb
she's not going her or making a baby in
here let's go huh that's not how babies
made you know how a baby is made note of
human being looks like when a babies to
be made
watch a pregnant woman watch a pregnant
woman she's often if she's a balanced
woman she's often very peaceful and
serene if she's left alone I see my wife
be bothered when she's pregnant that's
never a good thing
a pregnant woman should have a quiet
peaceful serene environment that which
she wants to cultivate because all of
her Energy's going in to bring out life
that's what happens to you too you might
not have a vagina might not make babies
but you're cultivating life during the
winter go in allow those energies to
grow all the energetic and physiological
changes that and stuff things that need
to happen inside you so that when it's
time to burst out you're just like a
baby popping in and popping out on the
scene with all the energy that a baby
has when the springtime comes yeah this
is all metaphor but it's literal when
the springtime comes so now that you can
go and do the things that you did that
just rise up in you because the energy
is high you don't have to do anything
different you're just going because you
are different things are going to happen
differently the the you or just is just
gonna do stuff that's different you're
gonna you know what happens during a
spring time they call it spring spring
fever right or you like all of a sudden
like women start looking more beautiful
and you're getting more erections you're
just kind of like oh mate you're moving
out sexual energy increases so you want
you to move out and that's one like you
know people fall in love so on and so
forth so that's it the invitation here
really is to become sensitive to the
changes in your physiology annually
recognize in you these cycles and how
they happen and how they affect your
ability to do the things you want to do
and how you can navigate them
appropriately we all have different
lifestyles you all have different
physiology we're all different in that
way but we do change
recognize when the changes are on the
way think back to how you what kind of
mistakes you made about it last year or
I make so many mistakes I'm realizing
discovering that like every year like in
like in the early fall like after the
the height of summer I get depressed and
I know because that's a big transition
time for me particularly September is a
big transition time from the kids have
been out of school now they're going
back to school and obviously the the
changes in the position of the earth but
also my responsibilities so on and so
forth and two years in a row I've
watched myself grow depressed so now
it's like I'm having this conversation
with myself I'm like okay next summer
all right there are some things I need
to avoid some things I need to make sure
I do more of and then when I see the
time of the year coming that this
depression sort of sort of creeps up on
me I'm prepared for it I can handle it
from an objective standpoint and also
like I said I can I can do things to
make sure that it doesn't doesn't dig me
deep into the hole that I've gotten
myself into in the past this is the idea
this is the power of being aware of
what's happening to you and and you're
empowered in that way so that's it my
friend very great conversation I really
enjoy ideas like this it's all
recognizing the dynamic the dynamics of
becoming the strongest version of
yourself how there's a very cyclical
nature to our personal growth it's not
as linear as we'd like to think it is
and also learn to learning to detach
ourselves from the demands of the path a
lot the pathology the math math
pathology the the the mass neuroses of
the world and how society would have you
behave regardless of how your physiology
and energy is changing from season to
season and as you evolve as a human
being done