today I'm going to answer a question
from one of our friends he wants to know
how to deal with negative people into
the question how do you deal with
negative people first thing you need to
know is that there are two perspectives
with regard to approaching this
situation one external and one internal
externally you've got to find a way to
put up shields a forcefield between
yourself and the people around you and
continue on your mission the one of the
greatest stories ever is a rebellion
that took place about 2,000 years ago
and his words and his deeds are still
felt today regardless of your religious
convictions the story of the man they
call the Christ is very empowering to
anyone who truly believes in themselves
and is on a mission regardless of what
everyone else says he was willing to die
just to prove his point the people that
he came to serve were against him the
people on the outside world were there
against him everyone was against him he
had a small band of followers because he
knew what he was saying was the truth
and the people that were attracted to
him were willing to go to great lengths
to fulfill his mission again regardless
of your religious conviction I don't
even call myself a Christian but the
story of the Christ is an empowering one
do what he did know what you're
convicted of know what God is speaking
in your heart about and continue on your
mission ignore everyone else you've got
to keep them away from you doesn't mean
physically it means psychologically the
second thing is the internal perspective
I'm going to give you a gauge for how
well you're protecting your internal
perspective and growing it so that you
can and I'm also going to give you an
exercise to continue to improve the
quality of your internal perspective
because the most important story that
you are going to be involved with is the
one that you tell yourself the most
important critic to get on your side
is going to be yourself once you've set
up that forcefield you've got to protect
preserve and grow your own internal
strength so here's an affirmation that
you're going to say a few times a day
and in between each time that you say it
you're going to perform a particular
exercise that I'll teach you the
affirmation is I go beyond the fears and
limitations of other people and if
you're like me and most of us who tend
to feel a bit angry with our situation
there's a lot of frustration when we say
that it's probably going to come out
like I go beyond the fears and
limitations of other people I control my
life with a very rebellious angry
frustrated tone but what I want you to
do after saying it that first time and
feeling that frustration is to get that
frustration out now where you're going
to get that out is with an exercise that
I teach to my students it's called get
off my back so when you're feeling
really charged up really excited about
the situation really angry and
frustrated what you drive your elbows
back fuck you and discharge all of that
frustration and energy that you've got
inside you do it for 30 seconds do it
for 30 minutes whatever you have to do
get all their conditioning out out of
you shake off all the frustration it
doesn't belong to you it's been given to
you those negative people have robbed
you or the strongest version of yourself
and you've got to peel off layers to get
to that some of those layers of
pathological anger is pathology it will
kill you get it out of you so that you
can get to the root to the core to the
strongest version yourself you'll know
that you're becoming stronger when you
repeat the phrase I go beyond the fears
of limitations of other people I control
my life and you say it from a place of
freedom and peace and love not
frustration
the christ died and on his dying bed on
his cross he repeated forgive them for
they do not know he took his conviction
with him and he asked for forgiveness
for those who persecuted him he came
from a place of love he didn't carry the
layers of frustration He shed it just
like water off his back learn to do the
same Eliot said what