one of the greatest human needs is for
primal Association we all need to feel
as if we belong to a cohesive unit and
one of the strongest way to unify a
cohesive unit is through the pointing
out of an enemy so when ass should we
destroy the Jew completely Hitler
responded no then we should have to
create him this mass movement can't take
root without a common tangible enemy it
works the same way with racism with
sexism with religious strife with
bullying so I ask you who is your enemy
who are you pointing out as the bad guy
as the devil in order to make yourself
feel unified with a particular group of
people is it Muslims is it the gay is it
blacks do you do it through bullying who
have you turned into an enemy so that
you could feel like you belong Elliot
said what