I woke up like this
and I felt like answering some questions
so we've got a question from our buddy
that lives in Greece he says I message
you because I'm truly stuck in my life
right now since the day I was born I
realized I only fit into sports so I
couldn't wait for the bell to ring when
school was over my parents though had a
different opinion so they kind of took
everything away from me that I loved in
order to get a fucking university degree
he says in technology management at that
point I'm not even responsible for my
actions because I don't understand what
I did wrong you know so I followed this
career path never had any money I've
been struggling alone in this deep ocean
for more than 15 years trying to find my
way which is never coming I know it is
not something new to you but I really
need your advice how to unlock myself
how do I find my passion again they
fucked me up I don't want to work again
in this dead-end job with a boss yelling
in my face without a specific reason
please help me says well my grecian
buddy
the very first thing I'm going to do was
congratulate you on choosing the exact
challenges you need for your growth I'm
going to share with you a very
interesting idea something that is very
resourceful something that has been very
helpful to me in my life yet some of you
might call it bullshit whether it's
bullshit or not very helpful and that is
that before you incarnated in this flesh
before you got to this planet before you
emerge from your mom's womb you chose
exactly the circumstances that you
needed for your Souls progression
your soul knows exactly or knew exactly
what kind of parents you needed to have
the challenges you need what kind of
country you need to be born in to have
brothers and sisters and all the things
that you struggle with in your life you
chose because it was for your soul's
growth there is no growth without
struggle it's on the same level as it is
with weightlifting as it is with your
soul with your psychology with your
heart you must go through struggles so
that you can ascend right you have to
break free from the limitations so that
you can find yourself again
and so congratulations once again you
chose these struggles take full
responsibility this is your life
everything I hear coming from your mouth
sound like victimhood they fuck me up
they made me I had no choice you had all
the choice in the world before you got
here bro so the very first thing I would
invite you to do is to embrace these
challenges embrace the struggled embrace
this heartache embrace all these things
that seem to be Dee railing you because
it's exact path you need for your
success man you see if you were given
different circumstances if you were
given different parents if you were
given different struggles that would
have been for a different soul these are
yours oh no with that being said now you
have to find your way back home mommy
and daddy aren't going to give you your
ball back they took them from you
because you wanted them to take them
from you so you can find them now so
you're on your path to getting your ball
back by breathing into them my man
that's the path that's what you're going
to need to do it is no curiosity it is
no wonder that you knew yourself through
sports you knew yourself through
physical activity you knew yourself
through
heavy breathing through spontaneous
movement right that's what sport is all
the elation associated with charging
your body up and allowing it to go
full-speed in the direction of scoring a
basket scoring a goal knocking the shit
out of a quarterback like I used to do
so now you're going to apply the very
same principles that gave you the joy
you had when you were young to achieving
your goals in life it is the exact same
steps that you took when that bell rung
you say the bell rang and I couldn't
wait to get outside or guess what bro
the bell is fucking ringing right now
get outside get outside and start
breathing start exercising start moving
you have to animate yourself you find
yourself not through books you find
yourself map through videos you find
yourself not through ideas and ideals or
religion you find yourself by ascending
back into your body and you my man were
lucky enough to have known yourself
through your body think of those poor
suckers who grow up with no athletic
prowess at all who never experienced
what it's like to to run and jump and to
be athletically inclined whoo sorry for
them they've got their own challenges in
fact congratulations to them they've got
their own challenges so you've got the
tools you need big man reignite your
soul by reigniting the spark in your
body get back into your balls
done Elliot's it what
[Music]