okay so we got an anonymous question
from our friend who has has recently
suffered a breakup apparently he and his
woman have been dating for several years
and she grew tired of the fact that
their relationship wasn't moving forward
in the you know whatever way she deemed
necessary so has left our friend right
now he's devastated he's still madly in
love with this woman and unwilling to
just let her go right he's asking how do
I win her back so the very first thing
my friend that I'd like to draw to your
attention which you probably already
recognize but I want to draw some
metaphors between what I'm going to
share with you and your current
situation between men and women right
obviously men have penises women have
vaginas those are physical differences
but what you've got to recognize and in
nature and God the universe is just so
freakin brilliant in this way that the
physical manifestation of the man and
woman or everything in nature also draws
conclusions - and points to character
differences in both men and women so for
briefly women are like vaginas in their
behavior and men are like penises in
their behavior naturally speaking
granted that they haven't been stripped
of their sexual roles and forced into
you know strange behaviors that our
society kind of like forces us into but
that's neither here nor there anyway
the woman in being vagina like is a
bringer in of the environment right
she's moved by what she can bring in
does that make sense the the sexual
orgasm is a great example of how the
physical nature of a man inserts itself
into a woman and she's moved by that
well the character outside of the
bedroom is very similar for women the
environment is very important to her and
she wants an environment and she's
stimulated by an
that that aggresses towards her I hope
this all makes sense the environment is
everything to women that's why they you
know they decorate men don't decorate
because our environment doesn't mean
anything to us any great degree our
environment is on the inside we build
energy from the inside and we reach out
just like the penis right the organism
is stimulated and the body moves out
right and reaches towards the object of
its affection and that works sexually in
the bedroom the penis reaches out
towards the woman inserts itself but
also in life a manly man a man who's
fulfilling male the male role in nature
is a man that moves forward that reaches
out that inserts himself into the
environment remember the one brings the
environment in the man inserts himself
into the environment that's manifested
as a man who's moving forward in
business in his sport in school he's
very driven like the penis is moving out
and a woman is very attracted to
naturally it's very attracted to a man
who moves out in his life because he's
fulfilling the male role she and he may
not necessarily consciously accept these
ideas or even be aware that that's
what's animating their behavior and
their attraction to one another but it
is very obvious you know a man who is
successful generally is very attractive
to a woman because he's a man that's
moving forward he's male like he's
representing the penis in the rest in
all of his life which is attractive to a
woman if your woman has decided to leave
you there's a good chance that she feels
that you are not moving forward like you
described things aren't penis enough
around you to sexually arouse her or to
keep her interested in what's happening
with the relationship and in your life
so what do you do about this right the
very first thing that you've got to do
is look to stimulate the power within
you first right now you're being like a
woman you're looking for her to come and
insert herself into you so that you're
happy again that's very woman-like your
your attitude about her not letting her
go it's very feminine and it's very it
turns women off when you're like
grasping for her to come
that's the vagina does so you're being a
vagina what you got to do is become more
penis like become more male so that she
will naturally soften and want to
receive you you won't have to go after
her too hard because you'll see how
manly you are right I hope you're
following these metaphors the way you do
that is to find something outside of the
relationship with her to drive towards
go and fuck life if that makes sense
and when I say fuck I don't mean ruin it
like screw it screw it up I mean go
after it you know insert yourself into
life find something that you can move
towards with all of your energy you've
got to be stimulated inside in order to
move out you've got to look at different
realms of science different realms of
art different sports different business
opportunities find something that you
can attach yourself to and reach out
into and move forward in in life okay so
the way I do it is through weight
training that's one of the things that
I've always done I move forward in into
the weight training realm I bodybuild
and I strength train this is one area
where you can fully immerse yourself in
the moving forward of exercise building
of muscle building of strength she's
going to see this right granted that
she's still in your environment because
it may be time for you to move on
because you're going to find that as you
become more male maybe she's not
fulfilling the vagina part enough for
you and it just wasn't working out a lot
of women that are almost 2 penis they've
got too much reaching out quality that
it's it's incompatible with penis penis
and penis unless you're homosexual and
the totally different story don't work
well together opposites you need
negative and positive poles
so go and find something that you can
reach out into start building a new
business learn how to speak a new
language take up an art to learn how to
play the guitar learn how to play the
piano start sculpting do something that
you can insert yourself into and you
will draw the feminine towards you I
hope this all makes sense it all sounds
very poetic and in metaphorical but
you've got to see that these contrasts
these these connections are obvious
they're there they're relevant and
obvious and they point to how we are to
proceed in life especially as it relates
to the opposite sex great book for you
I'll give you a good resource where he
talks a lot about what I just described
is david deida way the superior man
every man needs to read this book it's
all about penis and vagina contrast and
how it how the penis and the vagina are
metaphors well I use a lot of my own
ideas but he's brought shed light on the
idea for me that the penis and the
vagina are metaphors for what's
happening character-wise for men and
women I hope that's helpful dude good
luck grow a dick and go fuck life
Elliot's it what
you