I got a question from our buddy one who
wants to know how to discover his
masculinity he goes on to say growing up
my father was very abusive and
completely absent in my life he provided
zero guidance on what becoming a man
meant and it felt like I had no moral
grounding for my development as a male
as I got older I started taking pride in
my appearance since society told me that
men are supposed to be muscular stoic
and emotionless I stumbled on your
advice channel from watching your
workout videos and I started seeing you
as a father figure you see me as the
embodiment of what might be masculinity
don't you with that being the case will
you please enlighten me on what
masculinity means to you very good I
like that you say means to you
this is just my definition of it and
share it with you is this something you
have to constantly keep track of or
should it be a part of your unconscious
importantly how does your masculinity
affect the way you treat women okay okay
so uh let's let's get back to that the
second last question is masculinity
something that you have to constantly
keep track of in other words do you go
to your head and think about the steps
by which a man would typically act are
there rules is there a code to
masculinity that I should be following
no there isn't
and the reason why I say that is because
the expression of masculinity is just as
unique as each and every one of our
fingerprints and to say that this
fingerprint is created in this
particular way and flows this particular
way and and is the blueprint for
masculinity denies the essence of
masculinity because masculinity is
already in you you have a unique brand
of masculinity earlier this week I did a
video or you might see it where I talked
about human beings as sparks of divine
energy each spark is unique although we
are the same we are one we are very
unique one form of masculinity is just
that a single one amongst billions
okay and it's an energy more so than
penis and vagina sexual energy that's
not the point here another video and
more importantly how do
your masculinity affect the way you
treat women greatly tremendously because
that is the polar opposite men and women
are polar opposites in our energy I
don't give a shit what anyone tells you
right it's been popular to believe men
and women are the same right
it's not fair you need to be equal we
are equally respectable but we're not
the same okay and here is why and it's
going to begin with this and I'm going
to carry us down this particular road
our bodies are different you cut my head
off and you cut my wife's head off and
besides the makeup and hairstyles
they're pretty much the same all the
organs are exactly the same up here
unfortunately we live in an abstract
world right we live more in our hands
than in our bodies that's evident in
many different realms of our existence
but the fact is if you want to find your
masculinity you've got to find your body
because that's where it lies it
literally and figuratively meaning it is
tangibly in your balls your masculinity
lies in your body in your balls when you
find and come into communication respect
and admiration for the expression of
masculinity in your body in your balls
you will find your unique of brand of
masculinity your balls are probably very
different than my balls and a woman has
no balls so she ain't gonna go about it
the same way that's not to say that
there isn't a bit of feminine energy in
the male a little bit of feminine
masculine energy in the female but not
so much that it shows up in our bodies a
woman does the things I'm about to share
with you with regard to getting it out
of your body or coming in touch with it
in your body she's going to have a
different response there are different
things that are going to happen in the
woman she has different hormones right
from her chest her breast she has
breasts breasts are associated there are
hormones associated with the breast
there's feelings emotions
with the nipples ejecting ejaculating
the nipples almost ejaculate nourishment
into the world via the baby she brings
forth through her gaping hole in her
body which absorbs seeds and builds a
body a human being and pushes it out
completely different dynamics all
together the energy meaning the
psychology the biology the chemistry is
all completely different make that one
stamp that one down because for you for
us to get in touch with our masculinity
we've got to recognize that we're not
the same as women okay the world has
been making us believe that we should
play their game and they should play our
games I have a video like this coming
for a woman one day telling you guys to
embrace your vaginas and your breasts Oh
women you've been robbed playing this
male dick-measuring game with us in this
world not just that you shouldn't try to
achieve but you've lost your femininity
in so many regards we are not the same
we are equally beautiful but beautifully
different so my man one will know how I
get in touch with my masculinity wanna
know how I access the power of my balls
in a very similar fashion that our
ancestors did and it is through dance
when I dance my body vibrates when my
body vibrates I come to feel and
experience it when my balls hang in
vibrates and my pelvic floor is
stimulated with my conscious energy and
the vibrations through my feet up into
my head I feel all that is a man and I
allow my dance to carry me through
whatever expression that is purely
masculine but Elliott Hulse masculine
and I watch it I love it I embrace it
and I use it as I go about my day being
more and more and more uniquely
I access my masculinity through Bop III
by yah yah yah yah yah yah yah yah yah
that's a lot of fucking man right there
my body is stimulated I have more
testosterone book moving through my
blood then you probably have ever cuz I
ain't afraid to be a man in my body
can't think about being a man you do
what the male body does and do
everything that you can to get send
vibrations through your body send
vibrations through your body by stamping
and hooing just like you would see in
Native American dances or through a
dynamic meditation whoo keep your belly
relaxed keep your pelvic floor relaxed
feel the vibration moving up through
your feet into your pelvic floor into
your belly into your chest and out of
your expressive organs your mouth in
your eyes masculinity comes through my
eyes when I draw it up from the ground
through my balls through my heart and
into this camera this is the unique
spark of masculinity that is Elliott
Hulse you go breathe into your balls
shaking vibrate stamp the masculinity
out of your sick rigid tired body go
breathe and become vibrant vibrantly man
done