on a on an assembly line here's the
thing that worked that worked for many
generations you know what I mean I mean
the world that we know it especially in
the United States is a byproduct of the
Industrial Revolution in that factories
and factory workers built this country
but the world has changed the Industrial
Revolution is over the type of jobs that
people had back then just look at the
city of Detroit they don't exist any
longer or there are other developing
countries that were where we were
hundred years ago that we can find cheap
labor labor for we live in a more
creative more sensitive more spiritual
time it's not so much how much can you
do because you can do shit and the value
of it is very low and as is evident
those jobs don't they're becoming fewer
and fewer and fewer right but at the
same time what's emerging is a brand new
creative connection economy that's
associated with art like Seth Godin
would call it and sharing communication
the more you can share the more you
could the more you can grow as an
individual in the more you can share the
greater that's the commodity that's
what's valuable right ideas right
valuable today right so the problem is
that the school systems are still
designed off the old industrial
revolution model you know where
everything is standardized will you be a
good cop crisis and and they really
reduce the creativity and the
individuality and the godlike expression
in every human being by making a sit in
rows and follow directions and become
standardized mmm yes yes what you go
back to doing what you love like
following having that courage to follow
your heart really and to not fall into
that trap I mean yeah it takes courage a
part of what the Industrial Revolution
and just the culture at large for many
different reasons
has done is it has alienated us from
ourselves so you literally have to
stifle the the heart and the sexuality
and a human beings body in order to get
him to sit as like a Pavlov's dog and to
respond to bells and whistles right no
these bells go off when we go to our
places you want to say we're very easily
conditioned because we we've been we've
been castrated from our bodies and we're
way up in our heads so what ends up
happening is first of all we're taught
not to trust our hearts we're taught not
to trust our sexuality so there's your
battle against culture because culture
wants you up in your head because you
could be you can I ring a bell in your
head you'll respond back you're far
easier to respond to control someone by
their head and someone at their balls
yeah I mean let's say that someone who's
moving from you know deep rooted in
motion that's a wild hysterical
character you don't want to fuck with
that guy because he's nuts right to you
know someone who's very easily
manipulated yeah so there's a culture
that you're fighting against but then
there's also you now have become
schizoid you become schizophrenic
because there's a part of you that
really does exist and some brilliant
brilliant part of you it's the part of
you that beats your heart without you
having to think about it it's the part
of a woman that grows a baby without her
having to do it it's a part of you that
digest your food assimilates and
eliminates waste from your body it's the
part of you that your intuition lies in
your everything it's all in this part of
our body that we've rejected so when you
ask most young people who have rejected
every all the brilliance that's within
them you ask them what do you want to do
they have no clue and if the feelings do
come up in their body like yeah I really
do want to do blank but because the head
is you know there's cognitive dissonance
and fighting the body there's this doubt
you know everyone tells me I can't do it
it's weird it doesn't no one else has
done it it's brand new um I'll make
money doing it there's no money in there
so the invitation is to mr. it is in a
way to reject the conditioning society
we gain the connection with your heart
and then learn to follow what does it
mean you say that a lot what does it
mean to breathe into your balls then
what and then can women do it yeah I say
breathe into your balls because it's it
really when I say balls I mean you're
with the roots through which your sexual
energy which is if you study Freud he
called it the libido and if you study
like chi gong Tai Chi they call this a
lowered on TN this is where like the
true human energy comes from down
between your like about two inches below
your belly button they called it the
lowered on TN it's your it's your bio
battery it's what fuels your you know
your so many of your hormones are
produced in that area your sex hormones
and your adrenal hormones I mean they're
all centered around the hips the thing
is that to access that particular part
of you you've got to have soft
musculature so that you can breathe deep
into your body breathing in so many ways
ignites our physiology it not only
brings oxygen in for your blood to
transport but it also if you're soft
enough and this is what i invite people
to do through the things that i teach if
you're soft enough your diaphragm drops
down where it pushes your belly and your
organs out watch a baby breathe its
belly does this and it stimulates it
most literally massages the everything
from the pelvic floor up through your
the entire abdominal cavity it literally
it massages and stimulates the hormonal
production it is similar ads to your
ability to digest and assimilate food I
mean we are breathing creatures when it
went when the the ancients wrote the
story about creation they said that the
god breathed into clay breathes into the
dirt we're literally breath
and dirt and we've kind of created a
situation where because we're so much up
in our heads we create what I call
neurotic holding patterns and you know
that these holding patterns are evident
when you look at someone's body and
their clenched that are holding their
hands tight they're chewing their faces
they gotten like nervous tics there if
you notice if you to take notice if
you're holding your belly tights that
you don't breathe deep people who are
figuratively but literally tight asses
yeah are sucking their cheeks together
and sucking their anus up just think
about that area again you're holding
your belly tight you're holding your ass
up your entire pelvic floor is the
energy is being cycled if you're always
grinding your teeth right if you're
always thinking and that's causing
tension in your head in your face you
cannot soften enough to allow full what
will hum right call respiratory wave
this is what it looks like when a baby
breathes so wave yeah so what I invite
you to do and I invite people to do
because I'm an exercise specialist and I
also seek to support people in growing
stronger in all areas of their life
which means that your body again is a
physical manifestation of what's
happening psychologically right to stop
be so tense right and there are
exercises that help reduce the tension
across the eyes across the jaw across
the chest across the belly and the
pelvic floor all of which are extra
respiratory muscles so when you breathe
into your balls that literally means
you're soft enough to breathe deep yeah
and you've said actually a father son
Holy Spirit yeah caught that I love that
I never I guess would have thought of
that because we need them we need them
all of course but it's like do you see
it as coming more from that place of
spirit though first out to the mind or
how would you relate that there needs to
be a and that's why we do father son
Holy Ghost that's why there is in all
traditions there's this triad
of understanding if you study like the
Kahuna model in Hawaii there's there's
the father the mother and the child
right there's always there always seems
to be this 3 i'm trying to think of
other examples but if you study
physiology you recognize that physically
within the brain there are three brains
we literally have three brains we've got
our neocortex which is kind of our the
brain that we use to create language and
technology you know the the brain that
allows us to go to the moon it's this
deductive reasoning brain has given us
science or technology but just below it
we have the limbic system we've got the
the cortex which is our heart brain but
it's in the head but this is our madman
or you would also called the mammalian
brain of a million or neocortex
mammalian okay this pavilion brain is
the same brain that animals but Amelia
mammal type animals have its associated
with warm feelings with connecting with
one another with love with community and
then there's that reptilian brain that
that brain stem I think you can call
that via the medulla down into the brain
stem this is our reptilian brain this is
that this is the balls brain this is the
one that that's associated with
sexuality and safety you know they hold
a reptilian brain because alligators you
know all its thinking about is eating
and screwing and that's where that's
like our route brain that's the brain
that extends itself down into our into
our peripheral nervous system which is
all down here right when we say I'm
thinking we really were doing this
neocortex what we're saying we're
feeling we're doing this nice are trains
the car cortex you know father's son it
called Jesus the Son harm the Holy
Spirit is that which guides us that we
don't see right that what guides us what
who's beating your heart right who's
digesting your food who's dilating your
eyes who's helping the bowels move down
there who's doing that that spirit that
Holy Spirit and this is just a metaphor
that the ancients use that we can see
parallels to in regard to the science
that we use today to explain everything
but it's there so and i'm a bit of a
poet getting figured it out i tend to
think we lost the meeting of a lot of
the brilliance the poetic meeting that
can be that's pointing to the scientific
reality that we use today right well
which is all inside of us really and
like you said pointing back to really
what's all within us the Son and the
Holy Spirit are also there its
associated with emotion feeling loved
and down Finn else it's that intuition
is that you that does the things you
need done without you having to do it
and you stared recently I love this too
and I actually thought of you this
weekend it's so crazy because you share
in a video about and this is so
beautiful that you again as a as a big
tough guy right shared this about crying
and the importance and just the
beautiful power that is crying and not
holding it back and how it's actually
unnatural when we try to hold it back
and I and I don't have a problem you
know women don't have a problem with
crying you're softer yeah right i mean
we know I I can try you know of course
them but usually spot us on my own that
I don't have a problem with crying and
this weekend I had an opportunity when
I've met with a friend a dear friend of
mine another woman as well and we were
getting into some things that were that
we were feeling and stuff and she was
started tearing up and she was holding
back and I just said to her simply I
said and we were in starbucks and how
afraid are we right of crying in public
and stuff like that Riley global people
think well people you know where we make
people uncomfortable i said to her i
said to her you know it's it's okay go
ahead and cry and she just let it out
and she was like thank you and then I
was crying with her and it was just the
most beautiful thing we were just
bawling in the middle of starbuck it was
amazing that's great I me what what is
it that really happens when we cry like
why is it so important well one of the
things that if you ever studied the work
of Wilhelm Reich he is an interesting
guy he's crazy bad scientist but a lot
of things that you said brought to this
day the body site in somatic psychology
is that the stuff the mine
body stuff that we've grown so
fascinated with he's really one of the
first guys to bring that these ideas to
the west and they say about these old
rose had yoga they've always had she
gone Taichi these were they understood
that the mind and body were the same and
you don't train the mind without
considering the body one of the things
that he recognized and even like that
which is well recognized in the East
also especially through the tantric
tradition is that the sexual orgasm is
the perfect assessment of the health the
psychological and physical health the
combination of it the yoking of the mind
and body in an individual right and he
studied the orgasm the physical orgasm
when you would have sex nude orgasm and
he noticed that there was an energy
associated a movement of energy in the
body associated with full orgastic
release that's what he called it that
also showed up when we cry and when we
laugh and when you think about what
makes human beings human beings it's
that we cry we laugh and we orgasm and
he named this if you study like the
traditions of the East they would call
miss cheap how the energy the energy in
the bodies is being used house being
expressed Freud started moving in this
direction and equaled it libido but you
know it was very crude time and he kind
of had to back off and but he had a
crazy student named Reich who he took it
and ran and he called it over or dome
called it Oregon but really it's it's
sexual energy in the body the same
energy that is released when we cry is
the same type of energy that we
experience when we orgasm there are
certain conditions that are necessary
for orgasm and one of them which is the
toughest one for all of us it's tougher
for men than women like you said you
know women are generally softer they can
allow their bodies more so she woman who
can orgasm a woman who can orgasm has
great sex and orgasms freely as a woman
that knows how to
let go easier for women because it's in
their nature to soften in order to
invite in sexually men we stiffen so
it's this idea of letting go that's so
difficult and when we physically hold on
so when you notice your friend about to
cry she's the chin might be rippling you
feel it just notice next time you're
about to put feel it all from your jaw
right down into your heart it's this
area that's associated with crying
interesting thing this area when we
cycle it in order to hold back our tears
we're also holding back some of the most
sexually absorbing areas of our body
think about this area and our mouth and
our jaw our heart how much how sexual
this area is in bringing in warm
feelings yeah so if you become
accustomed to chronically holding in
your tears you're also setting yourself
up for holding in your ability to
release sexually and have full orgastic
release there's this tide it goes
between them laughter also if you notice
how a child laughs is belly is just
hurting its whole body laughs oh if you
know someone very rarely do you find
adults that really laughs not just
giggle yeah yeah everything it's just
let go you go into literally a laughter
orgasm if you watch children sometimes
it's that same energy so joy pleasure
softness receiving they're all very
feminine traits and they're all ones
that require yein yielding letting go
that's our biggest problems letting go
yeah yeah and so this is good this is an
exercise in it is to notice when you
want to cry let it go because I think
it's all this energy in motion right
it's all the flow of energy through us
and I think as humans we think well the
crying the Laughing is a good thing but
the crying
is a bad thing so I can't let that flow
through me but you gotta let it all flow
through you it's st. channel if you if
you stuff up that channel you're
stuffing it all up yes right there's any
last words of Elliot wisdom you'd like
to share with us you know trusting
yourself it's such a difficult thing but
it's them it's really the main message
in all of this it's that there is a you
that same you that I spoke about that
beats your heart digest your food that
grows babies inside you there's a you
that is profoundly magnificently
brilliant it's where's the heart it's
where the Son and the Holy Ghost lot
it's down within your body you've got to
be able to let go and allow trust your
body that's where your genius is going
to come from that's where the strongest
version of you lies you can't do the
strongest version of you you've got to
allow the strongest version of you and
that requires courage or wires trusting
yourself and that's the main invitation
this is beautiful you are poetic Elliot
look at that thank you so much where can
people it's um your website is hulle
strength calm right i'm having elliott
hulse calm worked on but eventually that
will be one that you can go to but my
youtube channels aware i'm usually
answering questions and sharing ideas
like this so i've got two channels one
is strength camp strength like muscle
camp like you're camping the other one
is Elliot said what my name Elliot said
what and you could just probably google
those and they'll pop up ok great well
I'll include all the the links and the
details as well in the post so thank you
so much Elliot for spending time with me
and sharing and flowing it's beautiful I
appreciate it very much
you