hey what's up guys today I got about
three or four questions from various
people who have very similar concerns
about feeling lonely and without an
identity and it usually happens around
the age where you've either graduated
from college or high school and you've
come to know life in a particular way
but now things are different you know
you either move out of your parents home
you are no longer part of a sports team
you you broke up with your girlfriend
basically the world that you've come to
know for the past ten years or so ceases
to exist and because the circumstances
have changed you no longer fit you no
longer have an identity because our
identity our identity oftentimes most of
the times is a product of the mirror
that the world provides for us I come to
know myself through the world right and
it's through the contrast of your
environment and what people have told
you about who you are that allows you to
be your identity so it's a very
depressing place to be and one that I'm
very familiar with and I'll share with
you a place where you feel as if you
don't belong anywhere you don't know
what to do you're floating in an abyss
with no purpose you're all alone and you
have no identity most of you know that I
played football almost my entire life I
began football at probably about fifth
grade and I was always a part of a team
throughout high school I was captain in
football I was always an MVP I was
always one of the most valuable players
I always did really well my identity was
built up around the idea that that I was
a warrior and an athlete I was a winner
I was always very aggressive I was not
to be messed with
right and other teams I would strike
fear in their hearts because they do
when they would go to play Baldwyn
football they had Elliott house to go up
against and he was a badass nose guard I
played in high school and and and I felt
good about myself I want Awards I had
friends all of my friends were
associated with playing sports and
football and so on and so forth my
parents have finally come to see value
in me
began to see value in myself because of
football I my dad would for the first
time I could remember since I was in
middle school I started getting in
trouble in middle schools by the time I
was in high school I was doing great in
football my dad began hugging me and
giving me and being grateful towards me
once again because I had begin to begun
doing pleasing things I began weight
training through football my uncle who I
had deeply admired as a child its
thunder and lightning out there today
whoa and it's raining right here my
uncle who a deeply admired as a young
child you know during my first stages of
coming to know myself four or five years
old I had admired him because he was in
martial arts he would do backflips he
would chop bricks he was just an
all-around badass boy the rate is coming
in
like a monsoon out there forgive me
anyway he came back into my life around
the time I began playing football
because he was into weight training and
he taught me said Eliot you ever want to
be really good at football you had
better start weight training I got
really good at weight training and then
my friends began to recognize me is the
guy that teaches them how to weight
train because my high school was across
the street from my house and they'd all
come over all my football player friends
would come over and I showed them how to
workout so I had an identity for
throughout high school throughout
college that centered around sports and
shrimp training I come to appreciate
myself and I grew my identity through it
then came college graduation I hate the
lighting over here let me get a little
closer
then came college graduation I'll let
you guys see how nasty it looks out
there later
Oh Oh
and then it comes in look
that's it I'm gonna try my best to stay
dry and keep this camera right on me
get that coal - so I graduated college
and went to grad school but I no longer
played football and I and I no longer
had people who recognized me my family
the first time I left my family people
who recognized me for who I really am
I'm Elliott Hulse a football player and
I'm really strong and I know how to
weight train and I was amongst strangers
and I gotta tell ya I felt like I had no
identity and I was alone I was in a new
city and I was a man around people who
didn't know me for the way that I had
been known by those in my previous life
I didn't know myself any longer it was a
very challenging time in my life and I
venture to say that you know I went
through a stage of a form of depression
I really didn't even want to leave my
house I didn't want to go anywhere I was
confused about things that my life was
kind of a mess I was about 22 23 years
old
I'm going to share what I did to find my
way out of it and I'm not saying this is
exactly the way you need to do it but
think about the sentiment behind it is
what I would invite you to consider
I had begun looking for religion at that
time I wanted to be a part of something
and I wanted to be a part of something
that had a mission greater than myself
so I began looking for religion now I
had a lot of friends who taught me about
Christianity when I was in Kyle at
college and I gained some perspective
about religion through Christianity and
I appreciated it but one thing about the
Christian churches that I had been
familiar with was at least just where I
was is that they were lacking in
diversity they almost seemed segregated
and it seemed to me that that was a you
know that was against everything that
Christ stood for so I was like you know
fuck it I want a religion I want to be a
part of something I want something that
I can attach myself to that is
transcendent that is beyond me
it is bigger than me and long-lasting
but man like I just couldn't dig the
Christians no judgement to get against
them or any of you today at this
particular point I'm just saying my
experience wasn't well but then I found
the Baha'i faith
bah ai and all their literature centered
around a series of principles most of
which were grounded in unity oneness
unity really that's like their religions
calling is oneness unity bringing
together all types of people from
different races and religions and
backgrounds and and you know all their
marketing material were faces of many
different colored people wearing
different clothing and just looking
completely different and it was
important to me because
being multiracial I never fit I never
really fit in anywhere or fit in with
white kids I didn't really fit in with
black kids I kind of was like I was a
football player that's really what
mattered I come to know myself not as
white black or Christian or or anything
else I get my identity was around
football and when weight training but
these people they marketed to me in a
way that was a plea appealing to my
desire for being accepted no matter what
I was and also because I wanted to
promulgate I wanted to move forward a
mission that was about unity and oneness
amongst people
so I immerse myself I deep I began
studying all the books all of the Baha'i
literature I would spend all my time
reading it and I would then go to behind
meetings that they had and the behind
meetings are wonderful because these
people they all hugged they would come
in and you come in and you see in a
little old black lady and a big white
man in a suit and they would do and
hugging they would love each other and
then you'd see people speaking different
languages they don't really understand
whether what's being said here but you
they could feel the energy and they're
smiling and everybody's sharing food and
it was just a beautiful community B to
be a part of and they all band together
in a mission to uphold the ideal that
mankind is one and to share the message
of unity that baha'u'llah who was their
messenger came to share with us man it
was a good time we got involved in study
groups and even more so we began doing
work in the community we would help each
other we would find other people to help
and I got to tell you although this to
this day I'm not involved in any
organized religion I recently took a
test with a business coach and he said
you know your biggest problem Elliott is
your relationship to institutions so he
tells me so I'm like I go figure
you know why I can't dig
institutionalized religion
so you know for various reasons I've got
my own screw-ups but institutions is
particularly organized religions just
don't work well for me in the long run
but I am so grateful for the two or
three years perhaps that I spent with
these people getting out of my own
misery and active in supporting other
people and in being a part of a mission
that was bigger than me this is kind of
a long and strange video I'm kind of in
a strange energy today so my advice to
you my friend my invitation to you is if
you're feeling lonely look for various
communities that are looking to support
a bigger mission or vision for
themselves I'm not saying you need to
get involved in religion although it
might be right a good choice for you
sometimes it's a crutch it's what we
need I'm not making any judgement pro or
con religion I'm saying sometimes it's
what you need and sometimes it's what
you might want to use to help you get
through life in particular stages it
helped me but there are various mentor
groups if you're if you're in a city
where that big brother big sister join
big brother and have a little brother
the organization is all about supporting
young children into adulthood get out of
yourself get out of your misery and go
and help some young kid who could really
use you go and volunteer for a Habitat
for Humanity and go build homes for
homeless people go and do something
where you can work not just for yourself
but for the benefit of those who are
less fortunate or for a mission that's
bigger and greater than you
done