I had this question from John he goes on
to say that over the summer he made
strides and becoming the strongest
version of himself he built muscle he
was meditating he was sleeping well
focused on the things he loves doing
however school started and it all went
to shit because now he's got to go to
class he's feeling less confident about
himself he doesn't have time to meditate
time to work out barely gets any sleep
and has tons of work to do homework to
do well congratulations and welcome back
to the economic machine that we all live
in so you're in training now you when
you were free there in the summer you
were free to be yourself and to train
yourself the way your heart desires
you're meditating you were exercising
you were sleeping all normal natural
human being things now you're being
trained to operate for the machine the
machine doesn't need people who are
happy that meditate it doesn't need
healthy people that works out
it doesn't need well rested people it
needs really good robots it needs people
that are really good at grinding their
nose and doing the work that they're
told to do and pay their fucking taxes
so that the system can continue right so
then so the machine can go on this is
what school is its conditioning you for
the work world and you're feeling
resistance right now you're upset you're
feeling resistance because you know what
it feels like to be a human being and
now they're grinding you down into a cog
while you're in school and it's
upsetting to you you're confused we're
all confused a lot of people take it a
little easier than others I wasn't one
of those people that fell in easily to
being a cog you know that's why I don't
have a job you know I don't do well with
fitting in nor debt nor did I ever want
to and you it seems is experiencing the
same thing you know what it feels like
to be yourself and it was good and who
you are who all of us are unsullied by
the conditioning of the Machine are good
we're happy we're healthy we do things
that are normal and natural like sleep
right go figure
and and there's this cognitive
dissonance there's this sort of
resentment that either it's buried down
or shines forth like it is in you and
and I'm happy that it shines forth in
you because it shows that you're still
awake you're still a fucking human being
congratulations
my advice because here's the thing
here's the fucking thing I talk a lot of
shit and I put my kids in school I've
got my daughter in a special school you
know like kind of like hippy weirdo
school for people like me and then my
other children are still too young but
it's kind of a I don't want to say a
necessary evil because I don't think
it's necessary but it's what we do you
know and I part of me regrets putting my
children in school but here is what I
would offer you continue to remain awake
while you do the things that you're
supposed to do to get through this shit
because my children my daughter in
particular comes home and I remind I so
her what waking up is about I remind her
school is just me they're just teaching
you a couple things but don't take it
too seriously right
I could give two shits my daughter's is
a they called her a genius because her
test scores are so high she has a
dictionary we just bought a dictionary
she reads this shit all day long I'm
like what kind of seven-year-old is a
dictionary but I could give two shits if
she fails I could give two shits if she
fails every fucking test because has
nothing to do with the character that's
within her the person that she is the
real her because she can't or cannot
memorize a bunch of shit she does well
but I could care less I care less if she
continues to mold her character into one
of the sprockets that runs the system by
going to college and give two shits
right so you gotta go ahead you've got
to be detached to a degree you've got to
do it right because you have to but
don't be too attached to it I'm not
telling you to fail out but you know
what if you failed gives a shit it will
have no bearing on your future I
guarantee you like I've been saying for
years
the system is changing it's falling
apart it's crumbling so all those really
good followers those really good robots
they can't find jobs anymore creative
people who are at
with their roots are going to be the
ones that pave the way for the creative
future I have a feeling that you're one
of those people because uh because you
feel that cognitive dissonance that's it
my man
Google up just you know buckle down and
do it but don't lose yourself be in the
world but not of it don't lose yourself
in this shit do it hey if you sleep in
one day who cares yeah skip a day of
school what are they gonna do get some
rest because your hearts going to need
it and go on get out of the fucking
machine good luck
Eliot sit what
[Music]