yo Eliot what's up guys today I got a
question from Tobias Tobias why I didn't
and basically is question revolves
around breaking mental barriers he says
that whenever he sets a goal for himself
for example like in order to pass a math
exam he needs to take some time off from
work and sit down and study but you know
when he does that he sits down and he
just can't study and it goes to shit
another examples with his diet he says
you know he sets himself up on a diet he
knows what to do but every time he goes
to do it he just can't do it you know
it's like mental barriers mental blocks
it's like the shit is very obvious and
clear and you know what to do which I
think you know it's part of this
generation of political if ik
information is like y'all know what the
fuck to do you know what to do that
means you didn't pick up the phone you
didn't pick up the computer I mean
goddamn it everybody knows what to do
and he's you know I know what to do I
even set myself up to do it he gave me
one more example always a need to get
surgery on his foot and you know there's
foot fucked up but every time you know
he knows needs to do it but uh he
doesn't set the appointment or whatever
Sally he's walking around stupid because
he can't pass his tests fat and broke
broke downright broken foot poor
nutrition can't pass his test right and
although he knows what to do we can't
eat just can't seem to make himself do
it you call this a mental barrier well
you know what I'm going to call it an
addiction to being a loser and what I
mean by that is we tend to become
addicted to or very comfortable with the
feelings associated with who we think we
are you see what I'm saying
so you know yourself with these
particular feelings you know yourself in
your circumstance that's really what it
is you know yourself in the
circumstances that create the certain
feelings about who you think you are
right so you you think yourself as a
loser
you really do that's why you keep doing
you can't win every time you set
yourself up to win you choose not to
you'd rather lose so you think of
yourself as a loser
and the circumstances are set up so that
you maintain illiteracy poor diet
fatness or whatever that might be you
know poor diet can mean just sickness
fatness and a broken foot so here you
are hobbling around as a loser what you
need to do my man to break the addiction
of being a loser is to do the thing in
order to have the power just like any
other addiction so you don't go to a
12-step program and they say you know I
know you've been addicted to alcohol sir
what we're going to do is we're going to
take you off a hard liquor and put you
on beer or tell you or tell you exactly
what to do and allow you to show up
every single day drunk again
you know maybe they do I don't know but
at some point you got to just you got to
fucking stop right at some point you got
it the gig is up the game is up just
give it up and stop so what that would
look like for you my man is to set an
appointment and keep it set a goal and
keep it regardless of what you feel
about it you see so the addict the
alcoholic alcoholic addict he feels like
he wants a beer but he doesn't take a
beer now he's got all the support that's
associated with the 12-step program and
that might be something you need you
know you also mentioned how you're
around negative people who put yourself
in the realm of positive people read
positive uplifting books watch positive
uplifting videos find positive uplifting
friends you know they're usually friends
you wouldn't even think of that's the
thing because you're so addicted to you
who you think you are in your
circumstances all your friends are
probably gonna be losers and you're
going to keep attracting losers to you
so that's all that's you know
circle-jerk so what you got to do is
look at someone who you normally
wouldn't choose as a friend and be like
dude will you be my friend right it's
gonna be that guy that's like I could
never be friends with him yeah that's
the one because it's the opposite you
got to do something that's completely
different
now what you've been doing to keep you
getting what you're getting set an
appointment and make it like I say you
got to get your foot fixed go into your
fucking calendar which you should have
right set the appointment and regardless
of how you feel about it
it doesn't matter if the world is
crumbling or down around you it doesn't
matter what's happening your wife just
busted water all over the floor the
baby's coming you say I'll be right back
I got my foot appointment go get your
fucking foot fix no matter what there's
no if ands or buts about it oh I don't
feel so good today get your lazy sick
ass up out of bed reason why you don't
feel so good today is because you eating
shit begin with a simple step die it's a
tough one because it's all day long you
know going to school and passing your
tests you know set the appointment in
making getting your foot fixed set the
appointment and make it diet that's all
day long begin simple my man drink water
revolutionize your fucking life by
drinking water don't go crazy with all
the diet information out there there's a
hundred and one different diets and they
all contradict themselves and if you
follow this one and then two weeks later
you read a blog post or you see a video
about that one you get all this ad D
bullshit going on which I boy choose to
drink water say I will drink half my
body weight in ounces of water a day no
matter what it does not matter if you're
choking on the fucking water who filled
your belly up so much it's gonna burst
drink the water this requires a warrior
mindset and I think that's a part of
what's lacking it's interesting you know
the more and more I read these questions
and more and more I meet you guys the
more more I'm realizing we ain't got
enough warriors in this culture you guys
are addicted lovers that's what I keep
finding addicted lovers and in clever
magicians if you wouldn't follow my
videos you know my metaphors addicted
lovers meaning like oh I love this oh
I'm passionate about this oh I love that
huh and it's like there's this just I've
keep falling in love with different
things and you never get
anything done and the clever the clever
magician is the cynic who holds
everything at a distance well I know all
about that hey they're the best
commenters here oh I know all about that
he's wrong and I'm right but you know
what you're the guys that don't try
anything because you're just sitting in
your dark caves Wizarding about
different things and thinking and
reading and flipping through your your
books there's more information about
stuff I can't do anything yet I still
have to learn where are the Warriors
let's say I'm going to make a decision
and I'm keeping it devotion discipline
where's that devote yourself to
something bigger be decisive about what
you gonna do say I'm gonna do it and
that's it and then be disciplined about
getting it done every single day whether
you feel like it or not done Elliots it
what