hey so this video is a follow-up to our
discussion last week about non jobs and
escaping the rat race before we get
started and embark upon this campaign
for non jobs cuz everybody's talking
about jobs right now the elections
coming up pretty soon and the big debate
the big issue is jobs fuck the jobs i
want to show you how to create a non job
in a non job lifestyle just like i
described in the video last week where
you share the things that you love and
you get paid very well to do it so
before we embark and before i invite you
on that campaign for non jobs i want to
give you three reasons why you need to
shut this video off and completely
forget the idea of creating a non job
lifestyle for yourself because i don't
want to blow smoke up your ass
everything I spoke about in that video
last week came from the bottom of my
heart and is a hundred percent true but
there are three things that you need to
know before you decide to step foot on
this journey the very first one is that
there are no guarantees there's
absolutely no guarantee that you're
going to have whatever your imagination
is conjuring up right now so you may or
may not become a millionaire by creating
your own non job I'm not a millionaire
but I have friends who within three to
six months earn their first million
dollars by creating and developing their
non jobs I don't want to say they're
lucky but that was in the cards for them
the way things were and the market they
chose to serve and the way they chose to
serve it things just clicked off and
then behind Amelia knows I'm thinking of
a couple people right now I don't want
to share their names which you might
meet them later on as I interview some
of my non job having friends that might
happen like I said I'm not a millionaire
that didn't happen for me my journey is
quite different but I have a very
comfortable lifestyle I for children I
have a nice house will you go on
vacations I own my gym I have a pretty
good lifestyle and I have no job in no
career there are
friends of mine as well who have been
doing this just as long as I have that
are still struggling the way they're
serving their market is it just hasn't
clicked yet for them it may never click
for them but they're more attached the
idea of freedom than they are safety and
security they're more attached to the
journey and the personal development
associated with living a non job
lifestyle than the guarantee of any
types of riches so if you need to make
six or seven figures and that guarantee
needs to be set in stone for you then
this is not for you this is not for you
what you need to do if you want to
guarantee is to go and look for a job
that guarantees a paycheck from week to
week that adds up at the end of the year
for to a million dollars or whatever the
case may be no guarantees you've got to
be willing to sink or swim with this
courage is the defining virtue of
someone who is going to embark upon the
non job lifestyle there's going to be a
lot of hard work but the fruits of your
labor are going to be completely
subjective everyone's going to get
something different hope you can deal
with that because it brings us to the
second reason why you don't want to
embark upon this journey second reason
why you should shut this video off
safety and security if you need if you
need safety and security if the idea of
safety and security is very important to
you this is not going to work because
there's no safety there's no security
and the same way that there's no
guarantee I have four children I started
mine on job when I had one child a
mortgage and a wife there were times
where there was no money for food I
remember several times that my car would
break down and I'd have to stop pull
over and walk because I had no money for
gas we were deeply deeply in debt
creditors calling my house all times a
night no money staying up at night with
butterflies in my stomach can't sleep
frustration sadness anger all associated
with not having the safety and security
of a regular paycheck and benefits
speaking of benefits i just bought
health insurance for my family like i
said i have four children call me
irresponsible irrational crazy whatever
it was whatever is it you like to call
me but the idea of freedom was far more
important to me than safety and security
I have it now I'm a lot safer and more
secure or at least in my mind because a
lot of times that shit is a is a
complete imaginary concept but the
things that a lot of my friends had that
decided to go get jobs steady paychecks
benefits I did not have for several
years and if you need those things to
feel good about yourself if you need the
solid foundation of a job a career a
paycheck then this is not going to work
for you I could tell you what though
you're going to end up far more safe by
creating your own non job then depending
on a freaking job because your boss can
quit can fire you at any time the
customers could decide that they don't
want to partake of this business anymore
the economy could collapse as it is
collapsing before our eyes and your job
could go away and guess what you're
going to be left with no skills
whatsoever for making money on your own
earning a lifestyle on your own but if
you go if you decide to join me on this
campaign for non jobs you have all the
skills that you need to develop a non
job lifestyle earn a living from scratch
no matter what happens all the things
that I have can be taken from me right
now I can be left with nothing but ten
dollars in my pocket and I can get up
and create a non job lifestyle for
myself in a matter of months those are
the skills that are going to offer you
safety and security not a fucking
paycheck and finally the third reason
why you should not join us in the
campaign for non jobs is you're going to
be lonely guaranteed you're going to be
lonely for several months or even years
because your friends aren't going to
understand what you're doing they're
going to have brand new cars which by
the way the bank's own they're going to
houses they're going to have regular
paychecks they're going to go ahead and
live the traditional lifestyle while you
are hanging out in the in your bedroom
at three o'clock in the morning trying
to figure shit out on the computer or
developing plans that seem like you know
they belong in the cloud somewhere
you're going to be doing shit that they
just don't understand they're gonna
think you're you're out of your mind you
need to go get a job family the same
thing my mom for several years would
tell me Elliot why don't you go get a
job as a hospital administrator because
that's what your your degree is in right
you know why don't you go and do
something that's were step respectable
and upstanding join society and it
wasn't that my mom didn't care for me
the fact is that she cared for me so
much that she didn't want to see me in
this place where there's no safety and
security and I decided that if I have to
ostracize myself or deal with the
ostracization or being ostracized from
my friends and family so that I could
build this freaking thing I'm going to
do it that was very lonely I give you my
experience as well this is about here
it's me sharing my experiences with you
and my knowledge with you so that you
can do what I which you see me do my
experience has been there was lonely for
quite some time so I found friends non
job friends that do exactly what I do
and I'll introduce some of them to you
in their coming months and together you
know we're kind of a weird bunch but we
live our non job lifestyles and most
people cannot relate to us you're going
to experience that as well but I'm going
to invite you to a community
where we campaign for non jobs by
helping each other develop non jobs i
will offer you absolutely all the
information that I have at my fingertips
and experience that I've gathered to
help you create your own on job and
together we're going to campaign for
this thing just like the presidents are
campaigning for jobs and spending what
we're going to do it on our own terms
we're going to live our own lifestyles
we're going to create our own non jobs
by serving people with the things we
love most I have a ton of things I want
to share with you here's how it's going
to work down below there's going to be a
link to a new YouTube channel I don't
have any videos on it yet but i wanna
put them up very soon where i will offer
you tidbits because i don't to give you
it all to you right away i will give it
all to you but i want to give it all to
you right away because there's a
foundation that needs to be built and
most of its character structure it's a
lot of personal development that needs
to be under went before the nuts and
bolts of actually creating a non job
i've got tons of stuff that i want to
share with you this is something i'm
committed to doing for you because I
love you and I love this idea of
escaping the rat race so join us over
there and over the course of the next
couple weeks I'll be sharing a community
website but you could join for free and
and some new resources that i put
together for free that you can have so
we can do this together that's it folks
i'll see you on the next channel