yo Elliot what's up guys today we got a
question from our friend Dan Makka
mm-hmm nekem Europe and his question is
essentially how do I feel about the way
the system is built essentially the
economic system and all of its you know
he's really focusing on the negative
aspects of it although he's doing a
pretty good job winning in it let me
describe so the thing is he says I
believe that the system is so damn
corrupt got one percent of the so-called
elite families and companies they're
ruling the world and thinking only about
themselves right so you got these greedy
people who are he calls them Big Pharma
doing crazy shit companies buying water
to control us chemtrails banks vaccines
jamo Monsanto etc he can go on so all
the all the negative bad shit that he's
he's focused on and he says the thing is
if I stay live in the system i'm
basically feeding his system that I
don't believe in he says that I have an
odd job and I'm an alternative
therapists and I have time for myself
and my kids and earn much more than the
average person here and I work a lot
less I'm grateful for all this so you're
grateful for the system however I can't
stop feeling that I'm beating this
system by paying taxes Social Security
debts and I see the system as an unjust
one many people are struggling and
obviously I would love to change this if
I could any advice what do you think
about living off the grid creating an
independent self-sustaining community or
starting a big revolution so on and so
forth so Dan you and I are kind of
swimming in the same river there buddy
because we both have animosity towards
something that has blessed us well the
system is not perfect at all but it is a
system and it's a system by which you
and I have both seen increase in life we
were able to take advantage of the
technology that's available
during this particular day and age we've
been able to take advantage of the
economic machinery that allows us to
receive monetary or currency I love that
word currency because it means the
movement of stuff right when something
is in a current it's moving electricity
is in a current that means it's moving
if there is a current in the ocean that
means it's moving currency is like the
movement of life force all right so we
call it money you can call it dollars
euros whatever the whatever the title
it's given its currency it's an energy
currency is not really a thing it's a
movement but anyway point is you and I
are able to dive into the river of this
currency where we can be swept away and
offered we can offer our good things and
have good things come back to us but
underneath the currency there is a there
there's muck muck at the bottom of the
river and like with everything in life
in general if nothing is all a hundred
percent good nothing is all one hundred
percent gap bad nothing is ever a
hundred percent or whole in any way
shape or form everything is in flux and
balancing itself out both daytime
nighttime up down sista diastole inhale
exhale male female wherever you look God
and nature is doing this thing right
you're watching me through this camera
which is a series of on and off switches
right 10 10 10 right all the digital
stuff that we participated so that's the
first thing I'd like to offer you is to
recognize that there never is and there
never will be a good without a bad it's
our attachment to what we think really
the egos attachment right because the
ego is a conglomerate of stories we've
been told in stories that we tell
ourselves about what is good and what is
bad right and it's really the egos
attachment to what we think is
preferable at the particular moment when
I say moment I mean in time right
because we've been doing this for a long
long time right this story with regard
to civilization is as old as Cain and
Abel right so that's a principle that's
something that is just you you got to
realize that even if you go off the grid
and you start your own backpacking
snacking on berries and nuts
civilization you're going to have
fucking problems to the problems might
be worse because it didn't take several
generations to kind of define to it and
figure out how we could manipulate the
thing to get us all to one particular
place which is what this new world order
is like we talked about that one percent
of people and those who make the money
those who own the money as if there are
other evil but then too there's also the
good side of course you know there are
those who suffer under the weight of
this system but hey your kids are fed
right how do you like that you got the
internet right how do you like that you
got wrong clothes to wear when it's cold
you turn on the heat when it's hot you
can turn it on the a/c you got cold
beverages in your refrigerator right all
kinds of shit that's really comfortable
cozy lovely magical even because you got
some evil guys at the top spilling
currency into a system that grows heavy
on the backs of some people and destroys
the earth right so really
really it's a matter of taking a step
back and I often think this way the
matter is taking a step back from our
particular place in time and looking at
the evolution of mankind as a whole from
the larger god perspective if you will
meaning that just because things look a
particular way right now doesn't mean
that this is the this is the end really
there is no end its cycles right there
was a time when Africa was the land of
Kings gold now Africa is the land of war
and terrorism right there's a time when
you know various aspects of the of this
planet were good sometimes we're bad
sometimes bad places are good and some
play at times good good places are bad
you know we had matriarchy now we have
patriarchy you had the barter system and
now you have currency with the barter
system you have all types of negatives
also right because if you want if you
want a new car and all you got is cattle
and the guy that owns the cap car don't
want no cattle you you're fucked you got
to find somebody wants your cattle so
that you can get something that the guy
that has a car once so that you can buy
it
so the solution right as if there is one
is to do the best you can being the
strongest version of yourself and
empowering or inspiring others the way
you feel foot fit this day and this time
so that you can create a world to come
back to several generations from now
that's a bit better than the one you're
in right now previous generations
thought they were doing the best that
they could to create what we have right
now we could be grateful for it and try
to do a better job by being the best
that we can and empowering other people
or we could be resentful towards it and
being resentful towards it only builds
more of what you put out there if you're
resentful you put out more resent more
fear more frustration more anger
everything that you do is going to come
from that frequency and they're going to
come back to a world when I say come
back I kind of I dig the idea of
reincarnation I kind of dig the idea
that this thing is just happening this
way and we do really don't go anywhere
when we die we just how to come back
again play this play our karma out if
you will come back to a world that is
perhaps bit better than the one that you
left because you made a decision to make
it a better world pick up garbage see
small things the other thing is we want
to do big things we want to do gigantic
things like revolutions right
revolutions happen when revolutions
supposed to happen I wouldn't go
tinkering around with trying to make a
revolution happen start small like
cleaning up right how simple is that
just cleaning up shit you see garbage
just pick it up that's a simple one make
the world a cleaner place by picking up
garbage like but it's too simple for us
we want to do grand things right what
are other simple things that we could do
to make this a better world smile at
someone right you wouldn't you want to
make this a better world you're upset
with the system then you go around
scowling have an upset nasty face about
it maybe just smile at someone you know
you're so upset about the money well
then maybe give some it away to someone
right by someone that I used to get by a
stranger a gift donate some that money
to a cause that you believe in
donate it to the neighbor the neighbor
cuz his car broke down give him some of
the evil money he'll be happy as fuck to
have that evil money so he can fix his
car love its currency also the physical
currency that we do to exchange material
goods just a medium by which we get
through this we get along in this
material world right the physical world
but love is currency also but it is
something that you can share and then
when it's shared it can be shared on
with more people so that's it man don't
be too upset try to put yourself into
the frequency of love rather than the
frequency of fear try to look at the
things that you do love and be grateful
for say a prayer tonight say thank you
thank you for this fucking system that
has given me the opportunity to have
cool water Hey yeah clean water you've
got roads you don't have somebody
banging on your door demanding your
children because of your debts right
you're upset about your debts you know
there was a time when we were so
devolved that someone would come for
your child if you owe their money now
you just get a bad score it's pretty
fucking cozy I like it focus on the
things you love chair love it's not
being so upset done Elliot's it what