we got it we're blessed one of my
favorite violin concertos new knowledge
in tutu kueh to put the to practice our
softness and hardness combination
I'd like to know more about it I'd like
to you we have to the are missing my you
know it's funny I grew up in New York
like the guitar music the to listen to
the season like gangster rap we've got
other egg Bob listen it to to not really
like nas was campus so it's either that
was like heavy bass club music but I
came down and there was no country music
at all when I came down south by
accident I
and can only figure out a few stations
on my radio this was broken and I saw
this in the country music in the first
country music song I listened to was
about a guy raising his daughter you
know what it grows up it gets married
like you just know something about like
that cry it was like music it's so
softening of the heart to the heart that
it's a perfect contrast to the strong
man heavy lifting this is my body this
year because you've got an idea it's so
strong that into the body discharge
discharge that good when you vomit love
artists they they they use they love
movies leaves this pharmacy for recently
discharged can't is so full right the
only internet if you drive around
vomiting like I love the videos the bomb
buddy crying like vaginas anyway like
you know these charts this job you feel
good after you know that's what I might
do the biogenic videos yeah so let me
know that you can discharge the emotion
that holds back with the wall holds back
tears where Brian is often Menace
angry behavior so a lot of guys are just
kind of angry like fly off the handle
like it low ratings done it's because
they're holding that it's here is they
want to cry they want to discharge
through their eyes like you're saying
and if they would just express some of
the anger and then let themselves cry
but they would feel like after orgasm
it's almost like in return times which
became they didn't a semester we didn't
Nick Jackson Christine became accident
but what's the value that you do in this
thing but was like now that you know
your master date
yeah it's the same thing it's like you
cannot mistake in silence recharge a
position what we're talking about the
form of the universe that's expanding is
that thing that it's the same principle
so there's charging body the problem is
that we're living in a time where we're
so charged by our iPhones by the
computer to my music everywhere I tell
them in charge charge charge
George and there's no discharge nobody's
exercising there but it's moving the one
is expressing their emotions do what
they do they play video games and they
think that that's a discharge because
there's some tension in their body but
the character is doing about Lulu yeah
when you do when you eat with this is
take these right baby this your kids at
the end that means it's not you that's
Riley
fuck's up here your wire if you think
you're discharged but then WITSEC - Fort
Bragg West more like the middle America
must aspire on the bride and then they
sit there the dilgar comes but they
didn't you just watch through faith when
they reflect the group people do it and
then we have a bunch of because of this
prepper what we do with so many kids who
have no meaning in their library there's
no meaning because they dismiss mind
that the show you some brightness be
doing like they disagree
discharged men dishonored by inserting
themselves into the world and why do you
do get to a point where instead just
something back that's the point you know
why these go hey the child builds things
up with his blocks my son he's three
years old it's the point in staying in
watching he builds up structures with
his blocks and then goes that's great
and that is so symbolic of the nature of
the
we build up so that we can break them in
some cities break down break down but
you know what 25 sports thank you watch
the video maybe they feel the same way
maybe I'll just watch yeah they like
talking about they think about they can
have the greatest conversation I think
everybody about your son it's like is
even trickier because you're talking
about it directly yeah
rather than sport but you're talking
about other people would really think if
I watch the videos they're different
yeah but they do talk about this right
there right right right stop this run
but they're really yeah it's not a
metaphor for discharging I'm actually
saying this yeah butBut yeah butBut then
for like once we discharge a lady
we actually have to do it life is found
in our bodies our world will be more
more than
that's what we're doing that me a little
video like they might be stolen and
medium-haul team yeah derby that's the
most things in it like twenty fifty
years not to bring their people by like
if you like before the machination to
build a cathedral people do it by now
machines but I read this book this guy
was saying our belief industry now is
the preeminent form like you the way you
would make me still think the way they
would build right fifty years later
experience so much stop talking about it
stop thinking about it stop moving in an
abstract world and go and use your body
we're so uncomfortable about our bodies
we're so much physical tension down
between our legs
we're so sexually clenched we think
we're like anaerobic tough
sex we were so sexually liberal that we
have you know what literally naked women
the videos but we plan for sectioning
just as you watch some moves on
there's just physicality being human
being touch one another mean what you
just said is in the flesh is just an
illusion we're spiritually
when you have sex with someone you have
physical closeness with someone the
image is associated with all parts of I
mean if you consider the chakra system
or the don TS there is psychological
energy there's love energy and there's
sexual energy and to really know someone
isn't just fucking we stop at the mind
because abstract wise like I'm never
going to read my blog close physically
anyone watching this video you and I
have this conversation and we're doing
it right the next step beyond that which
is so uncomfortable here is love and
love energy that embraces physicality
because it's in our peripheral nervous
system it's not in our head it's down
here and to touch is to love so for
unites to have a deeper relationship
with one another
or getting too close and it would be too
homosexual but in reality for us to
truly love as a race of human means
we've got an impersonal comfortable
enough in our bodies and then open up
physically to one another doesn't mean
that we have to have physical sex but
hugging one another touching one another
being intimate beyond just the ma at the
hearts you know if we have the same
conversation you and I have the same
conversation you do this I do this