dis confirm our show that the
Netherlands traveled 500 miles from
Scotland to come and see a Liam
fucking amazing there's nothing like
this I'll nothing else like this out
there really highly advise everyone to
go and give this a try amazing
experience the things Elliott shared
with us today are immensely valuable and
i'll definitely be taking them home with
me to my local community this is an
awesome
well worth the time in the many
birthdays my man too much about growing
stronger baby it's life-changing
experience it's been fantastic I think
I've learned a lot and yeah thoroughly
enjoyed it but one of the best days of
my life we'll certainly a day to
remember I think everybody here also
empowered after it was amazing inspiring
and it's just something you need to
experience for yourself i could sell it
to you but if you get to chance to meet
him meet him it makes you feel revalued
in your life again it was amazing I
definitely come again to change my life
change everyone else's life balancing
like I said you'll see me again in the
future Constantine
you