yo Eliot what's up guys today we got a
question for my buddy Ollie and uh Ollie
goes on to ask why doesn't the world
allow us to follow our passion people I
know have this idea that we should work
hard at our jobs that we hate and then
spend our free time following our
passion I don't understand the way the
world works he says I think it'd be
better if everyone followed what they
were interested in if someone's
interested in becoming a teacher they
should be allowed to become a teacher
the same is true if someone wants to
become a strong man or a computer games
programmer yes the world seems to want
to have us on jobs earn money and pay
our taxes could you give me some insight
or advice on how the world works well
and to answer that question no cuz I
don't know how the world works I'm doing
my best to be a decent part of it that's
really the only thing I'm interested in
is is is contributing in some way and
that's just my belief right that's just
my dogma I believe that in order to make
the most of yourself you provide as much
as you can for the people in your
environment in your world and the world
is getting smaller and smaller and
smaller so it's easier and easier to
serve more and more people fantastic
right so so really the question you want
to ask my man is why won't the world pay
you for your passion right and I think a
lot of you guys get some of the things
that I've said in the past about non
jobs and things of that sort a little
screwed up and misunderstood and you're
missing two thirds of the equation when
I say follow your passion there's also
share it share your passion and learn
how to receive there are three fuckin
parts to that guys just because you're
passionate and feely about something
don't mean you're gonna get a paycheck
paycheck Obama is not giving out passion
checks okay if you think that you should
be paid just because you're passionate
about some shit you want to do something
cuz you love it well that's a utopian
world man your passion is only a value
if you can share it what can you do for
someone else with it you see and that's
the second part of the equation there
buddy boy and everybody else watching
this who's all passionate cuz you know I
had a rant in one of my bit my vlog
videos the other day because uh you know
over the course of past eight months I
didn't die and I've been around and I'm
like meeting a lot of you guys and I
keep seeing this pattern of yeah I
dropped out of school so oh great what
you gonna do I don't know oh I quit my
job so what you gonna do I don't know
and you guys think it's courageous cuz
you're just dropping out of shit but you
actually have nothing to offer and it
economics aside I think you're pretty
much a waste of a human being if you
can't offer something Ralph Waldo
Emerson says even if you leave a garden
patch you've been a success in the world
what can you do can you plant the garden
right maybe you don't have to get a job
you could plant a garden and you can eat
your vegetables but you got to do
something cuz you're a human fucking
being you live on earth you live in a
time in a place in a civilization that
requires resources you gotta eat right
now you can go on food stamps that's
always available to you I see there a
guys downtown that have their hand out
waiting for money they have no passion
except how to put their hand out and ask
for money you can do that but you're
still gonna have to put food in your
mouth and guess what if you're
passionate about something and you know
how to share it you're providing
something for someone so that you can
earn back and that's the third part of
the equation which is you've got to know
how to market and sell right
you either market and sell yourself as a
worker as someone who can provide a
service for a bigger company right
somebody who's already done the work you
got to understand that these people that
own companies they've done the work and
perhaps you can be of service
to that entity and you'll get paid right
but you got to be of some value what you
can't just show up and some guys show up
here Eliot I want to be at strength camp
for what what you gonna do mmm can't use
you right you got to be up some value
gotta be up some value to the place that
you're you're offering some good or
service you know you got to market and
sell yourself to someone who's gonna
create a situation where you can earn
some money or if that's not the case for
you you still got to market and sell
yourself to the world
you can't put money in your you can't
put food I mean that's really when I say
money it's really about sustenance
taking care of yourself if you have
nothing to give someone and you don't
know how to receive big part of the
equation a lot of you guys leave out
here so Ollie my man no the world's not
gonna pay you for your passion and you
might not need to be paid for your
passion you can go and do all the lovely
things you want to do if you want to if
you want to follow leaves as they blow
in the wind great but at some point
you're going to have to ask for
resources or you're going to have to
scrounge it up somehow it's just the way
of the world no you can't reject that
you can't leave that part out it doesn't
feel good to know that you do need money
and guess what you do have to pay
fucking taxes right otherwise you go to
jail Hey
you could be real passionate and getting
taken care of in jail
done