what's up y'all today we got a question
from our buddy Casper he says that he's
19 years old I can't seem to accomplish
anything in his life a lot of life ahead
of you buddy don't worry
he says I've tried many things to find
my call but always I end up motivated
and depressed because of all of the
negativity associated with failure
I can't tune myself into finding the one
main goal for my life neither can i I
find mental fog and low energy and then
I get frustrated and aggressive
destroying myself with dangerous
behaviors like alcohol and drugs etc how
do I stop this destructive cycle and
what should I do to find my goal for
life well Casper the very first and most
simple piece that I like to offer you
now it's simple but it's not really easy
meaning it's going to take quite a bit
to really integrate this into who you
are see a lot of times information is
cool and a lot of people you know
they're they're attached and they
worship information ideas but
integrating these things into who you
are requires experience right so that's
one of the things that I offer you guys
when you watch these videos is don't
take my words or anyone's words for
gospel which is just gossip just talking
experience them because only then does
it become true nothing I say is true
until it's integrated into your
personality your consciousness who you
are at a core level the things I share
with you especially if I come at you
with a very deep and profound passion
about the thing I'm talking about isn't
because I've read about it and it
because someone told me about it's
because I've experienced it so it comes
out of my body like it does because it's
a piece of who I am that's why I speak
with my body I am my body and when I
speak to you I give you Who I am
but if you notice there are a lot of
those who of course I'm going on a rant
now there are those who give you
information then there are very embodied
with their language because they don't
own that information it's regurgitate it
bullshit and I don't want you guys to
regurgitate my bullshit make it your own
but make it your own by trying it
out okay and they're multiple different
levels to this so I'm going to begin
like this my friend understand come to
really appreciate and integrate into
your behavior the idea that failure is
necessary failure is success and success
is failure right their implicit they
need each other the more deep and
profound your failure the deep the more
deep and profound your success the more
failures you have the more successes you
will have the darker the night the
brighter the day the harder the ball
hits the ground the higher it goes up do
you understand this is physics of course
it's a metaphysics with the regard to of
the ideas that got our life that would
be it on the stories we tell ourselves
about failure and success but the but
physics still applies fail hard bro go
deep into the failure not only allowing
yourself to have the failure meaning
it's happening to me failures happening
right now but experience the failure for
all it is explore it feel it look at it
from every angle because it is in the
depths of that failure deep in that hole
deep in that darkness that you learn all
the lessons that allow your success to
be that much more profound do you see we
only get attached we all think it
attached to the stories of someone's
success why this guy's successful and
then we hear a couple stories about how
he failed but what we never really do is
get into the experience into the deep
consciousness of that person's failure
and the stories they told themselves
about it the lessons that they taught
themselves about it because they were
aware the entire time what was going on
and not judging it that allows them to
be so freakin successful and awesome
the more your
awesome the more you're a sucker and a
failure the more you have the potential
to be awesome to be great to be a
success but it all depends on the story
you tell yourself about the
circumstances when I fail I tell myself
resourceful stories about the failure
and I don't get attached to the
circumstances meaning I lose a thousand
dollars in an investment I lose ten
thousand dollars in investment now the
circumstances can make you depressed can
make you as you say become unmotivated
and start drinking because I lost ten
thousand dollars and you know what
someone who's attached to the
circumstances will do they won't they
won't begin delving into and telling
themselves repeated repeatedly telling
themselves stories about how bad it is
it took me eight months to save ten
thousand dollars and it's gone in five
minutes oh you know what I had to do
there in the ten thousand dollars I bet
those assholes stole it from me it's
just and they're using it to buy
prostitutes and alcohol and drugs and
you start you can really go into because
it's all stories we do this to ourselves
never think you're not telling yourself
stories you're always telling yourself
stories always all we know ourselves by
the stories now these stories brainwash
you that's why you know are in it and
not only in our ancestral culture did we
sit around fires and the and the elders
told stories because that's how they
brainwash the children but we have
Disney today no we have TV they
brainwash us with what stories it's all
fucking stories this whole thing we come
to know it by stories the beautiful
thing is you can tell yourself any story
you want stop telling yourself on
resourceful stories about your failure
cuz I think gonna help you get out of it
it's going to make you go deeper and
deeper into the depression into the into
the sickness of the failure and it's
your fault at that point when failure
happens because of circumstances is not
really always your fault but when you
stay in the depression and the
unmotivated 'no sand the alcohol
is associated with the pain that's your
fault I lose $10,000 I immediately begin
telling myself stories about why it was
supposed to happen I believe everything
was supposed to happen everything's
supposed to happen everything happens
for a reason now I don't have scientific
proof fuck scientific proof it's a story
in fact science is a story and it's a
story that helps me it might be complete
bullshit I like to believe there's a god
that's producing these failures for me
because each one of these failures is
like God being my coach saying Elliott
pick up a little bit of a heavier weight
cuz I want you to get stronger God is my
bullshit story and I love it and God
being my coach giving me failures
because it's heavier weights for me to
grow stronger with is my story and I
love it be okay with telling yourself
bullshit if it's going to help you my
bullshit got us here you're watching me
because I'm a good bullshitter i
bullshitted myself into making these
videos in fact there are times when I'm
very depressed about some of the
feedback about my videos it hurts my
heart and you wanna do tell myself a
story about why I gotta keep making them
I feel like a failure tell yourself a
story about why that failure is
necessary for your success in fact don't
even call it failure call it a lesson my
friend
as far as discovering your way the thing
you're going to do the thing you're
going to be your calling you call it my
man it's all about the story you tell
yourself once again and that story as
with all stories are dynamic they
constantly change because your
circumstances are constantly changing
especially if your story starts coming
true in the world you all these things
change life is not a linear process life
is this weird dynamic mix of shit
happening all over the place with energy
from other people from yourself from the
food you eat from the way the stars are
aligned I'm not an astral odd what does
it cost Rolla gist or or someone who
studies the positions of the stars but I
guarantee you that that's a fascinating
story go into astrology and figure out
hey why is shits up for me right now the
stars are aligned in a weird way every
time I happen to read my astrology which
I use to be spot-on I like that story
and I read it brainwash yourself my
friends that's really my my invitation
here I'll give you one last piece is
that you know I I don't aim to make
these videos sound bites I really want
to get delve into your your issue who
you are issues are usually the
manifestation of who you are and you you
mentioned to me a little piece of who
you are and you said that you that I
Elliott Hulse is like a father figure
that you've never had you never had a
father a lot of times the experiences
that we have in life that are out of our
control then embed stories into our
consciousness that we are completely
unaware of and unless we take time to
explore the emotion the feelings in our
body associated with it and its Ross and
realist until we allow that to happen
we're going to have a very difficult
time doing what I said just now and
that's telling yourself better stories
because a lot of those pains are trapped
in your body explore the pain associated
with not having a tangible father figure
a real one there with you deal with the
pain associated with that because I I
know a big part of it is what's holding
you back from experiencing the successes
that you should have on the flip side
come to know yourself my friends but not
only coming to know yourself but begin
to create yourself see where you are
assess your hurts your pains your
circumstances be real about it and then
develop a fairy tale about how you're
going to deal with it done