so our buddy Lloyd is in love by
accident he found this girl on Facebook
right and she lives 1,300 miles away I
think he lives in Northern Europe and
she lives in northern Africa so it's
quite a distance away and she also
happens to be Muslim and he doesn't
describe what religion he has I'm not
even sure if he he has a religion but he
sees these as obstacles Geographic lock
obstacles as well as ideological
obstacles but he's in love okay so this
is here's what I'm gonna do and here's
what I often do and some of you guys get
this and some of you guys don't I don't
really answer your questions a lot of
times most of the times because I'm
looking at the context through which
you're asking this question I'm looking
at this situation from afar and I'm also
looking at who you are as opposed to the
content of the situation so you know I
can answer this and and entangle with
the fact that you know there's a
geographic distance from you and the
whole religious thing that's going to
make a lot of people upset but the fact
is the problem is not the distance and
it's not the religion the problem is
you're in love I once heard that you
should never trust someone who is in
love because when you are in love you
are literally in balance in such a way
that you're thinking all with your heart
and balls and your mind has completely
been turned off right and I often talk
about breathing into your balls trusting
your heart but recognize that it is a
balance between Father Son Holy Spirit
they are the Trinity they have to work
together it can't be all head which it
is for a lot of people they never fall
in love they never have any warm
feelings it can't be all balls because
then it's like you know there would be
anarchy you know a weird kind of anarchy
not that people can't take care of
themselves but you know everybody would
be acting based on their instinct all
the time without consideration for love
abstract ideas of the such
as well as thinking you know you gotta
fucking think you still got to use your
head
I often invite you to trust your body
trust your feelings but do not let it
rule you and forget your head and when
you're in love this is just a biological
response so it's not that you did the
wrong thing
the problem is you cannot make decisions
when one the third of that triad is
turned off and when you're in love we've
all been in love I've fallen in love is
the difference between loving someone
and falling in love falling literally
means you're swept off your feet why do
you think they say fall because you're
not standing on your ground you are not
grounded bro do not even consider making
any type of big decisions when you are
in love
explore the love experience it to its
fullest pulling with it write poetry
send her pictures be in it as it is
experience it feel it and and enjoy it
but do not make any life-altering
decisions okay because you're going to
find that eventually and this is always
the case that you Fork feeling of
sociated with letting go falling in love
which is so great you're on a fucking
cloud goes away and then you're left
with the mess and the mess for you it's
going to look like you know her parents
might want to kill you your parents
might want to kill her there is a
distance between you that's going to
cause her to be stripped from her family
and I don't know what that looks like
and for you to be stripped from your
home there's a lot to be considered now
it doesn't mean that you can't choose to
go down that route that's a beautiful
route I'm always telling people to be
courageous about the steps that they
take in their life and never let other
people's opinions and other people's
conditionings rule you so you may want
to do that you might want to deal with
that but don't decide to deal with that
while you're in love decide to deal with
that when you're thinking practically
when you're thinking pragmatically see
people are courageous in love but then
when there's
ending on the ground they chose I spoken
about this in the video last week they
don't realize that now now the work
begins dude so you're going to face a
lot of shit
be prepared too late face a lot of shit
if you decide to make this decision but
don't do it just yet spend some time
talking to her thinking about it being
practical just for a moment maybe a
little bit maybe maybe a month from now
experience the love but don't make any
big decisions dude never trust the man
who's in love peace