yeah what's up man hey nice drew comes
your dream come true
that's great what's up oh man how are
you I'm good man you look great man you
really like that bodybuilder
oh no I just started like did I get any
sleep today me ask you questions it do
you feel more neurotic never bustle
I feel so much better when I have less
Momo so I had it's like we have
psychological funny because I'm much of
anything makes you crazy yeah you get me
buddy
oh talking are people looking at it's
hard to maintain - my thing is gotta be
able to breathe how to grieve you know a
lot of crazy shit I talked about yeah
hey so how are you this is brian of the
time Thank You cake right actually
jacket yellow he guess which is the
policy okay well I mean the way he's
dressed
he's a complete kinetic pop he looks
like he's ready to do something with the
way he's dressed
yeah this guy is a yeah any safer to her
you know what is that I wasn't rich
enough for a whole week you guys wanna
come inside yeah yeah I drove I drove
for I let me out so I'm scared you spoke
at augustana lot because I'm protected
when you were kids
yeah it one of my home after them I'm
starting to get that side of you with
your life was here because I don't
oh I'll just walk away as you like
because I've been muscles yeah you know
what that's fine and you stepped on my
shoes okay and watch it off but but I'm
leaving right now
I don't know fucking stupidest thing in
the world and butt
[Music]
which are basically is one of the
quintessential questions out community
quality is do you want to be loved fear
and what you're thinking about no you
are in no way
if you're trying anything or crazy it's
because your feet are to actually walk
so you're all your power comes from fear
absolutely but if you have to be loved
your Bofur and I'll say when I
oh when I like hit my videos some people
hum guru pickleball is a meanness oh
yeah different means here in the story
so I rush he's like that all the time
I also help that you I your pupils are
so low so light yeah you know in
diminishing returns that disappoint
everything like you went out my eyeballs
I was thinking about zombies like if you
like completely wide incite the opposite
you have no soul goes too far
diminishing return like the money thing
you know it's like we view homeless they
even get money more money you're happier
but then you get to a point where it
doesn't make people keep thinking that
way they keep thinking that out because
when I didn't have money have a little
bit and I'm happier then it means that
when I have more money I'm happier right
but then we get to a point where it is
somebody's falls off like even you know
yeah you guys like money is no longer
everyone said that you're poor to the
degree then worried about money
yeah so if you have a very little bit
amount of money but you're not thinking
about money yeah yeah it's like a
byproduct then you're not necessarily as
poor yeah yeah it's sort of thinking
about is money
yeah well money
yeah worry about the places head tech
happiness if you see crap here as itself
see yeah it's like then you know yeah
hola even if your CP happens you're
striving so hard to get it that anxiety
here is it very effort that yeah same
stem with ice aesthetic like like when I
was tricked like you know lock you look
really good but they they training for
strength and like power that it's like a
byproduct like spinners are just so
aesthetic but they're on the trim
prosthetics no yeah yeah but but evv we
can sprint 100 meters like in nine point
five seconds you can look at steady you
got yeah if I evey key if you look like
I say it doesn't mean that you can't
spring you know right right so I find
that interesting going back to
authenticity yeah leaving bodybuilding
like you look like it yeah believe is
impossible
yeah yeah yeah you know we're an
authentic body right now yeah right
right so it looks good because it is
fucking good yeah you know so the neck
goes to get back to what we're
describing about 10 Tennessee alright
you know we are we constantly trying to
put on and live up to particular facade
or are we just going to be ourself right
and it's been my experience that there's
no better strategy than just being
yourself there leaning to your heart can
you change your state just decide I will
be grounded yeah yeah
learn to control your state learn to
control your energy just like cheese
whoa yeah there's a way and if you come
to a class of maturity where you can
control the energy in your life like
right now you don't want to see her when
I see her my lancia pictures and I'm
gonna terrible right now when I see her
pictures and I like even when you get
cut like when I see you muscles like you
don't look like bodybuilder but like
it's weird just like you're you're like
your own your your you know your own
like unique like action figure like you
like you see all this body but they all
look the same right on the stage right
right base we're like maybe the way you
train the way you live like you're your
body just looks different like if I if I
carve your head I can just see like to
LA house right
but if I cut off like J color or what
whoever likes hardtail yeah it's weird
[Music]
you're powerful person that you can
control you know what you're told me out
don't out but you cannot really go it's
a game like everything else yeah Pima
this is just like like that nothing like
when I was doing my part
because like I'm like right here right
then like oh my Energy's like oh my god
let me give you back I wish I could go
back I can't do that very well what
you're just like a cat laser being in
community with right radius
Mikey's Fitness yes because you follow
might happen yeah so I'm going to sew
and you're like laser beam so I'm really
out of a person would be able to go from
son born to later be hot and from a
candy box so whenever they want
see I accept for me to be laser to be in
sharp but I naturally have a son one so
I work with Harvey would be and what I
see in you is just out you might
it might be beneficial for you to learn
how to not be so focused on time come
out out of it and see a bigger picture
and be a more of a soft warming nourish
a character because look at the sunset
laser beam the architects slowly too
much see some of those five but because
the Sun is bigger more nourishes of the
air so not good or bad you can see my
doing ownership where you're a focus to
use the body to manifest one yeah
because I'd like to when I was doing my
head like serves the artist and it all
right they're just you know they're
skinny and it
this is look stupid like I look stupid
but they're shutting down in her home
form understanding that if they have to
be way ours
yeah type this in their bodyguard in the
missing out the interests of the world
like right you know to their head and a
body that Irish the peripheral nervous
system are like a rule system ever for
the flower to you cannot really truly
flower if your root system is weeds
actors you have to stretch your neck
to be able to really produce how about
results
yeah because the body is the only thing
that you can interact with all right
waiting to catch