got a question here from one of our
17-year old buddies so you know towards
the end of high school this is
definitely one of those transitionary
periods in life and he's an a-level
student he says so essentially he's been
doing everything that a good boy should
be doing up until this point right an
a-level student all throughout high
school but he's reaching a point now
where he's battling with this problem of
procrastination he gets everything he
needs or supposed to get done done but
he waits until the last minute before he
does it
and then he it upsets him because he's
dragging all the anxiety about having to
do the fucking thing then he friggin
does it he always does a good job but
he's like man I wish I didn't carry you
know three weeks of anxiety I wish I
just would have fucking done the thing
when I was supposed to do it
procrastinate with everything especially
the schoolwork
he's doing well but he suffers with this
inability to get shit done when it's
supposed to get done right except for
one thing
when it comes to rugby or playing sports
athleticism he's right on top of it
yo call rugby he's there well whistle
he's there no hesitation whatsoever this
is the thing that he wants to do there
is no procrastination in fact he could
probably do it all day long right so the
question really is let me just get to
the to the bottle I'm here bottom line
here is uh you know you have any advice
you know I've suffered from depression
for about a year after losing someone
close to me okay sort of relevant but
I'm not gonna go down that route but
basically how do I deal with this
procrastination really interesting stuff
so essentially your procrastination is
the lion growing in you I'm gonna tell
you what I mean in a moment but
essentially you're becoming a man and
you're moving into a new phase in your
life where you're beginning to say no I
won't but you keep it sort of passive
aggressive because you can't say that to
your teacher fuck you I ain't doing this
classwork fuck you I ain't taking the
test no I'm not going to class you can't
you can't can't do that right because
you're still a camel tell you what I
mean in a moment and ultimately this is
a journey to becoming the strongest
version of yourself or form
wisdom that is encapsulated in another
metaphor which is the child so what am I
talking about what is Eliot talking
about if you've ever read thus Spoke
darah kustra there are through stir this
is Nietzsche of course like I I can't
pronounce half the shit that he he
writes but this is this is a metaphor
that's used in this book by Frederick
Nietzsche where he describes the
evolution the spiritual evolution of the
man where he goes from the beginning
stages of his life he's physically and
spiritually emotionally immature and he
calls this your camo stage Zarathustra
right I think I said all right this is
the camel stage of your revolution what
is the camel the camel is a beast of
burden you basically are at a stage in
your life from birth you know where you
start walking and talking and they start
teaching you shit they start laying
burdens on your shoulders right Society
your parents teachers religion they
start low putting things on your
shoulders you're a beast of burden until
about the age of you know about 17 like
kind of like you know where you're at
right now will you bow down what does
the camel do it's such a great metaphor
beautiful beautiful passage in the book
he boughs down and the world is loading
his back with burdens you're a beast of
fucking burden you're supposed to go to
school you're supposed to pass your
tests are supposed to do your homework
you're supposed to clean your bedroom
you're supposed suppose suppose supposed
to both supposed to poza right all the
things you're supposed to do all the
conditioning and lay it upon you all the
beliefs that you've been given they're
not yours a lot of us think we have our
own beliefs I've got my own beliefs no
you know no you have not developed your
own beliefs your own ideas your own
conditioning you have not become a lion
just yet until that camel at about that
age where you start exploring and
questioning just a little bit if you if
you're a mature individual you don't
question that means is new no
inclination towards maturity in you but
you're you know most of us in this day
and age with the internet and you know
so much ideas being proliferate
of course we're gonna mature right here
in all this other shit and I'm asked to
do all this stuff stuff here what's
going on sorry about 17 years old
you've been all that has been laid on
your shoulders right beasts of burden
now travels out into the desert this is
the world you're going to either go to
college you're gonna go and get a career
but essentially you're now sort of free
right we've extended college we have me
we could extend college that's all
you're fuckin you know 3040 years old it
depends on when you want to grow up but
essentially you're now going out into
the world so that camel stands up
beautiful metaphor and wanders out into
the desert with this giant load on its
back
and he meets a dragon and the dragons
name is thou shalt thou shalt is this
dragon and on every one of his little
pieces of you know dragon scales there's
as thou shalt there's a belief there is
a there's an admonition there's
something that you you're supposed to do
all these supposed to that the world
tells us it's all over this dragon here
comes this dragon thou shalt thou shout
in your way you're carrying this burden
that the world is laid upon you and it
is your responsibility as a maturing
individual to slay that dragon because
one of two things will happen you either
bow down and you continue to live your
life as a bee burst beasts of burden and
you allow thou shalt to control you so
now that dragon rules your life a lot of
us live that way or you slay that
fucking dragon
right this is kind of where you are
right now all that procrastination is
because you feel this anxiety between
you know all this stuff is being laid
upon me but I really don't want to do
this you're out in the desert right now
you start it you started you're sort of
out there and you're meeting this dragon
thou shalt thou shalt your
responsibility at this point and I know
it's your responsibility this is your
plight because you're asking me this
fucking question is to slay that fucking
dragon and by slaying that dragon you
become a lion and that Lions name and
his attitude is I will and no so the
know goes towards all the things that
the world has told you you're supposed
to do thou shalt you destroy the dragon
with your no no no see right now you
can't do it that way because you're
still living in the confines you're
still bowed down you're still you but
you're about to get up
you're still bowed down as that camel
but you're about to get up remember this
my friend the now as you're walking is
you're on your own four feet as that
camel and out into the desert and at
this point no one can do this for you
your parents are not there for you
anymore because you're becoming a man
your most powerful position against the
dragon of thou shalt is your no and once
you slay that dragon with your no you
begin a new journey in your ever
spiritual evolution as a man and that is
your I will now how many of us even make
it that far that become a man of I will
now you go out there and the lion is
completely hysterical he's rebellious
he's angry ah it was at everybody's
heads off heads off and he just uses
pure will that's why his new power is
called I will
you're living out of your you're living
out of this part of your body right now
this is where your will is of course I'm
talking about other things but follow me
this is your heart this is your
breathing this is your solar plexus that
which combusts and manifests in your
body does so in your life now it's the
will you build up your will you go out
there and you do have a fuck you wanna
do you go and you choose the type of
woman you want you choose the type of
career you want you to step your
business you want you choose whether or
not you want to go into business you
decide you want what type of poetry you
want to involve yourself in type of art
you go out there now and you exert your
will the way you want to and thou shalt
has already died so you do it out of
your own sense of purpose and strength
and this is where you'll be for quite a
while and this is where you'll find your
greatest successes and your deepest
hurts when you become that lion and you
need to go through it you need to go
through those very difficult and
treacherous times challenge discomfort
hunger as a lion because a lion doesn't
bow down to nobody right he'll starve
for he boughs to the other animals ain't
bowing fucker he killed that dragon for
a reason kill me or I'll starve that's
the attitude of the lion this has been
my attitude in the attitude that I've
been sharing with you guys through these
videos for the past several years it's
the attitude of the lion that I will the
know that you used to slay that fucking
dragon and the I will but you'll carry
with you to succeed in that next
evolution of your life
and I can't speak very very eloquently
or in any type of coherent way about the
next phase which is the child to become
a child again it's a full circle but
it's not an immaturity as in you know
baby child there's a sense of peace and
joy and pleasure but also grounding
associated with all the things that the
society has taught you you know how to
read and write write baby doesn't have
to read write read and write know how to
calculate and how to think you know how
to you've got wisdom it's the wisdom of
the child but it's a full circle type
wisdom just for perspective me in my
life at this point that's sort of where
I feel myself going I have all very
quickly
thirty-four years old and I'm the lion
is kind of almost dead in me or has
growing into that child but that's me
keep watching my videos for the next ten
years and I'll talk to you about that
next evolution watch these ones right
this is ten years after this video has
been created watch this one and know
that if you're 1718 up till about 27
perhaps thirty four years old you're in
a lion phase right now what you're
experiencing is the is the dissonance
this is Comfort between the the old
passing away in the new coming forth
good luck bro be a lion