so in more than one occasion I've heard
someone say or I've read comments that
sound a bit like this that guy Elliott
Hulse he's pretty interesting but
everything he says is common sense
somehow seeking to dilute the messages I
bring across in these videos so the very
first thing you've got to understand is
that none of this is common sense what
you're talking about is common think so
there's a difference between thinking
something and sensing something to think
something means that you know it in your
head so obese people know in their head
that exercise and eating right will make
them not fat but they don't sense it
because sensing is an action of the body
sensing sanctioning happens in the body
right we have senses that aren't
necessarily tied to the conscious brain
to the thinking brain right or what we
would call the thinking brain they're
more tied to the vegetative nervous
system that part of the brain that
thinks without you having to think about
it and that's where senses come from so
when I say things that seem pretty
common thinkable it's because those
ideas are simply in people's heads and
they could go around spilling them all
day long they've watched my videos
they've read books they live on earth a
lot of these I none of these ideas are
new but they're not common sense when
you actually put them into practice and
feel them in your body because of your
experience then it becomes common sense
until then it's just common fucking
think